import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as k,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},x={class:"review-content"};function S(e,a,s,h,t,u){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",x,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const M=g(q,[["render",S],["__scopeId","data-v-8e4e02e6"]]),C=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：哪个法案于1820年确立了一个州的自由州和奴隶州平衡？","answer":"答案：1820年通过的密苏里妥协法案确立了一个州的自由州和奴隶州平衡。《密苏里妥协法案》（Missouri Compromise），于1820年通过。密苏里妥协是美国历史上一项重要的立法，旨在解决奴隶制问题，尤其是在新领土的扩张问题上。随着美国向西扩张，关于新领土是否应该容许奴隶制引起了激烈的争论。"},{"question":"لخص المقال التالي: السترات الرياضية متاحة بزرين أو بثلاثة أزرار، وكلما زادت الأزرار طال الخط الناشئ عن غلقها كلها. ينصح بغلق أزرار السترة عند الوقوف وفكها عند الجلوس في العموم، كما يشيع لبعض الناس فك الأزرار عند المشي.  يرجع لك أمر اختيار طريقة ارتداء السترة تمامًا، إذ لست ملزمًا بغلق كل الأزرار أو فكها في أي وقت ولكن غلقها عند الوقوف يبدو أفضل ويساعد في تنحيف قوامك. أغلق الزر العلوي فقط إذا كان هناك عدة أزرار بالسترة. قد يكون المعطف الخارجي ضروريًا في الطقس شديد البرودة حتى لو كنت ترتدي سترة رياضية. لا تنس وضع الطقس في اعتبارك وتجنب تقليل الثياب. المعاطف الصوفية ومعاطف الطيارين ومعاطف الخندق جميعها تلائم السترة الرياضية، وستضطر لاختيارها في الغالب بألوان أحادية هادئة: الأسود أو الرمادي أو الأخضر الداكن أو البيج. السترات الرياضية متعددة الاستعمالات في الإطلالات اليومية لكنها جيدة بما يكفي للمناسبات الرسمية. قد يكون من المقبول ارتداؤها في العمل - حسب مقر عملك- وفي ممارسة الرياضات، كما أنها ستكون جيدة إذا تواجدت في مكان يستلزم ارتداء السترات.   السترة الرياضية للبيت والمطعم والحانة وعند المشرب وعند طلب أحد الأصدقاء لتناول العشاء. تشمل الألوان الجيدة للمناسبات الاجتماعية البيج والبني والكريمي والكاكي والبرونزي والأبيض وكلما كانت الألوان أفتح قلت ملاءمتها للمناسبات الرسمية. قد لا تلائم السترات الرياضية المناسبات الرسمية – خاصة ذات النقوش الزاهية – لذا اختر سترة بذلة أو بليزر. لا ترتد سترة متسخة أو مجعدة أو تيشيرت بولو وتخرج ياقته. يجب الحفاظ على السترات في حالة جيدة وتنظيفها تنظيفًا جافًا بانتظام ليظل شكلها جميلًا، وفي العموم يجب ألا تعرض السترة للتنظيف الجاف أكثر من مرة كل 6 أشهر.  نصيحة للميزانية: في رواية Theophilus North لثورنتون وايلدر كانت الشخصية الرئيسية تملك بذلة واحدة وكان عليه ضغطها كل يوم بين زنبركات السرير والمرتبة لتظل مفرودة ونظيفة. قد لا تحتاج لفعل كل هذا لكن كي سترتك بانتظام سيساعد في الحفاظ على شكلها الجيد.","answer":"يمكن تلخيص المقال كما يلي:يسلط المقال الضوء على السترات الرياضية ويقدم نصائح حول كيفية ارتدائها بشكل صحيح. يشدد المقال على غلق أزرار السترة عند الوقوف لتحقيق مظهر أنيق وتنحيف القوام. يشير أيضًا إلى أن استخدام معاطف خارجية قد يكون ضروريًا في ظروف الطقس البارد. يُشجع على الحفاظ على نظافة السترة وتنظيفها بانتظام للحفاظ على مظهرها الجيد. وأخيرًا، يلفت الانتباه إلى استخدام السترات الرياضية في مجموعة متنوعة من المناسبات، سواء في الحياة اليومية أو في المناسبات الرسمية، مع التركيز على اختيار الألوان المناسبة للسياق."},{"question":"வினா:யானைக்கும் பானைக்கும் சரி என்ற கதையை உம் சொந்தநடையில் கூறுக.","answer":"விடை:மரியாதை இராமனிடம் வந்த விசித்திரமான வழக்கு இது.உழவரின் மீது அரபு வணிகர் தொடுத்த வழக்கு.ஓர் உழவர் தம் மகன் திருமண விழாவில் ஊர்வலம் விடுவதற்காக அரபு வணிகர் ஒருவரிடம் யானையை இரவல் கேட்டார். அவரும் கொடுத்தார். ஊர்வலத்தின்போது யானை இறந்துவிட்டது.அரபு வணிகர் யானையைத் திருப்பித் தரும்படி கேட்கிறார்.உழவரோ, “யானை ஊர்வலத்தில் தற்செயலாக இறந்துவிட்டதாகவும், மாற்றாக வேறு யானை வாங்கித் தருவதாகவும் அல்லது யானைக்குரிய விலையைத் தருவதாகவும் நான் கூறினேன். ஆனால் வணிகர் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளாமல் அடம்பிடிக்கிறார்,” என்று கூறினார்.உண்மையை அறிந்த மரியாதை இராமன், இருவரையும் பார்த்து, “நீங்கள் இருவரும் நாளை நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு வாருங்கள்” என்று கூறி அனுப்பினார். பின்னர் உழவரைத் தனியாக அழைத்து, தான் ஆள் அனுப்பும்போது வந்தால் போதும் என்றார். பிறகு அவரிடம், “வீட்டுக் கதவிற்குப் பின் பழைய பானைகளை அடுக்கி வைத்து, கதவைத் தாழ்ப்பாள் போடாமல் வைத்திருங்கள்” என்று கூறி அனுப்பி விட்டார்.மரியாதை இராமன் கூறியபடி உழவர் செய்தார். வணிகர் உழவரை நீதிமன்றத்திற்கு அழைப்பதற்காக வேகமாக வந்து கதவைத் திறந்தார். பானைகள் விழுந்து உடைந்தன. உழவர் வணிகரிடம், “அப்பானைகள் காலங்காலமாக வைத்திருந்த பழம் பானைகள். இவற்றை உடைத்துவிட்டீரே, எனக்கு இதே பானைகளைத் திருப்பித் தாருங்கள்,” என்று சத்தமிட்டார். வணிகர் செய்வதறியாமல் திகைத்தார்.வணிகர் நடந்ததை மரியாதை இராமனிடம் கூறினார். மரியாதை ராமன் வணிகரிடம் “நீங்கள் இறந்துபோன யானையை உயிருடன் திருப்பிக் கேட்கிறீர். அவர் உடைந்த பழம்பானைகள் வேண்டும் என்று கேட்கிறார். நீங்கள் பானையைக் கொடுத்தால் அவர் யானையைக் கொடுத்துவிடுவார்” என்று கூறினார். வணிகர் தன்னால் பழைய பானைகளைத் தரமுடியாது என்றார்.மரியாதை இராமன் ”உங்களால் திருப்பித் தர முடியாது என்றால் அவரால் மட்டும் எப்படித் திருப்பித் தர முடியும்” என்றார். ஆதலால் யானைக்கும் பானைக்கும் சரியாகப் போய்விட்டது’ என்று தீர்ப்பளித்தார்."},{"question":"حاول تستنتج العلاقة بين الجملتين اللى جايين، توافق - تناقض - مفيش علاقة.الجملة الأولى: الأيس كريم مبيعاته بتعلى فى الصيف.الجملة التانية: الناس بتستهلك المثلجات فى الصيف.","answer":"بالتأكيد، الجملة الثانية توافق الجملة الأولى."},{"question":"வினா: மகாராஷ்டிராவில் அமைந்துள்ள அஜந்தா குகைகள் யாருடைய ஆட்சி காலத்தில் கட்டப்பட்டது?","answer":"விடை: மகாராஷ்டிராவில் அமைந்துள்ள அஜந்தா குகைகள் குப்த ஆட்சியாளர்களின் காலத்தில் கட்டப்பட்டவை."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਹਾਲ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ?","answer":"ਵਦੀਆ ਜੀ, ਆਪ ਜੀ  ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹੋ  "},{"question":"Суроо: Жасалма интеллект (AI) деген эмне?","answer":"Жооп: AI - бул адамдын интеллект процесстерин компьютер менен моделдөө. Анын ичине окуу, кеп түшүнүү, оозеки сүйлөп берүү, ой жүгүртүү, көйгөйлөрдү чечүү жана чечим кабыл алуу кирет."},{"question":" Chọn câu đúng:A. 6 ∈ NB. 9 ∉ NC.  – 9 ∈ ND. -19 ∈ Z","answer":"Lời giảiTa có:+ Vì – 6 là số nguyên âm, không phải số tự nhiên nên – 6 ∉ N, do đó A sai. + Vì 9 là số tự nhiên nên 9 ∈ N , do đó B sai. + Vì – 9 là số nguyên âm, không phải số tự nhiên nên – 9 ∉ N , do đó C sai. + Vì -19 là số nguyên âm nên -19 ∈ Z  , do đó D đúng.Chọn đáp án D."},{"question":"Àwọn Àdúgbò Oyé-Èkìtì","answer":"1. Ijisẹ:- Àdúgbò ti a n pen i Ijisẹ ni o fẹ ilu Ọye do lati Ile Ifẹ wa. Wọn pa erin ibi ti ẹrin náà ku si iba ni wọn pe ni atẹba ẹni to pa erin náà ni ọlọta aburo ijise ibi ti wọn pa erin náà si ni wọn pe ni ijisẹ. Ijisẹ lo pa àwọn ara Ọyẹ wa lati ile ifẹ pe wọn ti ri ibi tí wọn magbe. Ijisẹ ni orisu ilu Ọyẹ lati ile-ifẹ wa.2. Ọgbọ mẹta :- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni àwọn ara ọgbọ mẹta ti si wa ki wọn to tẹ̀dó si ilu Ọyẹ.3. Ọmọdọwa:- Ibi jẹ agbegbe ti ọba ilu maa n gbe.4. Ire:- Aburo Oloye ni Àdúgbò to wa ni Iyeni, Ọde ni se idi ti o fi ń de ade ogun5. Ulọdo:- Ibe ni wọn ti se ọdẹ6. Ilẹsẹ:- Àdúgbò yi kọ de igọsi ko si de ilu Ọyẹ wọn wa ni arin meji.7. Ilẹdara:- Orukọ ti àdúgbò yi jẹ wa lati ile-ifẹ wa ni wọn tun jẹ ni ìgba ti wọn de ilu Ọyẹ.8. Odo:- ibi ti àdúgbò yi deto si je egbe odọ.9. Iwaro:- Oni imọlẹ kan ti wọn máa ń jo ni ibẹ ìdí ti wọn fi pe ni ìwarọ ni yẹn.10. Ijagun:- Awọn ti on jagun ni wọn gbe ni àdúgbò yìi.11. Oke-Ọfa:- Apa oke ni àdúgbo naa wa12. Ayegbaju:- Wọn tun pe àdúgbò yi ni odo-oje nitori pe ẹgbẹ odo ni ilu náà wa.13. Ẹgbẹ:- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni àwọn ara ẹgbẹ ti si wa ki wọn to wa si mọ àwọn ara ijisẹ.14. Ijagẹmọ:- Àwọn ara àdúgbò yin i a mọ si ologun tàbí onija láti ìle-ifẹ wa. Igbati wọn de ilu Ọyẹ wọn sit un pe wọn ni ijagẹmọ nitorí ija wọn.15. Ilogbo:- àdúgbo yi jẹ pàtàkì ni ìlú Ọye, Ijalọ po púpọ̀ si arin wọn itorí náà ni wọn ni ọmọ orin yọyọ ilugbo.16. Ilupeju:- Ireko ilu Ọyẹ ni, àwọn ni wọn máa ń sin ọba Ọyẹ wọn máa ń pe jọ si ilu Ọyẹ láti ba ọba ji roro, ìdí ti wọn fi pe wọn ni ilupeju.17. Orisunmíbare:- Wọn jẹ àdúgbò ti o ko owo ati oríṣìíríṣìí dukiya wa si ilu Ọyẹ, àwọn ara Ọyẹ ri pe ọlọrọ ni wọn jẹ ni wọn se pe wọn ni orísunmibare.18. Esọ sin :- àdúgbò yi ti wọn pe ni esọ sin jẹ ara àwọn ti ogun ko wa lati ile- ifẹ.19. Ile ya o :- Ogun ko wọn láti Iyao wa si ìlú Ọyẹ ti wọn wa ya ile gbe ni ilu Ọyẹ ni wọn fi ń pe ni ile-yao.20. Ileesa:- Wọn jẹ àdúgbò to ji náà si ìlú nitorí wọn ko ogùn ba ilu púpọ̀.21. Ilẹmọ:- O wa lati ile-ifẹ wa si ilu Ọyẹ wọn si kin jẹ iyọ ni àdúgbọ̀ yi.22. Ipamọ:- wọn jẹ ọmọ ìya si ilẹmọ, wọn jẹ ara ilẹmọ ìdí ti wọn fi ń pe ni ilẹmọ ni yen.23. Idọfin:- Ọ̀nà mẹrin ni àwọn ara àdúgbò yi ti si wa kì wọn to para po wa si Ijisẹ.24. Irare:- Ilare ni wọn jẹ ni ilẹ-Ifẹ wọn wa ń jẹ́ irare ni ìgbati wọn de ilu Ọyẹ.25. Oke ìyin-Araroni:- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni wọn ti si wa26. Iyeni:- jẹ àdúgbò ti wọn ti jẹ orogun ni ilu Ọyé.27. Asara:- àdúgbò yìí jẹ ibi àwọn ìransẹ ọba ń gbe.28. Oloyagba:- Iya gba ni ogun tí ki wọn wa sí ilu Ọyẹ ni wọn se ń jẹ oloyagbe. 29. Ibẹru:- Ọlota ni aburo Ijise lati ile ifẹ wa nígbati wọn de Ọyẹ iberu ati Ijisẹ wa yapa o sit un jẹ àdúgbò ti o bẹru ogun tàbí ija púpọ̀.30. Imijẹ:- Àdúgbò yii wa láti ilu Itapu iṣẹ ọdẹ ni baba ń la wa n se. Iṣẹ yii lo se wa si ilu Ọyẹ ìdí ti wọn fi tẹ̀dó si ìlú Ọyẹ ni èyí."},{"question":"கேள்வி : சமணர்களின் தமிழ்த் தொண்டினை விளக்குக.","answer":"பதில் : சமணர்களின் தமிழ்த் தொண்டுசமண சமயம் தமிழகம் வந்த பிறகு தமிழறிஞர்கள் பலர் சமணத்தைத் தழுவினர். ஊன் உணவு இல்லாத காய்கறி உணவை இப்போது சைவ உணவு எனக் கூறுகிறோம். ஆனால், பழங்காலத்தில் இவ்வகை உணவு ஆருகத உணவு எனப்பட்டது. ஆருகதம் என்பது சமணத்தின் மற்றொரு பெயர் ஆகும். மகாவீரர் என்ற சமணப் பெரியவர் மோட்சம் அடைந்த நாளே தீபாவளி ஆகும். இதனை இந்து சமயம் பிற்காலத்தில் தங்களுடைய விழாவாக ஆக்கிக் கொண்டது. இவ்வாறு மக்களின் வாழ்வில் பல மாற்றங்களை ஏற்படுத்திய சமணர்கள், இலக்கிய, இலக்கணங்கள், நிகண்டுகள், சிறு பிரபந்தங்கள் ஆகியவற்றை இயற்றித் தமிழை வளமுடையதாக்கினர்.இலக்கியம்சங்க காலத்தில் சமண அறிஞர் பலர் இலக்கியப் பணிகளைச் செய்துள்ளனர். ஐம்பெரும் காப்பியங்களில் சிலப்பதிகாரம் சமண சமயக் கருத்துகள் பலவற்றைக் கூறும் நூலாகும். சீவக சிந்தாமணி சமண முனிவராகிய திருத்தக்க தேவரால் இயற்றப்பட்டதாகும். ஐம்பெரும் காப்பியங்களில் வளையாபதி என்ற மற்றொரு காவியமும் சமணர் அளித்த நன்கொடையாகும். நாலடியார், பழமொழி நானூறு, ஏலாதி, சிறுபஞ்சமூலம், அறநெறிச்சாரம் ஆகிய அறநூல்கள் சமணர் அளித்தவையேயாகும்.இலக்கணம்தொல்காப்பியம் உயிர்களை ஆறு வகையாகப் பகுத்துக் கூறுகின்றது. அது சமண சமயத்தைச் சார்ந்த கருத்தாகும் என அறிஞர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். கி.பி. பதின்மூன்றாம் நூற்றாண்டில் தோன்றிய நன்னூல் என்னும் இலக்கண நூலும் இதற்குப் பின்னர்த் தோன்றிய நேமிநாதம், நம்பி அகப்பொருள், புறப்பொருள் வெண்பாமாலை, யாப்பருங்கலம், யாப்பருங்கலக்காரிகை ஆகிய இலக்கண நூல்களும் சமணர் படைத்து அளித்தவையேயாகும். தமிழில் அதிக இலக்கண நூல்களை எழுதிய பெருமை சமணர்களையே சார்ந்ததாகும்.பிற நூல்கள்செய்யுள் நூல்களுக்கு விரிவாக உரை எழுதுகின்ற ஒரு நிலையைச் சமணர்கள் வளர்த்தனர். இது கல்வி பெறுவதற்கு அடிப்படையாக ஆயிற்று. தொல்காப்பியத்திற்கு முதன்முதல் உரை எழுதியவர் இளம்பூரணர் என்ற சமணரே ஆவார். இவர் தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டு நிலையைத் தழுவி அந்த நூலுக்கு உரை எழுதியுள்ளார். அவரை அடுத்து உரை ஆசிரியர் பலர் தோன்றியுள்ளனர்.இந்தக் காலத்தில் அகராதி என்ற நூல் வகையை நாம் அறிவோம். அந்த அகராதிகளுக்கு மூல நூல்கள் என்று குறிப்பிடப்படுவன நிகண்டுகள் என்பனவாகும். நிகண்டுகள் என்பன செய்யுள் வடிவில் உள்ள அகராதிகளேயாகும். அந்த நிகண்டினைத் தோற்றுவித்த பெருமை சமணர்களையே சாரும். திவாகரம், சூடாமணி, பிங்கலந்தை என்ற நிகண்டுகள் சமணர்களால் படைக்கப்பட்டன.சிறு காப்பியங்கள் எனச் சொல்லப்படும் ஐந்து நூல்களைச் சமணர்கள் இயற்றித் தந்தனர். மேருமந்தர புராணம் என்ற புராண நூலைத் தந்தவரும் சமணரே ஆவர். இவ்வாறு பலவகை நூல்களைத் தந்த பெருமை சமணர்களுடையதாகும்."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو نظام الكمبيوتر؟","answer":"الإجابة: نظام الكمبيوتر هو مزيج من الذاكرة ووحدة المعالجة المركزية والأجهزة الطرفية المتصلة به ونظام التشغيل (نظام التشغيل)."},{"question":"Si Kurt ay gumugol ng 17 minuto para sa pag-aral sa loob ng kanyang bahay. Nagpahinga siya ng 3 minuto para magmeryenda. Pagkatapos, nag-aral pa siya ng 10 minuto. Gaano katagal nag-aral si Kurt?","answer":"Nag-aral ng kabuuang 17 + 10 = 27 minuto si Kurt. Hindi natin isasama ang 3 minuto na ginamit para sa pagmemeryenda."},{"question":"Y- అక్షం నుండి (4, 0) కు గల దూరం ఎంత ?","answer":"4 యూనిట్లు"},{"question":"Sanwo-Olu yan igbimọ ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ tuntun","answer":"Nitori bi opin ṣe ti de ba asiko to yẹ ki awọn ọmọ igbimọ to n ri si ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ nipinlẹ Eko to wa nibẹ tẹlẹ lo, Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu, ti yan awọn ọmọ igbimọ tuntun ti yoo maa mojuto ijọba ibilẹ naa bayii.Ninu atejade kan ti Olori awọn oṣiṣẹ nipinlẹ naa, Hakeem Muri-Okunọla fi sita lo ti sọ pe bi gomina ṣe fọwọ si awọn eeyan naa wa ni ibamu pelu ofin ti ipinlẹ Eko n lo, paapaa nigba to ṣe pe asiko awọn igbimọ to wa nibẹ ti tan. Beẹ lo ki wọn fun iṣẹ takuntakun ti wọn ṣe nigba ti wọn fi wa nipo.Atẹjade yii fi kun un pe ile igbimọ aṣofin nikan lo lẹtọọ lati fọwọ si awọn eeyan ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ yan ọhun, eyi ti wọn ni yiyan wọn da lori awọn iwe ẹri ti won ni, iwa wọn ati iriri ti wọn ti ni lori ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ.Alaga igbimọ naa ni Họnarebu Kamil Baiyewu. Awọn yooku ni Họnọrebu Taofeek Adaranijọ, Ahmed Seriki, Biọdun Ọrẹkọya ati Akeem Bamgbọla."},{"question":"ما هي السورة من القرآن التي تشفع لقارئها يوم القيامة؟\\t","answer":"هي سورة الملك كما جاء في الصحيحين."},{"question":"Zer oparitu ahal diot nire neskalagunari","answer":"Liburu bat ondo egongo litzateke. Halan eta guztiz ere, beste opari batzuk ere badaude, halanola, kolonia, erropa edota esperientziaren bat"},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay mpanamboatra fiara amerikana malaza, mpamorona ny maodely malaza toy ny Mustang, F-150 ary Explorer?","answer":"Ny mpanamboatra fiara amerikana malaza dia Ford."},{"question":"ఠుర్స్దయ్ తరువాత ఏ రోజు వస్తుంది?","answer":"ఠుర్స్దయ్ తరువాత ఫ్రైడే వస్తుంది. "},{"question":"Wọn ti mu Sajẹnti to sa lọ lẹyin to yinbọn mọ afẹsọna ẹ lẹnu n’Ikẹja","answer":"Awari ti obinrin n wa nnkan ọbẹ lawọn ọlọpaa fi ọrọ afurasi ọdaran kan, Eze Aiwansone, ṣe, ọlọpaa ti wọn fẹsun kan pe o fibinu yinbọn mọ afẹsọna ẹ, Joy Eze, lori ọrọ ti ko to nnkan to dija laarin wọn, to si sa lọ.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, SP Ademuyiwa Adejọbi, lo ṣalaye f’ALAROYE lọfiisi rẹ n’Ikẹja pe Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọse yii lawọn ri i mu, ẹgbọn rẹ kan toun naa jẹ inspẹkitọ nipinlẹ Eko lo waa fa a kalẹ fawọn ọlọpaa ni olu ileeṣẹ wọn to wa n’Ikẹja.Adejọbi ni ẹka ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ CID to wa ni Panti, Yaba, ti n ba iṣẹ iwadii lọ lori ọrọ yii tẹlẹ, o ni bọwọ si ṣe tẹ Sajẹnti Eze yii yoo mu ki ọrọ ọhun tete lojuutu.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ni nnkan bii ọsẹ meji ni ALAROYE gbe iṣẹlẹ to waye ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an aabọ alẹ ọjọ kẹjọ, oṣu kẹwaa, naa.Aigbọra-ẹni-ye ranpẹ kan ni wọn lo waye laarin ọlọpaa yii ati Joy, nigba to n sin ọmọbinrin naa lọ sibudokọ Salvation, lagbegbe Ọpẹbi, n’Ikẹja, nibi tiyẹn ti fẹẹ wọ mọto pada sile to n gbe ni Ọgba ni Sajẹnti Eze fi tawọ si adọdọ ibọn to gbe kọrun, lo ba yin in fun afẹsọna rẹ, ṣugbọn ori ko o yọ, ẹnu ni ibọn naa ti ba a, niṣe lẹnu ẹ faya, ti ẹjẹ si bo o, ki wọn too sare gbe e lọ sọsibitu."},{"question":"Millaisia erilaisia revontulia on olemassa?","answer":"Eri revontulimuotoja erotetaan muutamia päätyyppejä. Perusmuoto on kaukaisesti sateenkaarta muistuttava itä-länsisuuntainen kaari pohjoisella taivaalla. Niitä kutsutaan kansanperinteessä usein nimellä Pohjan Portti. Aktiiviset revontulimuodot muuttavat muotoaan nopeasti siten, että jopa muutamassa sekunnissa taivaankansi on revontulivalojen peittämä. Tyypillisiä värejä ovat vihertävän kellertävä ja violetti.Revontulikorona nähdään silloin kun revontulimuodot ovat suoraan katsoja yläpuolella. Tällöin revontulien alhaalta ylöspäin suuntautuvat nauhamaiset rakenteet näyttävät supistuvan yhteen taivaannavassa. Ilmiö johtuu perspektiivistä, koska revontuliverhot muodostavat vertikaalisen rakenteen, jota alhaalta ylöspäin tähyillään.Aktiiviset revontulimuodot raukeavat yleensä aamuyön tunteina liekehdittyään iltayöstä kaiken aikaa. Aamuyöllä revontulet sykkivät tai loimuavat jaksollisesti ennen kuin sammuvat kokonaan. Usein ne täyttävät taivaankannen harsomaisilla muodoilla."},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para este parágrafo - Ele apitou profissionalmente por 17 anos (1958 a 1975), incluindo o Campeonato Sul-Americano de Futebol de 1963","answer":", as Olimpíadas de 1968, e as Copas de 1962 (apitou o jogo entre Brasil e Chile, sendo o responsável pela única expulsão na carreira de Garrincha, que no entanto foi liberado para disputar a final por \\"falta de provas\\"), 1966 (foi o árbitro de Inglaterra e França) e 1970 (representando o México), tendo apitado a partida entre Itália e Alemanha Ocidental, conhecida como o \\"Jogo do século\\". Yamasaki apitou também os 3 jogos que decidiram a Copa Libertadores da América de 1965, além da segunda partida válida pela Copa Intercontinental."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Selepas tahu hasilnya, apakah yang akan anda buat?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah keputusan. "},{"question":"Define the GIS","answer":"GIS stands for geographic information systems, it can be defined as the common ground between information processing and the many fields using spatial analysis techniques."},{"question":"Inona no revolisiona nanongana ny fitondrana Tsarista tany Rosia tamin’ny 1917?","answer":"Ny Revolisiona Rosiana tamin'ny 1917 dia nanongana ny fitondrana Tsarista ary nitarika ny fananganana ny Firaisana Sovietika."},{"question":"\\"Si l'escroc avait réussi à tromper Samuel, _ aurait pu gagner beaucoup d'argent.\\" Remplacez le \\"_\\" dans la phrase ci-dessus par la bonne option : - \\"l'escroc\\" - \\"Samuel\\"","answer":"La bonne option est \\"l'escroc\\"."},{"question":" Индияда канча улуттук парктар бар?","answer":"103"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk daging masak lada hitam? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah cara menyediakannya.","answer":"Bahan: ½ kg daging lembu batang pinang, 4 ulas bawang putih, ½ inci halia, 1 sudu besar sos tiram, 2 sudu besar kicap manis, 1 sudu kecil lada hitam, 1 biji lada benggala (capsicum), 1 biji bawang besar, 2 sudu kecil tepung jagung, garam, minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Kisar bawang putih dan halia. Tumbuk kasar lada hitam.2. Potong daging nipis-nipis melintang urat supaya cepat empuk.3. Gaulkan daging dengan bahan kisar, lada hitam, sos tiram, kicap dan gula. Perap selama satu jam atau lebih.4. Belah lapan bawang besar dan potong capsicum.Cara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali. Masukkan daging yang telah diperap. Tambah air hingga tenggelam daging dan dan renehkan sehingga daging lembut. Tambah air jika air kering sebelum daging empuk.2. Setelah daging lembut dan air kering, besarkan api dan goreng daging secara stir fry sehingga garing. Tahap kegaringan mengikut citarasa anda.3. Masukkan garam, hirisan bawang besar dan capsicum. Kacau rata.4. Akhir sekali masukkan bancuhan tepung jagung dan kacau.5. Apabila kuah sudah pekat, padamkan api, angkat dan hidangkan panas-panas."},{"question":"Bulgaristan Türkiye'ye düşman mı?","answer":"Günümüzde Türkiye-Bulgaristan ilişkileri dostluk zemininde gelişmesine devam etmektedir. İki ülke arasında geniş bir ticaret ilişkisi mevcuttur. Bulgaristan Türkleri iki ülke arasında önemli bir köprü rolü oynamaktadırlar."},{"question":"Ecris une phrase qui signifie la même chose que celle-ci : \\"L 'équipe masculine de basketball 2007 - 08 des Kansas City Wildcats représente l' Université du Kansas à la saison 2007-08 du Collège - Basketball.\\"","answer":"L 'équipe de basketball 2007 - 08 des Kansas City Wildcats du Kansas a représenté la Kansas State University lors de la saison 2007-08 du basket universitaire."},{"question":"When was the first FIFA World Cup held?","answer":"The first FIFA World Cup was held in 1930. This inaugural international football tournament was hosted by Uruguay from July 13 to July 30. The tournament featured 13 teams, with Uruguay emerging as the champions by defeating Argentina 4-2 in the final match. This event marked the beginning of the now globally celebrated FIFA World Cup, which has since become the most prestigious football tournament in the world."},{"question":"Oxlade","answer":"Ikúforíjì Oláìtán Abdulrahman, tí ayé mọ sí Oxlade, jẹ́ Ọ̀kọrin àti Olórin tí wà lábé ilé iṣé orin kàn ní orílé èdè faransé tí ó ń jẹ́ Troniq Music, ẹ̀ka Epic records àti ilé iṣé orin mìíràn ní U.K tí orúko rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Fuenlabrada Records. Ó di olókìkí nígbà tí orin tí ó pè ní Away jáde tí ó jẹyọ nínú àwọn àádọta orin tí Rolling Stone fẹràn julọ ní 2020. Oxlade gbà orúkọ àti àmì Africa's Next Artist ni Pandora Alákọkọ́ ní ọdún 2022.Ni ọjọ kejìdínlógún ọdún 2020, Oxlade wà lára àwọn tí wọn fara pa ni ìgbà ìfi ẹ̀honú hàn tí EndSARS ní Surulere, agbègbè kan ní Ìpínlè Èkó. Àwọn olùgbé àti àwọn tí wọn jáde láti fí fi ẹ̀honú hàn pé àsìkò yìí àti ìsèlè náà lórí àwọn èrò ayélujára ní #EndSARS, nínú àgekurú fídíò kan tí olusàkóso Oxlade ti orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Ojah'B gbé sójú ẹrọ internet ní a tí rí àwọn ọlọpa tí lùú níbi tí wọn tiń fi agbára pa àtakò náà.Ni ọjọ kẹjọ, oṣù Kejì ọdún 2022 ni téèpù fídíò ìbálòpọ̀ tí Oxlade jáde sórí ẹ̀rọ Ayélujára Snapchat, èyí tí ódi ohun àríyànjiyàn lórí èrò Twitter. Ní oṣù Kejì ọjọ kẹwàá Ọdún 2022, Obìnrin inú Téèpù náà jáde pé òun yóò pé Oxlade ní ẹjọ́ , èyí tí ilé ẹjọ ní kìí Oxlade san ogún mílíọ́nù náírà. Ní ọjọ kejìlélógún oṣù Kejì, odun náà ní Oxlade tọrọ Ìdáríjì lórí Twitter lọ́wọ́ àwọn olólùfẹ́ rẹ àti obìnrin tí ó wà nínú fídíò náà.Gẹ́gẹ́ bí Ọ̀gbéni Efe Ukpebor tí ilé iṣẹ Nigerian Entertainment Today ṣe ṣàpèjúwe Ohùn Oxlade, ó ní, ohùn rẹ̀ dán bẹ́ẹ̀ síni ó wà ní ìbámu pẹ̀lú ìdàpọ̀ orin àlàígbẹ́. Ó ṣẹ àpèjúwe ohùn rẹ̀ bí afárá láàrin Alte (Afro-fusion àti experimental music expressions) àti àwọn mainstream. Àwọn orin rẹ̀ jẹ́ àdàlú Gẹ̀ẹ́sì, àti Pidgin English, nígbà gbogbo ní ó ń ṣàwarí àwọn kókó-ọ̀rọ̀ ìmísí gẹ́gẹ́ bí ìfẹ."},{"question":"Sino ang unang hari ng bansang England?","answer":"Ang anak ni Edward, si Æthelstan, ang unang namamahala sa buong lugar na bubuo sa kaharian ng England. Ang kapatid ni Æthelstan ay nagpakasal kay Sihtric, ang Viking na pinuno ng mga Northumbrian."},{"question":"Мотивация (түрткү) бере турган сөздөр менен бөлүш !","answer":"Адам баласы жарыкта - караңгыны, кубанычта - кайгыны, токчулукта - жокчулукту ойлонбойт. Бирок, караңгыда - жарыкты, кайгыда - кубанычты, жокчулукта - токчулукту дайыма ойлойт."},{"question":"ดูบทความข้างล่าง แล้วตอบคําถามในภาษาเดียวกันกับบทความ  ตอนที่: ในวันที่เกิดเหตุ รัฐมนตรีว่าการกระทรวงพลังงาน สุชิลคูมาร์ ชินเด ได้สั่งให้คณะกรรมการ 3 คน กําหนดสาเหตุของความล้มเหลว และรายงานภายใน 15 วัน ในการตอบสนองต่อการวิจารณ์ เขาสังเกตว่า อินเดียไม่ใช่ประเทศเดียวที่ได้รับความเดือดร้อนจากการขาดแคลนไฟฟ้าอย่างใหญ่หลวง เพราะการขาดแคลนตัดไฟฟ้าก็เกิดขึ้นในสหรัฐอเมริกาและบราซิลในช่วงไม่กี่ปีที่ผ่านมา วอชิงตันโพสต์อธิบายความล้มเหลวนี้ว่าเป็นการเพิ่มความเร่งด่วนต่อแผนของนายกรัฐมนตรีอินเดีย ดร. มนโมหาน ซิงห์ สําหรับการปรับปรุงเครือข่ายไฟฟ้าของอินเดียด้วยเงิน 400 พันล้านดอลลาร์สหรัฐ แผนของเขาเรียกร้องให้มีการเพิ่มกำลังการผลิต 76 กิกะวัตต์ โดยในปี 2017 กำลังการผลิตบางส่วนมาจากพลังงานนิวเคลียร์  คําถาม: อะไรคือแผนหลักของนายกรัฐมนตรี ดร.มนโมฮัน ซิงห์ สําหรับการปรับปรุงเครือข่ายพลังงานของอินเดีย?","answer":"พลังงานนิวเคลียร์"},{"question":"Sheeg Goorma ayaa la Farad yeelay zakaatul Fidriga?","answer":"Waxaa la Farad yeelay Sanadkii labaad ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"ஒரு காவிரியைப் போலஎனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர்? ","answer":"விடை : \\tலட்சுமி திரிபுரசுந்தரி"},{"question":"જૂના અમદાવાદ વિશે કહો.","answer":"ભારતમાં અમદાવાદનું ઐતિહાસિક શહેર અથવા જૂનું અમદાવાદ, દિવાલોથી ઘેરાયેલું શહેર છે. અમદાવાદ 1411 માં ગુજરાત સલ્તનતના અહમદ શાહ પહેલા દ્વારા સ્થાપવામાં આવ્યું હતું. તે છ સદીઓ સુધી ગુજરાત રાજ્યની રાજધાની રહ્યું અને બાદમાં મહત્વપૂર્ણ રાજકીય અને વ્યાપારી બન્યું. ગુજરાતનું કેન્દ્ર. આજે, ગીચ અને જર્જરિત બની ગયા હોવા છતાં, તે હજુ પણ મેટ્રોપોલિટન અમદાવાદના પ્રતીકાત્મક હૃદય તરીકે સેવા આપે છે. જુલાઈ 2017 માં યુનેસ્કો દ્વારા તેને વર્લ્ડ હેરિટેજ સિટી તરીકે અંકિત કરવામાં આવ્યું હતું.જૂના અમદાવાદના પડોશનો એક ભાગ કે જે પોળ તરિકે ઓળખાય છે. પોળ એ જૂના શહેરની એક અલગ જ પ્રકાર ની હાઉસિંગ વ્યવસ્થા હતી અને 1872 માં ત્યાં 356 જેટલી પોળ હતી. હિંદુ અને મુસ્લિમો વચ્ચેના ધાર્મિક તણાવને કારણે 1738-1753 ના વિભાજિત શાસન દરમિયાન આ પ્રકારના આવાસની સ્થાપના કરવામાં આવી હતી. જ્યારે શહેરની દિવાલો બગડતી ગઈ અને લૂંટારુઓથી રક્ષણ પૂરું પાડતું ન હતું, ત્યારે પોળ નો દરવાજો રક્ષણ માટે વધુ મહત્વપૂર્ણ બન્યો.જૂના શહેરમાં સમૃદ્ધ લાકડાનું સ્થાપત્ય, હવેલીઓ, ખડકીઓ અને પોળ છે. લાકડાનું સ્થાપત્ય અમદાવાદના અનોખા વારસા અને સંસ્કૃતિનું ઉદાહરણ છે. તે કળા અને હસ્તકલા, પરંપરાઓ અને બંધારણની રચનામાં યોગદાનને દર્શાવે છે અને શહેરના રહેવાસીઓને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે. શહેરનું આર્કિટેક્ચર સમુદાય, કુટુંબ અને વિવિધ સંસ્કૃતિઓની ભાવનાને પ્રોત્સાહન આપવા માટે બનાવા મા આવ્યું હતું. આ શહેરમાં હિન્દુ ધર્મ, ઇસ્લામ, ખ્રિસ્તી અને યહુદી ધર્મ સહિત અનેક ધર્મોની સંસ્થાઓનું ઘર હોવાનું સ્પષ્ટ થાય છે."},{"question":"અહીં એક ગુજરાતી કવિતા ની શરૂઆત ની પંક્તિઓ નીચે આપેલી છે: માની શકો ના એવી કથા થઈ ગયો છું હું,તારા વિનાય જિંદગી જીવી ગયો છું હું.આ કવિતા ની આગળની પંક્તિઓ લખો.","answer":"માની શકો ના એવી કથા થઈ ગયો છું હું,તારા વિનાય જિંદગી જીવી ગયો છું હું.આવી જશે, આવશે કાલે નહીં કદી,એવા ઘણા ઝાંઝવા ઝીરવી ગયો છું હું.સૂરજ વિષેનો ભાસ તો શાયદ થયો તો પણ,આંખો મીંચી શહેરથી નીકળી ગયો છું હું.તારી ગલીની રાહ એ ઘટના નથી હવે,કોને કહું કે ક્યારનો અટકી ગયો છું હું.મૃત્યુ વિષેની વાત તો કૈલાસથી છે,રસ્તામાં અર્ધે આવતાં થાકી ગયો છું હું."},{"question":"السؤال: اشرح المعنى ديال الملف؟","answer":"الإجابة: الملف هو واحد الموقع عندو واحد الاسم كانخبيوه فيه المعلومات والبيانات بواحد الشكل دائم ودائما ما تايتخزن في جهاز التخزين "},{"question":"दिइएको वाक्यलाई कोष्ठकमा बताएअनुसार परिवर्तन गर्नुहोस् :उनीहरु बजार गएछ्न् । (सामान्य वर्तमान)","answer":"उनीहरु बजार जान्छन् ।"},{"question":"متى تاريخ إندلاع الثورة التجارية الجزائرية؟","answer":"ثورة التحرير الجزائرية أو حرب الجزائر أو حرب الاستقلال الجزائرية هو نزاع مسلح اندلع بين فرنسا وجبهة التحرير الوطني الجزائرية من عام 1954 إلى 1962، وأدى في النهاية إلى نيل الجزائر استقلالها عن فرنسا."},{"question":"සාල්ලෙක ලාලා පාතට බානා කෙනෙක්කි යන්නේ මොකද්ද?මල්ලක දමා පහතට දමන අර්ථය නම් ඇයි කෙනෙක් කියලා දාලා තියෙන්නේ ?","answer":"\\"සාල්ලෙකැ ලාලා පාතට බාන කෙනෙකුන් මෙන්\\"(සාල්ලෙකැ = උඩහල්ලෙකැ / පැසෙකැ/උරයෙකැ)(කිසියම්) කෙනෙකුන් උරයෙකැ ලා පාතට බානවා වගේ, කේවට්ට බමුණාගේ හිසෙහි අසුචි ( වසුරු/ වර්චස්) පිඬක් ( පිණ්ඩයක්/ගුළියක්) හෙළා ( පහතට දමා)...කිසියම් කෙනෙකු උරයෙක දමා/බහා පහතට බාන්නාක් මෙන් (ගිරා පණ්ඩිතයා ද) බමුණාගේ හිස මතට අසුචි/ වසුරු පිඬක් හෙළා...උරයෙක දමා පහතට බෑමේ දී හරියට ම ඉලක්කය කරා යොමු කිරීමට පුළුවන. එවැනි අවස්ථාවක එය කරන කෙනෙකු ද සිටිය යුතුය. ප්‍රධාන ක්‍රියාව වර්චස් පිඬ එල්ලයට ම යොමු කිරීම යි. එය කළ ආකාරය දැක්වීමට ඉහත කී උපමාව යොදා ගෙන ඇත."},{"question":"Dê-me um exemplo de curiosidade nesta categoria: videogames.","answer":"Qual jogo na série Animal Crossing vendeu maior número de cópias? Animal Crossing: New Horizons. Animal Crossing: New Horizons é um jogo eletrônico de simulação social desenvolvido pela Nintendo Entertainment Planning & Development e publicado pela Nintendo.New Horizons foi um sucesso comercial, vendendo mais de 40 milhões de unidades até dezembro de 2021, e se tornando um dos jogos mais vendidos de Nintendo Switch e de todos os tempos. "},{"question":"Кайсы мамлекет өзүнүн көп сандаган суулары менен “Миң көлдүн өлкөсү” деп аталат?","answer":"Финляндияны көбүнчө \\"Миң көлдүн өлкөсү\\" деп аташат, анткени анда он миңдеген көлдөрдүн саны көп."},{"question":"Uyagula yini baba awakhuluma nje namuhla?Usebuyile yini umakoti?Akakabuyi. Kusho ukuthi ngabe uphethwe kabi ukuhamba kwaloluhlanya lwengane?Cha impela kwenzeke into embi mkami. Okokuqala asiyazi nokuthi iphile ngane. Kokunye izithele phezu kwezigebengu zayenzakalisa.Phela lapho ngabe umvundla ziyawunqanda phambili. Yona yiniingasilaleli uma siyitshela ngesiko lesintu.Namasiko lawa asefuna ukubhekisiswa. Sengathi akhona asephelelwayisikhathi manje. Amanye kufuneka achazwe kahle aziwe yibo bonkeabantu.Ubona sengathi umakoti akalazi leli siko. Ulazi kahle uyazihlanyisa.Mina ngibona sengathi sinecala manje.Icala lani? Musa ukudlala wena Manzini. Phela thina asiyixoshanga lengane lapha ekhaya. Izihambele. Uyangizwa? Izihambele.UMsindo onjengalo uzosixabanisa namadlozi.Nawo ngabe ayaganga lawo madlozi. Angayeka ukubuyisa uhlanyalukamakoti, axabane nathi? Kanti awalazi yini wona leli siko esilitshelale ntombazane.Mina ngisafuna ukuhlala phansi ngiyichazele kahle intombazane.Kokunye uma isizwe kahle iyobubona ubuhle baleli siko.Wena ubona sengathi izokulalela njengoba isiwumdlwembe nje? (Athiukuhleka) Kodwa ungichazile uDumisani. Wajika eduzenjengenkalankala.Nami ungimangazile impela lo mfana.1. Bhala amazwi noma inkulumo ekulesi siqeshana etshengisa ukuthiuMaMbatha simjabulisile isenzo sikaDumisani.","answer":"Kodwa ungichazile uDumisani. Wajika eduze njengenkalankala."},{"question":"कर्णाली प्रदेश","answer":"नेपालको सबैभन्दा ठूलो प्रदेश, कर्णाली प्रदेशले २७,९८४ वर्ग किलोमिटर क्षेत्रफल ओगटेको छ र यस क्षेत्रबाट बग्ने नेपालको सबैभन्दा लामो नदीबाट यसको नाम राखिएको हो। १० जिल्ला र दुई लोकप्रिय राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज, रारा राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज र शे फोक्सुण्डो राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्ज मिलेर बनेको यो नेपाल राराको सबैभन्दा ठूलो ताल र नेपालको दोस्रो ठूलो ताल शे फोक्सुण्डोको घर हो। प्रान्तको उच्च हिमाली क्षेत्रमा, हामी चुरे क्षेत्रमा उप-उष्णकटिबंधीय हावापानी अवस्थाहरू टुन्द्रा जलवायु अवस्थाहरू फेला पार्न सक्छौं।कर्णाली प्रदेशको अधिकांश भूभाग पहाड र हिमालले ओगटेको हुनाले यहाँ साहसिक खोजी गर्नेहरूका लागि उपयुक्त माथिल्लो डोल्पोजस्ता धेरै अफ बीट ट्रेकिङ ट्रेलहरू यहाँ पाउन सकिन्छ। जबकि प्रान्तको छेउमा बग्ने नदीले यसलाई व्हाइट वाटर र्याफ्टिङमा संलग्न हुनको लागि उत्तम स्थान बनाउँछ। जुम्ला, सुर्खेत, दैलेख जस्ता आध्यात्मिक, ऐतिहासिक र पुरातात्विक महत्वका क्षेत्रहरू कर्णाली प्रदेशलाई हिन्दू तीर्थयात्री र अनुसन्धानकर्ताहरूमाझ लोकप्रिय बनाएको छ। औषधीय गुण भएका दुर्लभ हिमाली जडिबुटी यस क्षेत्र वरिपरि पाइन्छ।"},{"question":"اتلانتيك ليه؟ وبالنظر للسؤال السابق، اكتب سياق يحتوي على الإجابة. ممكن يكون من 1 - 20 جملة. السياق:","answer":"خلال منتصف العصر الايوسيني، بيعتقد إن حوض الصرف الصحي في الأمازون تم تقسيمه على طول وسط القارة بواسطة قوس بوروس. المياه في الجانب الشرقي تتدفق باتجاه المحيط الأطلسي، في حين تتدفق المياه في الغرب باتجاه المحيط الهادئ عبر حوض الأمازون. ومع ذلك ، مع ارتفاع جبال الأنديز ، تم إنشاء حوض كبير محاط بحيرة ؛ المعروف الآن باسم حوض سوليمونز. في خلال 5  10 مليون سنة الأخيرة، حطم المياه المتراكمة دي خلال قوس بوروس، و انضم للتدفق الشرقي باتجاه المحيط الأطلسي."},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ අර්ථය කුමක්ද ? \\"උගුරට හොරා බෙහෙත් කනවා  වාගේ\\"","answer":"කිසියම් කටයුත්තක් නිසි පිළිවෙළකට නොකර යන්තම් සිදු කිරීම"},{"question":"ما هو عدد آيات سورة المائدة ؟ هل هذا سؤال استفهامي؟","answer":"لا"},{"question":"Awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ reluwee to n ge waya ọkọ oju irin bọ sọwọ ọlọpaa n’Ifọ","answer":"Oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ reluwee lawọn ọkunrin mẹta yii, orukọ wọn ni Frank Obi, Eze Ogbonna ati James Ejor, ṣugbọn niṣe ni wọn tun n ji awọn waya kan nibẹ nitori apo ara wọn. Ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kẹta yii, lọwọ palaba wọn segi ni Kajọla, Ifọ, nipinlẹ Ogun.Ọlọdẹ to n ṣọ ileeṣẹ naa ti i ṣe Kwochason Global Gas Company, lo ri awọn marun-un kan ti wọn n ge waya to ni i ṣe pẹlu ọna reluwee ti wọn n ṣe lọwọ. Ṣugbọn nitori wọn pọ ju ọlọdẹ lọ, wọn ri waya naa ge, wọn si sa lọ.Lẹyin ifisun ileeṣẹ yii ni teṣan ọlọpaa Ifọ, ni awọn ọlọpaa dọdẹ awọn eeyan naa de ibi ti wọn fara pamọ si, ọwọ wọn si ba awọn mẹta yii ti wọn jẹ oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ naa.Ayùn ti wọn fi n ge irin ati waya ti wọn ge lọ naa lawọn ọlọpaa ri gba lọwọ wọn.Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, sọ pe ọga awọn, CP Edward Ajogun, ti paṣẹ pe awọn gbọdọ wa awọn meji to sa lọ naa ri, ki wọn le waa jẹjọ bii awọn yooku wọn tọwọ ba."},{"question":"మనిషి జీవితం వస్తువులా ఎలా మారిపోతుంది ?","answer":"ప్రపంచదేశాల మధ్య అంతర్జాతీయ వ్యాపారం తుఫానులా వ్యాపిస్తుంది. ప్రతి రోజూ ఎన్నో వస్తువులు విదేశాల నుండి మన దేశానికి దిగుమతి అవుతున్నాయి. వీటి వలన మన సంస్కృతి సంపద, సొంతముద్రలు చెరిగిపోతున్నాయి. మనం స్వదేశీ ఉత్పత్తులను వదిలేసి విదేశీ వస్తువుల మోజులో టి.వి., ఏ.సి. మొదలగు వస్తువులపై శ్రద్ధ పెడుతున్నాము. విదేశీ వస్తువులను ఆదరించినట్లుగా స్వదేశీ వస్తువులను ఆదరించటం లేదు.పూర్వం మన వారు అవసరమైన వస్తువులనే కొనేవారు. ఇప్పుడు తన స్థాయిని సంఘంలో పెంచుకోవాలన్న తాపత్రయంతో విదేశీ వస్తువులను అవసరం ఉన్నా లేకపోయినా హోదా కోసం కొంటున్నారు. ఆ వస్తువులు తమ ఇంట్లో లేకపోతే పరువుపోతుందన్న భావనతో నేటి మనిషి ఉంటున్నాడు. ఇలా మనిషి జీవితం వస్తువులా మారిపోయే ప్రమాదం ఉందని అద్దేపల్లి వారు భావించారు."},{"question":"Awọn Musulumi Hausa ni ki Biṣọọbu Kukah kuro ni Sokoto","answer":"Ọrọ ti wọn pe lọ́wẹ́ ti n ni àárò ninu bayii pẹlu bi awọn ijọ Musulumi kan ṣe sọ fun Biṣọọbu Matthew Kukah ko fi ipinlẹ Sokoto silẹ patapata.Ìjọ Muslim Solidarity Forum, lo sọ pe oun ko fẹẹ ri Kukah nipinlẹ náà mọ lori ẹsun pe o sọrọ ta kò ẹsin Islam àtàwọn Mùsùlùmí.Ko ti ì ju bíi wakati mẹrinlelogun lọ ti Mattew Kukah náà pariwo sita pe nitori ọrọ ti oun sọ lọjọ Keresimesi lawọn ìjọ Mùsùlùmí kan, Jama’atul Nasril Islam, ti Sultan Sokoto n ṣolori ẹ, ṣe kọjú ìjà sí oun, ti awọn eleyii naa tun sọ pe awọn fẹ ko fi ipinlẹ naa silẹ ti ko ba fẹẹ kan idin ninu iyọ.Ọrọ ti Kukah sọ ninu ọrọ ìkíni fún ayẹyẹ ọdún Kérésìmesì ẹ fún aráàlú lo ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu ìjọba Buhari lori eto aabo ati ọrọ ajé tó ti dorikodo ni Naijiria.Ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun yii tun sọ pe niṣe ni Buhari n fi ọrọ ṣegbe lẹyin awọn to ba jẹ tiẹ, paapaa awọn Hausa.O ni ohun ti ijọba Buhari n ṣe, ka ni ki í ṣe pé o jẹ ọmọ Hausa ni, awọn ṣọja yóò ti fipa gbajọba yìí.Latigba ti Biṣọọbu Matthew Kukah ti sọrọ yii ni awọn Hausa ti n ba a fa wahala, ti wọn sọ pe ọrọ to sọ sí ijọba Buhari, ẹsin Islam gan–an lo fi ba wí, atawọn ti wọn jẹ ẹlẹsin ọhun.Bi ọrọ ọhun ṣe di wahala ni Kukah sọ pe lori ọrọ ifipa gbajọba, kì í ṣe bi oun ṣe gbé é kalẹ niyẹn, ati pe ohun ti oun sọ ko ju bi a ti ṣe lè f’ọrọ ẹsin wá àlàáfíà àti iṣọkan sí aarin ilu.O ni ọrọ ti ìjọ Jama’atul Nasril sọ pe leyin ti awọn Musulumi faaye gba oun tan nipinlẹ Sokoto, niṣe loun fẹẹ maa ge ọwọ tó fún oun lounjẹ nika jẹ.O ni irufẹ ọrọ bayii, bíi ẹni fi ẹmi oun sinu ewu ni, bẹẹ lo le fa ikọlu latọdọ awọn ọmọ ijọ to n tẹle awọn eeyan yii kiri.Ṣa o, Ọjọgbọn Isah Maishanu, ẹni tí i ṣe adele alaga fún ìjọ Muslim Solidarity Forum, sọ pe Kukah korira ẹsin Islam, bẹẹ ni ko fara mọ ofin Sharia pẹlu.Bakan naa lo tun fẹsun kan an pe pẹlu gbogbo anfààní to ti ri nilẹ Hausa laarin awọn Musulumi, sibẹ, Kukah ko ri ohun to dara ri nipa ẹsin ọhun.Ọjọgbọn Maishanu sọ pe fún ìdí èyí, ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun náà gbọdọ tọrọ aforiji lọwọ àwọn aṣáájú ẹsin Islam tabi ko fi ipinlẹ Sokoto silẹ jẹẹjẹ.Wọn láwọn ko le fara mọ bo ṣe fẹẹ fi ọrọ ẹnu ẹ da wahala silẹ laarin awọn Kristẹni atawọn Musulumi nipinlẹ náà."},{"question":"Психология илимнинин тарыхында эң биринчи жолу психологияга байланыштуу (эмгекти) китепти ким жазган?а)Гиппократб)Платон в)Демокрит г)Аристотель","answer":"Туура жообу: г)Аристотель"},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang bertajuk \\"Aktiviti Badan Beruniform dan Faedahnya\\".","answer":"  Kementerian Pelajaran Malaysia telah mendominankan kokurikulum dalam sistem pendidikan nasional. Langkah ini secara eksplisit menerangkan kokurikulum sebagai simbolik kepada kemasukan ke Institut Pengajian Tinggi Awam (IPTA). Oleh itu, badan-badan beruniform seperti Kadet Pertahanan Awam, Kadet Remaja Sekolah dan sebagainya mula dipromosikan dalam arus pendidikan negara.     Faedah-faedah yang boleh didapati apabila para pelajar menyertai badan beruniform adalah dapat memapankanketahanan diri. Dalam usia yang setahun jagung, banyak cabaran yang perlu ditongkah bahkan, formula ketahanan diri tersebut juga perlu diaplikasikanpada masa hadapan. Aktiviti-aktiviti lasak yang sudah termaktub dalam silabus badan beruniform seperti 'flying-fox', 'night-walk' dan seumpamanya merupakan pendekatan awal bagi membuka kotak penerimaan pelajar terhadap kepentingan hal ini.     Di samping itu, penyertaan pelajar dalam unit beruniform berpotensi memangkinkan semangat kerjasama ibarat aur dan tebing dan pembentukan disiplin mereka. Hal ini dapat dibuktikan melalui penglibatan pelajar yang mendesak ketepatan masa yang tinggi seperti aktiviti kawad kaki. Aktiviti tersebut memerlukan gemblengan tenaga yang maksimum daripada ahli-ahli pasukan bagi menghasilkan formasi yang mantap. Oleh itu, para pelajar yang menyertai badan beruniform sering masyhur dengan ketepatan masa dan disiplin yang tinggi.    Persis peribahasa melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya, para pelajar juga akan diasuh tentang ilmu asas kecemasan. Perkara ini sangat berfaedah kerana apabila berlaku sebarang kecederaan, para pelajar boleh tampil menghulurkan bantuan. Tamsilnya, Persatuan Bulan Sabit Merah (PBSM) merupakan unit utama di sekolah yang bertindak menyebarkan wadah kesihatan kepada ahli-ahlinya dan umum. Maka, tindakan ini dilihat sangat efektif demi memansuhkan kedaifan akal pelajar tentang ilmu kesihatan.     Akhirulkalam, semua pelajar wajib menyertai kegiatan kokurikulum untuk kemenjadian masa depan. Elakkan daripada tertumpu kepada kurikulum sahaja. Para pelajar perlu sedar  akan faedah yang terbentang justeru mereka harus mengikuti perkembangan sistem pendidikan untuk faedah diri sendiri."},{"question":"その口元が、ある能のお面に似ていることから、子供が泣くことを何というでしょう？","answer":"べそをかく（お面はおおべし）です。"},{"question":"س/ كم يبلغ عدد الخلفاء العباسيين ؟","answer":"ج/ سبعة وثلاثون."},{"question":"السؤال: متى استقلت سوريا ؟","answer":"الإجابة: 17 أبريل 1946م"},{"question":"Inona no teoria fianarana mifantoka amin'ny fampivelarana ny fahaiza-manaon'ny saina amin'ny famahana olana?1-Ny teoria momba ny fitondran-tena2-Ny teoria momba ny fanorenana3-Ny kaonitivism theory","answer":"Valiny: 3-Ny kaonitivism theory"},{"question":"Экинин цифра  түрүндө жазылганы кандай болот?","answer":"2 цифрасынын жазма түрүндө жазылганы."},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ  තේරුම කුමක්ද?සාස්තරේ විතරක් මදි සූස්තරෙත් ඕනලු.","answer":"ශිල්ප පමණක් නොව එය නිවැරදිව භාවිතා කිරීමට හැකියාවත් අවශ්‍ය වන බව."},{"question":"Jelaskan apa itu pasar malam di Malaysia. ","answer":"Seperti namanya, pasar malam biasanya dibuka lewat pada pukul 5:00 petang dan ditutup jam 11:00 malam atau sehingga makanan habis dijual.Peniaga mendapat lesen peniagaan daripada pihak berkuasa tempatan (PBT) yang berkaitan. Ini bagi mengawal kebersihan bandar dan kesihatan. Penjual makanan perlu mendapatkan suntikan kesihatan demam kepialu/tipod jenis Typhim VI. Tapak pasar malam diselia oleh pihak berkuasa tempatan.Pasar malam berbeza-beza mengikut etnik. Pasar malam Melayu biasanya menjual buku-buku keagamaan, kopiah, kain sarong, dan barangan Melayu lain. Pasar malam Cina pula lazimnya menjual set Mah Jong, setanggi, colok, kertas dan pelbagai barangan keagamaan Cina. Selain itu, pasar malam India pula menjual barangan keagamaan Hindu. "},{"question":"Üzüm çekirdeğinin cilde faydaları nelerdir?","answer":"Üzüm çekirdeği yağının cilt sağlığını destekleyen antioksidan etkisi, nemlendirici etkisi, akne tedavisi ve cilt tonunu eşitleme gibi faydaları vardır. Üzüm çekirdeği yağı, ciltteki serbest radikallerle savaşan güçlü antioksidanlar içerir."},{"question":"ਰੇਤਲੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੁਧਾਰ ਲਈ ਯੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਰੇਤਲੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੁਧਾਰ ਲਈ ਯੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹਨ-1. ਹਰੀ ਖਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਫੁੱਲ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਦੋ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਬਾ । ਦਿਓ । ਹਰੀ ਖਾਦ ਲਈ ਸਣ ਜਾਂ ਜੰਤਰ ਦੀ ਬੀਜਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ।2. ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਗਲੀ-ਸੜੀ ਰੂੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਤਰ ਖੇਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਹੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਖੇਤ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।3. ਮੁਰਗੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਖਾਦ, ਸੂਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਖਾਦ, ਕੰਪੋਸਟ ਖਾਦ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਸੁਧਾਰਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।4. ਮਈ-ਜੂਨ ਦੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਾਲੀ ਨਾ ਛੱਡੋ । ਕੋਈ ਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਸਲ ਬੀਜ ਕੇ ਰੱਖੋ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚਲੇ ਜੀਵ ਅੰਸ਼ ਮਾਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਚਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ ।5. ਫਲੀਦਾਰ ਫ਼ਸਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਸ਼ਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ।6. ਸਿੰਚਾਈ ਲਈ ਛੋਟੇ ਕਿਆਰੇ ਬਣਾਓ ।"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Sejenis sukan yang bermain bola yang botak dan berbulu.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah badminton. "},{"question":"Tỉnh nào không có núi?","answer":"Tỉnh Thái Bình thuộc khu vực Đồng bằng sông Hồng, rộng hơn 1.586 km2, địa hình tương đối bằng phẳng với độ dốc nhỏ hơn 1%. Thái Bình không có đồi núi, chỉ gồm các cánh đồng bằng phẳng, xen kẽ các khu dân cư. Mạng lưới sông ngòi ở đây chằng chịt, độ cao trung bình của tỉnh không quá 3m so với mực nước biển.Cũng thuộc Đồng bằng sông Hồng, tỉnh Hưng Yên rộng hơn 923 km2. Địa hình Hưng Yên tương đối bằng phẳng, không có núi đồi, thấp dần từ Bắc xuống Nam, từ Tây sang Đông."},{"question":"\\" ગણપતિદાદા મોરિયા \\" બાળગીત લખો.","answer":"ગણપતિદાદા મોરિયા, ઘીમાં લાડુ ચોળિયાગણપતિદાદા મોરિયા, ઘીમાં લાડુ ચોળિયાગણપતિદાદા લાડુ જમે,  એકવીસ લાડુ પેટમાં રમેઉંદર ઉપર સવારી કરે, મલક આખામાં ફરતા ફરેઉંદર ઉપર સવારી કરે, મલક આખામાં ફરતા ફરેગણપતિદાદા મોરિયા, ઘીમાં લાડુ ચોળિયાગણપતિદાદા મોરિયા, ઘીમાં લાડુ ચોળિયા"},{"question":"Responde a la siguiente pregunta. ¿Quién es la actriz que interpreta a Alicia en Crepúsculo?","answer":"La actriz que interpreta a Alicia en Crepúsculo es Ashley Michele Greene"},{"question":"Marabo ina madax noqdo anigo cilmi yeelan?","answer":"MA RABO IN AAN MADAX NOQDO ANIGA OO CILMI YEELAN!Xafiis Hey'adeed ayuu ka shaqeynayey. Mushaarkiisana 200 Dollar  ayuu ahaa. Qof aad shaqada ugu dadaalo oo howlkar loo aqoonsanyahay ayuu ahaa. Waxaa la gaaray sannadka xilligii la qiimeynayay shaqaalaha. Waxaa loo gartay in la dallacsiiyo, oo boos mushaarkiisu yahay 500 la siiyo. kana yara mas'uuliyad badan midka uu markaas haayey. Wuu ka cudurdaartay in uu aqbalo. Markii sababta la weydiiyayna wuxuu xusay booskaas in uu dhib weyn ku yeelanayo Mustaqbalkiisa. Wuxuuna yiri, \\" Hadda 200 ayaan qaataa, subixii 7.aroornimo ilaa 2.00 duhurkii ayaan shaqeeyaa. 3 kutub ayaan raacdaa galinka dambe llaa habeenki, waqti nasiinno waan heystaa, xasiloonni maskaxeedna kama marna. Iskuulna macallin ayaan ka ahay oo hal saac ayaan arday ingiriiska baraa. Lakiin hadii aan booskaan la ii soo jeediyay aqbalo, waa in aan subax iyo galab Hey.adda u shaqeeya. Maadaama ay tahay shaqo xafiiseed, waxay u badantahay taleefan ku hadal badan in uu i sugayo. Safaro badan meesha kama maqno, oo tuulooyin ayaa wax laga qabtaa.Jadwalka kutubadda aan ku xiranahay waqtiyada cayiman la aqriyo lama jaan-qaadi doono maadaama laga yaabo habeenno badan inaan u baahan doono in aan soo dibaddo ama soo dhaxo. Hadda wax badan ayaan isku heystaa (Shaqadii, waxbarashadii, nasiinnadii iyo waqtigii). Laakiin soojedintaan cusub waxaan ku luminaya waxyaabo badan oo nolosheyda muhiim u ah. Lacag kaliya ayey noloshayda ku soo uruureysaa. Marka, ma rabo anoo Cilmi yeelan in aan madax noqdo\\" Go'aan qaadashada waa u muhiim nolosha. Go'aan kasta oo aad qaadaneyso ha kuu yeesho halbeeg wanaagsan. Lacagta waxaa ka muhiimsan qanaacada. Qalbiga haduu kuu xasiloonyahay waxba kaama maqno ee xasuusnoow. Dad badan waxay heystaan lacag, laakiin ma heystaan nasiino, qanaaco iyo daganaan maskaxeed. Intaasna lagama helo lacagta, ee waxaa laga helaa xiriirka ilaahey oo la wanaajiyo. "},{"question":"No anime Pokémon, quem é Ash Ketchum?","answer":"Ash Ketchum é o protagonista do anime Pokémon, um treinador de Pokémon determinado e entusiasmado que sonha em se tornar um Mestre Pokémon. Ele é conhecido por seu parceiro Pikachu."},{"question":"وجدت  السؤال: من هو سيف الله المسلول ؟ في موقع ثقافي، ماهي الإجابة؟","answer":"الإجابة على السؤال هي:  سيدنا خالد بن الوليد. خالد بن الوليد بن المغيرة، والمعروف أيضًا باسم \\"خالد بن الوليد الفهري\\"، كان صحابيًا للنبي محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم ومن أبرز القادة العسكريين في الإسلام. وُلد في مكة المكرمة في العام 592 م، وكان في البداية من أعداء المسلمين. ومع ذلك، بعد أن أسلم في السنة 8 هـ (629م)، أصبح أحد أبرز القادة العسكريين المسلمين. خالد بن الوليد شارك في العديد من المعارك الهامة، مثل معركة مؤتة ومعركة مؤتة الثانية وغيرها. حصل على لقب \\"سيف الله المسلول\\" بسبب شجاعته في المعارك. وقاد الفتوحات الإسلامية في بلاد الشام وفارس ومصر. بعد وفاة النبي محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم، شارك خالد بن الوليد في توسيع الدولة الإسلامية تحت خلافة أبو بكر الصديق وعمر بن الخطاب. وتوفي خالد بن الوليد في العام 21 هـ (642م)."},{"question":"När gick Sverige med i EU?","answer":"Sverige gick med i EU år 1995 efter att en folkomröstning genomförts året innan med en majoritet som röstat för ett EU-medlemskap."},{"question":"Inona ny teny na andian-teny mifanohi-kevitra amin'ny hoe \\"niakatra\\" izay ampiasaina ato amin'ity fehezanteny ity:Hany ka niaktra ny vidim-piainana.","answer":"Ny teny na andian-teny mifanohi-kevitra amin'ny hoe \\"niakatra\\" dia midina, mora, mirary."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny iray amin'ireo vondrom-poko lehibe indrindra eto Madagasikara dia ny _.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Iray amin'ireo foko lehibe indrindra eto Madagasikara ny Merina."},{"question":"Ibi ti Korede atọrẹ ẹ ti n ja awọn oni-POS lole n’Ipaja ni wọn ti mu un","answer":"Ibi ti afurasi ọdaran eni ọdun mẹrinlelogun kan, Korede Anifowoṣe, ti fẹẹ ja Ṣọla Musa lole n’Ipaja, nipinlẹ Eko, lọwọ awọn agbofinro ti tẹ ẹ, laṣiiri ẹ ba tu pe ki i ṣe kọsitọma gidi rara, adigunjale pọnbele ni.Gẹgẹ bi Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Eko ṣe sọ f’ALAROYE ninu atẹjade to fi ṣọwọ si wa, o ni awọn to n ṣiṣẹ ni teṣan Ipaja ni wọn mu Korede lopin ọsẹ to kọja yii, ati pe meji ni wọn jọ n rin, ẹni keji ẹ ti wọn jọ n jale kiri Eko ti sa lọ, awọn ṣi n wa a bayii.Wọn niṣe lọkunrin naa kọkọ ṣe bii ẹni to fẹẹ fi kaadi ATM gba owo lori ẹrọ iṣiro ti Ṣọla n lo, aṣe o ti foju ṣọ ibi tọmọbinrin naa n gbe apo owo ẹ si, ojiji lo ki baagi owo naa mọlẹ, to si fẹẹ ju u si ẹni keji ẹ to ti sun mọ tosi nigba yẹn.Nigba ti Ṣọla fẹẹ pariwo, niṣe ni Korede fabọn yọ si i, to si paṣẹ fun un pe ko dakẹ, ṣugbọn ọmọbinrin naa figbe ta pe kawọn araadugbo gba oun, lawọn eeyan ba sare debẹ.Boya awọn eeyan to tete debẹ yii lori fi ko Ṣọla yọ, tori wọn gba Korede mu, wọn din dundu iya fun un, kawọn ọlọpaa to n ṣe patiroolu too de sasiko naa, wọn gba ibọn ọwọ ẹ ati katiriiji ọta ibọn to wa lapo ẹ, wọn si wọ afurasi ọdaran naa ju si mọto wọn.Adejọbi ni Korede ti wa ni Panti, Yaba, lakata awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ fun"},{"question":"එක්දින තරඟයකදී කණ්ඩායමක් රැස්කළ ඉහළම ලකුණු සංඛ්‍යාව ලබාගත්තේ කවර රටකට එරෙහිවද?","answer":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවට එරෙහිව"},{"question":"\\"විපුල ඵල ඇති \\" යන්නද හරි \\"විපුල පල \\" යන්නද?","answer":"විපුල් පල ( අමිශ්‍ර සිංහල)විපුල ඵල (මිශ්‍ර සිංහල)"},{"question":"O que é uma \\"defesa perfeita\\" no voleibol?","answer":"Uma \\"defesa perfeita\\" no voleibol ocorre quando um jogador ou líbero realiza uma defesa incrível e precisa, que impede a bola de tocar o chão e mantém a bola em jogo para que sua equipe continue a jogada. É um momento de destaque na defesa e pode ser crucial para a equipe manter a posse da bola."},{"question":"'Future Nostalgia' contendo o single 'Don't Start Now' é o segundo álbum de estúdio de qual cantora inglesa?","answer":"\\"Future Nostalgia\\", contendo o single \\"Don't Start Now\\", é o segundo álbum de estúdio da cantora inglesa Dua Lipa. O álbum foi lançado em 27 de março de 2020 e recebeu aclamação da crítica por sua mistura de elementos retro e contemporâneos, criando uma sensação de nostalgia futurista. \\"Don't Start Now\\" foi um dos singles de destaque do álbum e obteve grande sucesso nas paradas musicais."},{"question":"Man City din dundu iya fun Watford","answer":"Dundu iya ami-ayo mẹrin si odo ni Manchester United din fun Watford lalẹ yii nibi idije Premier League ilẹ England.Raheem Sterling lo gba meji wọle fun Man City, nigba ti Phil Foden ati Aymeric Laporte ju ẹyọ kọọkan sawọn.Nnkan ko rọgbọ fun Watford rara pẹlu bi wọn ṣe gbiyanju to ṣugbọn tọrọ yiwọ, afi bii igba ti wọn waa ta ẹpa lori papa.Man city ti bọ sipo keji bayii lori tabili liigi naa, nigba ti Watford n sinmi nipo kẹtadinlogun."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: W reprezentacji Egiptu Abu Zajd zadebiutował w 1982 roku. W 1990 roku został powołany przez selekcjonera Mahmouda El-Gohary'ego do kadry na Mistrzostwa Świata we Włoszech. Tam rozegrał jedno spotkanie grupowe, z Irlandią (0:0). W swojej karierze grał także w Pucharze Narodów Afryki 1984","answer":"(4. miejsce i król strzelców z 4 golami) i Pucharze Narodów Afryki 1986 (mistrzostwo Afryki i wiecekról strzelców z 3 golami). Był także królem strzelców młodzieżowych Mistrzostw Świata w 1981 roku w Australii."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Tỷ giá 1 USD hôm nay bằng bao nhiêu VND? Tỷ giá trung tâm được Ngân hàng Nhà nước niêm yết ở mức 23.176 VND/USD. Tỷ giá USD chợ đen hôm nay ở mức 24.350 - 24.410 đồng (mua - bán). Tỷ giá Vietcombank hôm nay niêm yết ở mức: 23.180 đồng - 23.480 đồng (mua vào - bán ra), không đổi ở cả hai chiều so với phiên giao dịch trước đó. Tỷ giá Euro Vietcombank hiện ở mức 23.183 đồng - 24.482 đồng (mua vào - bán ra). Tỷ giá Yên Nhật hiện ở mức 170 đồng - 180 đồng (mua vào - bán ra). Tỷ giá Bảng Anh hiện ở mức 27.627 đồng - 28.805 đồng (mua vào - bán ra). Tỷ giá Nhân dân tệ hôm nay ở mức 3.393 đồng - 3.538 đồng (mua vào - bán ra). Giá USD hôm nay giảm, giá vàng hôm nay tăng Chỉ số US Dollar Index (DXY) đo lường biến động đồng bạc xanh với 6 đồng tiền chủ chốt (EUR, JPY, GBP, CAD, SEK, CHF) hiện ở mức 105,707. Giá USD đang tụt nhanh nhưng giới phân tích dự báo giá USD sẽ sớm tăng trở lại khi có ý kiến cho rằng Fed đang tỏ thái độ \\"ôn hoà\\" quá sớm. Thêm vào đó, sự suy yếu trong nền kinh tế toàn cầu sẽ tiếp tục ảnh hưởng đến tâm lý các tài sản rủi ro. \\"Quan điểm của chúng tôi là đà giảm của đồng USD sau cuộc họp của Uỷ ban thị trường mở (FOMC) sẽ sớm bị đảo chiều\\", chuyên gia của ING nhận định. Fed vừa nâng lãi suất thêm 0,75%, lần thứ hai liên tiếp, để đối phó lạm phát tồi tệ nhất nhiều thập kỷ. Lãi suất tham chiếu tăng sẽ ảnh hưởng đến hàng triệu hộ gia đình và doanh nghiệp Mỹ. Do nó sẽ kéo hàng loạt lãi suất lên cao, như lãi vay mua nhà, mua ôtô, lãi thẻ tín dụng và vay kinh doanh, từ đó làm giảm tốc nền kinh tế. Lợi tức trái phiếu kho bạc gây áp lực khiến đồng bạc xanh trượt sâu trong sắc đỏ. Trong cuộc họp tháng 9 tới, Fed sẽ đánh giá lại tác động của việc tăng lãi suất đối với lạm phát và nền kinh tế. Chuyên gia ING cho rằng giới đầu tư tin việc Fed quay sang lập trường ít diều hâu hơn là quá sớm và nhà đầu tư nên giữ lại các hợp đồng đô la giao kỳ hạn cho đến khi Fed đưa ra các tín hiệu rõ ràng hơn\\". Các chuyên gia của Morgan Stanley có đồng quan điểm và cho rằng Fed có khả năng sẽ vẫn \\"tập trung vào việc chống lạm phát, bất chấp các dấu hiệu tăng trưởng yếu hơn\\". Giá vàng thế giới hiện ở mức 1766,50 - 1767,50 USD/ounce. Động thái tăng lãi suất chưa từng có tiền lệ cho thấy Fed quyết tâm đến mức nào trong cuộc chiến chống lạm phát hiện cao nhất 4 thập kỷ. Giá USD giảm đã tác động tích cực đến giá vàng. Giá vàng thế giới đảo chiều bật tăng sau 3 tháng giảm. Giá vàng SJC trong nước hiện ở mức 66,10 - 67,10 triệu đồng/lượng (mua vào - bán ra). Giá vàng SJC tăng 400.000 đồng/lượng ở cả hai chiều so với phiên trước đó.","answer":"Tranh thủ chốt lời, giá USD liên tục giảm, giá vàng tăng, ồ ạt bắt đáy"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"Aza manao toy Itsimadilo manaraka mpandranto, _\\"","answer":"\\"ka ny an-tanana ihany no manaraka.\\""},{"question":"ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਨੇ ੧੯ਵੀਂ ਤੇ ੨੦ਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਿਵੇਕਲਾ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਇਆ। ਭਾਈ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਬੋਲੀ ਦੇ ਰਾਹੀ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਕੀਤਾ। ਉਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਾਵਲਾਂ, ਕਿਤਾਬੜੀਆਂ, ਅਖਬਾਰ ਛਾਪ ਕੇ ਗੁਰਬਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੌਮ ਦੇ ਘਰਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਾਇਆ। ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਦੇ ਗ੍ਰੰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਛਪਾਈ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਗ੍ਰੰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਅਹਿਮ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ। ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ੫ ਦਸੰਬਰ  ੧੮੭੨ ਈ.ਨੂੰ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ। ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਦਾਦਾ ਭਾਈ ਕਾਹਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਵੀ ਗਿਆਨਵਾਨ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਸਨ। ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਖਾਨਦਾਨੀ ਮਰਿਆਦਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਅਤੇ ਅੱਠ ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਨ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ।  ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਬਤੀਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਦੇ ਵਡਮੁੱਲੇ ਕਾਰਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਵਿਉਂਤਬੰਦੀ ਨਾਲ ਵਿੱਦਿਅਕ ਢਾਂਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਦਲਿਆ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕੇਵਲ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਧਰਮ, ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਦਲਣਾ ਸੀ ਸਗੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿੱਦਿਅਕ ਢਾਂਚੇ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਈਸਾਈ ਧਰਮ, ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਵੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਸੀ।ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਲਾਉਣ, ਅਖਬਾਰ ਛਾਪਣ,ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟਾਂ,ਲੇਖਾਂ,ਸਾਹਿਤਕ ਰਚਨਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਗ੍ਰੰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਪਾਦਨਾ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਇਆ।ਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਲਾਉਣਾ :-  ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਵਜ਼ੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਜ਼ੀਰ ਏ ਹਿੰਦ ਪ੍ਰੈਸ ੧੮੯੨ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਲੂ ਕੀਤਾ। ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਓਹਲੇ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਚਲਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਰਚਨਾਵਾਂ ਇਸੇ ਪ੍ਰੈਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਛਪਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ।ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਰਾਹੀਂ:- ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਸਿਧਾਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਜਾਗ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਖ਼ਾਲਸਾ ਸਮਾਚਾਰ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ। ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਕਈ ਮਸਲੇ ਉਠਾਏ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਦਾ ਪਸਾਰ, ਇਸਤਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ,  ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਬੋਲੀ ਦੀ ਉੱਨਤੀ, ਅਕਾਦਮਿਕ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰਕ ਖੇਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਯੋਗ ਸਥਾਨ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ, ਸਿੱਖ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਧਾਰ। ਇਸ ਖ਼ਾਲਸਾ ਸਮਾਚਾਰ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਫੀ ਜਾਗ੍ਰਿਤੀ ਆਈ।ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟਾਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ:- ਭਾਈ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਛੋਟੇ ਛੋਟੇ ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟਾਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਵੀ ਸਿੱਖੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਅਹਿਮ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਇਆ। ਸੰਨ ੧੮੯੩  ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਖਾਲਸਾ ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟ ਸੁਸਾਇਟੀ ਦੀ ਨੀਂਹ ਰੱਖੀ। ਇਸ ਸੁਸਾਇਟੀ ਨੇ ੧੪੦੦ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟ ਛਾਪੇ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਟ੍ਰੈਕਟਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਇਹ ਹੋਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਧਰਮ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਤਮ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਸਰਵੋਤਮ ਹੈ। ਸਿੱਖ ਮੱਤ ਦੇ ਅਸੂਲਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਸਾਕਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਫ਼ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਤੇ ਸਰਲ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਜਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨੋਤਰ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ। ਸਾਹਿਤਕ ਰਚਨਾਵਾਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ:- ਭਾਈ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਵਿਤਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਵੀ ਸਿੱਖ ਸਿਧਾਂਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਝਲਕਾਰੇ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਹ ਕਵਿਤਾਵਾਂ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹਨ: ਲਹਿਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਾਰ, ਮਟਕ ਹੁਲਾਰੇ, ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਵੀਨਾ, ਕੰਬਦੀ ਕਲਾਈ-੧, ਕੰਬਦੀ ਕਲਾਈ-੨, ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਈਆਂ ਜੀਓ ਆਦਿ| ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਵਲ ਵੀ ਗੁਰਸਿੱਖੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਵਾਲੀ ਬਾਕਮਾਲ ਰਚਨਾ ਹੈ। ਗ੍ਰੰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਪਾਦਨਾ:- ਭਾਈ ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਗ੍ਰੰਥਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਰੜਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਖੋਜ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਪਾਦਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ।ਇਹ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਹਨ:- ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ, ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤਮਾਲਾ,  ਪ੍ਰਾਚੀਨ ਪੰਥ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼,  ਪੁਰਾਤਨ ਜਨਮਸਾਖੀ, ਸਾਖੀ ਪੋਥੀ, ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਕੋਸ਼, ਗੁਰਪ੍ਰਤਾਪ ਸੂਰਜ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ, ਪੰਜ ਗ੍ਰੰਥੀ ਸਟੀਕ, ਸੰਥਿਆ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ।"},{"question":"シミュレーションゲームなどでよく見られる、六角形型の枡目を何というでしょう？","answer":"ヘックスです。"},{"question":"निम्नलिखित कविताको अर्थ लेख्नुहोस्:शोभायमान भई बस्छ सभा विष को ?सब्को प्रसन्न मन गर्दछ शास्त्रले जो ।मातासरी सुख दिन्या कुन चिज छ जान्नू ?विधै छ त्यस्तो अरु कौन खोज्नू ?","answer":"सभामा सबैभन्दा शोभायुक्त भएर जो कोही बस्न सक्दैन । तर जो मानिसले आफ्नो ज्ञान र नैतिकताको प्रयोग गरेर आफु वरपरको मानिसलाई खुसी राख्न सक्छ ऊ सभामा सम्मानित भएर आसिन हुन्छ ।"},{"question":"Su’aal sheeg Magaca Buurta Afrika ugu dheer?","answer":"Jawab: Waa Kalaminjaaro."},{"question":"اردو میں مضحکہ خیز شعر لکھیں۔","answer":"اردو میں ایک مزاحیہ بند درج ذیل ہے۔شوقِ سنگھار بجا ہے میرا لیکنتیری تنخواہ میرے صدقات میں اڑ جائیگیس عہد کم ظرف میں بس یہ ہی اک رونا ہے کے تم کھانسو تو کھانسی ہم کھانسیں تو کرونا ہے زندگی میں ایک بات ہمیشہ یاد رکھنا غالب.پانی سے نہاؤ گے تو گیلے ہو جاؤ گے"},{"question":"විශාලත්වය හා සංයුතිය අතින් පෘථිවියට සමානතම ග්‍රහලෝකය කුමක්ද?","answer":"කෙප්ලර් 452-B"},{"question":"வினாதமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் \\"வால்டர் ஸ்காட்\\" எனப்படுவர் யார்? ","answer":" விடை   - கல்கிகல்கி (9 செப்டம்பர் 1899 – 5 திசம்பர் 1954) புகழ் பெற்ற தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர் ஆவார். இரா. கிருஷ்ணமூர்த்தி என்ற இயற்பெயர் கொண்ட இவர் 35 சிறுகதைத் தொகுதிகள், புதினங்கள், கட்டுரைகள், பயணக்கட்டுரைகள் மற்றும் வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்று நூல்களை எழுதியுள்ளார். எனினும், மிகச் சிறந்த சமூக மற்றும் வரலாற்றுப் புதினங்களை எழுதியதற்காக பரவலாக அறியப்படுகிறார். இவர் எழுதிய பொன்னியின் செல்வன் புதினம் மிகப் புகழ் பெற்றதாகும். தன் படைப்புகள் மூலம் இந்திய தேசிய விடுதலை போராட்டத்திற்கும் பங்களித்திருக்கிறார். தியாகபூமி புதினம் திரைப்படமாகவும் எடுக்கப்பட்டது.கல்கி 1899-ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் 9-ம் தேதி பழைய சென்னை மாகாணத்தில் ஒன்றிணைந்த தஞ்சாவூர் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள மயிலாடுதுறை அருகே அமைந்த பட்டமங்களம் எனும் ஊரில் ஒரு பிராமணக் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார். ஆரம்பப்பள்ளிப் படிப்பைத் தனது கிராமத்தில் முடித்த பிறகு அவர் திருச்சியில் உள்ள தேசிய உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் சேர்ந்தார். 1921-இல் மகாத்மா காந்தியடிகள் ஒத்துழையாமை இயக்கத்தைத் துவக்கிய போது, அவரது கருத்துக்களால் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டு கல்கி தனது பள்ளிப்படிப்பைப் பாதியில் துறந்து இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரசு கட்சியில் சேர்ந்தார். 1922-இல் சுதந்திரப் போராட்டத்தில் பங்கு பெற்றதற்காக ஓராண்டு சிறைத் தண்டனை அனுபவித்தார். 1923-இல் அவர் நவசக்தி என்னும் பத்திரிகையின் துணை ஆசிரியராகப் பணியாற்றினார். அவருடைய முதல் புத்தகம் ஏட்டிக்குப் போட்டி 1927-இல் வெளியானது."},{"question":"Haz una carta contundente para un aumento salarial por haber cumplido unos objetivos acordados anteriormente.","answer":"[Fecha de hoy][Remitente][Destinatario]Señor/a,Respetuosamente me dirijo a usted, para solicitarle el aumento salarial correspondiente al acuerdo pactado previamente entre la empresa [NOMBRE_EMPRESA] y yo. Este acuerdo quedó debidamente plasmado en el contrato que firmamos el día [Fecha del contrato,] en el cual se dejó claro que una vez se cumplieran ciertos objetivos, la empresa procedería a aumentar mi salario en [porcentaje o valor del aumento] de lo que devengo actualmente.Espero que, con la seriedad que los distingue, y teniendo en sus manos el justificante de los objetivos cumplidos, se lleve a cabo el correspondiente aumento de mi salario y podamos seguir trabajando juntos por el bienestar de la empresa.Atentamente,[Firma][Tu nombre] "},{"question":"Cố nhà giáo Nguyễn Ngọc Ký từng lập kỷ lục nào của Việt Nam?","answer":"Thầy giáo Nguyễn Ngọc Ký sinh ngày 28/6/1947 tại Hải Thanh, Hải Hậu, Nam Định. Đôi tay bị liệt từ nhỏ nhưng ông tự tập viết bằng chân và vào đại học, trở thành nhà giáo. Năm 2005, ông về hưu, vừa sáng tác văn học cho thiếu nhi, vừa làm tư vấn Tâm lý giáo dục qua tổng đài 1088 của TP HCM.Cùng năm này, Tổ chức Kỷ lục Việt Nam tặng ông danh hiệu: \\"Người thầy đầu tiên của Việt Nam dùng chân để viết\\". Năm 2011, ông được ghi nhận tiếp Kỷ lục \\"Nhà văn đầu tiên viết bằng chân\\".Thầy giáo Nguyễn Ngọc Ký qua đời sáng 28/9/2022, hưởng thọ 75 tuổi tại TP HCM."},{"question":"Бакыт деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Бактылуу болуу- бул ден соолукта болуу. Окумуштуулар позитивдүү адамдар азыраак ооруй турганын айтышат.Башкаларга жардам берүү менен биз өзүбүзгө да жакшылык кылган болобуз.Башкаларга жадам берүү батыраак бактылуу болууга жардам берери далилденген. Канчалык көп жакшы иш жасоо ошончолук бактылуулукту алып келери талашсыз.Бактылуулук кийинки урпактарга калуучу нерсеАлбетте, таң калыштуу бирок бул далилденген. Миннесота университетинин изилдөөлөрүнө ылайык бакыт генден генге өтөт.Бактылуу болуу биздин иммунитетибизге оң таасирин тийгизет."},{"question":"જ્યારે તેઓ માત્ર 15 વર્ષના હતા ત્યારે તેમણે ભારતીય સૈનિકો(ભારત-પાક યુદ્ધ 1965)ના સ્વંયસેવક તરીકે કાર્ય કરતા અને તેમને રેલ્વે સ્ટેશન સુધી પહોચાડતા. તેમણે 1967માં 17 વર્ષની વયે ગુજરાતમાં આવેલ પૂર દરમિયાન લોકોની મદદ કરી હતી. તેઓ ઓબીસી ફેમિલીમાંથી હતા અને તેમને બાળપણથી જ સંન્યાસી થવાની ઈચ્છા હતી. શાળાકીય શિક્ષણ પછી તેઓ ઘરેથી હિમાલય ભાગી ગયા હતા અને ત્યા તેઓ સાધુ સાથે થોડા મહિના રહ્યા હતા.જ્યારે તેમને પાસે બિલકુલ પૈસા બચ્યા નહી ત્યારે તેઓ બે મહિના પછી ઘરે આવ્યા. ત્યારે જ તેમણે સંન્યાસી થવાનો વિચાર આવ્યો હતો.","answer":"હિમાલયમાંથી પરત ફર્યા પછી નરેન્દ્રએ પોતાના ભાઈ સાથે રાજ્ય પરિવહન ઓફિસ પાસે ચા નો સ્ટોલ ચલાવવો શરૂ કર્યો. તેઓ પોતાના દેખાવને લઈને હંમેશા સચેત રહેતા. તેમને પ્રેસવાળા કપડા અને વાળ ઓળેલા રાખીને રહેવુ ગમતુ હતુ. તેઓ તેમની માતાના ખૂબ જ નિકટ છે. તેઓ કોઈપણ નિર્ણય લેતા પહેલા પોતાની માતાના આશીર્વાદ લેવાનુ ભૂલતા નથી. તેઓ શુદ્ધ શાકાહારી છે. મોદીએ કહે છે, માંની મમતા, માતાના આશીર્વાદથી જીવન જીવવાની જડીબુટ્ટી મળે છે. તેમની વ્યક્તિત્વ જોઈને ઘણી સ્ત્રીઓ તેમના તરફ આકર્ષતી હતી. તેમના ગઢ ગુજરાતમાં નરેન્દ્ર મોદી સ્ત્રીઓ માટે સેક્સ સિમ્બોલ છે."},{"question":"රූපවාහිනිය සොයා ගත්තේ කවුද?","answer":"රූපවාහිනිය සොයා ගත්තේ ජෝන්‌ ලොගී බෙයාඩ්‌ මහතාය."},{"question":"O que significa a expressão \\"Amigo da Onça\\" em Português do Brasil?","answer":"Essa expressão se refere à uma pessoa, que age como amiga, mas na verdade é traiçoeira, ou desleal."},{"question":"ما فكرة الكشافة؟","answer":"الكشافة هي حركة شبابية تربوية تطوعية غير سياسية عالمية، هدفها تنمية الشباب بدنيًا وثقافيًا. أسسها ووضع قواعدها اللورد بادن باول عام 1907.أتت فكرة الكشافة لبادن باول أثناء حصار مافكنج عندما حاصرت عصابات البوير (مهاجرين من أصل هولندي) معسكر الإنجليز فاستعان بالشباب للقيام بالأعمال العسكرية كالحراسة والطهي ونقل الرسائل، وتمكن من فك الحصار بعد 7 شهور ثم قام بإنشاء فرق كشفية لعمر الكشاف وأقام مخيم تجريبي عام 1907 في إنجلترا خلال الأيام التسعة الأولي من شهر أغسطس في جزيرة براونسي وشارك فيه 20 من الفتيان، وبعد نجاح الفكرة قام بتوسيع الفئة العمرية فضم الأشبال. كتب بادن باول مبادئ الكشَّافة في كشَّافة للأولاد (لندن، 1908)، مستندة على كُتُبِه العسكرية السابقة، بالتأثيرِ ودعمِ فريدريك روسل بيرنهام (رئيس الكشّافين في أفريقيا البريطانية). أثناء النصف الأوّل من القرن العشرون. نشأت الحركة على إحاطة ثلاثة مجموعات عمرية رئيسية للأولاد (شبل كشاف، كشّاف، روفر سكاوت)، وفي عام 1910, بدأت منظمة جديدة للفتيات سُميت «مرشدات»، أُنشِأتها أخت بادن باول (دليل حورية ومرشدة وفتاة كشافة ودليل حارس). بعد ذلك تم إنشاء فرق للفتيات بمساعدة زوجة بادن باول وأخته. و في عام 1909 نشر بادن باول كتابه الكشافة للأولاد الذي ترجم إلي عدة لغات بقي بادن باول وزوجته مترأسين الحركة الكشفية حتى مماته."},{"question":"def process_response(response):    return (*response, {} if len(response) == 2 else response[2])یہ ایک لائن کوڈ ہے جو اصل کوڈ کی مماثل منطق کو پورا کرتا ہے، یہ تپل کی انپیکنگ اور ایک ڈکشنری کی تشکیل کے لئے شرطی طور پر کلید-قیمت جوڑوں کو شامل کرنے کے لئے استعمال ہوتا ہے۔","answer":"یہ پایٹھون کا کوڈ ہے، اس کو بہتر بنانے کے لیے یہ یہ قدم لیے جا سکتے ہیں:1۔ فنکشن بنایا جاے2۔ اس کوڈ کو 1 لاین میں کردیا جاے۔ اس کو one-liner بھی کہتے ہیں۔\`\`\`pythondef process_response(response):    return (*response, {}) if len(response) == 2 else response\`\`\`"},{"question":" Noocyada Sadaqada tee ugu fadli badan","answer":" Waxaa ugu fadli badan Biyaha oo lays waraabsho"},{"question":"I wonder అర్మేనియన్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం యొక్క నినాదం ఏంటి?Can you get me some context to answer this (in the same language as my question)?","answer":"అర్మేనియన్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ (ఎ.ఎస్.యు.ఇ) (Armenian State University of Economics), ఆర్మేనియా రాజధాని యెరెవాన్ లోని విశ్వవిద్యాలయం. దీనిని 1975లో ప్రారంభించారు.చరిత్రయెరెవాన్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్సిటీలో ఎకనామిక్స్ అధ్యాపక వర్గం 1930 లో స్థాపించబడింది. 1975 లో ఇది యెరెవాన్ ఇన్స్టిట్యూట్ ఆఫ్ నేషనల్ ఎకానమీ అనే పేరుతో ఒక స్వతంత్ర విభాగంగా ఏర్పడింది, తర్వాత ఎరెవన్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ గా మారింది.1995 లో యూనివర్సిటీ కొత్త విద్యాసంవత్సరం నల్బందియాన్ 128లో కొత్త భవనంలో ప్రారంభించింది. ఇది జైతున్ జిల్లాలో ఒక విభాగం మాత్రమే.2006 లో ఈ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం ఆర్మేనియన్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ గా పేరు మార్చబడింది, ఇది రాష్ట్ర వాణిజ్యేతర సంస్థ.సుమారు 30.000 విద్యార్థులు ఈ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం నుండి పట్టభద్రులయ్యారు. విశ్వవిద్యాలయంలోని ఆరు విభాగాలలో మొత్తం 31 కుర్చీలు (21 ప్రొఫెషనల్ మరియు 10 ప్రొఫెషనల్ కానివి) కలిగి ఉన్నాయి.అర్మేనియా రిపబ్లిక్ నేషనల్ అకాడమీ ఆఫ్ సైన్సెస్ లో ఒక ప్రతినిధి సభ్యుడు, 35 సైన్సు వైద్యులు, ప్రొఫెసర్లు, 141 వైద్యులు, అసోసియేట్ ప్రొఫెసర్లు, 87 అసిస్టెంట్ ప్రొఫెసర్లు, 103 లెక్చరర్లు మరియు 60 మంది పార్టి-టైమ్ ఉపాధ్యాయులు. ఈ యూనివర్సిటీలోని 18 మంది ప్రత్యేక కోర్సులలో మరియు 7000 మంది విద్యార్థులు ప్రత్యేక కోర్సులు చదువుతున్నారు.ఈ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం 2005 నుంచి బాచిలర్ యొక్క పూర్తి స్థాయి డిగ్రీలను, 2004 నుండి పూర్తి సమయం మాస్టర్స్ డిగ్రీలను, అలాగే పార్ట్ టైంను కూడా అమలు చేస్తున్నారు. పూర్తి మరియు పార్ట్ టైమ్ డిగ్రీ కోర్సులను క్రెడిట్ సిస్టమ్ ద్వారా అమలు చేస్తారు.ఈ విశ్వవిద్యాలయంలో పోస్ట్ గ్రాడ్యుయేట్ స్టడీస్ (పార్ట్ టైమ్ మరియు ఫుల్-టైమ్ రెండూ) కూడా నిర్వహిస్తున్నారు. 2010-2011 విద్యా సంవత్సర పోస్ట్-గ్రాడ్యుయేట్ అధ్యయనాలు కూడా క్రెడిట్ వ్యవస్థను ఆమోదించాయి.ఎ.ఎస్.యు.ఇ క్రింది వాటితో విద్యా మరియు శాస్త్రీయ సంబంధాలను కలిగి ఉంది: రాస్సోవ్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ (రష్యా),టాంస్ బాటా విశ్వవిద్యాలయం, జ్లిన్ (చెక్ రెపబ్లిక్),టిబిసి స్టేట్ యూనివర్శిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్ రిలేషన్స్ (జార్జియా),సంక్ట్-పీటర్స్బర్గ్ స్టేట్ యూనివర్సిటీ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్ అండ్ ఫైనాన్స్ (రష్యా),స్వాన్సీ మెట్రోపాలిటన్ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం (ఇంగ్లాండు).వివిధ కోర్సులు2017 నాటికి, ఈ విశ్వవిద్యాలయం 6 కోర్సులకు కేంద్రంగా...వు0ది "},{"question":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya10- MAXAA LAGA DHAXLEY NIDAAMKII 21 OCT. e) -GARSOOR AAN LAHEEYN DASTUUR. ","answer":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya10- MAXAA LAGA DHAXLEY NIDAAMKII 21 OCT. e) -GARSOOR AAN LAHEEYN DASTUUR. Garsoorku waa heeyada ugu sareeysa nidaam dowladnimo ama nidaam kasta oo jira oo umada ka dhexeeya kuna hishiiyeen.   Hadana garsoorku wuxuu u baahan yahey awood u gaar ah hishiiska ama dastuurka, hadii uusan jirin dastuur loo noqdo waxa imaanaayo rayi shaqsi oo an umada u dhexeeyn Karin ama awood sheegato iney goaanka leedahey. Garsoorku wuxuu leyahey mid dowli ah iyo mid wadamada sameeystaan oo u gaar ah oo ku xusan dastuurkooda, mar kasta ama inta badan garsoorku wuu ka madax banana yahey heeyadaha kale ee dowlada, waana meesha loo noqdo hadii is khilaaf siyaasi ah ama midaan siyaasi aheyn uu dhaco go,aankana iyadaa iska leh. Hadaba soomaliya waxey laheyd dastuur la ansaxiyey 1961dii oo qeexayo doowrka uugarsoorku ku leeyahey dastuurka iyo awooda garsoorayaasha iyo shaqadooda waxaana jirey xiligaas oo ay dowladu ku shaqeyneeysey nidaamka dimoqoraadiyada maxkamad sare iyo kuwo iyada hoos yimaada iyo xeer ilaaliyaaliyo gudoomiye iyo gudoomiyaal qeybo kala duwan, waxeyna dadka denbiyada lagu soo oogo u ogolaan jirtey qareen u dooda waxaana lailaalin jirey xurmada qofka ilaa denbiga ku cadaado hadii qalad dhaco waxaa masuuliyadeeda iska leh shaqsiga xilka hayo ee sharciga ku xad gudbo, hadey dhinaca amniga tahey iyo hadey cadaalad daro kudhacdo maxkamadu waa arin shaqsi ku kooban isagaa amaanadeeda qaadaayo.Mar hadii sharci la raaco jiro la weymaayo shaqsi ilaaliya somalinimida waayo wey jiraan dad wadaniyiin ah oo wanaagsan oo ilaalinaayo sharafkisa iyo kan dalkiisa. Markii talada la wareegeen saraakiishii 21 oct sidaan hore u soo sheegney weey laabeen dastuurkii qeexayey garsoorkawaxeyna la yimaadeen waxay u baxsheen maxkamada badbaadada oo aan laheyn nidaam sharci ku saleeysan waayo qofkii lageeyo wax baaritaan ah lagu sameeymaayo, qaren u doodana qofku ma leh.Xeer ilaaliyaha oo barnaamij u degsan wata ayaa wuxuu rabo sheegaayo, gudoomiyuhuna sidoo kale wuu barnaamij gareeysna waxeyna xukunadoodu u badnaayeen dil ama 30 sano oo xabsi ah,waayo ruuxii loo dan leyahey ayaa la geyn jirey, nidaamka dhexdiisana weey isku kala reebi jireen ninkii la rabo in baska laga tuuro waa la geeyn jirey, marka waxey aheyd maxkamad waxa nidaamku doonayomeel marsiiso. halkii uu garsoorku uu ahaan lahaa mid sharciyeeysan oocaadil ah umaduna u siman tahey waayo dadku xuquuq ayeey leyihiin xitaa marka dastuur la sameeynayo waxaa loobandhigaa shacabka si ay u fahmaan oo u ogaadaan waxa ku qoran iyo wixii uu xuquuq ku leeyahey si gaar ah iyo si guudba sharcigaa wadanka u degsan kadibna ay doortaan waxeyna taasi ay fududeeyneeysaa in loo hogaansamo sharciga."},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال متى تم اكتشاف فرساي ؟ من النص التالي: أقدم ذكر لقرية فرساي وجد في وثيقة مؤرخة تعود إلى عام 1142، (\\"الميثاق من كنيسة سانت - بيتر دي شارتر\\"). كان من الموقعين على الميثاق \\"هوغو دي فيرساي\\"، حيث ذكرت اسم القرية لأول مرة. خلال هذه الفترة، تركزت قرية فيرساي على قلعة صغيرة وكنيسة حيث كانت المنطقة تحت سيطرة لورد أو إقطاعي محلي..","answer":"تم اكتشاف أقدم ذكر لقرية فرساي في وثيقة مؤرخة تعود إلى عام 1142، حيث ذُكر اسم القرية لأول مرة في \\"الميثاق من كنيسة سانت - بيتر دي شارتر\\"."},{"question":"什麼是歐洲冠軍聯賽？","answer":"是歐洲足總主辦的年度足球比賽，代表歐洲俱樂部足球最高榮譽，組織完善高效，被譽為全世界最高競技水準的俱樂部盃賽。"},{"question":"Quais são os nomes dos filhos de Kim Kardashian e Kanye West?","answer":"North, Saint, Chicago e Psalm."},{"question":"Celebrated for its ability to improve athletic capacity and glucose metabolism, HIIT is typically a cardiovascular exercise strategy that involves alternating periods of intense exercise with recovery. What does HIIT stand for?","answer":"High-Intensity Interval Training"},{"question":"‘మొక్కల పెంపకం’ ఆవశ్యకతను వివరిస్తూ ఒక కరపత్రం తయారు చేయండి.","answer":"“వృక్షముల పెంపకం”చెట్లు జీవన సౌభాగ్యానికి మెట్లు. నేడు నగరాలు, గ్రామాలు కూడా, పర్యావరణ కాలుష్యంతో సతమతమవుతున్నాయి. ప్రజలంతా రోగాలతో డాక్టర్ల వెంట తిరుగుతున్నారు. దీనికి కారణం దేశంలో పచ్చని చెట్లు తక్కువ కావడమే.చెట్లు బొగ్గుపులుసు వాయువును పీల్చి, ప్రాణవాయువును మనకు అందిస్తాయి. పూలను, పండ్లను ఇస్తాయి. చల్లని నీడను, గాలిని ఇస్తాయి. పర్యావరణ కాలుష్యం నుండి మనలను కాపాడతాయి.కాబట్టి ప్రతి వ్యక్తి ఒక్కొక్క చెట్టును పాతి పెంచాలి. ప్రభుత్వము మంచి మొక్కలను ప్రజలకు ఉచితంగా ఇచ్చి వాటిని పాతించాలి. మొక్కలను పెంచి, వాటికి రక్షణ కల్పించాలి. దేశంలో సహితం అడవుల విస్తీర్ణం నేడు తగ్గిపోయింది. అందుకే మనకు వర్షాలు లేవు.ప్రతి పంచాయితీ వారు మునిసిపాలిటీ వారు, మొక్కలను ఖాళీ ప్రదేశాల్లో పెంచాలి. మొక్కలను పెంచిన వారికి ప్రోత్సాహకాలు ఇవ్వాలి. గిరిజనులను ప్రోత్సహించి అడవులలో మొక్కలు పెంచాలి. మనమంతా మొక్కలను పెంచుదాం. మన దేశాన్ని సస్యశ్యామలం చేద్దాం.ఇట్లు,నగర రక్షణ సమితి."},{"question":"Viết bài báo tối đa 1000 chữ có tiêu đề và tóm tắt như sau:Tiêu đề văn bản: Giá xăng tăng mạnh, tại sao chi bình ổn vẫn nhỏ giọt?Tóm tắt văn bản: Quỹ bình ổn giá đang dương ở mức cao nhưng việc xả quỹ \\"nhỏ giọt\\" khiến xăng vọt lên mức cao nhất trong năm nay.","answer":"Tại sao \\"găm\\" quỹ, chi nhỏ giọt ?Giá xăng dầu tại kỳ điều chỉnh vừa qua (21.9) tăng mạnh, xăng tăng cao nhất gần 900 đồng/lít, dầu cũng tăng cao nhất 630 đồng/lít. Sau tăng, giá xăng RON 95 vọt đến mốc 26.000 đồng/lít, mức cao nhất trong 9 tháng qua. Đáng nói, Quỹ bình ổn (QBO) giá xăng dầu đang có số dư rất lớn, lại không được chi sử dụng suốt 5 kỳ điều hành vừa qua để kìm hãm đà tăng. Tại kỳ này, giá xăng thế giới tăng mạnh, liên bộ Công thương - Tài chính cũng chỉ cho chi sử dụng QBO 300 đồng mỗi lít (trừ dầu mazut), khá thấp. Trở lại quý 2, việc trích lập quỹ lên đến 1.780 tỉ đồng nhưng chi trong quý chỉ hơn 5,9 tỉ đồng. Theo báo cáo của Bộ Tài chính, tính đến ngày 31.7, số dư của quỹ đã lên tới hơn 7.438 tỉ đồng, mức cao nhất từ quý 1/2021 đến nay. Thế nhưng, kể từ đầu năm đến nay, mức chi quỹ hết sức khiêm tốn và số lần chi cũng hãn hữu.Cụ thể, tính từ kỳ điều hành ngày 12.6 đến kỳ điều hành ngày 21.9, giá xăng E5 RON92 đã tăng 3.683 đồng/lít, tương đương 17,64%, xăng RON95-III tăng 4.130 đồng/lít (18,76%), dầu diesel 0.05S tăng 5.964 đồng/lít (34,82%), dầu hỏa tăng 6.206 đồng/lít (34,82%), dầu mazut tăng 3.465 đồng/kg (23%).Theo Bộ Công thương, xăng dầu chiếm tỷ lệ cao trong tổng chi phí sản xuất của các ngành kinh tế. Chẳng hạn trong hoạt động khai thác thủy sản, chi phí xăng dầu chiếm 76,73% tổng chi phí sản xuất; vận tải 63,36%; khai thác than 45,18%... Việc tăng giá xăng dầu thường tác động mạnh đến các hoạt động sản xuất kinh doanh và cuộc sống thường nhật của người dân. Bà Nguyễn Quốc Khánh, đại diện một công ty logistics nước ngoài có trụ sở đặt tại Q.1, TP.HCM, nhận xét đừng nghĩ giá xăng dầu chưa đạt đỉnh như năm ngoái nên cứ cho tăng, không tác động giảm sớm. Chi phí vận chuyển nội địa cũng đã ước tính trong giá báo cho doanh nghiệp từ đầu năm. \\"Chẳng hạn, giá xăng dầu chúng tôi đưa vào bài toán tính giá vận tải cho doanh nghiệp năm nay dao động từ 22.000 - 24.000 đồng/lít, nay xăng vọt lên trên 26.000 đồng/lít và có thể tăng thêm. Trong khi đó, tiền trích trong QBO từ người mua xăng dầu còn hơn 7.400 tỉ đồng, đang được doanh nghiệp xăng dầu \\"giữ tạm\\", sao không cho xả nhiều hơn. Sao găm quỹ đó không chi? Tại sao lại ưu ái cho doanh nghiệp nhập khẩu xăng dầu mà bỏ qua quyền lợi của người tiêu dùng?\\", bà Nguyễn Quốc Khánh thắc mắc.Chi \\"dè sẻn\\" vì sợ giá tăng tiếp ?Việc tăng giá xăng dầu cao trong thời điểm này tất nhiên khiến doanh nghiệp sản xuất, kinh doanh dịch vụ lo lắng hơn. Bởi sau 2 quý đầu năm đơn hàng giảm, sản xuất kinh doanh giảm, quý 3 là thời điểm tăng tốc để phục hồi, lấy đà cho quý cuối năm. Chính phủ cũng có các chỉ đạo nhằm kìm giá hàng hóa để kích thích tiêu dùng trong nước. Thế nên, cùng ngày liên Bộ Công thương - Tài chính công bố điều chỉnh tăng giá xăng dầu, Văn phòng Chính phủ có văn bản gửi 2 bộ này liên quan việc quản lý và sử dụng QBO. Cụ thể, Phó thủ tướng Lê Minh Khái yêu cầu 2 bộ bám sát diễn biến giá xăng dầu thế giới và trong nước, theo thẩm quyền chủ động điều hành kịp thời, hiệu quả giá xăng dầu và sử dụng QBO theo đúng quy định. Yêu cầu tuyệt đối không để thiếu hụt, đứt gãy nguồn cung trong mọi tình huống, chịu trách nhiệm toàn diện về kết quả điều hành giá xăng dầu; tăng cường thanh tra, kiểm tra, giám sát, kịp thời ngăn chặn, xử lý nghiêm theo quy định các hành vi đầu cơ, trục lợi, găm hàng, buôn lậu xăng dầu qua biên giới…PGS-TS Ngô Trí Long, nguyên Viện trưởng Viện Nghiên cứu thị trường giá cả, đánh giá xăng tăng đến 26.000 đồng/lít trong bối cảnh nền kinh tế nỗ lực kìm lạm phát, kích cầu là tương đối cao, gây khó cho phục hồi. Theo ông, \\"lý tưởng\\" nhất lúc này là mua xăng dầu ở mức giá 18.000 - 20.000 đồng/lít. Tuy vậy, ông lại cho rằng việc quyết định chi sử dụng QBO bao nhiêu có thể được các cơ quan quản lý tính toán và dự báo rồi, không thể thấy \\"xông xênh\\" lại mạnh tay xả quỹ, đến khi giá thế giới tăng nữa, lại \\"không còn gì để chi\\". Ông Long chia sẻ xu hướng giá dầu thế giới từ nay đến cuối năm sẽ tăng nữa, khó giảm. Các nhà phân tích thị trường thế giới dự báo giá dầu thô Brent chuẩn toàn cầu đang dưới mốc 95 USD/thùng nhưng sẽ lên 100 USD/thùng từ nay đến cuối năm. Thế nên, cơ quan điều hành giá trong nước có thể tính phương án trong thời gian tới, việc trích quỹ nữa sẽ hơi gặp khó khăn, nên điều hành bằng hình thức xả quỹ từ từ. Mỗi kỳ điều chỉnh giá, xả quỹ một ít, sẽ giúp giá không tăng sốc lên 31.000 đồng/lít như năm ngoái… \\"Giá xăng đang ở đỉnh nếu tính từ đầu năm đến nay, nhưng cần có chiến lược phòng ngừa rủi ro, nguồn tài lực của quỹ cũng có giới hạn. Giá còn tăng nữa, chi ào ào thì khi giá thế giới tăng vọt, rất nguy hiểm. Quan trọng là phân bố, chi sử dụng hợp lý. Tôi nghĩ vậy\\", PGS-TS Ngô Trí Long nhấn mạnh.Tuy nhiên, chuyên gia thương mại Vũ Vinh Phú lại có quan điểm khác: Giá xăng dầu tại kỳ điều hành gần đây so với giá giữa tháng 6 đã cao hơn từ 17,64 - 34,82%, chỉ trong 3 tháng, mức tăng như vậy là quá lớn cho chi phí đầu vào của doanh nghiệp. Đáng nói, mức tăng giá dầu rất cao, trong khi dầu là nhiên liệu cho ngành sản xuất, khai thác, đánh bắt cá... \\"Tôi cũng như nhiều người quan sát thị trường trong và ngoài nước, khá băn khoăn khi kỳ điều chỉnh giá vừa rồi, liên bộ lại cho xả quỹ quá khiêm tốn. Là mặt hàng đặc biệt, nhưng thiết yếu, điều hành giá xăng dầu cần có sự linh hoạt và sự can thiệp kịp thời, đúng thời điểm mới hiệu quả. Giá đầu vào tăng thì sẽ đẩy giá hàng hóa, dịch vụ tăng theo. Giá xăng dầu tăng mạnh trước lúc người dân, doanh nghiệp vẫn còn nhiều khó khăn. Đồng thời, nguy cơ tăng chỉ số tiêu dùng (CPI) quý 4 với biên độ nhanh hơn. Theo tôi, liên bộ Công thương - Tài chính nên nghiên cứu sớm để có thể làm hạ nhiệt giá các mặt hàng là đầu vào toàn xã hội, đánh giá giá cả trên góc độ toàn diện và sát thực tế hơn\\", ông Phú nhấn mạnh. "},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Ranomaso tsy  ................................. \\"  ","answer":"\\"  Ranomaso tsy mahatana aina \\" "},{"question":"Gaweo crita anak-anak nganggo judul: Kethek, Pitik, lan Yuyu.Topik: wong kekancan kudu apik marang sapada-pada.Jawaban:","answer":"Ing jaman ndisik, ana satunggaling pitik kang kekancan karo kethek. Ananging paseduluran kuwi ora awet suwe amarga kelakuan si kethek. Sawijining dina, kethek ngejak pitik mlaku mlaku sinambi golek pangan. Nganti wayah srengenge angslep ana ing kulon loro kewan kul mau durung ugo nemu pangan kang bisa maregake wetenge. Dumadakan tanpa disangka lan dinyana kethek kang wis kadung ngeleh duwe pikiran elek marang kancane yaiku si pitik. Tanpa rasa mesakake kethek nyekel si pithik lan mbubuti wulune kanthi niat arep mangan mbakar pithik kanggo mangan wengi iku. Ananging mergo pitik terus-terusan usaha kanggo lolosake awake, akhire dheweke bisa ucul saka si kethek. Pitik banjur mlayu nganti tumeka sawijining pinggir segara kang dipanggoni sawijining yuyu sing ora liya ugo dadi kancane si pitik.Ana ing panggonan kul pitik cerita marang yuyu:Pitik: Hel Yuyu kancaku, tulungono aku, aku lagi diuber karo kethek sing arep mangan akuYuyu: Orasah kuwatir kancaku, aku bakal nyelametke awakmu saka kethek kang ora reti arti kekancan kui mau Aku bakal weneh pelajaran supaya kethek kui mau ora wani maneh ganggu awakmu.Sawise kahanan leren, pitik lan yuyu ngatur siasat kanggo weneh pelajaran marang kethek mau. Yuyu due ide nggawe perahu saka lemah lendut kanggo nyeberang ana ing pulau sacerake segara kui. Sawisi perahu kang digawe kui dadi banjur pitik lan yuyu ngundang kethek kanggo nyebrang bareng ana ing pulau sacerake kanggo golek pangan. Mergo kahanan ora ana pangan ing sakiwo tengene panggonan kui, banjur kethek langsung wae nyaguhi ajakane pitik kanggo menyang pulau seberang. Sawise prahu mlaku ana ing tengah segara banjur pitik mau kluruk sinambi notol prahu kang pada di tumpake kui mau. Alon-alon prahu kang digawe saka lemah lendut kui mau otomatis bocor lan banyu mlebu ing prahu. Ora bisa ditahan maneh prahu kang pada ditumpaki kui mau ambles ing segara. Pitik kang wis siap lan ngencanakake kedadean kui kanthi siap langsung mabur ing darat, yuyu kang ugo wis siap kedadean kui banjur nglangi ing dasar segara, sawentara kethek kang jahat lan ora reti arti kekancan kui mau amung bisa tulung-tulung lan angslep amarga ora bisa nglangi. Singkat cerita kethek kui mau mati glagepen ing tengah segara. Saka crita iki, bisa kita jupuk pelajaran yen wong kekancan kudu apik marang sapada-pada. Amarga kita ora mangerti kapan kita ugo butuh kanca sapada-pada."},{"question":"Soalan: Negara manakah yang mempunyai bahagian terbesar tenaga yang dihasilkan oleh tenaga nuklear?","answer":"Jawapan: Perancis mempunyai bahagian terbesar tenaga yang dihasilkan oleh tenaga nuklear."},{"question":"දෙස බස රැස යන්නෙහි 'රැස' කියන්නේ ජාතියට ද?","answer":"රැස කියන්නේ ජාතියට තමයි.දෙස - දේශයබස - භාෂාවරැස - රාශිය"},{"question":"问题：三星耳机的噪音隔离技术如何？","answer":"答案：三星耳机采用主动噪音隔离和被动噪音隔离技术，有效减少外界噪音的干扰。"},{"question":"Ilaa aad ka farxiso qofka aad tahay?","answer":"Ilaa aad ka farxiso qofka aad tahay, waligaa kuma farxi doontid waxaad haysato. Waa in aad yeelataa hannaan aad farxadda ku abuurato, haddii ay dadka ka shaqeeyaan, kaa horkeen waxaad la irkigto adna la imow hab aad isku farxad galiso. Waqti ha iskaga lumin sidii aad kaga fekeri lahayd caqabadaha yar yar ku hor imaan doona, ka feker sidii aad noloshaada u quruxsan lahayd. Sirta farxadda leh waa aqbalidda meesha aad joogto iyo waxa aad nolosha ku haysato oo aad maalin walba ka faa’iidaysato. Haku farax galiso nolosha aad ku nooshahay,  ahow mid imaankiisa dhammeystiran yahay, qanaacadda waa qeyb ka mi ah iimaanka. Marka ugu dambaysa ee aad hesho wax kasta oo aad rabto, waxaad arki doontaa inay jiraan waxyaabo badan oo badan oo la gaadhi karo.! Dib ha u dhigin farxaddaada ilaa aad ka gaarto yoolalkaaga, faraxsanoow mar waliba.  Dhoollacaddeynta awoodda lagu jabiyo cadowga kugu horgudban. Ha muujin fursad ay dadka kugu niyad burburshaan. Yeelo xeer kuu gaar ah si waliba wax isku kaa hortaagaan aadan ka leexan. Nolosha haka weecweecan wajah arrin waliba mustaqbaalkaada soo foodsaara.   Farxadeenna waxay ku jirtaa socdaalkii aan soo marnay, geeddi -socodyadii aan u adkaysannay, caqabadihii aan ka soo gudubnay,  koritaankii aan la kulannay, casharradii aan barannay, taasi waa waxa keenaya dhammaystir, halkaas ayay farxaddeennu ku jirtaa.Haddii aadan ku faraxsanayn meesha aad joogto iyo waxa aad haysato, farxaddaadu ma sii jiri doonto marka aad gaarto halka aad u socoto oo aakhirka hesho waxaad rabto.Haddii aad ka shaqayn karto sidii aad u fiicnaan lahayd intii aad la tartami lahayd dadka kale.Waad ku farxi doontaa dedaalkaada.! Ha sugin in aad hesho farxad kuu gaar ah ilaa aad ka fahanto, qofka rasmiga aad tahay, naftaada dhabcaal haku noqon, xaqa ay kaa mudan tahay,  tarbiyadeeda sii si ay kuu farxad galiso barritoole. "},{"question":"Mỗi xúc xắc có sáu mặt, số chấm ở mỗi mặt là một trong các số nguyên dương l; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6.Gieo xúc xắc một lần.a) Nêu những kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc.b) Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc có phải là phân tử của tập hợp {mặt 1 chấm; mặt 2 chấm; mặt 3 chấm; mặt 4 chấm; mặt 5 chấm; mặt 6 chấm} hay không?c) Viết tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc.d) Nêu hai điều cần chú ý trong mô hình xác suất của trò chơi trên.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Những kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc: mặt 1 chấm, mặt 2 chấm, mặt 3 chấm, mặt 4 chấm, mặt 5 chấm, mặt 6 chấm.b) Mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc là phân tử của tập hợp {mặt 1 chấm; mặt 2 chấm; mặt 3 chấm; mặt 4 chấm; mặt 5 chấm; mặt 6 chấm}.c) Tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc là {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}. Ở đây, 1 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 1 chấm, 2 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện 2 chấm, 3 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện 3 chấm, 4 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 4 chấm, 5 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 5 chấm, 6 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 6 chấm.d) Có hai điều cần chú ý trong mô hình xác suất của trò chơi trên là:- Gieo xúc xắc một lần;- Tập hợp các kết quả có thể xảy ra đối với mặt xuất hiện của xúc xắc là {1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6}. Ở đây, 1 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 1 chấm, 2 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện 2 chấm, 3 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện 3 chấm, 4 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 4 chấm, 5 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 5 chấm, 6 kí hiệu cho kết quả xúc xắc xuất hiện mặt 6 chấm."},{"question":"أكمل العبارة التالية:  وقد تزايدت المخاوف الأمنية للبطولة منذ الاحتجاجات ذات النطاق الواسع خلال تنظيم البرازيل لكأس القارات","answer":"2013 مع الاضطرابات التي تحدث ايضا خارج الملاعب. وأشار المتظاهرون إلى كمية الأموال العامة التي أنفقت من قبل الحكومة البرازيلية في استضافة كأس العالم على حساب الخدمات الاجتماعية لسكانها كخطأ رئيسي."},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra ny \\"Le Rouge et le Noir\\"?","answer":"\\"Le Rouge et le Noir\\" dia nosoratan'ny mpanoratra frantsay Stendhal. Izy io dia tantara ara-psikolojika izay mikaroka ny fiakaran'ny sosialin'ny tovolahy iray feno fatra-paniry laza."},{"question":"Medicana Fizik Tedavi SGK karşılıyor mu?","answer":"Medicana Sağlık Grubu, tüm branşlarda SGK anlaşmalıdır."},{"question":"Título : Corea del Norte asegura que en agosto tendrá listo el plan para atacar la base militar de Estados Unidos en la isla de Guam.Dame un buen artículo para el título anterior. ","answer":"La declaración resultó inusualmente detallada.El general Kim Rak-gyom, comandante de la Fuerza Estratégica del Ejército del Pueblo Coreano, dijo que \\"los cohetes Hwasong-12 cruzarán el cielo por encima de las prefecturas de Shimane, Hiroshima y Koichi de Japón\\".Según el general, citado por medios estatales norcoreanos, el plan es que los misiles vuelen 3.356,7 km durante 1.065 segundos hasta alcanzar las aguas de Guam, a unos 30 o 40 km de la isla.Lo inusualmente detallada de la declaración marca un paso más en la escalada de tensión entre Pyongyang y Washington después de que el presidente de EE.UU., Donald Trump, hablara de responder a Corea del Norte con \\"fuego y furia como nunca antes se había visto\\".Corea del Norte celebró manifestaciones en apoyo de la posición de su gobierno contra Estados Unidos.Antes el gobierno norcoreano dijo que iba a vengarse \\"mil veces\\" en contra de EE.UU. y sus aliados ante las sanciones que le impuso Naciones Unidas por su programa nuclear.Además, para el gobierno norcoreano, las palabras de Trump son \\"tonterías\\" de un hombre \\"desprovisto de razón\\", y \\"el diálogo sano no es posible\\".\\"Sólo la fuerza absoluta puede funcionar con él\\".DiálogoGuam, isla de unos 160.000 habitantes ubicada en el océano Pacífico, tiene un importante valor estratégico por ser sede de un importante contingente militar.Allí, el secretario de Estado, Rex Tillerson, llegó para asegurarle al personal estadounidense que Corea del Norte no supone una amenaza inminente.Tillerson se mostró esperanzado en que una campaña de \\"presión global\\" que incluya a China y Rusia pueda servir para iniciar un diálogo con Pyongyang.Tillerson paró en Guam tras su gira por Asia.En medio de la escalada retórica, el secretario de Defensa de EE.UU., James Mattis, emitió un comunicado con un llamamiento a Pyongyang a abandonar su programa armamentístico.\\"Deben elegir dejar de seguir aislándose y poner fin a su búsqueda de armas nucleares\\".\\"Mientras el Departamento de Estado hace todos los esfuerzos..."},{"question":"Шта је потребно спаковати за камповање?","answer":"Потребне ствари за камп у многоме зависе од тога где идете на камп, те од тога да ли неко од учесника има неке посебне потребе. Неке од основних ствари су: шатор, швајцарски нож, врећа за спавање, јастук на надувавање, храна, пиће, лампа и компас. "},{"question":"Türkiye hangi torbada yer alacak?","answer":"Grubunu lider olarak tamamlayan Türkiye'nin 2. torbada yer aldığı kura çekimi, Almanya'nın Hamburg kentinde 2 Aralık Cumartesi günü gerçekleştirilecek."},{"question":"දෙමළ එල්ලු.....තලවලටනමක් ( ධාන්‍ය) එතකොටතලෙළු තල එලළු යන ශරීර ස්වරූපය ගැන කියන වචනය ඉහත දෙමළ වදනට සබඳබවක් වේද?","answer":"ප්‍රශ්නෙට සියයට සීයක් අදාල නොවුනත් ඔබගේ දැනගැනීම පිණිසයි පහත සටහනලිඛිත බසින් තල වලට දෙමළ නම \\"එල්\\" எள் මිස එල්ලු නෙවෙයි.නමුත් වචනෙ යෙදෙන අයුර අනුව කතා කරන කොට එහෙම කියවෙනවා .ඒ වගේම් එල්ලු කියන කොට අවසන් අකුරේ ශබ්දය හරියටම සිංහලෙන් ලියන්න බෑ.එය ලු හා ලී අතර වූ සෞම්‍ය ශබ්දයක් . ඒ වගේමයි පල් සහ පල්ලු (දත) ල් අකුර දීර්ඝ ස්වරයක් හැටියට ශබ්ද කරනවා  වගේ."},{"question":"Pytanie: Ile meczów wygrali Oakland Raiders w zeszłym roku? ","answer":"Odpowiedź: Dwanaście"},{"question":"சூழல் - ஒன்று:  மீனாவின் அம்மா மீனாவுக்கு மட்டுமின்றி அவளின்  நண்பர்களுக்கும் பிறந்த நாள் வாழ்த்துகள் தெரிவிக்கிறார்.சூழல் – இரண்டு: வளவனின் அப்பா யார் எந்த உதவி கேட்டாலும் நீ செய்யக் கூடாது என்று கூறுகிறார். இதுபற்றி உங்கள் கருத்து என்ன?","answer":"சூழல் ஒன்று :தான் போற்றத்தக்கது. மீனாவின் அம்மாவைப் போல் நாமும் அனைவரிடமும் அன்புடனும் நட்புடனும்பழகவேண்டும். அப்போதுதான் ஒருவருக்கொருவர் விட்டுக் கொடுத்து வாழும் பண்பைப் பெறுவர். வளரும் குழந்தைகளுக்கு நற்பண்புகளைக் கற்றுக் கொடுக்க வேண்டும்.சூழல் இரண்டு : யாரும் பின்பற்றக் கூடாத குணம். உதவி செய்து வாழ்வதைப் பற்றி முதலில் வளவனின் அப்பா அறிய வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Iwe uneMamiriro ezvinhu: “Ndiri kuedza kutsvaga makiyi angu. Ndinoyeuka ndichipinda mukamuri mangu maawa maviri apfuura nadzo pandiri”Pindura mubvunzo \\"Makiyi angu aripi?\\" kupihwa zano rinotevera \\"ndabva kwechinguva kuti ndinoona shamwari\\"","answer":"Pamwe ndakavakanganwa mumba meshamwari yangu."},{"question":"Ko pẹ ti Rauf gba igbega lẹnu iṣẹ ọlọpaa ni wọn ni awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ pa a l’Osogbo","answer":"Ko sẹni to le de agbegbe ọja Olobu, nijọba ibilẹ Irẹpọdun, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, nibi ti awọn mọlẹbi ọmọkunrin ọlọpaa kan, Kọpura Fawale Rauf, to ti doloogbe bayii n gbe, ti ko ni i kaaanu abiamọ.Ṣe ti ọmọ ikoko ti ko ti i pe oṣu kan ti iyawo oloogbe naa n gbe dani ni, abi ti awọn obi rẹ ti wọn n wa ẹkun mu bii omi? Ṣe ti awọn aburo Rauf ti wọn n pariwo pe ogo idile awọn lo ti lọ ni, abi ti awọn araadugbo ti wọn n royin iwa tutu ati suuru rẹ?Bawo lọrọ ṣe jẹ gan an? Ọdun 2016 ni Rauf darapọ mọ iṣẹ ọlọpaa lẹyin to jade ileewe, inu oṣu kin-in-ni ti a wa yii lo si gba lẹta igbega si ipo kọbura lẹnu iṣẹ. Agọ ọlọpaa to wa ni Dada Estate, niluu Oṣogbo, lo ti n ṣiṣẹ ko too pade iku ojiji lọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu ti a wa yii.Gẹgẹ bi iyawo oloogbe, Fawale Balikis, ṣe sọ fun ALAROYE, “Ibiiṣẹ lo dagbere laaarọ ọjọ naa, nigba to si di alẹ ti n ko gburoo rẹ, mo ni boya o n ṣiṣẹ alẹ (night shift) ni. Foonu mi si ti ku, n ko raaye pe foonu rẹ.“Nigba to di aarọ ọjọ keji, mo gburoo ọkada kan niwaju ile, ẹnikan ti a n pe ni Bọọda Tunji ni wọn gbe ọkọ mi wale, o si rin wọnu ile lai sọrọ. Mo beere pe ki lo ṣẹlẹ, ṣugbọn ko da mi lohun, mo kọju si ẹni to gbe e wa pe ki lo ṣe ọkọ mi, iyẹn naa ko fun mi lesi, ṣe lo kan sọ pe ki ọkọ mi sinmi daadaa, ko si maa lo oogun rẹ, igba yẹn lo ko awọn oogun kan fun un pẹlu risiiti ileewosan LAUTECH.“Bi wọn ṣe lọ tan lọkọ mi sun sori bẹẹdi, ko sọrọ kankan, mo waa ro pe boya oogun tabi abẹrẹ ti wọn fun un lo mu ko rẹ ẹ ni. Ṣugbọn titi ti ilẹ fi ṣu, ko laju, bẹẹ ni ko sọrọ. Bi ilẹ ọjọ keji, ṣe mọ ni mo pe aburo ọkọ mi obinrin tawọn naa n gbe Ilobu pe bi ọkọ mi ṣe n ṣe ko ye mi.“Nigba ti ẹni yẹn de ni wọn fi agbara yi ẹgbẹ ọkọ mi pada lori bẹẹdi to sun si, bẹẹ la ri i pe ẹjẹ ti di sinu eti ẹ, oju-apa kekere kan si wa lẹyin ori rẹ. Aburo ọkọ mi sọ pe ka maa gbe e lọ si ọsibitu, a gbe e lọ si ọsibitu Aanu-Olu, lẹyin ayẹwo ni wọn dari wa sileewosan LAUTECH.“Ni LAUTECH, wọn ni ka lọọ ya aworan agbari ẹ, inu aworan yii la ti ri i pe ori yẹn ti san sinu, ẹjẹ ti rọ sibi ti ko yẹ ko rọ si, oriṣiiriṣii apa lo ti wa ninu agbari yẹn. Bayii ni wọn dari wa si UCH, Ibadan, ẹnikan lo wa sọ fun wa pe dokita kan wa lagbegbe Oke-fia toun naa kọṣẹ-mọṣẹ nipa iṣẹ-abẹ ori.“Bi a ṣe debẹ, dokita yẹn sọ pe oun le ṣe iṣẹ naa, ṣugbọn alẹ lawọn maa n ṣeru ẹ. O ni ka lọọ san ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta naira na (#500,000). A wa owo kaakiri, wọn si ṣe iṣẹ-abẹ naa lalẹ Satide yii kan naa, sibẹ ọkọ mi ko sọrọ.“Odidi ọsẹ kan la lo nibẹ, ẹrọ tawọn alaaarẹ fi maa n mi (oxygen) ni wọn gbe si i lẹnu, ṣugbọn nigba to di alẹ ọjọ Satide, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu yii, ọkọ mi jade laye, a si sin in nilana ẹsin Islam.“Ninu iwadii ti a ṣe lori ohun to ṣẹlẹ si ọkọ mi lo ti di mimọ pe nigba to ṣiwọ lẹnu iṣẹ lalẹ ọjọ kẹrinla, yẹn ni ọga rẹ kan, Mọdi, pe e sibi ayẹyẹ ọjọọbi to fẹẹ ṣe nileetura River Side, niluu Oṣogbo. Ibi ayẹyẹ naa la gbọ pe wọn wa tawọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ DSS mẹta kan fi doju ija kọ ọ.“A gbọ pe ọkan lara wọn, David Olowopọrọku, lo kọkọ jan irin mọ ọn lori, ki awọn meji ti wọn jọ wa nibẹ too bẹrẹ si i jan nnkan mọ ọn, koda, ọwọ to gbe soke lati da irin yẹn duro rọ (paralyse) loju-ẹsẹ, to si wa bẹẹ titi ti a fi sinku rẹ. Titi di asiko yii, a ko rẹni sọ fun wa ohun to pa oun atawọn DSS ọhun pọ to fi di pe wọn lu u pa.‘Mo n rawọ ẹbẹ sijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ati kọmisanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ yii pe ki wọn ṣaanu mi, ki wọn ma jẹ ki iya yii jẹ mi gbe, ọmọ mẹta ni mo ti bi fun un, ọmọ ọdun mẹjọ lakọbi wa. Ki wọn ma jẹ kawọn DSS yii fọwọ ọla gba mi loju, mi o lẹnikan, ki wọn ba mi wa awọn to wa pẹlu David Olowopọrọku lọjọ naa ri, ki awọn mẹtẹẹta naa le foju winna ofin”Bakan naa lọrọ ri lẹnu baba to bi Rauf, Alagba Fawale Rabiu. Baba yii ni oloogbe lakọbi ninu awọn ọmọ toun bi, o ni wọn ti kan oun leyin ọọkan pẹlu bi wọn ṣe pa ọmọdekunrin ẹni ọdun marunlelọgbọn naa, ṣugbọn oun nigbagbọ ninu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa pe wọn aa ṣawari awọn DSS mẹtẹẹta ti wọn fina ọmọ jo oun.ALAROYE de ọdọ Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, o ni loootọ lawọn ti gbọ nipa iku ọmọkunrin naa, ati pe ileeṣẹ ajọ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ nipinlẹ Ọṣun ti mu Olowopọrọku atawọn meji ti wọn fẹsun ọhun kan, bẹẹ ni wọn si ti n ṣewadii wọn lọwọ.O ni Kọmisanna ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde ko fi ọwọ yẹpẹrẹ mu ọrọ naa rara, o si ti beere fun pe ki awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ taari awọn mẹtẹẹta sọdọ awọn ọlọpaa fun iwadii to jinlẹ lori iṣẹlẹ naa lati le mọ nnkan to da wọn pọ lọjọ yii, bẹẹ lo ti fi to olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa leti l’Abuja.Ọpalọla ke si awọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ alaabo to ku lati ri ara wọn bii ọmọ iya, ki wọn mọ pe erongba aabo ẹmi ati dukia awọn araalu lawọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ tọ. O tun ke si awọn araalu lati ma ṣe jẹ ki iṣẹlẹ naa dẹruba wọn, nitori yoo yanju laipẹ, iru rẹ ko si tun ni ṣẹlẹ mọ."},{"question":"Is the tweet below expressing a positive, negative, or neutral sentiment?@user Gaskiya ina fatan haka amma dai abin kamar da wuya😢😢😢","answer":"Yes the tweet is expressing negative sentiment."},{"question":"Quantos caracteres tem na seguinte frase: O verdadeiro conhecimento é saber a extensão da própria ignorância.","answer":"Essa frase tem 67 caracteres."},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال من كان يتكون جيش التحرير اليوغوسلافي ؟ من النص التالي: لم يحظ جيش التحرير اليوغوسلافي بدعم كبير من الكروات في السنوات الأولى من الحرب، باستثناء الموجودين في منطقة دالماتيا، وتشكل معظمه من الصرب الكرواتيين. بدأ الكروات في الانضمام إلى جيش التحرير الوطني بأعداد أكبر في عام 1943، وازداد عددهم بشكل ملحوظ، ليشكوا 61٪ من أفراده عام 1944، بينما شكل الصرب 28٪؛ وشكلت الأعراق الأخرى نسبة 11٪ المتبقية..","answer":"جيش التحرير اليوغوسلافي كان يتكون من مجموعة متنوعة من الأعراق والقوميات في يوغوسلافيا خلال الحرب العالمية الثانية. وفقًا للنص المقدم، كان جيش التحرير اليوغوسلافي يشكله معظمًا الصرب الكرواتيين في البداية. ومع تقدم الحرب، بدأ الكروات في الانضمام إلى الجيش بأعداد أكبر في عام 1943. في العام 1944، بلغت نسبة الكروات في صفوف الجيش 61٪، في حين كانت نسبة الصرب تشكل 28٪. بالإضافة إلى ذلك، كان هناك أعضاء من أعراق أخرى يمثلون نسبة 11٪ المتبقية، مما يظهر تنوعًا قوميًا في تكوين جيش التحرير اليوغوسلافي."},{"question":"Inona ary izany: atoko tsy masaka, atono mora foana?","answer":"volo"},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 秋田犬のハチは、亡くなった飼い主が帰ってくるのを渋谷駅で待ち続けました。多くの人が知っている有名な話です。ハチが生まれてから今年11月で100年になります。","answer":"JR東日本の山手線で20日から、100年のお祝いのマークをつけた電車の運転が始まりました。20日は渋谷区出身で俳優の井上順さんが1日だけの駅長になって、出発の合図をしました。 マークは2つあって、ハチや数字の100などがかいてあります。この電車は来年3月まで走ります。 井上さんは「ハチの話はこれからも伝えられていきます。毎日たくさんの人が通る渋谷駅で、みんながいい思い出を作ってほしいと思います」と話していました。"},{"question":"Ποια θα ήταν η ερώτηση για την παρακάτω απάντηση: \\"Ο Έλβις Άαρον Πρέσλι (8 Ιανουαρίου 1935 - 16 Αυγούστου 1977) ήταν Αμερικανός τραγουδιστής και ηθοποιός\\".; Το θέμα είναι ο Έλβις Πρέσλι.","answer":"\\"Ποια χρονιά γεννήθηκε ο Έλβις;\\""},{"question":"Inona ny fantatra fa nitranga voalohany tany Wisconsin ny taona 1878?","answer":"Ny fandaminana fifaninanana moto no fantatra fa nitranga voalohany tany Wisconsin ny taona 1878."},{"question":"다음 단락을 완성시키시오. 카를 4세는 선거 군주제를 통해 선출된 군주였기 때문에 독일에서는 그의 입지가 약한 편이었다. 카를 4세는 \\"성직자왕\\"(Pfaffenkönig)이라는 별칭을 갖고 있었는데 신성 로마 제국의 여러 주교들과 도시들은 여전히 루트비히 4세 황제를 지지하고 있었다. 1346년 8월에 일어난 백년 전쟁의 크레시 전투","answer":"에서는 아버지인 얀과 함께 전투에 참전했지만 아버지인 얀은 전사했고 카를 4세는 부상을 당한 상태에서 도망쳤기 때문에 살아남았다."},{"question":"Wọn ti le ọlọpaa mẹta to fipa gbowo lọwọ akẹkọọ LASU lẹnu iṣẹ","answer":"Awọn ọlọpaa mẹta nni,Inspẹkitọ Sunday John, Sajẹnti Jimọh Asimiya ati Sajẹnti Solomon Adedapọ ti wọn fipa gbowo lọwọ akẹkọọ LASU, Sheriff Adedigba, l’Owode-Ẹgba, ti padanu iṣẹ wọn bayii, ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti gbaṣẹ lọwọ wọn.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ni aṣiri awọn ọlọpaa naa tu, lẹyin ti wọn fipa gba ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọjọ ati mẹta naira, (153,000) lọwọ akẹkọọ to n lọ s’Ekoo lati Abẹokuta.Ori ẹka ayelujara ni Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, Edward Ajogun, ti gbọ nipa ohun ti awọn ọlọpaa naa ṣe, ẹsẹkẹsẹ lo si ti pe DPO teṣan Owode-Ẹgba lati wa awọn ọlọpaa naa jade. Wọn kọkọ fi wọn si yara ahamọ, wọn si ni wọn yoo gba idajọ wọn laipẹ.Nigba ti yoo fi di ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹrin yii, idajọ wọn de. DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi sọ ọ di mimọ pe ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti le awọn mẹta yii danu lẹnu iṣẹ ọlọpaa, ki ohun ti wọn ṣe le jẹ ẹkọ fawọn abanilojujẹ agbofinro mi-in to ba n ṣe bẹẹ tabi ti wọn ba tun fẹẹ dan iru ẹ wo lọjọ iwaju.Wọn ti da owo Sheriiff pada fun un ni tiẹ, nitori bọwọ ṣe tẹ awọn ọlọpaa mẹta naa ni wọn ti gbowo ọhun pada lọwọ wọn.Bi ẹ ba kofiri ọlọpaa to n fipa gbowo lọwọ ẹnikẹni, ẹ ma jẹ ko pẹ ti ẹ oo fi fẹjọ rẹ sun ni olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, bẹẹ ni CP Edward Ajogun wi."},{"question":"Victor Hugo mất bao lâu để hoàn thành tiểu thuyết Những người khốn khổ?a. Khoảng 10 nămb. Khoảng 20 nămc. Khoảng 30 năm","answer":"Victor Hugo mất khoảng 20 nămTheo Telegraph, sau khi Nhà thờ Đức Bà Paris được xuất bản năm 1831, Victor Hugo ấp ủ ý tưởng về cuốn tiểu thuyết lột tả sự bất công trong xã hội. Tuy nhiên, đến năm 1862, ông mới hoàn thành tiểu thuyết Những người khốn khổ.Thông tin về thời gian đại văn hào viết tác phẩm không được khẳng định nhưng nhiều nhà nghiên cứu cho rằng ông bắt đầu viết từ năm 1840, tức mất khoảng 20 năm để hoàn thành."},{"question":"Apakah maksud nasionalisme?","answer":"Perasaan cinta yang mendalam terhadap bangsa dan negara."},{"question":"اذكر الحدث المهم في ما يلي: هدف روني ضد مقدونيا جعله أصغر هداف لمنتخب إنجلترا حتى ذلك التاريخ، حيث كان يبلغ من العمر آنذاك 17 عاماً و317 يوماً، فتجاوز بذلك الرقم القياسي الذي سجله مايكل أوين أمام المغرب سنة 1998 خلال بطولة كأس الملك الحسن الثاني الدولية. كما جعل هذا الهدف من روني أصغر هداف في التصفيات المؤهلة لبطولة أمم أوروبا، وهو اللقب الذي حمله روني إلى غاية تسجيل لاعب المنتخب الإسرائيلي بن سحر هدفاً ضد إستونيا في مارس 2007. في يونيو 2004، سجل روني أول أهداف إنجلترا الثلاثة للفوز على سويسرا خلال بطولة أمم أوروبا، وبذلك أصبح أصغر لاعب يسجل هدفاً في مباراة أوروبية. لكنه كان سجلاً قصير الأمد، إذ سجل السويسري يوهان فونلانتين -وهو أصغر من روني بثلاثة أشهر- هدفاً مماثلاً بعد أربعة أيام.","answer":"بطولة أمم أوروبا"},{"question":"Inona ny fisorohana ny aretin’ny voa ?","answer":"Ireto misy torohevitra vitsivitsy fisorohana ny aretin’ny voa :-Tsara raha misotro rano 1,5 hatramin’ny 2 litatra isan’andro ny olon-dehibe maherin’ny 40 kilao. -Sakafo madio sy voalanjalanja no ilain’ny vatan’olombelona. Tsara raha mihinana legioma sy voankazo maro isan’andro. -Ahena na ajanona tanteraka ny fihinanana sakafo misy fangaro manaitra (excitants/ épices) sy ireo ahitana akora simika tsy mahasalama ;-Mila matory adiny 7 na 8 isan’alina ny olona iray. Ny tsy fahampian’ny torimaso dia miteraka fikorontanan’ny fiasan’ny taova."},{"question":"வினா : அரசு நாணய மதிப்பை குறைப்பது எதை அதிகரிக்கிறது ? ","answer":"விடை : சேமிப்பைஅதிகரிக்கிறது"},{"question":"¿Qué significa invitar a alguien a ver Netflix?","answer":"Significa hacer de la suyas y tener un momento carnal (sexo)."},{"question":"Tichipa iyi ndima pamusoro peSelena Gomez, zita rake rekutanga rakabva kupi? Selena Marie Gomez akaberekwa munaChikunguru 22, 1992, muGrand Prairie, Texas, naRicardo Joel Gomez uye aimbova mutambi wenhanho wekuTexas Mandy Teefey. Akatumidzwa zita remuimbi weTejano Selena Quintanilla, akafa muna 1995. Baba vake vanobva kuMexico, asi amai vake, avo vakarerwa, vane madzitateguru eItaly. Sekuru nasekuru vaGomez vakatamira kuTexas kubva kuMonterrey muma1970. Nezvenhaka yake, Gomez akati \\"anodada chizvarwa chechitatu cheAmerica-Mexican\\" uye \\"Mhuri yangu ine quinceañeras, uye tinoenda kuchechi yechirairo. Isu tinoita zvese zviri muKatorike, asi isu hatina chero chechinyakare. kunze kwekuenda kupaki uye kunogocha nyama neSvondo tabva kuchechi.\\" Gomez ainyatsotaura chiSpanish kusvika pazera rechinomwe. Vabereki vake vakarambana paaiva nemakore mashanu, uye akaramba aina amai vake. Gomez ane vanun'una vaviri nemunin'ina wekurera: Gracie Elliot Teefey, kuburikidza naMandy nemurume wake wechipiri, Brian Teefey, naVictoria \\"Tori\\" naMarcus Gomez, kuburikidza naRicardo nemukadzi wake wechipiri, Sara. Akawana dhipuroma rechikoro chepamusoro kuburikidza nekudzidzira kumba muna Chivabvu 2010.","answer":"Selena Gomez akatumidzwa zita raSelena Quintanilla, muimbi weTejano."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Cuál es el segundo libro de la trilogía de Los Juegos del Hambre?","answer":"En llamas o en inglés : Catching Fire. "},{"question":"د جسټن بیبر د ورور نوم څه دی؟","answer":"جسټن بیبر بیولوژیکي ورور نلري. هغه د خپل پلار جیریمي بیبر پخوانیو اړیکو څخه د جازمین بیبر په نوم یو نیم ورور او نیمه خور لري."},{"question":"Sheeg Ninkii Ugu Horeeyey Gaalada Laga Dilo Dagaalkii Beder?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Al Aswad Bin Cabdil Azad"},{"question":"Iwadii bẹrẹ lori ijamba ina to paayan mẹta n’Ikẹja","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko ti lawọn maa tọpinpin, awọn yoo si jẹ karaalu mọ ohun to ṣokunfa ijamba ina nla kan to waye lalẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, niluu Ikẹja, nipinlẹ Eko, ninu eyi ti eeyan mẹta ti dagbere faye, awọn mẹtala si fara gbọgbẹ yannayanna.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, lo ṣọrọ ọhun nigba to ṣabẹwo sibi iṣẹlẹ ni deede aago mejila ọganjọ oru ọjọ naa.Odumosu ni ko ti i ṣeni to le sọ pato ibi ti ina naa ti wa, ṣugbọn ohun kan to daju ni pe awọn ileeṣẹ to n pọn afẹfẹ gaasi ati epo bẹntiroolu to wa nitosi maa wa lara ohun to mu ki ina naa ṣọṣẹ gidi.Atẹjade kan lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun, eyi ti ajọ to n ri si iṣẹlẹ pajawiri lorileede yii, National Emergency Management Agency (NEMA), ẹka ti Eko, fi lede laaarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe awọn mẹta lo ti doloogbe, wọn lawọn mẹta ọhun, oṣiṣẹ ile ounjẹ Chinese kan to wa nitosi otẹẹli Sheraton ni wọn, wọn l’Ọgbẹni Balogun to jẹ maneja ile ounjẹ naa wa lara awọn to ku.Alukoro NEMA, Ọgbẹni Ibrahim Farinloye, to buwọ lu atẹjade ọhun sọ pe awọn doola ẹmi awọn mẹsan-an ti ina naa ka mọ, ṣugbọn wọn ti fara gbọgbẹ gidi, tori ina naa ti mu wọn ki wọn too ri wọn fa jade, ti wọn si sare gbe wọn lọ sọsibitu ijọba to wa n’Ikẹja.O lawọn mẹrin mi-in tun fara pa nibi akọlu to ṣẹlẹ nigba tọrọ di bo-o-lọ-o-yago latari bawọn eeyan ṣe n sa asala fun ẹmi wọn.Bakan naa lo lawọn o ti i le sọ pato ohun to ṣokunfa ijamba naa, ṣugbọn iwadii ti n lọ lọwọ pẹlu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Eko.Ohun ta a gbọ, gẹgẹ bi Ọgbẹni Rotimi Ọlawale to n gbe lagbegbe ọhun ṣe sọ f’ALAROYE ni pe “Ojiji lawọn ṣadeede gburoo ariwo kan to da bii ki agba gaasi bẹ, ko si pẹ ti iro buruku naa dun lawọn tun ri i pe ina ti ṣẹ yọ, ina naa si lagbara gidi.“Nitori ọpọ eeyan ti wọle sun, oju oorun niṣẹlẹ naa ti ba wọn, ko si seeyan to mọ ibi ti ina naa ni n bọ, ikọlukọgba nla lo ṣẹlẹ, tonikaluku bẹrẹ si i sa asala fẹmii wọn, ki ina naa ma lọ ka wọn mọle.“Ẹgbẹ otẹẹli Sheraton to wa loju ọna Mobọlaji Bank-Anhony, lo ti ṣẹlẹ, ileepo Total kan si wa nibẹ, ileeṣẹ ti wọn ti n ta afẹfẹ gaasi idana kan tun wa nitosi, a si ri tanka epo diisu kan to n ja epo lọwọ lagbagbe naa lasiko tiṣẹlẹ naa waye.“Ina naa ti jo supamakẹẹti Oasis kanlẹ, o si ti mu otẹẹli Sheraton to wa lẹgbẹẹ ẹ. Gbogbo awọn alejo to wa ninu otẹẹli ti bẹ sita, ṣun-kẹrẹ-fa-kẹrẹ ọkọ ti ṣẹlẹ loju popo, kaluku lo n wa ọna lati sa asala.” Ọgbẹni Ọlawale lo ṣalaye bẹẹ.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe ko pe tawọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ panapana fi de sibi iṣẹlẹ naa, ti wọn si tete kapa ina ọhun."},{"question":"Sheeg Asxaabigii Dhimashadiisa Dartiis Uu Cashriga La Gil Gishay ?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Sacad Bin Mucaad."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berkut: Negara apakah yang mengalami banjir sebelum hujan?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Bahrain. Nama negara ini terdiri daripada 'bah' dan diikuti oleh 'rain'. Bah bermaksud banjir,  perkataan 'rain' ialah hujan dalam bahasa Inggeris."},{"question":"Responda à seguinte pergunta. Quando foi a última vez que a Villanova ganhou um campeonato da NCAA?","answer":"A última vez que Villanova ganhou o campeonato foi em 2018"},{"question":"Ọlọpaa ti mu meji lara awọn janduku to fajọngbọn l’Ebute-Mẹta","answer":"Latari bawọn janduku kan ṣe da wahala silẹ l’Opopona Herbert Macauly, lagbegbe Ebute-Mẹta, ni Yaba, ipinlẹ Eko, lọsan-an Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee yii, ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa lawọn ti bomi pana rukerudo ọhun, ọwọ awọn si ti ba meji lara awọn ewele ọmọ to dana ijọngbọn ọhun, iyẹn Tunde Rosanye, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogoji, ati Muyideen Ayede, ẹni ogun ọdun.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko to sọrọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii f’ALAROYE ninu atẹjade kan sọ pe lara awọn nnkan ija ti wọn ri gba lọwọ awọn afurasi ọdaran ọhun ni ibọn ibilẹ kan, awọn katiriiji ọta ibọn ti wọn ti yin ateyi ti wọn o ti i yin, ada meji, ọbẹ mẹta, foonu alagbeeka kan ati baagi kekere kan ti wọn fi nko awọn nnkan ija kiri.O ni kawọn ọlọpaa too debi iṣẹlẹ ọhun, awọn ọmọ iṣọta yii ti n da awọn eeyan lọna, wọn n gba awọn dukia wọn bii foonu, ṣeeni ọrun ati owo, eyi si mu kawọn araalu ko ọkan soke, ti wọn n sa kijokijo.Ipe tawọn ọlọpaa gba lori aago wọn leralera lo mu ki wọn tete yọju sibi iṣẹlẹ ọhun, bawọn ọmọ ganfe naa si ṣe ri mọto ọlọpaa ni wọn fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ.Ni bayii, Adejọbi lawọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ti wa laarin igboro lagbegbe naa, wọn n fimu finlẹ lati wa awọn to sa lọ nibikibi ti wọn ba mori mu si.O lawọn meji tọwọ ba yii ti balẹ sahaamọ ẹka ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba, wọn ti n ran awọn agbofinro lọwọ lẹnu iṣẹ iwadii wọn, ko si ni i pẹ ti wọn maa foju wọn bale-ẹjọ, gẹgẹ bi aṣẹ ti Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, pa."},{"question":"Saameynta nafsi ee cabashoyinka baraha bulshada?","answer":"Saamaynta nafsi ee  cabashooyinka baraha bulshada lagu faafiyo ...Dalkan Ruushka dhakhaatiirta nafsiga ku takhasusay waxa lagu dacaayadeeyaa inay iyagu laftoodu aanay fayoobayn oo xataa markaad bilawdo barashadiisa ayaa kaftan ahaan lagu waydiinayaa \\",ma dhabaa dhakhtarka dhimirka dhakhaatiirta dhimirka iyo dadka dhimirka ah ee ku jira hadba kii koodhka dhakhtar hor xidhaa dhakhtar ah\\" ? :) Sababta ay huuhaa daasi ku faaftay wax kale maaha waa wax ay wax ka jiraan oo dhakhtar nafsiga ah badanaa waxa noqda dad leh la damqasho oo dadka kale la dareen noqon kara oo dhibtooda dhagaysan kara sidoo kalena ah dad dhagaysan kara dadka oo sheekada ka guri kara oo u salaxi kara hadalka si uu qofku hadalka u sii wado dhibanaha ahi ilaa uuba isagu xalka keeno marka danbe ,se sida ay hadba bukaano u dhagaysanayaan kuwo xaalad nafsi ah oo fudud ku jira iyo kuwo xaalado dhimir ah ku jiraba walaw kuwa fududi u tagaan(psychologist) ka aanay u baahnayn dawooyin se cid la talin siisa ama hadalka iyo cabashada Ka gurta uun u baahan yihiin halka kuwa u baahan in dadka kale laga dhex saaro ama naftooda halis galin karaa u tagaan ama loo geeyo dhakhtarka dhimirka(Psychiatrist) waa sida aan labadaas ku kala saari karo e siday bukaanadaas ugu dhex jiraan ayaa marka danbe iyaga ay saamaysaa qaarkood oo dhaqankoodu noqdaa mid fudud oo waxyaabo dadka qaar aanay caadi u haysan iyaga la caadi noqdaan sidaasna loo yidhaahdaa iyaga laftoodaan fayoobayn ,amaba waxa takhasusyadaas qaata dad iyaga lagtooda sabab u gaysay ha ahaato ehelkooda oo xanuunadaasi ku badan yihiin oo uu iyaga dartood u qaatay isagoo isagu isaga baqaya iyo in uuba isku arkay calaamado xanuuno nagsi sidaasna is yidhi maadba baratid dad xiiseeya oo sidaa ku bartaana way jiraan . Waxaan uga socdaa baraha bulshada laftoodii mar hadii qof kastoo xaalad nafsiya ku jiraa halkuu dhakhtar nafsiya u tagi lahaa uu soo galinayo dareenkiisa oo nooc kasta ah dadkiina sidaas ku arkayaan waliba dad aan u tababarnayn oo sida dareenada loo dhiifshiido la qabsan waxa suurto gal noqonaysa inay dad badan arinkaasi saameeyo oo marka maalin walba qof ooyayaa soo dhigo muuqaalkiisii wuxuu ka cabanayaba waxa halis ugu jira inta qalbiga jilicsan ee la damqashada leh inuu arinkaas culays Ka soo fuulo iyagoon is ogayn oo siday maalinkasta qof ula ooyayaan waxna aanay u qaban karin oo laga yaabo in qofkuba qaaradkale joogo iyagoo si kalaysan marka danbe la arko ...Waxaan soo jeedin lahaa in bulshada Soomaalida la baro meelkastay kala joogaanba marka xaalad qoysi ahi la soo daristo joogaana meel aan laysu wareegin oonay haysan cid ay u tagaan oo arinkoodu la wadaagaan ama ay ku kalsoon yihiin inay helayaan dhakhaatiir bahda caafimaad ka ah oo ay xaaladooda la wadaagi karaan oo nafsiga ah (Psychologist)  oo ah kuwo kaliya Ku kooban la talin maaha kuwa dhimirka ee dawada u qora (Psychiatrist) waayo dadka debada joogaa waxay ka baqayaan in xanuun dhimir ah lagu sheego ama la ogaado inay dawo dhimir qaadato sidaana looga qaado caruurta amaba ku inkaar qaboo kadhalay adeegsado xaaladeeda nafsi yidhaahdana aniga ayaa masuuliyadeeda qaadaya e dhaqaale halaygu siiyo sidaasna uu wuxuu doono u sameeyo kamadanbaysna haduu doono dhakhtarka dhimirka geeya yidhaahdo isaguna suuqa iska galo sidaana nolosheedii ku burburto ...Arintaasi waxay Kala badbaadin kartaa bulshada baraha bulshada isugu timi oo ay ka dul qaadi kartaa cadaadiska nafsi ee kaga imanaya dadka kalee dhiban oo iyagoon waxba u qaban karin maalin walba dareemo Kala daran lala wadaagayo kuwa dhibana cid xaaladooda nafsiyadeed wax uga qaban karta ayay helayaan iyadoon qaaradaha aduunka laga wada ogaanin waxa haya iyo xaalada qofkaasi ku jiro ."},{"question":"வினா  :     உனக்குத் தெரிந்த சித்த மருத்துவ குறிப்புக்கள் சிலவற்றைத் தருக .","answer":"விடை:      நவீன வாழ்க்கை முறையில், நாம் அன்றாடம் பல்வேறு உடல்நலக்கோளாறுகளை சந்திக்க நேரிடுகிறது. அவற்றை நிவர்த்தி செய்வதற்கான சில எளிமையான சித்து மருத்துவக் குறிப்புகளைப் பற்றி பார்க்கலாம். சித்த மருத்துவ குறிப்புகள் : 1. வறட்டு இருமல் குணமாக: கருவேலமரக் கொழுந்தை கசக்கி சாறு எடுத்து வெந்நரில் கலந்து சாப்பிட வறட்டு இருமல் குறையும் வெள்ளை முதலான நோய்கள் குணமாகும்.2. ஆஸ்துமா, மூச்சுத்திணறல் குணமாக: முசுமுசுக்கை இலையை அரித்து வெங்காயத்துடன் நெய் விட்டு வதக்கி பகல் உணவில் சேர்த்து சாப்பிட ஆஸ்துமா, மூச்சுதிணறல் குணமாகும்.3. சளிகட்டு நீங்க: தூதுவளை, ஆடாதோடா, சங்கன் இலை கண்டங்கத்திரி இலை, சுக்கு, மிளகு, திப்பிலி சேர்த்து கஷாயம் செய்து சாப்பிட இறைப்பு சளிகட்டு நீங்கும்.4.ஒரு டம்ளர் தண்ணீரில் கருவேப்பிலை, இஞ்சி, சீரகம் ஆகிய மூன்றையும் கொதிக்க வைத்து; ஆறவைத்து வடிகட்டி குடித்தால், அஜீரணம் சரியாகும்.5.வேப்பம் பூவை உலர்த்தி தூளாக வெந்நீரில் உட்கொள்வதினால் வாயுதொல்லை நீங்கும். அத்துடன் ஆறாத வயிற்றுப்புண்ணும் நீங்கும்.6.செம்பருத்தி இலைகளை பொடியாக்கி, தினமும் இருவேளை சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் மலச்சிக்கல் தீரும்.7.கற்பூரம், சுக்கு, சாம்பிராணி, பெருங்காயம் இவைகளை சம அளவு எடுத்து சேர்த்து வடித்த கஞ்சியில் கலக்கி மறுபடியும் சூடுபடுத்தி, மூச்சுப்பிடிப்பு உள்ள இடத்தில் மூன்று வேளை தடவினால் குணமாகும்.8.கமலா ஆரஞ்சு தோலை வெயிலில் காயவைத்து பொடி செய்து தினமும் சோப்புக்கு பதிலாக உடம்பில் தேய்த்து குளித்து வந்தால் சரும நோய் குணமாகும்."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම වර්ණ චිත්‍රපටය ?","answer":"රන්මුතුදූව (1962)"},{"question":"கணவன் மற்றும் மனைவியை வைத்து ஒரு கடி ஜோக் சொல்லவும்.","answer":"மனைவி: டியர். நீங்க என்னை எவ்வளவு காதிலிக்கிறேன்னு சொல்ல முடியுமா?கணவன்: ஆஹா என்னோட டீப் லவ். 72%டி என் செல்லம்.மனைவி: போங்க. டார்லிங் நீங்க மோசம் அப்ப அந்த 28% எவளுக்காம்?கணவன்: அட கிறுக்கி..அழகுப் பொருள்களுக்கு 28% ஜிஎஸ்டி கவர்மெண்டுல புடிச்சுக்குவாண்ட!"},{"question":"উচ্চ শ্রেণির জীবের দেহকোষে এক ধরনের কোষ বিভাজন হয়। উক্ত বিভাজন প্রক্রিয়ার একটি ধাপে সেন্ট্রোমিয়ার দুই ভাগে বিভক্ত হয়।জীব জগতের গুণগত বৈশিষ্ট্যের স্থিতিশীলতা বজায় রাখার ক্ষেত্রে উদ্দীপকে উল্লিখিত কোষ বিভাজন প্রক্রিয়াটি উল্লেখযোগ্য ভূমিকা পালন করে— বিশ্লেষণ কর।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে উল্লিখিত জীবটির দেহকোষে সংঘটিত কোষ বিভাজন হলো মাইটোসিস। সমগ্র জীবজগতের জন্য মাইটোসিস প্রক্রিয়ার গুরুত্ব অপরিসীম। মাইটোসিস প্রক্রিয়ায় কোষ বিভাজনের কারণে প্রতিটি কোষের নিউক্লিয়াস ও সাইটোপ্লাজমের মধ্যকার আয়তন ও পরিমাণগত ভারসাম্য রক্ষিত হয়। এর ফলে বহুকোষী জীব জাইগোট নামক একটি কোষ থেকে জীবন শুরু করে। এই একটি কোষই বার বার মাইটোসিস কোষ বিভাজনের ফলে অসংখ্য কোষ সৃষ্টির মাধ্যমে পূর্ণ জীবে পরিণত হয়। মাইটোসিসের ফলে অপত্য কোষে ক্রোমোজোম সংখ্যা ও গুণাগুণ একই থাকায় জীবের দেহের বৃদ্ধি সুশৃঙ্খলভাবে হতে পারে। এককোষী জীব এই প্রক্রিয়ায় বংশবৃদ্ধি করে, মাইটোসিসের ফলে অঙ্গজ প্রজনন সাধিত হয় এবং জনন কোষের সংখ্যাবৃদ্ধিতে গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা পালন করে। ক্ষতস্থানে নতুন কোষ সৃষ্টির মাধ্যমে ক্ষতস্থান পূরণ হয় এই প্রক্রিয়ায়। মাইটোসিসের ফলে একই ধরনের কোষের উৎপত্তি হওয়ায় জীবজগতের গুণগত বৈশিষ্ট্যের স্থিতিশীলতা বজায় রাখতে এটি উল্লেখযোগ্য ভূমিকা পালন করে।"},{"question":"Miten denguekuumetta hoidetaan?","answer":"Dengueinfektioon ei ole olemassa lääkehoitoa, vaan hoito on oireiden mukaista. Kuumelääkkeeksi ei tulisi valita non-steroidaalisia tulehduskipulääkkeitä, kuten ibuprofeiinia, niiden verenvuotoa lisäävän vaaran vuoksi. Kuumelääkkeeksi voi käyttää parasetamolia."},{"question":"Write a poem celebrating the diversity of cultures around the world.","answer":"विश्व भर की सांस्कृतिक विविधता की स्तुति करने वाली कविता लिखें।"},{"question":"Кыргыз накыл кептери англис тилинде жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Experience is the mother of wisdom - Көп жашагандан эмес, көптү көргөндөн сура."},{"question":"Zer dira bitaminak?","answer":"Bitaminak organismoen funtzionamendu normalerako beharrezkoak diren molekula organikoak dira, eta gehienetan gorputzak ezin ditu sortu, beraz, dietaren bidez lortu behar dira."},{"question":"Mennyi (4+5)*2 eredménye?","answer":"(4+5)*2 eredményének kiszámításához előbb a záróhelben levő kifejezést kell kiszámolnunk.4+5=9Ezt követően behelyettesítva a feladat 9*2-re módusul.9*2=18Tehát az eredmény 18."},{"question":"ਤਹਿਰਾਨ: ਗੈਸਪਾਈਪ ਲਾਈਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਧਮਾਕਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਰਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੰਜ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ। ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਮਾਹਸ਼ਰ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਅਹਵਾਜ਼ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਪਾਈਪ ਲਾਈਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਧਮਾਕਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੰਜ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਛੇ ਜ਼ਖ਼ਮੀ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ। ਅਹਵਾਜ਼ ਦੇ ਗਵਰਨਰ 'ਜਾਮਾਲ ਆਲਾਮੀ ਨਿਸੀ' ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਧਮਾਕਾ ਗੈਸ ਰਿਸਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਧਮਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਰ ਕਾਰਾਂ ਵੀ ਤਬਾਹ ਹੋ ਗਈਆਂ।ਗੈਸ ਪਾਈਪਲਾਈਨ ਕਿਸ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤੋਂ  ਕਿਸ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਖਬਰਾਂ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਗੈਸ ਪਾਈਪਲਾਈਨ ਮਹਸ਼ਰ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਅਹਵਾਜ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Duşakabin su lekesi nasıl çıkar?","answer":"4 tatlı kaşığı limon tuzu ile 1 su bardağı suyu karıştırın. Hazırladığınız karışımı limon tuzu eriyene kadar sprey şişesinde güzelce çalkalayın. Limon tuzlu suyunuzu cam silme deterjanları gibi kullanabilirsiniz. Son olarak duşakabini duru suyla durulayın ve kuru bezle leke kalmayacak şekilde silin."},{"question":"\\"喜马拉雅学乖\\"有哪些特色功能？","answer":"\\"喜马拉雅学乖\\"有一些特色功能，如智能推荐、离线下载、语速调节等，可以提高用户的学习体验。"},{"question":"Башын куттуктоо","answer":"Кандайдыр бир жагымсыз начар иштен (катуу оорудан, чоң кырсыктан, узак жолдон ж.б.) аман калган адамга сый көрсөтүү иретинде кийим-кече кийгизүү же бир нерсе тартуулоо.Иниң өзү келгенде, башын куттуктап ат мингизейин. (Жантөшев)"},{"question":"Phòng khách của căn hộ tôi đang ở có trần cao khoảng 2,6 m. Vì muốn không gia có điểm nhấn hơn nên tôi dự định làm trần thạch cao giật cấp, đồng thời lắp thêm quạt trần.Tuy nhiên, tôi không biết giải pháp này có thật sự hiệu quả. Ngoài ra, để đảm bảo thẩm mỹ và an toàn thì cần làm kích thước tối thiểu ra sao và việc vệ sinh trong quá trình sử dụng liệu có gặp bất tiện?Rất mong nhận được tư vấn của các chuyên gia và độc giả!","answer":"Trần phòng khách hiện tại 2,6m thì tốt nhất không nên làm thêm trần thạch cao. Đối với phòng khách là không gian sinh hoạt thường xuyên, làm thêm thì trần sẽ thấp xuống tạo không gian hẹp hơn tuy có điểm nhấn. Tôi thấy 2,6m làm trần thạch cao thì xuống 2,4m cũng được, nhưng chiều cao trần phòng khách phải cao hơn các phòng khác."},{"question":"ඇම්බැක්කේ දේවාලයේ වහලයේ සැලසුමේ වඩාත්ම කැපී පෙනෙන ලක්ෂණය කුමක්ද සහ එය කැපී පෙනෙන්නේ කුමක් ද?","answer":"වඩාත්ම කැපී පෙනෙන ලක්ෂණය වන්නේ වහලය මත ඇති ප්‍රධාන කදම්භයේ ලී කලම්පය මඩොල් කුරුපාව නම් වේ. මෙම විශාල ලී පින් එක පුරාණ වඩු කර්මාන්තය ප්‍රදර්ශනය කරමින් පරාල විසි-හයක්(26) එකට තබා  ඇත. මෙම සම්පූර්ණ ව්යුහය ලී වලින් සාදා ඇති අතර, වෙනත් ද්‍රව්‍ය භාවිත කර නොමැත."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Aza manao kobaka _, volana an-tenda, ka hatreo no miakatra ihany\\"","answer":"\\"Aza manao kobaka am-bava, volana an-tenda, ka hatreo no miakatra ihany\\""},{"question":"Em que clube o goleiro de futebol Alisson foi revelado?","answer":"O jogador Alisson foi revelado no Internacional."},{"question":"கேள்வி: பல்லுயிர் இழப்பின் முக்கிய இயக்கிகள் என்ன, பல்லுயிர் ஏன் முக்கியமானது?","answer":"பதில்: பல்லுயிர் இழப்பு முதன்மையாக வாழ்விடம் அழிவு, உயிரினங்களின் அதிகப்படியான சுரண்டல், மாசுபாடு, ஆக்கிரமிப்பு இனங்கள் மற்றும் காலநிலை மாற்றம் ஆகியவற்றால் இயக்கப்படுகிறது. உயிர்ப்பல்வகைமை இன்றியமையாதது, ஏனெனில் அது சுற்றுச்சூழல் நிலைத்தன்மையை ஆதரிக்கிறது, மனித உயிர்வாழ்விற்கான ஆதாரங்களை வழங்குகிறது (உணவு மற்றும் மருந்து போன்றவை), மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் சவால்களை எதிர்கொள்வதில் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளின் பின்னடைவுக்கு பங்களிக்கிறது."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਤਾ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਤਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਬੰਧਪੁ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਭ੍ਰਾਤਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਸਭਨੀ ਥਾਈ ਤਾ ਭਉ ਕੇਹਾ ਕਾੜਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਤੁਮਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾ ਤੇ ਤੁਧੁ ਪਛਾਣਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੀ ਓਟ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਣਾ ॥ਤੁਝ ਬਿਨੁ ਦੂਜਾ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਈ ਸਭੁ ਤੇਰਾ ਖੇਲੁ ਅਖਾੜਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਸਭਿ ਤੁਧੁ ਉਪਾਏ ॥ਜਿਤੁ ਜਿਤੁ ਭਾਣਾ ਤਿਤੁ ਤਿਤੁ ਲਾਏ ॥ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੋਵੈ ਨਾਹੀ ਕਿਛੁ ਅਸਾੜਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ਮਹਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨੁ ਸੀਤਲਾਇਆ ॥ਗੁਰਿ ਪੂਰੈ ਵਜੀ ਵਾਧਾਈ ਨਾਨਕ ਜਿਤਾ ਬਿਖਾੜਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੨੪॥੩੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 103 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਉ (ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਂ (ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰ ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਭਰਾ ਹੈਂ । (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਜਦੋਂ) ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਡਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ, ਕੋਈ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਮੇਰੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦੀ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹਾਂ । ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਫ਼ਖ਼ਰ ਦਾ ਥਾਂ ਹੈਂ । ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਤਮਾਸ਼ਾ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਅਖਾੜਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਸ ਜਿਸ ਕੰਮ ਵਿਚ ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੋਈ ਤੂੰ ਉਸ ਉਸ ਕੰਮ ਵਿਚ (ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ) ਲਾਏ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ।(ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) ਸਭ ਤੇਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਸਾਡਾ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਜ਼ੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੱਲ ਸਕਦਾ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਤਾਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਬੜਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਠੰਢਾ-ਠਾਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—) ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਆਤਮਕ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਢੋਲ ਵੱਜ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ) ਔਖਾ ਘੋਲ ਜਿੱਤ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੨੪।੩੧।\\""},{"question":"Passolig nasıl girilir?","answer":"En az bir adet sonuçlandırılmış Passolig Kartı başvurunuz varsa ancak kartınız henüz size teslim edilmemiş ise Passo Mobil uygulamamızdaki Maça Gir bölümünden giriş yapabilirsiniz ya da stadyum gişelerinden Passolig Tek Girişlik Pass Kart temin edebilirsiniz."},{"question":"Qual o hino do Flamengo?","answer":"Uma vez FlamengoSempre FlamengoFlamengo sempre eu hei de serÉ meu maior prazer vê-lo brilharSeja na terra, seja no marVencer, vencer, vencerUma vez FlamengoFlamengo até morrerNa regata, ele me mataMe maltrata, me arrebataQue emoção no coraçãoConsagrado no gramadoSempre amado, o mais cotadoNo Fla-Flu é o: Ai, Jesus!Eu teria um desgosto profundoSe faltasse o Flamengo no mundoUma vez FlamengoSempre FlamengoFlamengo sempre eu hei de serÉ meu maior prazer vê-lo brilharSeja na terra, seja no marVencer, vencer, vencerUma vez FlamengoFlamengo até morrerNa regata, ele me mataMe maltrata, me arrebataQue emoção no coraçãoConsagrado no gramadoSempre amado, o mais cotadoNo Fla-Flu é o: Ai, Jesus!Eu teria um desgosto profundoSe faltasse o Flamengo no mundoEle vibra, ele é fibraMuita libra já pesouFlamengo até morrer eu sou"},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত বাক্যাংশটি সম্পূর্ণ করুন :২০১১ সালেই শূন্য প্রকাশ করে তাদের তৃতীয় অ্যালবাম \\"গড়বো বাংলাদেশ\\"। ২০১২ সালে ঢাকা গ্ল্যাডিয়েটরস দলের থিম সংও গায় শূন্য৷ ২০১৪ সালে প্রকাশিত হয় তাদের চতুর্থ অ্যালবাম \\"ভাগো\\"।","answer":"২০১৫ ক্রিকেট বিশ্বকাপে \\"চলো বাংলাদেশ\\" গানটিতে কণ্ঠ দেয় দলটি। রবি প্রযোজিত \\"দেশপ্রেমিকের গান\\" শিরোনামের একটি গানেও কণ্ঠ দেয় তারা। সর্বশেষ ২০১৭ সালে প্রকাশিত হয় তাদের পঞ্চম অ্যালবাম \\"লটারি\\"।"},{"question":"यस्यास्ति सर्वत्र गति: स कस्मात्स्वदेशरागेण हि याति नाशम् |तातस्य कूपोऽयमिति ब्रुवाणाक्षारं जलं कापुरुषा पिबन्ति ||– योगवासिष्ठ-उत्तरार्ध, भोजप्रबंध","answer":"जो सगळीकडे हिंडत असतो तो आपल्या जागेच्या प्रेमात स्वतःचे नुकसान करून घेत नाही. “ही माझ्या वडिलांची विहीर आहे” असे म्हणत बसणारे क्षुद्र लोक तिचे खारे पाणी पितात."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bajak sudah terdorong ke bencah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sudah terlanjur."},{"question":"Manao ahoana ny rafi-pampianarana frantsay?","answer":"Ny rafi-panabeazana frantsay dia ahitana fampianarana ambaratonga voalohany, ambaratonga faharoa ary fampianarana ambony."},{"question":"Wybierz prawidłową odpowiedź.AS Roma to klub piłkarski grający w lidze...A. Serie AB. LaLigaC. Premier LeagueD. Bundesliga","answer":"Poprawna odpowiedź to A."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම විභාග කොමසාරිස් කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම විභාග කොමසාරිස් ආතර් වෙදමුල්ල මහතා"},{"question":"Yanığına hangi krem iyi gelir?","answer":"Yanık KremiLamidermYara Ve Yanık Kremi 60 ml. ...GüzeldostAft Ve Ağız Yarası Tedavi Spreyi. ...ConvatecGranugel Hidrokolloid Yara Jeli 15gr. ...TeraPineDoğal Kantaron Kremi Yara Ve Yanık Kremi, 9 Bitkisel Yağ, Iz Kalmasını Önler, Egzamalı Cilt. ...LamidermYara Ve Yanık Kremi 60 Ml 2 Adet."},{"question":"Svar på dette indviklede spørgsmål: Hvilken nationalitet var den person, der skrev musikken til Soft Flowing Avon?","answer":"Englænder"},{"question":"Nkechi bụ nwata nwaagbọgho bitụrụ mma aka, too ma kwụrụ chim. Eze dị ya n’ ọnụ na-enwu ka anyanwụ ụtụtụ. Nne na nna ya hụrụ ya n’anya nke ukwu n’ ihi na o bụ ọtu mkpụrụ anya ji isi ụgwọ.Mgbe Nkechi ruru afo iri na asaa, isi bidoro nwube ya ọkụ. O nwekwaghi onye ọ na-atụ egwu. Ọ mechara banye mahadum dị na Nsụkka bụ ebe ọ na-amu etu ọ ga-esi bụrụ onyeokaiwu. O bidoro na-epiogharị. Ihe kachasị njọ bụ na Nkechi na-eso ụmụnwoke ndịLụrụla nwaanyị. Ọ nakwaghi anọ n’ụlọakwụkwọ ma ya fọdụ ịgụ akwụkwọ. E mechara chụọ ya n’ ụlọakwụkwọ maka na ọ dara ule ihe-ọmụmụ niile o mere n’afọ nke abụọ ya. Otu mgbe ahụkwa ka nne na nna ya nwụrụ n’ihe mgberede okporoụzo. Mma Nkechi rụrụ mgbe ọ tụụrụ ime ọkwa. O mechara buru afọ ime a gbafuo. Nkechi eriela Ihe oji maka ya mụrụ anya, ura eburu ya.Otu mkpụrụ anya ji isi ụgwọ pụtaraNhọrọ A) otu mkpụrụ anyaB) otu isiC) otu nwaanyịD) otu nwa","answer":"Otu mkpụrụ anya pụtara otu nwa na ala Igbo, ya bụ azịza ajụjụ a bụ (D)"},{"question":"ලෝකයේ වැඩිම අන්තර්ජාල භාවිතයක් ඇති රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"2022 වන විට, චීනයේ අන්තර්ජාල භාවිතා කරන්නන් බිලියනයකට වඩා ඇති අතර එය ලෝකයේ වැඩිම අන්තර්ජාල භාවිතයක් ඇති රට  වේ."},{"question":"Isiokwu: Ụlọ ikpe ntuli aka: Ndị n'ọchị ndị n'akwasite n'isiokwu dị n'elu nke akụkọ ifo, dee akụkọ ahụ.","answer":"N'Enugwu steeti, ụlọikpe ntuliaka nke ọkaikpe H.H Kereng nọ n'isi ya eweliela aka Ike Ekweremadu nke PDP dịka onye meriri ntụliaka nke Enugwu West nke ya na Juliet Ibekaku nke APC dọrọ.Ndị okaiwu anọ kpere ya bụ ikpe sị na Ibekaku achitaghị aja na ya bụ ikpe.N'otu aka ahụ ọkaikpe Sunday Olorundahunsi anọrọla n'Awka,Nkee Steeti Anambra  kpebie na Victor Ume nke APGA achitaghị aja na ntuliaka ya na Uche Ekwunife mere na ọnwa nke abụọ nke afọ 2019 gbasara oche nke Anambra Centralu.Otu ahụkwa ka ụlọikpe sị welie aka Ifeanyi Uba dịka onye meriri ntuliaka nke ya na Chris Uba n'oche nke Anambra Saụt ha zọrọ.Ụlọikpe ntuliaka nke ọkaikpe A.O. Chijoke nọ n'isi ya kpebiri na aga atụgharị ntuliaka emere na Kogi West nke Dino Melaye meriburu. Chinedu OgahN'Ebonyi steeti, ụlọikpe ntuliaka nke Jọsitis Sika Henry nọ n'isi ya sị na ọ bụzị Chinedu Ogah nke APC meriri ntuliaka e mere n'Ezza South/Ikwo constituency n'ọnwa nke abụọ nke afọ a.Ụlọikpe ahụ gwara Inec ka ha nwere ọsọ nwere iji napụta Laz Ogbee nke PDP asambodo mmeri nke ha nyere ya na mbụ ma ye ha Ogah bụ onye ha sị ọ bụ ya ji votu 36,238 merie.Dino etinyelarị akwụkwọ maka ikpegharị ya bụ ikpe ị sị na ya ekwetaghị ihe ya bụ ụlọikpe kwuru.Na Steeti Sokoto , ụlọikpe ntuliaka ekpebiela na a ga-emegharị ntuliaka e mere na steeti ahụ makana emecheghị ntuliaka e mere na ọgbọnta votu isii nke Sokoto Nọt ii ụlọ nnọchiteanya nke steeti ahụ."},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahan'ny fametrahana tanjona manokana mampitombo ny fahombiazan'ny traikefa fianarana iray?","answer":"Ny tanjona manokana dia manome mazava sy manentana, mitarika ny mpianatra ho amin'ny vokatra tadiavina ary manampy azy ireo handrefesana ny fivoarany."},{"question":"Peygamber çiçeği nasıl bir bitki?","answer":"Halk arasında peygamber çiçeği ya da paşa kılıcı olarak bilinen kılıç çiçeği, en kolay yetiştirilen çiçekler arasındadır. Renkli çiçeklerden ziyade daha uzun ömürlü olan kılıç çiçeği, değişen hava koşullarına ve susuzluğa karşı oldukça dayanıklıdır."},{"question":"UKUNGCWEKAUkungcweka ngumdlalo omnandi kakhulu lapho izinsizwa zizwana khona amandla.Zisuke zingenanxa nalowo ezingcwekisana naye kodwa ziqinisana ukhakhayi ukuzezizohloniphana, kwaziwe ukuthi ubani ingqwele. Insizwa kumele iqinelwe ukhakhayiukuze ingabi lula uma ihlangene nezinye izinsizwa. Ingazitholaphi izibongo insizwauma ingumnqolo ogumbetsheni umachoba izintwala zikanina? Izibongo akuyona intoolala ungenayo uvuke ekuseni usunayo kodwa zingamagalelo akho obuqhawe.Izibongo zensizwa zisuke zichaza imivimbo enayo emzimbeni eyithole kade ilwa, ivika,ithubeleza kunzima.Ukuba nezibongo eziningi ukuthola ekungcwekeni ngoba usuke usufana nenkunziemidwayidwa. Noma bengakubhaxabula kanjani ezimbanjeni kodwa ikhanda ngekebalinuke uma uyiqhawe ngoba uzobe ulivikela ngazo zonke izindlela. Uma sekuphelileukungcweka akukho muntu obambela omunye igqubu. Phela izinsizwa amabhubesi,ziyaphelezelana zifike zigezane igazi emfuleni. Hhiya Zulu, kusuke kungempi phelakodwa kusuke kungcwekwa nje.1. Phinda ubhale umusho osemgqeni nciphise igamaelingundaweni.","answer":"Phela izinsizwa amabhubesi, ziyaphelezelana zifike zigezane igaziemfudlaneni."},{"question":"Siapakah Ning Baizura? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 150 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Ning Baizura (lahir 28 Jun 1975) dengan nama penuh Ning Baizura Sheikh Hamzah ialah seorang penyanyi dan pelakon wanita Malaysia.Dilahirkan di Kajang, Selangor, beliau memulakan kerjaya muzik pada usia 17 tahun setelah memenangi tempat ketiga di pertandingan Voices of Asia yang berlangsung di Kazakhstan. Beliau menandatangani kontrak bersama pelbagai label rakaman termasuk Sony Music dan telah menerbitkan sebanyak 12 album studio.Dikenali sebagai penyanyi bersuara soprano dan kehebatan vokalnya yang versatil dan unik,antara lagu-lagu yang menjulang nama Ning ialah \\"Curiga\\", \\"Kau dan Aku\\", \\"Asmara\\", \\"Kembali\\", \\"Selagi Ada... (Cinta)\\", \\"Awan Yang Terpilu\\" dan \\"Bukan Wanita Sempurna\\". Selain bidang muzik, Ning juga berkecimpung dalam bidang lakonan. Antara filem-filem lakonannya ialah \\"Gemilang\\" (1997), \\"Maria Mariana II\\" (1998), \\"Mimpi Moon\\" (2001), \\"Lady Boss\\" (2005) dan \\"Diva\\" (2007). Beliau telah menerima pelbagai anugerah dan pencalonan dalam industri muzik dan lakonan, termasuk Anugerah Industri Muzik, Anugerah Juara Lagu dan Anugerah Bintang Popular Berita Harian."},{"question":"De que estado origina o Bolo de Rolo?","answer":"De Pernambuco."},{"question":"Аба ырайы деген эмне ?","answer":"Аба ырайы-айрым бир аймакта атмосферанын учурдагы же белгилуу бир мезгил ичиндеги (сутка,ай) абалы."},{"question":"എനിക്ക് വീട്ടിൽ വെള്ളം സംരക്ഷിക്കാൻ കഴിയുന്ന ചില വഴികൾ ഏതാണ്?","answer":"കുളിക്കുന്നത് പരിമിതപ്പെടുത്തുകയോ ഒഴിവാക്കുകയോ ചെയ്യുക, നിങ്ങളുടെ ഷവറിൽ ഉയർന്ന മർദ്ദമുള്ള ഷവർ തലകൾ സ്ഥാപിക്കുക, ടോയ്‌ലറ്റ് ഫ്ലഷിംഗ് കുറയ്ക്കുക എന്നിവയാണ് നിങ്ങൾക്ക് വീട്ടിൽ വെള്ളം സംരക്ഷിക്കാൻ കഴിയുന്ന ചില വഴികൾ. വീട്ടുചെടികൾ നനയ്ക്കാൻ നിങ്ങളുടെ പച്ചക്കറികൾ കഴുകാൻ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്ന വെള്ളം വീണ്ടും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത് ചില ക്രിയാത്മകമായ മാർഗങ്ങളിൽ ഉൾപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"Apakah latar belakang Bank Simpanan Nasional (BSN)? ","answer":"Bank Simpanan Nasional Malaysia adalah sebuah pertubuhan perbadanan ditubuhkan di bawah Akta Bank Simpanan Nasional 1974 dan ditubuhkan pada 1 hari bulan Disember 1974, di bawah Akta Parlimen 146 – Undang-Undang Malaysia 1974 atas kendalian Menteri Kewangan Malaysia pada ketika itu, Tengku Razaleigh Hamzah. Ia dilancarkan dengan rasminya pada 5 Disember 1974 oleh Allahyarham Tun Abdul Razak, Perdana Menteri Malaysia yang kedua, di mana semua tugas dan tanggungjawab di bawah Akta Bank Simpanan Pejabat POS (melalui khidmat Post Office Savings Bank yang wujud sejak zaman pemerintahan British sehinggalah ke pascamerdeka) telah diambil alih oleh Bank Simpanan Nasional. Bank Simpanan Nasional adalah sebuah Badan Berkanun di bawah Kementerian Kewangan."},{"question":"戦後ＧＨＱが日本に対して行った、新聞や放送についての報道規制のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"プレスコードです。"},{"question":"රුසියාවේ (Russian) පළමු ජනාධිපති කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"බොරිස් යෙල්ට්සින් (Boris Yeltsin)"},{"question":"Determina si las dos oraciones se parafrasean entre sí. Oración 1: El 17 de agosto de 1865, el 3º Regimiento de Caballería de Voluntarios de Nueva York se fusionó con el 16º Regimiento de Caballería Provisional de Nueva York.Oración 2: El 17 de agosto de 1865, la 13.° Caballería Voluntaria de Nueva York se consolidó con la 16.° Caballería Voluntaria de Nueva York para formar la 3.° Caballería Provisional de Nueva York.","answer":"Si se parafrasean entre sí. "},{"question":"अरावली पर्वताचा सर्वोच्च शिखर कोणत्या नावाने ओळखला जातो?(A) डोडाबेटा(B) सेर(C) गुरुशिखर(D) यापैकी नाही=>","answer":"(C) गुरुशिखर"},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir?Kasım ayında Wyatt, bir maçta Matt Hardy'yi yendikten sonra onunla rekabete başladı. Bu mağlubiyetin sonucunda Hardy'nin \\"Broken\\" karakteri yeniden ortaya çıktı. İkisi Ocak 2018'de yapılan \\"Raw 25 Years\\" programında tekrar karşılaştı ve Wyatt yine kazandı. 28 Ocak'ta Wyatt, Royal Rumble maçına 8. sıradan girdi, ancak Wyatt ve Hardy aynı anda birbirlerini eledi. Şubat ayında yapılan Elimination Chamber'da Wyatt, Hardy'ye teke tek maçta yenildi. 19 Mart \\"Raw\\" programında Hardy, Wyatt'ı Ultimate Deletion (Nihai Silinme) maçında yendi. Maçtan sonra Hardy, Wyatt'ı \\"Reenkarnasyon Gölü\\"ne itti. Wyatt gözden kayboldu ve bir süre görünmedi. WrestleMania 34'te Wyatt geri döndü ve André the Giant anısına yapılan Battle Royal'da Hardy'nin kazanmasına yardımcı olarak WWE kariyerinde ilk kez iyi karakter oldu. İkisi bir takım oluşturdu ve 27 Nisan'da yapılan Greatest Royal Rumble'da Cesaro ve Sheamus'ı yenerek Raw Takım Şampiyonluğu kemerlerini aldı. Takım, Extreme Rules'da yaptıkları ilk izle ve öde kemer savunması maçında The B-Team'e (Bo Dallas ve Curtis Axel) yenilerek kemerleri kaybetti. 23 Temmuz \\"Raw\\" programında The B-Team'e karşı kemer için rövanş hakkını kullansa da başarısız oldu. Kısa bir süre sonra Hardy sakatlandı ve iyileşme süreci sırasında takım dağıldı. 25 Kasım'da Wyatt, Starrcade'de geri dönerek diskalifiyesiz maçta Baron Corbin'i yendi.","answer":"Bu metindeki önemli olay Elimination Chamber'dır."},{"question":"Monster IPS ekran mı?","answer":"Bu monitör, rekabetçi oyunları tercih eden oyuncular için tasarlandı ve Fast IPS teknolojisi, kişiselleştirilebilen yükseklik ve açı ayarları, Gsync ve FreeSync desteği gibi yeni nesil özellikler sunuyor."},{"question":"வினா: புறநானூறு குறித்துக் குறிப்பெழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:புறநானூறு என்னும் தொகைநூல் நானூறு பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட புறத்திணை சார்ந்த ஒரு சங்கத் தமிழ் நூலாகும். புறம், புறப்பாட்டு, நந்தா விளக்கம் என்றும் வழங்கப்படும். இது சங்க காலத் தமிழ் நூல் தொகுப்பான எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களில் புறநூல்களுள் ஒன்று. இந்நூலைத் தொகுத்தவர் பெயரும், தொகுப்பித்தவர் பெயரும் தெரியவில்லை. இந்நூலின் பாக்கள் 4 அடி முதல் 40 அடி வரையிலான ஆசிரியப்பாவால் அமைந்து உள்ளன. சிறுபான்மையாக வஞ்சி அடிகளும் விரவி வரும். புறநானூற்றின் பாடல்கள் சங்ககாலத்தில் ஆண்ட அரசர்களைப் பற்றியும் மக்களின் சமூக வாழ்க்கை பற்றியும் எடுத்துரைக்கின்றன. இதனை ஜி. யு. போப் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மொழிபெயர்த்துள்ளார்.பாடியவர்கள்இந் நூலில் அடங்கியுள்ள பாடல்கள் பல்வேறு புலவர்களால் பல்வேறு காலங்களில் பாடப்பட்டவை. அகவற்பா வகையைச் சேர்ந்த இப்பாடல்கள், 150க்கும் மேற்பட்ட புலவர்களால் எழுதப்பட்டவை. இந்நூலில் அதிக பாடல்களைப் பாடியவர் ஔவையார் (33 பாடல்கள்) ஆவார். அவரை அடுத்து அதிக பாடலைப் பாடியவர் கபிலர் (28 பாடல்கள்) ஆவார். இந்நூலில் இடம்பெறும் புலவர்கள் அனைவரும் ஒரே சமூகத்தையோ நாட்டையோ சார்ந்தவர்கள் அல்லர். அரசன் முதல் எளிய குயவன்மகள் வரை பல்வேறு நிலைகளில் இருந்த ஆடவரும் பெண்டிருமான புலவர்கள் பாடியுள்ளனர். புலவர் அரசர்களைப் பாடியதை ”அவனை அவர் பாடியது” என்று சொல்வதன் மூலம் புலவர்களுக்கிருந்த செல்வாக்கும் மதிப்பும் புலனாகிறது.நூல் அமைப்புஇந்நூலில் பாடல்கள் தொகுக்கப்படும்போது ஒருவகை இயைபு கருதி, முதலில் முடிமன்னர் மூவர், அடுத்து குறுநில மன்னர், வேளிர் ஆகியோரைப் பற்றிய பாடல்களும் அதனை அடுத்துப் போர்ப் பற்றிய பாடல்களும் கையறுநிலைப்பாடல், நடுகல், மகளிர் தீப்பாய்தல் என்று தொகுத்துள்ளனர். புறப்பொருள் கருத்துகளைத் தழுவிப் பாடப்பட்ட இந்நூலில் ஒவ்வொரு பாடலின் இறுதியிலும் திணை, துறை, பாடினோர், பாடப்பட்டோர், பாடப்பட்ட சூழல் போன்ற குறிப்புகள் உள்ளன.புறப்பொருள்அகப்பாடல்கள் ஐந்திணை ஒழுக்கங்களைக் குறித்தது போலப் புற ஒழுக்கங்களைக் குறித்து அமைந்த பழங்கால வாய்பாட்டுப் பாடல் நமக்கு விளக்குகிறது.பாடல்:வெட்சி நிரைக்கவர்தல் மீட்டல் கரந்தையாம்வட்கார்மேல் செல்வது வஞ்சியாம் - உட்காதெதிரூன்றல் காஞ்சி எயில்காத்தல் நொச்சிஅதுவளைத்த லாகு முழிஞை - அதிரப்பொருவது தும்பையாம் போர்க்களத்து மிக்கோர்செருவென் றதுவாகை யாம்.இப்புற ஒழுக்கங்களை வெட்சி, கரந்தை, வஞ்சி, காஞ்சி, நொச்சி, உழிஞை, தும்பை, வாகை என்ற எட்டுத் திணைகளாகக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன. இதில் பாடாண், பொதுவியல், கைக்கிளை, பெருந்திணை ஆகிய திணைகளும் அடங்கும். திணையின் உட்பிரிவு துறை எனப்படுகிறது.புறப்பாடல்கள் புற ஒழுக்கங்களான போர்த்திறம், வள்ளல் தன்மை, மகளிர் மாண்பு, சான்றோர்களின் இயல்பு போன்றவற்றைக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன.புறநானூறு வழி அறியலாகும் செய்திகள்அக்காலத் தமிழ் மக்களின் அரசியல், சமூகம், பொருளாதாரம், கல்வி, நாகரிகம், கலை வளர்ச்சி, வீரம், கொடை, ஆடை, அணிகலன், பழக்க வழக்கங்கள், வாணிபம் போன்ற பல செய்திகளைப் புறநானூறு வழி அறியலாம்.சமூக நிலைபெண்கள் மங்கல அணி அணிதல், இறந்தவரைத் தாழியில் கவித்தல், நடுகல் நடுதல், நட்ட கல்லைச் சுற்றி மயிற்பீலி அணிவித்து மது வார்த்தல், கணவனை இழந்த பெண்கள் அணிகளைக் களைந்து, கைம்மை நோன்பு நோற்றல், உடன்கட்டையேறல் போன்ற பழக்க வழக்கங்களையும் 10 வகை ஆடைகளையும், 28 வகை அணிகலன்களையும் 30 படைக்கலக்கருவிகளையும் 67வகை உணவுகளையும் எடுத்து இயம்புகின்றன. பால்மணம் மாறாத பச்சிளம் குழந்தைக்குக் கையில் வேல் கொடுத்துப் போருக்கு அனுப்பும் மகளிர், முறத்தால் புலியை விரட்டும் மகளிர் எனப் பெண்களின் வீரத்தையும் போற்றுகின்றன. அக்கால சமூக நிலையைக் காட்டும் கண்ணாடி எனப் புறநானூறு விளங்குகிறது.வரலாற்றுக் குறிப்புகள்புறநானூற்றுப் பாடல்களில் ஏராளமான வரலாற்றுக் குறிப்புகள் உள்ளன. பாண்டியன் நெடுஞ்செழியன் முதலான 15 பாண்டிய மன்னர்களையும் கரிகாற்சோழன் போன்ற 18 சோழ அரசர்களையும் இமயவரம்பன் நெடுஞ்சேரலாதன், சேரன் செங்குட்டுவன் போன்ற 18 சேர அரசர்களையும் சிறப்பித்துப் பாடியுள்ளனர். பண்டைய போர்க் களங்களான வெண்ணிப்பறந்தலை, வாகைப்பறந்தலை, கழுமலம், தகடூர், தலையாலங்கானம், கானப்பேரெயில் போன்ற போர்க்களங்கள் குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளன.எடுத்துக்காட்டுப் பாடல்தொடியுடைய தோண்மணந்தனன்கடிகாவிற் பூச்சூடினன்தண்கமழுஞ் சாந்துநீவினன்செற்றோரை வழிதபுத்தனன்நட்டோரை யுயர்புகூறினன்வலியரென வழிமொழியலன்மெலியரென மீக்கூறலன்பிறரைத்தா னிரப்பறியலன்வேந்துடை யவையத் தேங்குபுகழ் தோற்றினன்வருபடை எதிர் தாங்கினன்பெயர்படை புறங்கண்டனன்கடும்பரிய மாக்கடவினன்நெடுந்தெருவிற் றேர்வழங்கினன்ஓங்குகியல களிறூர்ந்தனன்தீஞ்செறி தசும்புதொலைச்சினன்,பாணுவப்பப் பசிதீர்த்தனன்மயக்குடைய மொழிவிடுத்தனன், ஆங்குச்செய்ப வெல்லாஞ் செய்தன னாகலின்இடுக வொன்றோ சுடுக வொன்றோபடுவழிப் படுகவிப் புகழ்வெய்யோன் றலையே.- நம்பி நெடுஞ்செழியன் - புறம் - பாடல் 235மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள்பேராசிரியர் யோர்ச். எல். அகார்ட் என்பவரால் புறநானூறு  ஆங்கிலத்தில் (1999) மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.ஜி.யு.போப் (போப்பையர்) என்பவராலும்  மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.பதிப்பு வரலாறுசுவடிகளில் எழுதப்பட்டுப் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டு வந்த இந்நூல் பிற்காலத்தில் அழிந்துபோகும் நிலை எய்தியபோது பல சுவடிகளைச் சோதித்துத் தற்காலத் தமிழரும் பயன் பெறும் வகையில், டாக்டர் உ. வே. சாமிநாதையர் 1894-ஆம் ஆண்டு பழைய உரையோடு (முதல் 266 பாடல்களுக்கு மட்டுமே பழைய உரை கிடைத்துள்ளது) நூல் முழுமைக்கும் குறிப்புரையும் எழுதி முதன் முதலாகப் பதிப்பித்து வெளியிட்டார். இதன் பின்னர் வேறு பலரும் வெளியிட்டுள்ளனர்"},{"question":" Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Madaxweynihii Ugu Horeyey Ee Afrikan Kursiga Madaxtinimada SixurAh Kaga Dago?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Aadan Cabdule Cusmaan (Aadan Cadde)"},{"question":"Takip eden paragraf hangi konu hakkındadır?: Fiber optik, ışığın özel cam veya plastik teller boyunca yüksek hızda iletilmesini sağlayan bir iletişim teknolojisidir. Fiber optik kablolar, binlerce ince cam veya plastik tel içerir ve bu teller, verileri ışık sinyalleri olarak iletebilirler. Bu sinyaller, yüksek hızda ve büyük bant genişliği ile iletilir, bu da fiber optiğin yüksek hızlı iletişim için ideal bir seçenek olmasını sağlar.","answer":"Paragraf, fiber optik ve fiber optik kablolar hakkındadır."},{"question":"Waa maxay caqiidadu?","answer":"Ereyga \\"Caqiido\\" macnihiisu waa; rumayn iyo wax aaminid. (Caqiido waa kalmad af-carabi ah oo sheegaysa; adkayn, guntid, sugid iyo goyn. Haddii la sii macneeyo waa; arrinka aan qofka aaminsani ka shakisanayn. Xagga diinta waa arrimaha la aamino qalbi ahaan sida rumaynta Alle iyo Rasuulkiisa. Markaa caqiidada Islaamku waa lixda tiir ee iimaanka iyo wixii soo raaca oo lagu faahfaahin doono kitaabka gudihiisa."},{"question":"Ma’anar Karin Magana?","answer":"Masana Harshen Hausa sun fassara karin magana gwargwadon fahimtarsu. Daga ciki akwai:Farfesa Ɗangambo (1984) da ya ce, “Karin magana dabara ce ta dunƙule magana mai yawa a cikin zance ko ‘yan kalmomi kaɗan, cikin hikima”.Yahaya, Zariya, Gusau, da ‘Yar’aduwa (1992) , “Karin Magana Tsararren zance ne wanda yake zuwa a gajarce na hikima da zalaƙa tare da bayar da ma’ana gamsasshiya, mai faɗi, mai yalwa, musamman idan aka tsaya aka yi bayani daki-daki”.Kenan idan aka lura sosai, za a ga cewa ita karin magana, magana ce dunƙulalliya wacce ba kowa ne zai iya gane ta ba tare da an yi masa cikakken bayani ba. Amma yau da gobe da kuma yawan amfani da ita, musamman a zamunan da suka shuɗe, da ake yawan tsarma ta a cikin zance, sai ya zama shi Bahaushe yana iya gane abinsa. Misali, ana iya yiwa mutumin da bashi da tattali nuni cikin ‘yan kalmomi marasa yawa, kamar a ce da shi, wannan abin da ka ke yi zai hana ka farcen susa. Ko kuma idan ana son yin magana game da wani abu mai amfani da kuma maras amfani. Kamar a ce idan an aikata abin, wani abu maras daɗi zai faru da wanda ya aikata, to ana iya yi masa nuni ta hanyar cewa da shi, wannan abin ba zai haifar maka da ɗa, mai ido ba. Da sauransu.Kowace ɗaya aka ɗauka daga cikin waɗannan karin magana guda biyu, za a taras cewa maganganu ne dunƙulallu, waɗanda idan aka tashi farfasa su, za su ci guri mai yawa. Amma idan aka faɗe su da baki ko aka rubuta su, za a ji su ko a gan su gajeru, sannan kuma shi wanda ake magana da shi zai iya fahimtar abin da ake nufi."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: గురువు","answer":" ఉపాధ్యాయుడు, తండ్రి, బృహస్పతి, పురోహితుడు"},{"question":"Por favor complete este parágrafo - A Matabelelândia é uma região","answer":"localizada no sudoeste do Zimbábue que é dividida em três províncias: Matabelelândia Norte, Bulawayo e Matabelelândia Sul. Estas províncias estão localizadas a oeste e sudoeste do Zimbábue, entre os rios Limpopo e Zambeze e são separadas de Midlands pelo rio Shangani, no centro do Zimbábue. A região tem o nome de seus habitantes, o povo Ndebele que foi chamado de 'Matabele' pelos britânicos por não pronunciarem 'Ma Ndebele'."},{"question":"ఈ కింది మాటల క్రమాన్ని సరిచేస్తే గేయంలోని పాదాలుగా అవుతాయి. సరిచేసి రాయండి. భావం చెప్పండి.“దీప్తి దేశ చెందగ గర్వముచరితము దేశ తేజరిల్లగధీర దేశ పురుషుల మరసినతమ్ముడా ! పాడర తెలిసి.”","answer":"గేయ సవరణ ఇలా ఉండాలి.“దేశ గర్వము దీప్తిచెందగదేశ చరితము తేజరిల్లగదేశమరసిన ధీరపురుషులతెలిసి పాడర తమ్ముడా !పై గేయానికి భావం :దేశ గౌరవం ప్రకాశించేటట్లుగా, దేశచరిత్ర విస్తరించేటట్లుగా, దేశాన్ని కాపాడిన వీరపురుషులను – గురించి తెలుసుకొని కీర్తించాలి."},{"question":"(Uzwakala engaphakathi ngezwi elinokweyisa)Uqambe ushilo phoyisa ndini. Lutho olubaziwe! Angivuli mina!Kukwami phela lapha. Yihlazo phela leli olikhulumayo wena lokuthiufuna ukungena ngo 'dli' ijazi lephoyisa ngibe ngazi kahlekamhlophe ukuthi uzoba yisiphazamiso esikhulu laphaebudlelanweni bami nomkami nokwenza ngisemshikashikeniomnandi kangaka nomkami?(Uzwakala engaphandle, ehleka engahleki) Hho! Mhlawumbe wenaucabanga ukuthi kwenqakwa amagenda lapha, yingakho njeungichithela isikhathi ngoba sewuze wakhohlwa nawukuthingiyasebenza lapha mina. Uyazi ukuthini? Angenqeni phela minaukuvele ngisebenzise amagunya ami njengephoyisa wokubangivele ngisibhodloze mina lesi sicabha. Awuthi futhi kengi …(asho esikhahlela ngamawala)(Uzwakala ngaphakathi) Kahle ngamawala bo muntu womthetho.Ngilinde ngikuvulele. (Asho abe egudluza umshudu ngaphakathimaqedane kuvuleke.)Ehhe! Sase sithelekile ngaphakathi. Sangena maqedane lagcwalaumoya ibhulukwe endodeni. E … ake usisize kanjena-kemnumzane wami: njengamanje phuma uyongena evenini.Uyangizwa ukuthi ngithini lapha kuwe?1. Chaza isizathu sokusebenzisa isu lokubikezela elitholakala ephushenilikaMdaluli.","answer":"Umbhali usicacisela ukuthi kunezinkolelo ezahlukene njengokukholelwaemaphusheni. Amaphupho akumele azitshwe ngoba asuke eyizinkombazekusasa lethu nokuthi ayasilekelela ukugwema/ukuxazulula izinkinganjengoba uMdaluli aphupha iphupho elalibikezela izinhlupheko ezizayookwathi maduzane naye uMdaluli wadilizwa emsebenzini kanjalo nempiloyasekhaya ayibange isaba yinhle."},{"question":"Menene sunan ginin mafi tsayi a Paris?","answer":"Hasumiyar Eiffel sunansa"},{"question":"तलेजु मन्दिर","answer":"सन् १५४९ मा राजा महेन्द्र मल्लले निर्माण गरेको तलेजु मन्दिर सबै संरचनामध्ये सबैभन्दा अग्लो मन्दिर हो। यो मन्दिर प्रत्येक वर्ष दशैंको समयमा एक दिन सर्वसाधारणका लागि खुला हुने गर्दछ ।"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية: وأشار المتحف إلى أن غالبية القطع \\"التي اختفت أو سرقت أو تضررت… قطع صغيرة\\" محفوظة في المخازن، ولم يتم عرضها","answer":"مؤخرًا وتستخدم \\"بشكل أساسي لأغراض البحث\\"."},{"question":"人を奮い立たせる、という意味の言葉で、「檄」は「飛ばす」と言いますが、「発破」はどうする、というでしょう？","answer":"掛ける"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Bénin nékk","answer":"Réwum Bénin mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"১২টি কলা থেকে ৬জন লোককে সমান পরিমাণ কলা দিলে প্রতিজন কয়টি করে কলা পাবে?","answer":"১২টি কলা থেকে ৬জন লোককে সমান পরিমাণ কলা দিলে প্রতিজন ২টি করে কলা পাবে। কারণ ১২-কে ৬ দিয়ে ভাগ করলে ২ হয়।"},{"question":"Diniho ity hafatra manaraka ity: “Tsy tokony hahazo fianarana ny olona amin’ity saranga ara-tsosialy ity.” Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay lahatsoratra?","answer":"Eny, ny hafatra dia maneho fanavakavahana amin'ny saranga sosialy."},{"question":"ਮਹਾਰਾਜਗੰਜ: ਇੱਥੋਂ ਦੇ ਪੁਰੇਂਦਰਪੁਰ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਨੌਲੀ-ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ ਉਪਰ ਦੋ ਬੱਸਾਂ ਦੀ ਟੱਕਰ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਘੱਟੋ ਘੱਟ 40 ਸਕੂਲੀ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਜ਼ਖ਼ਮੀ ਹੋ ਗਏ। ਇਹ ਹਾਦਸਾ ਅੱਜ ਸਵੇਰੇ 8.50 ਵਜੇ ਉਦੋਂ ਵਾਪਰਿਆ ਜਦੋਂ ਇਕ ਸਕੂਲ ਬੱਸ ਟੂਰਿਸਟ ਬੱਸ ਨਾਲ ਟਕਰਾ ਗਈ। ਜ਼ਖ਼ਮੀ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਲਿਜਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਢਲਾ ਇਲਾਜ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ।ਹਾਦਸਾ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਹੋਇਆ?","answer":"ਹਾਦਸਾ  ਸਨੌਲੀ-ਗੋਰਖਪੁਰ ਰਾਜਮਾਰਗ ਉਪਰ ਹੋਇਆ।"},{"question":"Apakah kebaikan biji chia untuk kesihatan kita?","answer":"Berikut adalah kebaikan biji chia:1. Menurunkan Berat Badan:Dengan pengambilan biji chia sebanyak 25 hingga 38 gram sehari dapat membantu membakar lemak dan menurunkan berat badan. Kandungan tryptophan dalam biji chia pula membantu melancarkan sistem pencernaan dan melangsingkan tubuh.2. Mencegah Sembelit:Biji chia boleh merawat sembelit kerana kandungan serat tidak larut yang terkandung di dalamnya. Bahagian luar biji biji chia yang terdiri daripada polisakarida non-pati (NSP) yang mudah larut dalam air akan mengembang dan berubah menjadi seperti jeli sehingga dapat membantu pencernaan dan memudahkan pembuangan air besar.3. Mengawal Kencing Manis:Biji chia merupakan salah satu rawatan semula jadi yang mudah dan efektif untuk pesakit diabetes tahap 2. Ini berikutan keupayaan biji chia untuk melambatkan pencernaan dikaitkan dengan pencegahan diabetes. Biji chia dapat membantu menstabilkan gula dan melawan rintangan bagi insulin yang telah terikat dalam peningkana pada lemak perut.4. Melawan Kanser:Ada laporan perubatan menyatakan biji chia turut berkhasiat dalam memerangi kanser. Minyakbiji  chia juga memiliki sifat antikanser yang dikenalpasti dapat mengurangkan pertumbuhan tumor.5. Menurukan Tahap Kolestrol:Kandungan dalam biji chia berupaya menurunkan kolestrol dalam darah dan mencegah penyakit jantung koroner.6. Meningkatkan Kesuburan:Kajian yang dilakukan menunjukkan bahawa biji chia mampu meningkatkan kadar kesuburan lelaki.7. Membantu Memperbaiki Kesihatan Kardiovaskular:Kajian mendapati kandungan dalam biji chia dapat meningkatkan kesihatan jantung dan mencegah penyakit yang berhubungan dengan jantung.8. Meningkatkan Tenaga Dan Metabolisme:Kandungan dalam biji chia turut mampu membuatkan anda lebih bertenaga seperti laporan yang diterbitkan berdasarkan kajian yang telah dilakukan."},{"question":"අද්‍යතන කෙටිකථාවේ ආදිකතෘ \\" ලෙස පිදුම් ලබන , ලෝක පූජිත ප්‍රංශ ලේඛකයා  කවුද ?","answer":"අද්‍යතන කෙටිකථාවේ ආදිකතෘ \\" ලෙස පිදුම් ලබන , ලෝක පූජිත ප්‍රංශ ලේඛකයා වන්නෙ ගී ද මෝ පසාං ය."},{"question":"Ndedzipi shanu dzakanyatsosiyana, nzira dzekugadzira dzekutsanangura kubatsira kweiyo yakatyoka stapler.","answer":"\\"Mumwe anogona kuisa stapler yakaputsika kuti ishandise zvakanaka se- uremu hwepepa- sando- kushongedza kumba- mutongi- chombo\\""},{"question":"به من درباره تخت جمشید توضیح بده.","answer":"تخت جمشید (پارسه) مجموعه‌ای از چند کاخ تو در تو در کنار دشت مرودشت و در کوهپایهٔ کوه رحمت در استان فارس واقع در ایران است.  تخت جمشید در شهر باستانی پارسه یکی از شهرهای باستانی ایران قرار داشته‌است که طی سالیان، پیوسته پایتخت تشریفاتی امپراتوری هخامنشیان بوده‌ است. در نخستین روز سال نو گروه‌های زیادی از کشورهای گوناگون به نمایندگی از ساتراپی‌ها یا استانداری‌ها با پیشکش‌هایی متنوع در تخت جمشید جمع می‌شدند و هدایای خود را به شاه پیشکش می‌کردند.در سال ۵۱۸ پیش از میلاد بنای تخت جمشید به عنوان پایتخت جدید هخامنشیان در پارسه آغاز گردید. بنیان‌گذار تخت جمشید داریوش بزرگ بود، البته پس از او پسرش خشایارشاه و نوه‌اش اردشیر یکم با افزودن بناهای دیگر، این مجموعه را گسترش دادند. بسیاری از آگاهی‌های موجود که در مورد پیشینهٔ هخامنشیان و فرهنگ آن‌ها در دسترس است به خاطر سنگ‌نوشته‌ها و گِل نوشته‌هایی است که در این کاخ‌ها و بر روی دیواره‌ها و لوحه‌های آن حکاکی شده‌است. سامنر برآورد کرده‌است که دشت تخت جمشید که شامل ۳۹ قرارگاه مسکونی بوده، در دورهٔ هخامنشیان ۴۳٬۶۰۰ نفر جمعیت داشته‌است. اسکندر مقدونی سردار مقدونی در ۳۳۰ پیش از میلاد، به ایران حمله کرد و تخت جمشید را به آتش کشید. با این ‌حال ویرانه‌های این مکان هنوز هم برپا است و باستان‌شناسان از ویرانه‌های آن نشانه‌های آتش و هجوم را بر آن تأیید می‌کنند.این مکان تاریخی از سال ۱۹۷۹ یکی از آثار ثبت شدهٔ ایران در میراث جهانی یونسکو است."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy matoky an'ireo mpanao gazety ireo aho fa samy manodikodina saim-bahoaka avokoa.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, kabary fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy ara-drariny no iantsoana ireo mpanao gazety ho manodikodina saim-bahoaka avokoa."},{"question":"*كم عدد أيام شهر فبراير في السنة الكبيسة ؟","answer":"29 يوم"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo toerana misy asa?","answer":"Misy toerana roa no ahitana ny asa:- asa andrenivohitra.- asa eny ambanivohitra."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 山形県天童市に、5万本ぐらいのひまわりで作った迷路ができました。24日は、天童市の小学校と、夏休みで来ていた東京の小学校の子どもたちが全部で50人集まりました。迷路の全部の道は500mぐらいあります。ひまわりは高さが2mぐらいあって、周りがよく見えません。子どもたちは出口をさがしながら、元気に走っていました。東京の小学校の男の子は「こんなにたくさんのひまわりを見たのは初めてです。楽しむことができました」と話していました。ひまわりの迷路は無料で、8月上旬まで楽しむことができます。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- ひまわり: 1）キクの仲間の草花。夏、二メートルをこす茎の先に、大きな黄色の花が咲く。種は食用にしたり、油をとったりする。- 迷路: 1）入ると、入り口も出口も、方向さえもわからなくなるような道。迷いやすい道。- 無料: 1）料金のいらないこと。ただ。- 上旬: 1）月の初めの十日間。"},{"question":"Siapakah digelarkan Bapa Kemerdekaan di Malaysia?","answer":"Tunku Abdul Rahman"},{"question":"டயரின் கடலோர இயற்கை இடங்கள் மற்றும் மூன்று மண்டலங்களாகப் பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது: சுற்றுலா மண்டலம் (பொது கடற்கரைகள், பழைய நகரம் மற்றும் சூக்ஸ், பண்டைய துறைமுகம்), வேளாண் மற்றும் தொல்பொருள் மண்டலம் மற்றும் பாதுகாப்பு மண்டலம் ஃபீனீசியன் நீரூற்றுகள். அதன் மாறுபட்ட தாவரங்கள் மற்றும் விலங்கினங்கள் காரணமாக, இந்த இருப்பு ஒரு நியமிக்கப்பட்ட ராம்சார் தளமாகும் . இது புலம்பெயர்ந்த பறவைகள் மற்றும் ஆபத்தான பெருந்தலை கடலாமை மற்றும் பச்சை கடல் ஆமை மற்றும் அரேபிய ஊசிமுனைத எலி மற்றும் பல முக்கிய உயிரினங்களின் தங்குமிடம் ( சுவர் பல்லிகள், பொதுவான வௌவால் இனங்கள் மற்றும் ஐரோப்பிய பேட்ஜர் (வளையில் வாழும் ஒருவகை விலங்கினம் உட்பட) ஒரு முக்கியமான கூடு கட்டும் இடமாகும்.","answer":"ராம்சார் தளமாகும்"},{"question":"سوال: آیا جمله 1 و جمله 2 همان معنی را بیان می کنند؟ بله یا نه؟جمله اول:  \\" فيرنلي \\" جوان و صاحب زمين \\" توماس فيرنلي \\" بود که با الیزابت یانگ (1854 تا 1932) ازدواج کرد و پدر مغناطيس کشتي ناو بود. جمله دوم:  \\"فرنلي\\" جوون با الیزابت یانگ (۱۸۵۴ تا ۱۹۳۲) ازدواج کرد و پدر بزرگ کشتیرانی توماس فارنلی و صاحب زمین N.O. بود. ","answer":"خیر این دو جمله یک معنی را نمی‌رسانند."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي : كم سنة عاش سيدنا محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم ؟","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي 63 سنة."},{"question":"Folytasd a bekezdést - Trefort Ágoston a Pesti Műegylet megalapításának egyik kezdeményezője. Az 1848−49-es szabadságharc","answer":"idején a Magyar Álladalmi Bankjegynyomda igazgatója. A Kossuth-bankók litográfusa, a magyar államjegyek és a kormány minden sajtótermékének kinyomtatója."},{"question":"ルイス・キャロルが書いたのは「不思議な国のアリス」と「どこの国のアリス」でしょう？","answer":"鏡の国です。"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Criteria lagu jiifiyo caruurta qabta nafaqa darada.?","answer":"Cunug kastoo oo aad rabto in ka baarto nafaqa darada waa in aad ka baartaa waxyaabahaan soo socda sida weight, height, weight/height(z-score)iyo MUAC1. Bilatera edema (barar labada lugood ah).2. MUAC asna waxaa lagu ogaadaa carruurtanafaqa darada ay heeyso oo ka yar 5 sano,MUAC waxaa aqriyaa sadex qeyb:- 11.5 wixii ka yar- severe malnourished. 11.5-12.5 moderate malnourished. 12.5 -13.4 risk for malnourished.3. Z-score:- hadii uu gaaro -3.4. Hadii uu la socdo fuuqbax (dehydration)."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Po raz szósty i ostatni wziął udział w mistrzostwach kontynentalnych podczas turnieju Copa América 1929, gdzie Paragwaj został","answer":" wicemistrzem Ameryki Południowej. Fretes zagrał tylko w meczu przeciwko Peru."},{"question":"வினா:  விடை: பின்வரும் பத்தியைப் படித்து வார இதழ் ஒன்றிற்கு அனுப்பும் வகையில் சமையல் குறிப்பாக மாற்றுக:கம்மங்கூழ் தயாரித்தல் :பொசுக்குகிறது வெயில், ஒரு துளி மழை பட்டால் வறுத்த உளுத்தின் வாசம் பரப்பும் வறண்ட மண். வெடித்த நிலம் செழித்து விளைகிறது கம்மம் பயிர். உரலில் குத்தி, சுளகில் புடைக்க அதன் உழி நீங்கும். நீர் தெளித்துத் தெளித்து, மீண்டும் உரலில் இடிக்க அது ஒன்றுடன் ஒன்று ஒட்டி மாவாகும். உப்புக் கலந்து உலையில் ஏற்றி, கொதிக்கும் நீரில் கரையவிட்டுக் கிண்ட, கட்டியாகி அது சோறாகும். கம்மஞ் சோற்றை உருட்டி வைத்து, பின் மோர் விட்டுக் கரைத்தால் அது கம்மங்கஞ்சி அல்லது கம்மங்கூழ், மோர் மிளகாய் வற்றல், உப்பில் தோய்த்த பச்சை மிளகாய் அல்லது சின்ன வெங்காயம் கடித்துக் கஞ்சியைக் குடித்தால் உச்சி தொட்டு உள்ளங்கால் வரை தேகம் குளிர்ந்து போகும், அனல் அடங்கும். உயிர் வரும் கம்பு கறுப்பு நிறக் கரிசல் மண்ணின் இயற்கைத் தங்கம்.","answer":"கம்மங்கூழ் : (தேவையான பொருட்கள்)கம்மம் பயிர் – 2 கைப்பிடிஉப்பு – தேவைக்கு ஏற்பவிடை: நீர் – தேவைக்கு ஏற்பமோர் – அரை லிட்டர்மோர் மிளகாய் வற்றல் – 10 எண்ணம்பச்சை மிளகாய் (அல்லது) சின்ன வெங்காயம் – தேவைக்கு ஏற்பசெய்முறை :கம்மம் பயிரை நீர் தெளித்துத் தெளித்து உரலில் இடிக்க அது ஒன்றுடன் ஒன்று ஒட்டி மாவாகும். அதனுள் தேவையான அளவு நீரும் உப்பும் சேர்த்து உலையிலிட்டால் அது இறுகி சோறாகும். அந்தச் சோற்றுடன் மோர் விட்டுக் கரைத்தால் கம்மங்கூழ் தயார். மோர் மிளகாய் வற்றல், பச்சை மிளகாய் அல்லது சின்ன வெங்காயத்தைக் கடித்துக் கொண்டு இக்கஞ்சியைக் குடிக்கலாம்."},{"question":"\\"Ny fiantraikan'ny faharanitan-tsaina amin'ny indostrian'ny famoronana dia miteraka fanontaniana momba ny ho avin'ny famoronana olombelona. Ny zava-kanto, mozika ary famoronana votoaty AI dia fanamby amin'ny hevitra mahazatra momba ny mpanoratra sy ny fanehoana famoronana.\\"","answer":"Ny lohahevitra tamin'ny andalana teo aloha dia ny AI amin'ny orinasa mamorona"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia con esta categoría: política. ","answer":"¿En qué año fue asesinado John F. Kennedy? Fue asesinado en el año 1963. "},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"__ no anaran'ny fanjakana manan-tantara miorina any amin'ny faritra avon'i Madagasikara.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Imerina no anaran'ny fanjakana manan-tantara any amin'ny faritra avon'i Madagasikara."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Saya memakai seluar pendek tanpa kasut berdiri di atas pentas, tangan bersarung untuk mengalahkan pencabar, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah ahli tinju"},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Xeet u jàmbat la'y niru.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Xeet u jàmbat la'y niru.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Xeet: NOUNu: ADPjàmbat: NOUNla: AUX'y: AUXniru: ADJ.: PUNCT"},{"question":"问题：我如何在QQ上创建群聊？","answer":"答案：你可以在QQ的\\"联系人\\"页面点击\\"创建群聊\\"，然后按照提示操作。"},{"question":"大根などを煮る時、煮崩れを防ぐために野菜の角をとることを何というでしょう？","answer":"面取り"},{"question":"Маалымат базасы(англ. database) деген эмне?","answer":"Маалымат базасы – бул маалыматтардын системалуу жыйындысы. ЭЭМдин жардамы менен керектүү учурда таап алып, кайра пайдалануу үчүн бир нукка салынган маалыматтардын (м.: макалаларды, эсептерди ж. б.) уюштуруунун жана жыйындысын берүүнүн жалпы таризи."},{"question":"ਪੱਛਮੀ ਤੱਟ ਦੇ ਮੈਦਾਨ ਨਾ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤੰਗ ਹਨ, ਬਲਕਿ ਡੈਲਟਾਈ ਨਿਪੇਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਵਿਹੀਨ ਹਨ, ਵਿਆਖਿਆ ਕਰੋ |","answer":"ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਤੱਟ ਦੇ ਮੈਦਾਨ ਤੰਗ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਥੇ ਡੈਲਟਾਈ ਨਿਖੇਪ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਅਭਾਵ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਲਿਖੇ ਹਨ :* ਪੱਛਮੀ ਤੱਟ ‘ਤੇ ਸਾਗਰ ਦੂਰ ਤਕ ਅੰਦਰ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੇ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਹਾੜੀਆਂ ‘ਕੱਟੀਆਂ-ਫੱਟੀਆਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ ।ਪਰਿਣਾਮਸਵਰੂਪ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਤੱਟ ਦੇ ਮੈਦਾਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਸਤਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਰੁਕਾਵਟ ਆ ਗਈ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਹ ਮੈਦਾਨ ਤੰਗ ਹਨ।* ਜਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਤੋਂ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਅਰਬ ਸਾਗਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਡਿੱਗਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਹਾਓ ਤੇਜ਼ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਵਹਾਓ ਖੇਤਰ ਘੱਟ ਹੈ ਪਰਿਣਾਮਸਵਰੂਪ ਇਹ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਨਰਮਦਾ, ਤਾਪਤੀ) ਡੈਲਟੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ, ਬਲਕਿ ਜਵਾਰਨਮੁੱਖ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"வினா:வாழை இலையில் உண்பதால் ஏற்படும் நன்மைகள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை :1) வாழை இலையில் சாப்பிடுவதால், இளநரை வராமல் நீண்ட நாட்கள் தலைமுடி கருப்பாக இருக்கும். 2) வாழை இலை ஒரு கிருமிநாசினி. அது உணவில் உள்ள நச்சுக்கிருமிகளை அழிக்கும் தன்மை கொண்டது. 3) வாழை இலையில் தொடர்ந்து உண்பவர்களுக்கு நோய் தாக்குவதில்லை. தோல் பளபளப்பாகும்; பித்தம் தணிக்கும்.4) வயிற்றுப் புண் ஆற்றும்; பசியைத் தூண்டும்."},{"question":"'මාර්ගස්ථ ' තද්ධිතයක් ද?","answer":"ඔව්. තද්ධිතයක්."},{"question":"වී වගාවේ බලපෑම් ඇති කරන වල් පැළෑටි ද ප්‍රධාන කාණ්ඩ නම් කරන්න.","answer":"වී වගාවේ බලපෑම් ඇති කරන වල් පැළෑටි ද ප්‍රධාන කාණ්ඩ 03 ක් හඳුනා ගත හැක. එනම් ,1. තෘණ වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටි2. පන් වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටි3. පළල් පත්‍ර වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටි"},{"question":"சோபியா அஷ்ரப் என்பவர் இந்திய ராப் இசைப் பாடகர் ஆவார். போபால் விஷக் கழிவுகள் ,இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதவும் -","answer":"கொடைக்கானல் பாதரசக் கழிவுகள் உள்ளிட்ட சமூகப் பிரச்சனைகளைப் பேசுகிற ஆக்கங்கள் இவருடையவை. சோபியா ஓகில்வி ; மேதர் என்ற பன்னாட்டு விளம்பர நிறுவனத்தில் படைப்பூக்க மேற்பார்வையாளராகப் பணிபுரிந்தவர்."},{"question":"ఒక చెట్టు యొక్క నీడ పొడవు 8 మీ. మరియు అది 45°ల కోణము చేయుచున్న దాని పొడవు","answer":"tan 45° = AB/BC=AB/81 = AB/8∴ చెట్టు ఎత్తు AB = 8 మీ."},{"question":"එදා මෙදා තුර වැඩිම ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන ගණනක් දිනා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය චිත්‍රපටය කුමක්ද?","answer":"විෂම භාග චිත්‍රපටය වැඩිම ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන ගණනක් දිනා ඇති ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය චිත්‍රපටයයි. එ​ය ජාත්‍යන්තර සම්මාන 51කින් පිදුම් ලබා ඇත."},{"question":"Anong relihiyon sa Pilipinas ang may pinakamaraming miyembro?","answer":"Katolisismo ang relihiyong may pinakamaraming miyembro sa Pilipinas. Sa katunayan, ang Pilipinas lamang ang tanging bansa sa Southeast Asia na Katoliko. Mahigit 86% ng kabuuang populasyon ng bansa ay Katoliko."},{"question":"Kuhle ukuzenzela isidlo sasemini esinempilo nsuku zonke. Ukuthenga ukudlakwasemini ezitolo akubizi nje kuphela kodwa kuvame ukungabi nayo impilo.Ama-wraps enziwe ngaphambilini, amasemishi ngisho namasaladi angabanoshukela omningi1. Lenza msebenzi muni igama elibhalwe ngokugqamile kulo mushoolandelayo?Abantu bathwala kanzima bezama ukudla okunomsoco","answer":"Liyakhanyisa./Likhanyisa isimo./Isandiso sesimo."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在數學中，什麼是拓撲同調？","answer":"答案：拓撲同調是拓撲學中研究拓撲空間間的連續變形和映射的同調理論，用於研究空間的同源性、連接性和變形等性質。"},{"question":"సంధి పదాలను విడదీసి, సంధి పేరు రాయండి.నీరవుతుందికన్నీరవుతుందిదారవుతుందిఫలమేమిఎత్తులకెగిరినావిలువేమి","answer":"నీరవుతుంది = నీరు + అవుతుంది – ఉత్వసంధికన్నీరవుతుంది = కన్నీరు + అవుతుంది – ఉత్వసంధిదారవుతుంది = దారి + అవుతుంది – ఉత్వసంధిఫలమేమి = ఫలము + ఏమి – ఉత్వసంధిఎత్తులకెగిరినా = ఎత్తులకు + ఎగిరినా – ఉత్వసంధివిలువేమి = విలువ + ఏమి – ఉత్వసంధి"},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa \\"batu pun empuk, jangankan hati manusia\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah hati manusia yang keras dapat ditawan dan dilembutkan dengan perkataan yang manis dan lemah lembut."},{"question":"Que aclamado cineasta vencedor do Oscar dirigiu Happy Feet, Babe - O Porquinho Atrapalhado na Cidade e Mad Max: Estrada da Fúria.","answer":"Quem dirigiu os ambos filmes citados foi George Miller"},{"question":"வினா : நேதாஜி சுபாஷ் சந்திர போஸே பற்றி கண்டறிய அமைக்கப்பட்ட கமிஷன்கள் எவை?","answer":"விடை : ஷாநவாஸ் கமிஷன், கோஸ்லா கமிஷன், ஜஸ்டிஸ் முகர்ஜிகமிஷன்"},{"question":"ලංකාව හා චීනය අතර ප්‍රථම ආර්ථික ගිවිසුම වූයේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලංකාව හා චීනය අතර ප්‍රථම ආර්ථික ගිවිසුම වූයේ සහල් රබර් ගිවිසුමයි."},{"question":"Cho hai hệ cân bằng sau trong hai bình kín:C + CO2 ⇔ 2CO      DELTA H = 172 kJCO + H20 ⇔ CO2     DELTA H = -41 kJCó bao nhiêu điều kiện trong các điều kiện sau đây làm các cân bằng trên chuyển dịch ngược chiều nhau (giữ nguyên các điều kiện khác)Tăng nhiệt độTăng áp suấtThêm khí CO2 vàoDùng chất xúc tácThêm khí H2 vàoThêm khí CO vào","answer":"Có 2 điều kiện trong các điều kiện sau đây làm các cân bằng trên chuyển dịch ngược chiều nhau: tăng nhiệt độ và thêm khí CO vào.Tăng nhiệt độ: Đối với cân bằng C + CO2 ⇔ 2CO, phản ứng thuận là phản ứng tỏa nhiệt, nên khi tăng nhiệt độ, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều nghịch. Đối với cân bằng CO + H2O ⇔ CO2, phản ứng thuận là phản ứng thu nhiệt, nên khi tăng nhiệt độ, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều thuận.Thêm khí CO vào: Đối với cân bằng C + CO2 ⇔ 2CO, CO là sản phẩm của phản ứng thuận và là chất phản ứng của phản ứng nghịch. Khi thêm khí CO vào, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều nghịch để tiêu thụ CO. Đối với cân bằng CO + H2O ⇔ CO2, CO là chất phản ứng của phản ứng thuận và là sản phẩm của phản ứng nghịch. Khi thêm khí CO vào, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều thuận để sản xuất CO2.Các điều kiện còn lại sẽ không làm các cân bằng trên chuyển dịch ngược chiều nhau.Tăng áp suất: Đối với cả hai cân bằng, số mol phân tử khí ở hai vế là bằng nhau. Vì vậy, tăng áp suất sẽ không làm cân bằng chuyển dịch.Dùng chất xúc tác: Chất xúc tác không làm thay đổi trạng thái cân bằng, chỉ làm tăng tốc độ phản ứng.Thêm khí H2 vào: Đối với cân bằng C + CO2 ⇔ 2CO, H2 là chất phản ứng của phản ứng thuận. Khi thêm khí H2 vào, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều thuận để sản xuất CO. Đối với cân bằng CO + H2O ⇔ CO2, H2 là chất phản ứng của phản ứng nghịch. Khi thêm khí H2 vào, cân bằng sẽ chuyển dịch theo chiều nghịch để tiêu thụ H2.Do đó, đáp án là 2."},{"question":"Mbabane moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Mbabane moy péeyu réwum Eswatini"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Inför revolutionens","answer":"sammanbrott flydde Mörn till Viborg, där man planerade att fortsätta ge ut \\"Arbetet.\\" Staden föll snabbt i de vitas händer och efter ett misslyckat flyktförsök genom skärgården fängslades han och dömdes i en statsförbrytelsedomstol till döden samt avrättades på Sveaborg den 6 september 1918."},{"question":"Qui était le réalisateur Lee Yoon-ki ?","answer":"Né le 1er juillet 1965 à Daejon en Corée du Sud, Lee Yoon-ki suit des études commerciales à l’université de Southern California (USC) aux Etats-Unis. De retour dans son pays natal, il entame une carrière de producteur et réalise plusieurs courts métrages. Son premier long métrage, « This Charming Girl », dont il a également écrit le scénario, remporte le Prix de la Révélation au festival de Pusan en 2004. Ce portrait intimiste d’une jeune fille solitaire est ensuite sélectionné dans de nombreux autres festivals internationaux, dont le festival de Deauville où il obtient le Prix du Jury. Son second film, « Love Talk », entièrement tourné aux Etats-Unis, raconte les difficultés d’adaptation rencontrées à Los Angeles par des expatriés d’origine sud-coréenne. Son troisième long métrage, « Ad Lib Night », un drame au style épuré sur la douleur intérieure, est présenté dans le cadre du Forum du festival de Berlin en 2006 et remporte le Prix de la Critique au Festival du Film Asiatique de Deauville. « My Dear Enemy » est son quatrième long métrage.Lee Yoon-ki est connu pour ses drames introspectifs et axés sur les personnages qui se concentrent sur les émotions et les relations subtiles. Ses films, comme « My Dear Enemy » et « Ad-lib Night », offrent des portraits nuancés des luttes quotidiennes et des liens humains."},{"question":"Como ocorre a fermentação na produção de alimentos?","answer":"A fermentação é um processo que envolve o crescimento e a atividade de micro-organismos nos alimentos, como bolores, bactérias ou leveduras. Esse processo ocorre na ausência de oxigênio e resulta na transformação da matéria orgânica em diferentes produtos, como álcool, ácido lático, gás carbônico, entre outros. A fermentação é utilizada na produção de diversos alimentos, como iogurte, queijo, pão, vinho, cerveja, missô, kimchi e chucrute. Esses alimentos podem ter benefícios para a saúde, como melhorar a digestão, aumentar a biodisponibilidade de nutrientes e prevenir infecções intestinais."},{"question":"請問有哪些英國歌曲在國際上很受歡迎？","answer":"答：許多英國歌曲在國際音樂界具有重要的影響力，如Adele的《Rolling in the Deep》、Ed Sheeran的《Shape of You》等。"},{"question":"یوه ټوکه ولیکه:","answer":"یوه سړی اوریدلی وه چی په بازار کی يو دکان ډیر ښهاينځر خرڅوی . دی چی هغه دکان ته ولاړ او هلته يی وکتل ، و دکاندار ته یی وويل: مااوریدلی وه چی ته ښه اينځر لری ، مګر دا ډیر بد رنګه اينځر دی . دکاندار جواب ورکړاو ويی ويل : دا چی ته وينی دا اينځر ندی بلکه ته خپل مخ په هنداره کی وينی."},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚С. Орозбаковдун варианты жөнүндө эң биринчи терең илимий талдоо жазган окумуштууа) Р. Сарыпбеков б) А. Эсеналиевв) С. Мусаев г) М. Богданова","answer":"г) М. Богданова"},{"question":"請回答以下問題. 法國的自由女神像建於何時","answer":"1886年10月28日"},{"question":"Кежигеси кер тартуу","answer":"Кежирленүү, мойну жар бербөө.Асылбектин бүгүн кежигеси кер тартып, иш кылгысы келген жок."},{"question":"Sentence A: Il vit dans une grande, dans une profonde retraite. Sa santé le condamne à la retraite.Sentence B: On en parlait souvent, de la retraite, et comme d’une opération de haute magie, qui transforme un maître d’école en rentier. La retraite, c’était le grand mot, le maître-mot.« Retraite » a une signification similaire dans les phrases A et B. Vrai ou faux ?","answer":"Faux"},{"question":"Haa, wọn ni ọmọ Ibo yii ki ika bọ ọmọ ọdun marun-un labẹ, wọn ti wọ ọ de teṣan o","answer":"Ni agọ ọlọpaa Festac l’Ekoo ni ọkunrin ọmọ Ibo kan ti n wo pakopako bayii, lẹyin ti ọwọ tẹ ẹ nibi to ti n fi ika ro ọmọ ọdun marun-un labẹ.Nnamadi Emdriuokhe, ni wọn pe orukọ ẹ, agbegbe Festac, l’Ekoo gan-an niṣẹlẹ ọhun ti waye. Wọn lo pẹ ti ọkunrin ọmọ Ibo yii ti maa n ra ounjẹ lọwọ iya ọmọ to n ṣe iṣekuṣe pẹlu ẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe, nibi to ti n fika ro ọmọ naa labẹ ni ẹjẹ ti bẹrẹ si jade, n lawọn eeyan ba ki i mọle, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i lu u bii ẹni maa ku!Ọkunrin kan lagbegbe naa, Ọlagunju ̀Ọladele, ti iṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju ẹ lo gbe e sori ẹrọ alatagba, ohun to si kọ sibẹ ni pe, ṣọja kan lo gba a kalẹ lọwọ awọn eeyan ti wọn fẹẹ lu u pa, nigba tọwọ tẹ ẹ.O ni lojuẹsẹ naa lawọn obi ọmọ ọhun ti fọrọ ọhun to teṣan ọlọpaa leti, ṣugbọn ti awọn yẹn naa tun n beere owo lọwọ wọn, ki wọn too le gba ọrọ wọn silẹ.Siwaju si i, o ni, nibi ti ọkunrin to hu iwa ọdaran yii ti fẹẹ fowo bọ awọn eeyan ọhun ninu loun ti dide sọrọ ọhun, oun si ti gbe e lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa to wa ni Festac bayii."},{"question":"Idlewild Airport no anaran'ilay seranam-piaramanidina iraisam-pirenena ao New York. Mba ho fanomezam-boninahitra an'i John Kennedy, ilay Filoha Amerikana voatifitra dia niova ny anaran'ilay seranam-piaramanidina tamin'ny 1963. Lasa inona ny anaran'ny \\" Idlewild Airport \\"? ","answer":"Niova ho \\" John F. Kennedy International Airport \\" ny anaran'ny seranam-piaramanidina Idlewild Airport nanomboka ny 1963 hatramin'izao. "},{"question":"\\"කේතුමතී\\" යන්නෙහි අර්ථය කුමක් ද?","answer":"කේතුමතී රාජධානිය දිගින් දොළොස් යොදුනකි. පලලින් සත් යොදුනකි. මෙහි ඇති නගර සංඛ්‍යව අසූහාර දහසකි. ඉන් පුදානම වන්නේ කේතුමතී නගරය. එය පාලනය කරනුයේ සංඛ නැමැති රජ කෙනෙකි. මෙය පිනෙන් පිරි් රාජධානියකි.එහි මිනිසෙකුගේ පරමායුෂ අවුරැදු අසූහාර දහසකි.ඔවුන් රෝගාබාධ වලින් තොරය. එකම ආබාධය හැටියට සැලකෙන්නේ කුසගින්න- නිදිමත සහ වයසට යාම පමණි.කේතුමතිය බව භෝග සමිපත්තියෙන් අනූන රාජධානියකි. පලබර ගහකොළ වල හටගත් පලතුරැ ඉතා රසවත් අතර ධාන්‍ය වර්ග ඔිජෝ ගුණයෙන් යුක්තය. දේශගුණය ඉතා සුවදායකය.තුසිත දෙවි ලොව වැඩසිටින බෝසතානන්න් වහන්සේ බ්‍රහ්මයාගේ ඉල්ලීම පරිදි රට පාලනය කරන සක්විති රජතුමාගේ් පුරෝහිත බමුනු සුබ්‍රහ්ම එම බැමණියට දාව දඹදිව උපත ලබා නා ගසක් බෝ වෘක්ෂය කරලනිමින්බුදුබවට පත්වෙි."},{"question":"पुढील वाक्ये कोठल्या घटनेसंदर्भात आहे? : हे शहर मोगामी नदीच्या काठावर वसेले आहे. येथे दुसऱ्या महायुद्धादरम्यान झालेल्या कोहिमाच्या लढाईत कामी आलेल्या जपानी सैनिकांचे स्मारक आहे.","answer":"कोहिमाच्या लढाई संदर्भात."},{"question":"Arak' ity lahatsoratra manaraka ity, inona no lafiny ara-jeografika manodidina an’i Ejipta?Ejipta dia firenena any avaratra atsinanan'i Afrika, manamorona ny Ranomasina Mediterane eo avaratra ary ny Ranomasina Mena eo atsinanana.","answer":"Voahodidin'ny Ranomasina Mediterane any avaratra sy ny Ranomasina Mena any atsinanana ny ankamaroan'i Ejipta."},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan kepentingan pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya. ","answer":"Saban hari kita dikhabarkan dengan berita kemalangan jalan raya yang berlaku sehingga meragut nyawa-nyawa yang tidak bersalah. Malah ada yang menjadi sebatang kara apabila ahli keluarga yang lain meninggal dunia akibat kemalangan jalan raya. Perkara ini telah membuka mata pelbagai pihak untuk memastikan ia tidak berulang maka pihak berkuasa telah memasukkan pendidikan berkenaan keselamatan dan penggunaan jalan raya dalam kurikulum sekolah untuk dipelajari oleh generasi muda. Matlamatnya supaya kanak-kanak serta ibu dan bapa memahami bahaya, risiko dan amalan terbaik dalam menggunakan jalan raya di negara ini selain menyelamatkan nyawa yang tidak berdosa daripada terkorban akibat kemalangan di jalan raya. Oleh itu, wajar untuk kita bincangkan kepentingan PKJR dalam kalangan kanak-kanak demi perubahan dalam jangka masa kini dan seterusnya.Sebagai pengenalan, kanak-kanak di sekolah seharusnya mendapat pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya untuk memahami papan tanda yang digunakan sepanjang jalan raya di Malaysia. Perkara ini penting kerana apabila mereka mengenali dan memahami maksud setiap papan tanda yang dipacak di tepi jalan raya, mereka dapat memastikan ibu bapa atau pemandu yang memandu kenderaan yang mereka naiki untuk patuh pada arahan papan tanda tersebut. Sebagai contoh, papan tanda melintas jalan di hadapan sekolah dimana kenderaan perlu memperlahankan kelajuan dan tidak melebihi had laju 30 kilometer sejam. Murid-murid boleh menasihati ibu bapa untuk membawa kenderaan dengan mematuhi had laju yang ditetapkan setiap kali melalui jalan di hadapan sekolah. Ibarat peribahasa Melayu, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Intihannya, mendidik tentang keselamatan jalan raya adalah penting untuk muridi-murid mengenal dan memahami papan tanda sepanjang jalan raya.Kepentingan lain pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya adalah untuk mengetahui peraturan-peraturan yang ditetapkan oleh pihak berkuasa seperti Jabatan Pengangkutan Jalan (JPJ) dan Polis Di Raja Malaysia (PDRM). Apabila peraturan am penggunaan jalan raya dipelajari oleh murid-murid, mereka secara langsung dapat memerhati samada ibu bapa atau mana-mana pemandu yang melakukan kesalahan di atas jalan raya. Misalnya apabila motorsikal yang tidak mematuhi lampu isyarat dan melintas satu persimpangan dalam keadaan bahaya hanya untuk merebut pesanan makanan tetapi mengabaikan keselamatan. Murid-murid boleh mengenal pasti kesalahan tersebut dan membantu penguatkuasaan peraturan jalan raya oleh pihak berkuasa. Izharnya, pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya mustahak untuk melahirkan masyarakat yang peka terhadap peraturan-peraturan jalan raya.Di samping itu, pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya penting untuk mengurangkan kadar kemalangan jalan raya. Menurut Kementerian Pengangkutan Malaysia, kadar kemalangan di Malaysia telah meningkat dalam tempoh 10 tahun. Manakala kemalangan yang melibatkan kematian pernah mencecah sehingga 7000 kematian dalam tempoh masa satu tahun. Statistik yang tragis ini sewajarnya boleh dielakkan dengan pemanduan yang cermat oleh semua pengguna jalan raya bak kata pepatah pandu cermat, jiwa selamat. Justeru, murid-murid yang telah mempelajari sedikit sebanyak tentang keselamatan jalan raya pastinya akan mengingatkan ibu bapa atau mana-mana pemandu untuk sentiasa memandu di bawah had laju yang ditetapkan serta sentiasa memakai tali pinggang keselamatan atau topi keledar apabila menunggang motorsikal. Tegasnya, pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya dapat membantu murid untuk menasihati sesiapa sahaja yang memandu kenderaan yang mereka naiki agar mematuhi peraturan jalan raya agar keselamatan diri mereka terjamin.Akhir sekali, pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya dalam kalangan kanak-kanak dapat melahirkan pengguna jalan raya yang berhemah. Hal ini kerana mereka adalah generasi masa hadapan yang akan mendukung misi dan visi negara untuk berkembang maju dan bersaing dengan negara maju yang lain. Setelah murid-murid melepasi had umur untuk mendapatkan lesen memandu kenderaan, mereka akan menjadi pemandu yang berhemah kerana telah mempelajari dan memahami tentang keselamatan jalan raya. Tamsilnya, pembelajaran tentang papan tanda di sepanjang jalan raya yang mereka boleh aplikasikan apabila memandu kenderaan sendiri. Mereka hanya perlu mengelak daripada sebarang anasir jahat daripada rakan atau media yang mengajak kepada penyalahgunaan jalan raya seperti memandu melebihi had laju di lebuhraya. Perkara yang jelas berbahaya akan merisikokan keselamatan diri kita dan juga pengguna jalan raya yang lain. Oleh itu, pendidikan berkenaan keselamatan jalan raya adalah penting untuk melahirkan pemandu yang berhemah persis kata mutiara biar lambat, asal selamat.Secara tuntas, banyak kepentingan yang diperoleh daripada pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya. Bukan sahaja untuk kanak-kanak tetapi juga buat semua lapisan umur masyarakat kerana keselamatan jalan raya terpakai untuk semua. Justeru, pihak berkuasa seharusnya meningkatkan usaha dalam berkempen untuk memberikan kesedaran kepada masyarakat umum tentang kepentingan mendidik seseorang agar keselamatan di atas jalan raya terjamin. Pengguna jalan raya yang semakin bertambah dari hari ke hari perlu sejajar dengan inisiatif dalam memastikan jalan raya di seluruh pelusuk negara kita selamat dan baik. Kecuaian manusia yang merupakan antara faktor utama kemalangan berlaku dapat dielakkan dengan langkah-langkah tertentu yang terkandung dalam pendidikan keselamatan jalan raya. Semoga inisiatif ini dapat melahirkan masyarakat yang berhemah tinggi serta mengangkat imej negara sebagai negara yang selamat untuk memandu dan didiami."},{"question":"கேள்வி: உடலின் மிக முக்கியமான உறுப்பு எது?","answer":"பதில்:            மூளை. மூளை நம்முடைய சிந்தனை, உணர்வு, இயக்கம் ஆகிய அனைத்தையும் கட்டுப்படுத்துகிறது."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anak ikan ketohoran\\"?","answer":"Hilang akal melihat bahaya"},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina diso amin'ity fehezanteny ity:\\"Miroborobo fatratra anketriny ny fitovana moderina samihafa izay entina hanovana ireo asa aman-draharaha.\\"","answer":"Indro ny fehezanteny voahitsy tsipelina:\\"Miroborobo fatratra ankehitriny ny fitaovana maoderina samihafa izay entina hanaovana ireo asa aman-draharaha.\\""},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : మీ ఇంటికి ముఖద్వారం ఏ దిశలో ఉంది? ఆలోచించి చెప్పండి. తర్వాత దిక్సూచి ఉపయోగించి కచ్చితంగా అది ఏ దిశలో ఉందో కనుక్కొని మీ సమాధానంతో పోల్చి చూడండి. అదేవిధంగా కింది విషయాలను కూడా . ఊహించండి, పరీక్షించండి.ఎ) నువ్వు ఏ దిశలో తల ఉంచి పడుకుంటావు?బి) నువ్వు ఏ దిశవైపు తిరిగి చదువుకుంటావు?సి) భోజనం చేసేటప్పుడు ఏ దిశవైపు మరలి కూర్చుంటావు?","answer":"మా ఇల్లు తూర్పు దిక్కులో ఉందని భావించాను. కానీ దిక్సూచితో చూసినపుడు తూర్పుదిశకు కొంచెము పక్కకు ఉన్నట్టు గుర్తించాను.ఎ) నేను నిద్రిస్తున్నప్పుడు నా తల తూర్పు వైపు ఉంచుతాను అని ఊహించాను, కాని అది కొంచెం ఈశాన్యం వైపు ఉంది.బి) నేను చదివేటప్పుడు తూర్పు వైపు ఉంటానని ఊహించాను. కానీ నేను పైన చెప్పినట్లుగానే ఈశాన్యం వైపు ఉన్నాను.సి) తినేటప్పుడు తూర్పు వైపు కూర్చుంటానని ఊహించాను. కానీ నేను పైన చెప్పినట్లుగానే ఈశాన్యం వైపు ఉన్నాను."},{"question":"Mene makera?","answer":"MAKERA yana nufin guri ne da ake sarrafa karfe zuwa abun amfani."},{"question":"\\"Осака префектурасынын борбору жана ошондой эле Япониянын үч ири шаарын камтыган Кейханшин мегаполисинин эң ири бөлүгү болуп саналат, Киото, Осака жана Кобе\\". Темасы Осака.","answer":"\\"Осака Жапониянын кай жагында жайгашкан?\\""},{"question":"ਮੇਰੇ ਹੱਥ ਚਿਪਚਿਪੇ ਹੋ ਗਏ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਡੋਨਟ ਖਾਧਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਿੱਠੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਪਸੰਦ ਸਨ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਡੋਨਟ ਖਾਧਾ।"},{"question":"வினா: பாரதியாரின் பெற்றோர்கள் பெயர்?","answer":"விடை: சின்னசாமி ஐயர் – இலக்குமி அம்மாள்"},{"question":"විසන්ධි කරන්න.සියලඟ","answer":"සියල්+අඟ"},{"question":"Ndagi: Zungulila uku tikumane uku?","answer":"Yankho: Lamba"},{"question":"యాంత్రికశక్తిని విద్యుత్ శక్తిగా మార్చేదిA) విద్యుత్ జనరేటర్B) విద్యుత్ మోటరుC) బ్యాటరీD) ఎలక్ట్రిక్ స్విచ్","answer":"A) విద్యుత్ జనరేటర్"},{"question":"எழுத்துகளின் பிறப்பு பற்றி விளக்குக?","answer":"ஒலிகள் எல்லாம் உள்ளிருந்து எழும் காற்றால் பிறக்கின்றன. அந்த காற்று மார்பு, கழுத்து, தலை, மூக்கு ஆகியவற்றில் பொருந்தி இதழ்கள், நாக்கு, பல், மேல்வாய் ஆகிய நான்கில் முயற்சி வேறுபாட்டால் பல்வேறு எழுத்து ஒலிகள் பிறக்கின்றன இவையே எழுத்துக்களின் பிறப்பு என்பர்.அதாவது உயிரின் முயற்சியால் உடலின் உள்ளிருந்து எழும் காற்றானது மார்பு, தலை, கழுத்து, மூக்கு ஆகிய நான்கு இடங்களுள் ஒன்றில் பொருந்தி இதழ், நாக்கு, பல், மேல்வாய் ஆகிய உறுப்புகளின் முயற்சியினால் வேறு வேறு ஒலிகளாகத் தோன்றுகின்றன இதுவே எழுத்துக்களின் பிறப்பு ஆகும்.எழுத்துகளின் பிறப்பு எத்தனை வகைப்படும்இடப்பிறப்புமுயற்சி பிறப்புஎன இரு வகைப்படும்.ஒலி தோன்ற உதவும் உறுப்புக்கள் எட்டு ஆகும். தலை, கழுத்து, நெஞ்சு, மூக்கு, பல், இதழ், நாக்கு, அண்ணம் இவை இரண்டு வகையாகக் கூறப்படுகின்றது. தலை, கழுத்து, நெஞ்சு, மூக்கு காற்றறையாகவும், இதழ்கள், நாக்கு, அண்ணம், பல் இவை ஒலியெழுப்பியாகவும் செயல்படுகின்றன.எழுத்துக்களின் இடப்பிறப்புஇடப்பிறப்பு என்பது எழுத்துகள் தோன்றுகின்ற மார்பு, கழுத்து, தலை, மூக்கு ஆகிய நான்கு இடங்களைக் குறிக்கிறது.ஒலி எழக் காரணமான காற்று நிலைபெறும் இடங்களை “காற்றறைகள்” என கூறலாம்.வயிற்றிலிருந்து வெளிவரும் காற்றானது மார்பில் தங்கி வாயில் அடைபட்டு வன்மையான ஓசை உடையதாக வெளிப்படுகின்றது. இவ்வெழுத்துக்களை வல்லினம் என்கின்றனர்.இதேபோல் வயிற்றில் இருக்கும் காற்றானது மூக்கில் தங்கி மென்மையான ஓசையாக வெளிவருகின்றது. இவற்றை மெல்லினம் என்கின்றனர். மார்பிற்கும், மூக்கிற்கும் இடைப்பட்ட பகுதி கழுத்து.காற்றானது கழுத்தில் தங்கி வாய்வழியாக வெளிபடுவதனை இடையினம் என்கின்றனர். உயிரெழுத்துக்கள் பன்னிரண்டும் கழுத்தை இடமாக கொண்டு பிறக்கின்றன. வன்மையான ஓசையும் அல்லாமல், மென்மையான ஓசையும் இல்லாமல் இடைப்பட்ட ஓசையைக் கொண்டதனால் இதனை இடையினம் என்றனர்.எழுத்துக்களின் முயற்சி பிறப்புமுயற்சிப் பிறப்பு என்பது உதடு, நாக்கு, மேல்வாய் (அண்ணம்), பல் ஆகிய உறுப்புகளின் தொழில் வேறுபாட்டினால் ஒலிப்பதனை குறிக்கிறது.ஒலி எழுவதற்குத் துணை செய்யும் உறுப்புகளை ஒலிப்புமுனைகள் என கூறுவர்.உயிர் எழுத்துக்களின் முயற்சிப் பிறப்புவாய் திறந்தால் அ, ஆ பிறக்கின்றது. வாய் திறத்தல் மூலம் நாக்கின் அடி ஓரமானது மேல்வாய்ப் பல்லில் பொருந்துவதால் இ, ஈ, எ, ஏ, ஐ போன்ற எழுத்துக்கள் பிறக்கின்றன. வாய் திறத்தலோடு இதழைக் குவிப்பதால் உ, ஊ, ஒ, ஓ, ஒள போன்ற 5 எழுத்துக்களும் பிறக்கின்றன.மெய் எழுத்துக்களின் முயற்சிப் பிறப்புநாவின் முதற்பகுதியும், அண்ணத்தின் அடிப்பகுதியும் பொருந்துவதால் க், ங் பிறக்கின்றன.நாவின் இடைப்பகுதியும், அண்ணத்தின் இடைப்பகுதியும் பொருந்துவதால் ச், ஞ் பிறக்கின்றன.நாவின் நுனிப்பகுதியும், அண்ணத்தின் நுனிப்பகுதியும் பொருந்துவதால் ட், ண் பிறக்கின்றன.மேல்வாய்ப் பல்லின் அடியை நாக்கின் நுனி பொருந்துவதால் த், ந் பிறக்கின்றன.மேலிதழும், கீழிதழும் பொருந்துவதால் ப், ம் பிறக்கின்றன.நாக்கின் அடிப்பகுதி மேல்வாய் அடிப்பகுதியைப் பொருந்துவதால் ய் பிறக்கின்றது.மேல்வாயை நாக்கின் நுனி வருடுவதால் ர, ழ் பிறக்கின்றன.மேல்வாய்ப் பல்லின் அடியை நாக்கின் ஓரங்கள் தடித்து நெருங்குவதால் ல் பிறக்கின்றது.மேல்வாயை நாக்கின் ஓரங்கள் தடித்துத் தடவுதவதால் ள் பிறக்கின்றது.மேல்வாய்ப் பல்லைக் கீழ் உதடு பொருந்துவதால் வ் பிறக்கின்றது.மேல்வாயை நாக்கின் நுனி மிகவும் பொருந்துவதால் ற், ன் போன்ற எழுத்துக்கள் பிறக்கின்றன."},{"question":"س102 - من هو أول من آمن من المدينة المنورة ؟","answer":"ج102 - سيدنا أسعد بن زرارة "},{"question":"Scrivi una continuazione per questo paragrafo - \\"Nel giugno 2007, a Rooney è stato assegnato il numero 10 della squadra, indossato per l'ultima volta da Ruud van Nistelrooy. Rooney diceva di aver sempre amato quel numero. Si è fratturato il metatarso sinistro nel pareggio senza gol del primo giorno del United contro il Reading il 12 agosto, lo stesso infortunio che aveva subito al piede destro nel 2004. Dopo essere stato in pensione per sei settimane, è tornato e ha segnato nella vittoria della fase a gironi della Champions League contro la Roma il 2 ottobre. Rooney si è nuovamente infortunato il 9 novembre, ferendosi la caviglia durante una sessione di allenamento e mancando altre due settimane. La sua prossima partita dopo l'infortunio fu contro il Fulham il 3 dicembre, in cui giocò 70 minuti. Rooney ha perso dieci partite e ha finito la stagione 2007-08 con 18 gol (12 di loro in campionato), mentre il United ha conquistato la Premier League. Nella prima finale di Champions League interamente inglese, ...\\"","answer":"\\"... United ha sconfitto il rivale Chelsea per vincere un altro trofeo.\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bangkai gajah bolehkah ditudung oleh nyiru\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kejahatan yang besar itu tidak dapat disembunyikan."},{"question":"මාන රහිත භෞතික රාශීන් තිබේ ද?","answer":"ඔව්. භෞතික විද්‍යාවේ දී මාන රහිත මාන දැකිය හැකි ය. නිදසුන් ලෙස සාපේක්ෂ ඝනත්වය හා වර්තනාංකය යනාදිය දැක්විය හැකි ය."},{"question":"వ్యవసాయ, ఉద్యానవన, ఔషధపరంగా వృక్షశాస్త్ర పరిధిని క్లుప్తంగా వర్ణించండి.","answer":"హరితవిప్లవం ద్వారా వ్యాధి నిరోధక, కీటక నిరోధక పంటలను జీవ సాంకేతిక పద్ధతులలో అభివృద్ధి పరిచి, జనాభా పెరుగుదల, వనరుల తరుగుదల వంటి సమస్యలను చాలా వరకు పరిష్కరించవచ్చు.సంకరణం, జన్యు ఇంజనీరింగ్ ప్రయోగాల ద్వారా వృక్షశాస్త్రంలోని వ్యవసాయము, అటవీసంపద, ఉద్యానవన, పుష్పోత్పత్తి తాంటి అనువర్తన శాస్త్రాలలో మంచి పురోగతి సాధించవచ్చు.సాగు మొక్కలైన వరి, గోధుమ, మొక్కజొన్న, చెరుకులలో కొత్త వంగడాలను ఏర్పరచడానికి క్రొత్త ప్రజనన పద్ధతులు ఉపయోగపడును.వృక్ష వ్యాధి శాస్త్రంలో జరిపిన పరిశోధనల ఫలితాలు మొక్కల్లో వచ్చే అనేక వ్యాధులను నివారించడం, నిర్మూలనకు ‘ఉపయోగపడతాయి.మొక్కల వృద్ధి నియంత్రికాల పాత్ర, వాటి పరిజ్ఞానం వల్ల వ్యవసాయ, ఉద్యాన వనరంగాల్లో అభివృద్ధి సాధించడమైంది.కణజాల, అవయవవర్ధనం వల్ల అతితక్కువ సమయంలో అధిక సంఖ్యలో మొక్కలను ప్రయోగశాలలో ఉత్పత్తిచేయవచ్చు.వృక్షశాస్త్ర అభివృద్ధి వల్ల బట్టలు, కాగితం, చక్కెర లాంటి ఎన్నో, పరిశ్రమలు వృద్ధిచెందాయి.ఆర్నికా, సింకోనా, వేప, దతురా, డిజిటాలిస్, రావుల్ఫియా, తులసి మొదలైన ఔషధ విలువలు గల మొక్కల పరిజ్ఞానం, వాటిని మానవుని ఆరోగ్య సంరక్షణ కోసం ఉపయోగించుటలో దోహదపడును.సూక్ష్మజీవనాశక పదార్థాలైన పెనిసిలిన్, జీవకీటకనాశినిలు, స్పైరులినా, క్లోరెల్లా లాంటి ఏకకణ ప్రోటీన్ల ఉత్పత్తి కూడా ఆయా పదార్థాలనిచ్చే మొక్కల విస్తృత అధ్యయనం వల్ల సాధ్యమవుతుంది."},{"question":"Inona no filôzôfian'ny fanabeazana?","answer":"Ny filôzôfian'ny fanabeazana dia mikaroka ireo fitsipika fototra amin'ny fanabeazana."},{"question":"Iza no nahita an'i Amerika tamin'ny 1492?","answer":"Nahita an’i Amerika tamin’ny 1492 i Christophe Colomb, italianina mpikaroka tany amin’ny fanompoana an’i Espaina, nandritra ny diany voalohany."},{"question":"Вена шаары жөнүндө кыскача эмне айта аласың ?","answer":"Вена шаары - вальс ритминде жашаган шаар . Бул жерде тарыхый эстеликтердин топтолушу өтө жогору. Өздөрүндө жүздөн ашык музей бар. Бардык консерватизмге карабастан, заманбап Вена көркөм долбоорлорго жана инновациялык технологияларга ачык.Австрия 🇦🇹"},{"question":"Tụọ ma kọwaa ofu ilu metụtara anwụrụ ọkụ? ","answer":"Ilu metụtara anwụrụ ọkụOzi eziri anwụrụ ọkụ eruola eligwe ntị. Ilu a n'akọwa na ihe ọ bụla e tinyere n'aka onye mara eme ya ezuola oke, nke n'anaghị atụ anya na onye ahụ agaghị emeta ya."},{"question":" Ity misy lahatsoratra : «  Ny hainteny dia amboara teny feno ohatrohatra sy tarehin-teny tsara, ifamalian’ny lehilahy sy ny vehivavy momban’ny fitiavana. Taty aoriana dia tsy voatery ho olon-dro intsony no miangaly ny hainteny fa azon’ny olon-tokana natao, ary mihitatra amin’ny lohahevitra hafa ankoatry ny fitiavana. »Arak’io lahatsoratra io, iza no nifamaly tamin’ny hainteny tamin’ny voalohany ?","answer":"Lehilahy sy vehivavy no nifamaly tamin’ny hainteny tamin’ny voalohany, miresaka momban’ny fitiavana."},{"question":"ఘన బహుపది యొక్క వక్రము X-అక్షాన్ని ఖండించే గరిష్ఠ బిందువుల సంఖ్య ఎంత ?","answer":"3"},{"question":"What is the correct answer to this question: n¿Fue John F. Kennedy el primer presidente de los EE. UU. asesinado mientras estaba en funciones?","answer":"Yes, John F. Kennedy was the first president of the United States to be assassinated while in office."},{"question":"Inona ny antsoina hoe Munroes ? ","answer":"Ny Munroes dia tendrombohitra any Scotland. "},{"question":"Tenha atenção a esta sequência de letras: U D T Q C S S. Será que você consegue descobrir quais são as próximas 3 letras?","answer":"As letras O N D, porque são as iniciais dos números: Um, Dois, Três, Quatro, Cinco, Seis, Sete, Oito, Nove, Dez."},{"question":"તુષાર શુક્લ ની \\"ના તને ખબર પડી, ના મને ખબર પડી\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"ના તને ખબર પડી, ના મને ખબર પડી,કે હું પ્રેમમાં પડ્યો કે તું પ્રેમમાં પડી;કારણમાં આમ કંઈ નહીં બે આંખ બસ લડી,ને તું પ્રેમમાં પડ્યો ને હું પ્રેમમાં પડી.બંનેના દિલ ઘડકતાં હતાં જે જુદાં જુદાં,આ પ્રેમ એટલે કે એને જોડતી કડી;શરમાઈ જતી તોય મને જાણ તો થતી;મારી તરફ તું જે રીતે જોતો ઘડી ઘડી.હૈયુંના રહ્યું ન હાથ, ગયું ઢાળમાં દડી;મેળામાં કોણ કોને ક્યારે ક્યાં ગયું જડી.ઢળતા સૂરજની સામે સમંદરની રેતમાં,બેસી શકે તો બેસ અડોઅડ અડી અડી;મારા વિના ઉદાસ છું એ જાણું છું પ્રિયેમેં પણ વિતાવી કેટલી રાતો રડી રડી.મેં સાચવ્યો ’તો સોળ વરસ જે રૂમાલને;તું આવ્યો જ્યાં નજીકને ત્યાં ઉકલી ગઈ ગડી."},{"question":"Mikä on yersinia?","answer":"Yersiniat ovat eläimissä esiintyviä bakteereja, jotka voivat aiheuttaa ihmiselle suolisto- ja yleisinfektioita. Tärkeimmät ihmisille tautia aiheuttavat yersinialajit ovat Yersinia enterocolitica ja Yersinia pseudotuberculosis."},{"question":"சொற்றொடர் என்றால் என்ன? எ.கா. தருக.","answer":"சொற்கள் பல தொடர்ந்து நின்று பொருள் தரும். இது தொடர் அல்லது சொற்றொடர் எனப்படும். எ.கா: நீர் பருகினான்."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Imisa Maal-Mood Ayuu Rasuulka (NNKH) Joogay Daa’if?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu Joogay 10 Maal-Mood."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Na czym polega efekt Dunninga-Krugera?","answer":"Efekt Dunninga-Krugera polega na tym, że osoby niewykwalifikowane w jakiejś dziedzinie życia mają tendencję do przeceniania swoich umiejętności w tej dziedzinie, podczas gdy osoby wysoko wykwalifikowane mają tendencję do zaniżania oceny swoich umiejętności."},{"question":" ਇੱਕ ਦਰਜਨ ਤੋਂ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਸੰਗੀਤਕ ਅਤੇ ਕੁਝ ਮਲਟੀ ਐਲਬਮਾਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ‘ਚ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਚਰਚਿਤ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਗਾਇਕ ਤੇ ਨਾਇਕ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ‘ਮੇਲ ਕਰਾਦੇ ਰੱਬਾ’ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਇੱਕ ਜ਼ਬਰਦਸਤ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾ ਕੇ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਦੂਜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਜੀਹਨੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਦਿਲ ਲੁੱਟਿਆ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਦੇਸ਼-ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਦਿਲ ਲੁੱਟ ਕੇ ਲੋਕਪ੍ਰਿਅਤਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਿਖ਼ਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੂਹਿਆ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਦਮਦਾਰ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਲੋਹਾ ਮਨਵਾਇਆ। ਬੇਹੱਦ ਸਾਊ ਤੇ ਯਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਯਾਰ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਆਮ ਜੀਵਨ ‘ਚ ਇੱਕ ਸਿੱਧਾ-ਸਾਦਾ, ਹੱਸਮੁੱਖ ਤੇ ਮਿਲਾਪੜੇ ਸੁਭਾਅ ਦਾ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਟਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਕੋਈ ਫੂੰ-ਫਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ, ਉਹ ਫੋਕੀ ਦਿਖਾਵੇਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਛੋਕੜ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਤੇ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰੱਬ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ‘ਚ ਰਾਜੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਫੱਕਰ ਸੁਭਾਅ ਦਾ ਦੇਸੀ ਜੱਟ ਹੈ।ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੌਕ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਨੇ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਆਪਣੀ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਐਲਬਮ ‘ਤਲਵਾਰ’ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਪ੍ਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੁਕਰਾਨਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਵਰਗ ਦਾ ਚਹੇਤਾ ਸਟਾਰ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਬੇਹੱਦ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹਿਤ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ੀਸ਼ ਮਹਿਲ ਪਟਿਆਲਾ ਵਿਖੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ਦੇ ਸੈੱਟ ‘ਤੇ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਹੋਈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਚੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਅੰਸ਼ ਇਹ ਹਨ:ਸਵਾਲ: ਗਿੱਪੀ ਜੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਪਿਛੋਕੜ, ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਤੇ ਜਨਮ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰਾ ਜਨਮ 2 ਜਨਵਰੀ 1982 ਨੂੰ ਪਿਤਾ ਸਵ.ਸ.ਸਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਤੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਮਿੰਦਰ ਕੌਰ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਪਿੰਡ ਕੂੰਮਕਲਾਂ (ਲੁਧਿਆਣਾ) ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਮੁਢਲੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਪਿੰਡ ਤੋਂ, ਕਾਲਜ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਚੰਡੀਗੜ੍ਹ ਤੋਂ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਟਲ ਮੈਨੇਜਮੈਂਟ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਤਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਗਾਇਕੀ ਵੱਲ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਆਏ ਤੇ ਕਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਐਲਬਮਾਂ ਆਈਆਂ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੌਕ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਸੰਨ 2000 ‘ਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਪਲੇਠੀ ਐਲਬਮ ‘ਚੱਕ ਲੈ’, ਦੂਜੀ ‘ਨਸ਼ਾ’ (2001) ਤੇ ਤੀਜੀ ‘ਆਜਾ ਵੇ ਮਿੱਤਰਾ’ (2002) ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਫਲਾਪ ਰਹੀਆਂ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਆਈ ਮੇਰੀ ਚੌਥੀ ਐਲਬਮ ‘ਮੇਲੇ ਮਿੱਤਰਾਂ ਦੇ’ (2003) ਵਿਚਲੇ ਗੀਤ ‘ਮਿੱਤਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਾਦਰੇ ‘ਤੇ ਪਾਦੇ ਮੋਰਨੀ’ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਚਰਚਾ ‘ਚ ਲਿਆਂਦਾ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ‘ਫੁੱਲਕਾਰੀ-2’, ‘ਅੱਖ ਲੜ ਗਈ’, ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦੇ ਛੱਲੇ’, ‘ਯਾਰ ਮੇਰਾ’, ‘ਦੇਸੀ ਰੌਕਸਟਾਰ’, ‘ਤਲਵਾਰ’ (ਧਾਰਮਿਕ), ਗੱਭਰੂ (ਮਲਟੀ), ਯੁਧਵੀਰ ਮਾਣਕ ਨਾਲ, ਮੁੰਡਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸ਼ਰਾਬੀ (ਮਲਟੀ) ਬੋਹਮੀਏ ਨਾਲ ਤੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਬੀਟ (ਮਲਟੀ)-ਹਨੀ ਸਿੰਘ ਨਾਲ ਆਦਿ ਆ ਚੁੱਕੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਨਵੀਂ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਅਮਨ ਖਟਕੜ ਤੇ ਇੰਦਾ ਰਾਏਕੋਟ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹੇਠ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ‘ਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਨਾਇਕਾ ਮੈਂਡੀ ਤੱਖਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ‘ਚ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦੇਵ, ਵੀਨੂੰ ਢਿੱਲੋਂ’ ਬੀ.ਐਨ. ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਤੇ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਹਨੀ ਸਿੰਘ ਆਦਿ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਲੇਖਕ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਬਲਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਿਓ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ‘ਜੱਗ ਜਿਉਂਦਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੇਲੇ’ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਣਾ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। ਵੱਡੇ ਬਜਟ ਨਾਲ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋਈ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ਹਰ ਪੱਖੋਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੇਵਲ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਵਧੀਆ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਸਾਨੂੰ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਉਮੀਦਾਂ ਹਨ ਕਿ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ’ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਕਰੇਗੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਕੀ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪੁਰਾਤਨ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਗਾਥਾ ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ-ਸਾਹਿਬਾ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ‘ਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਨਹੀਂ ਜੀ, ਇਹ ਪੁਰਾਣਾ ਘੋੜਿਆਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਸਗੋਂ ਨਵੇਂ ਯੁੱਗ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਐਕਸ਼ਨ ਲਵ ਸਟੋਰੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਿਰਜ਼ੇ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਹੈ। ਬਾਕੀ ਅਜੇ ਸਸਪੈਂਸ ਹੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਦਿਓ? ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾਤਰ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਕੈਨੇਡਾ ‘ਚ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਥੋੜ੍ਹਾ-ਥੋੜ੍ਹਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ‘ਚ ਸ਼ੂਟ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ 6 ਅਪਰੈਲ 2012 ਨੂੰ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਐਲਬਮ ਕਦੋਂ ਕੁ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਤਾਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਰੱਝਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਪੰਜ ਗੀਤ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਹਨੀ ਸਿੰਘ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਫਰਵਰੀ ‘ਚ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਨਵੀਂ ਐਲਬਮ ਤਾਂ 2013 ‘ਚ ਹੀ ਦੇਵਾਂਗੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਤੇ ਦਿਲਜੀਤ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ‘ਗੁੱਗੂ-ਯੋਗਰਾਜ’ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਵਾਂਗ ਹਿੱਟ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, ਕੀ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਕੋਈ ਨਵੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਹਾਂ, ਦਿਲਜੀਤ ਨਾਲ ਜਲਦੀ ਹੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਾਂਗੇ ਪਰ ਅਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਹੋਰ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ ਤੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ‘ਚ ਕੀ ਯੋਜਨਾ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਆ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਮੈਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਸੋਚ-ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਸਾਈਨ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਬਾਰੇ ਅਜੇ ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੋਚਿਆ। ਹਾਂ 2012 ‘ਚ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਗੀਤ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ 2013 ‘ਚ ਬਤੌਰ ਹੀਰੋ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵੀ ਆ ਜਾਵੇ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਗਾਇਕੀ ਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਕੀ-ਕੀ ਸ਼ੌਕ ਹਨ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਯਾਰਾਂ-ਬੇਲੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਤੇ ਘਰ ਆਰਾਮ ਕਰਨਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਤਮੰਨਾ ਜੋ ਪੂਰੀ ਨਾ ਹੋਈ ਹੋਵੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਵਾਹਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕੋਈ ਘਾਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਛੱਡੀ ਪਰ (ਭਾਵੁਕ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ) ਮੇਰੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਜੀ ਦੀ ਕਮੀ ਕਦੇ ਵੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੁਪਨਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਸਟਾਰ ਬਣਾਂ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਟਾਰ ਬਣਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਚਲੇ ਗਏ। ਅੱਜ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਬੜੀ ਘਾਟ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਅਜੋਕੀ ਮਾਰਧਾੜ ਵਾਲੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਵੀਰ ਜੋ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ ਚਲਦਾ। ਸਮੇਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੀਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਬਦਲਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ‘ਚ ਕੌਣ-ਕੌਣ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਰਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਜੀ, ਵੱਡਾ ਭਰਾ ਸਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਫੈਮਿਲੀ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਰਵਨੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਤੇ ਦੋ ਬੇਟੇ ਏਕਮਕਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਤੇ ਗੁਰਫ਼ਤਿਹ ਸਿੰਘ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਮੁਹਾਲੀ ‘ਚ ਰਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਹਾਂ। ਬਾਕੀ ਪਿੰਡ ਵੀ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਅਖੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਸਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਦਿਓਗੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਸਾਰੇ ਚਾਹੁਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਵੱਡਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਤਿਕਾਰ ਕਰੋ। ਚੰਗਾ ਸੁਣੋ ਤੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਮਾੜਾ ਨਾ ਕਰੋ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਗਿੱਪੀ ਗਰੇਵਾਲ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ‘ਮੇਲ ਕਰਾਦੇ ਰੱਬਾ’ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਇੱਕ ਜ਼ਬਰਦਸਤ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾ ਕੇ ਕੀਤੀ।"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: മലയാളത്തിലെ ആദ്യത്തെ സംസാരചിത്രം ഏതാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"1938-ൽ പുറത്തിറങ്ങിയ ബാലനാണ് മലയാളത്തിലെ ആദ്യ സംസാരചിത്രം. മുതുകുളം രാഘവൻ പിള്ളയുടെ തിരക്കഥയും ഗാനങ്ങളും രചിച്ച് എസ്. നൊട്ടാണിയാണ് സംവിധാനം ചെയ്തത്."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia. \\"Never ask a question like that!\\", said her mother. Then she walked off, frowning.Terjemahan:","answer":"Penggalan teks berbahasa Inggris tersebut, apabila diterjemahkan ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia adalah sebagai berikut:\\"Jangan pernah menanyakan hal itu!\\", kata ibunya. Lalu dia berjalan pergi sambil mengerutkan kening."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn pa ọlọpaa kan, wọn ji ikeji ẹ atawọn eeyan mẹta mi-in gbe l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Njẹ ẹ ti gbọ? Pe awọn agbebọnrin, ajinigbe, ti fi kun ọwọ ija wọn wayi, niṣe ni wọn pa ọlọpaa kan l’Ọjọruu, ọjọ karun-un, oṣu karun-un yii, niluu Abẹokuta. Wọn ji ọlọpaa keji ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ gbe pẹlu awọn eeyan mẹta mi-in wọgbo lọ.Koda, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe wọn pa ọlọpaa naa loootọ, wọn si gbe ikeji ẹ atawọn mẹta mi-in wọgbo lọ ni Ibara-Orile, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Abẹokuta.Ohun ti a gbọ ni pe awọn tọkọ-taya kan ni wọn fẹẹ bẹrẹ oṣin ẹja, wọn si lọ si ileeṣẹ to n ri si eto ọgbin l’Abẹokuta, lẹka ti wọn ti n mojuto ẹja sinsin.Ileeṣẹ yii fun wọn ni oṣiṣẹ wọn kan to kọṣẹ mọṣẹ, pe ko mu wọn lọ sibi ti wọn le lo lati bẹrẹ okoowo wọn. Awọn tọkọ-taya naa beere fun ọlọpaa to le daabo bo wọn bi wọn ba n lọ, a gbọ pe wọn si fun wọn ni ọlọpaa meji.Afi bi wọn ṣe de Ibara-Orile ti oko naa wa ti awọn agbebọn kọ lu wọn. Wọn kọkọ yinbọn fun ọlọpaa kan, wọn pa a, wọn si gbe ẹni keji ẹ pẹlu awọn tọkọ-taya naa wọgbo lọ. Wọn gbe oṣiṣẹ ẹka imọ ẹja ti ileeṣẹ ijọba ni ko mu wọn lọ pẹlu.Ṣugbọn  o, Alukoro ọlọpaa Ogun sọ pe iṣẹlẹ yii ni ọwọ kan araale ninu, o ni biku ile ko ba pa ni, tode ko le pa ni. Oyeyẹmi ni wọn dena de awọn eeyan ti wọn kọ lu yii ni.O lawọn to pa ọlọpaa ko ni i foju kan oorun mọ, wọn ti daran. O fi kun un pe awọn ti wa lẹnu ẹ bayii, awọn yoo mu wọn ṣinkun, awọn yoo si gba awọn ti wọn ko pamọ kalẹ lọwọ wọn."},{"question":"'තරු සහිත රාත්‍රිය' සිතුවම් කළේ කවුද?","answer":"වින්සන්ට් වැන් ගොග්"},{"question":"Qual é a principal fonte de alimentação das abelhas?","answer":"Quase todas as espécies de abelhas têm o néctar e no pólen das flores como principal fonte de alimentação, que fornecem, respectivamente, energia e proteínas. Existem 3 espécies carnívoras de abelhas (Trigona hypogea, T. crassipes e T. necrophaga) que digerem carne e outros tecidos animais, em vez de pólen."},{"question":"ਯਮਦਰੋਕ ਝੀਲ ਬਾਰੇ ਦਸੋ। ","answer":"ਯਮਦਰੋਕ ਝੀਲ, ਯਮਦਰੋਕ ਯੁਮਸੋ ਜਾਂ ਯਮਜ਼ੋ ਯੁਮਕੋ ਤਿੱਬਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਤਾਜ਼ੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਝੀਲ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਤਿੱਬਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀਆਂ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਝੀਲਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ। ਇਹ 72 km (45 mi) ਲੰਬਾ ਹੈ। ਝੀਲ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਬਰਫ਼ ਨਾਲ ਢਕੇ ਹੋਏ ਪਹਾੜਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਘਿਰੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਛੋਟੀਆਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਖੁਆਈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਝੀਲ ਦੇ ਦੂਰ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਸਿਰੇ 'ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਆਊਟਲੈਟ ਸਟ੍ਰੀਮ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦੇ ਰੰਗ ਕਾਰਨ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਫਿਰੋਜ਼ੀ ਹੈ। ਲਗਭਗ 90 km (56 mi) ਝੀਲ ਦੇ ਪੱਛਮ ਵੱਲ ਤਿੱਬਤੀ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਗਿਆਂਸੇ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਲਹਾਸਾ 100 km (62 mi) ਉੱਤਰ-ਪੂਰਬ ਵੱਲ ਹੈ। ਸਥਾਨਕ ਮਿਥਿਹਾਸ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, ਯਮਦੋਕ ਯੁਮਸੋ ਝੀਲ ਇੱਕ ਦੇਵੀ ਦਾ ਰੂਪਾਂਤਰ ਹੈ। "},{"question":"கேள்வி :மகாபலிபுரத்தில் ஒரே கல்லில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட ரதங்கள் எத்தனை உள்ளன?அ. 2ஆ. 3இ. 5ஈ. 19","answer":"பதில் :இ. 5"},{"question":"اشرح ما هي اللعبة ذات المجموع الصفري zero-sum games؟ ","answer":"اللعبة ذات المجموع الصفري هي نوع من الألعاب حيث يسبب ربح شخص ما خسارة لشخص آخر. وهذا يعني أن الفائدة الإجمالية أو المكافأة من اللعبة ثابتة، وأن أي مكسب للاعب سيؤدي إلى خسارة مقابلة لجميع اللاعبين الآخرين."},{"question":"இந்திய பாராளுமன்றத்தில் \\" இந்திய குடியுரிமைச் சட்டம்\\" இயற்றப்பட்ட ஆண்டு எது?","answer":"குடியுரிமைச் சட்டம், மக்களுக்கு இந்திய குடியுரிமை வழங்குவதற்காக 1955 ஆம் ஆண்டு இயற்றப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Volana inona no natokana ho an'ny fiteny malagasy?","answer":"Volana natokana ho an' ny fiteny malagasy ny volana Jona, ka ny Akademia Malagasy sy ny Ministera misahana ny kolontsaina no mikarakara ny fankalazana azy. "},{"question":"السؤال: من هو مخترع القطار البخاري ؟","answer":"الإجابة: جورج ستيفنسون ، ريتشارد تريفيثيك"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أصغر كوكب؟","answer":"الإجابة: هايجيا"},{"question":"Zer da fotosintesia?","answer":"Fotosintesia landare, algak eta zenbait bakteriak argiaren energia erabiltzeko duten prozesu kimikoa da, karbono dioxidoa eta ura azukreetan eraldatzeko."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ දිගම ගංගාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"නයිල්"},{"question":"முகிலனை எதற்காக அனைவரும் பாராட்டினர்?","answer":"முகிலன் பயன்படுத்தித் தூக்கி எறியப்பட்ட மின்னணுப் பொருள்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி நெடிதுயர்ந்த அரக்க வடிவில் ஓர் உருவத்தைப் படைத்தான். அது சுற்றுச்சூழல் மாசு அடைவது பற்றியும் அதற்கு மக்கள்தான் காரணம் என்றும் பேசுவது போல் அமைத்திருந்தான்.இப்படைப்பினால், அந்த ஆண்டிற்கான சிறந்த அறிவியல் படைப்புக்குரிய விருது, முகிலனது பள்ளிக்குக் கிடைத்தது.ஆதலால் மாணவர்களும், ஆசிரியர்களும், தலைமையாசிரியரும் முகிலனின் புதுமையான படைப்பைப் பாராட்டி மகிழ்ந்தனர்."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة الملقبة بقلب القرآن؟","answer":"الإجابة: يس"},{"question":"«Заманбап физиканын атасы» деп таанылган жана салыштырмалуулук теориясын түзгөн ким?","answer":"Жооп: Альберт Эйнштейн \\"Заманбап физиканын атасы\\" катары белгилүү жана өзүнүн салыштырмалуулук теориясы менен белгилүү."},{"question":"બેબી એટી મધરબોર્ડ્સ એટલે શું?","answer":"મધરબોર્ડ્સમાં બેબી એટીટી અને એટીનું સંયોજન છે. તેમાં બંને સ્લોટ ટાઇપ પ્રોસેસર સોકેટ્સ અને પીજીએ પ્રોસેસર સોકેટ્સ, એસડી રામ સ્લોટ અને ડીડીઆર રામ સ્લોટ્સ, પીસીઆઈ સ્લોટ અને ઇસાનો સ્લોટ્સ, 12 પિન પાવર કનેક્ટર અને 20 પિન પાવર કનેક્ટર અને પોર્ટ્સ છે.દા.ત .: પેન્ટિયમ-III અને પેન્ટિયમ -4"},{"question":"Nyatakan jenis peribahasa bagi peribahasa berikut:\\"Seperti pungguk rindukan bulan\\"","answer":"Peribahasa jenis perumpamaan"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Lợi ích thật sự của vật dụng thường thấy trên giường ở khách sạn: Không chỉ để trang trí","answer":"Thông thường, khi lưu trú tại những khách sạn, khu nghỉ dưỡng, những vật dụng thiết yếu trong phòng có thể kể tới như giường ngủ, tủ quần áo, bàn trang điểm, bàn uống trà hay những chiếc ghế cuối giường,... Tuy nhiên, có một số vật dụng trên giường khác mà nhiều người vẫn chưa biết chính xác tác dụng của chúng là gì. Đó chính là những chiếc ghế vuông và tấm vải được trải ngang ở cuối giường. Trên các trang mạng xã hội, vấn đề này gây ra một cuộc tranh cãi với nhiều ý kiến khác nhau. Đa số mọi người đều nghĩ rằng, mục đích của những vật dụng này đơn thuần chỉ là trang trí. \\"Để in logo của khách sạn, khu nghỉ dưỡng cho đẹp thôi.\\" \\"Chỉ để trang trí thôi chứ làm gì có tác dụng gì.\\" \\"Gối thì chắc để ôm còn cái tấm vải trải ngang chắc để trang trí.\\" Tuy nhiên trên thực tế, nó lại không hề đơn giản như vậy. Từ những chiếc gối vuông cho đến tấm khăn trải giường, chúng đều có những tác dụng nhất định, phục vụ cho mục đích của người dùng. Thông thường trên một chiếc giường tại các khách sạn, khu nghỉ dưỡng, sẽ có tổng cộng từ 3 - 4 chiếc gối. Chúng bao gồm: 2 chiếc gối nằm hình chữ nhật và 1 hoặc 2 chiếc gối hình vuông. Đây là một cách sắp xếp có dụng ý chứ không hề vô nghĩa. Những chiếc gối vuông được đặt thêm vào mang một ý nghĩa vì sức khỏe của người nằm. Giấc ngủ rất quan trọng đối với con người, là thời gian vàng để cơ thể nghỉ ngơi và tái tạo năng lượng. Chiếc gối chính là một trong những phần quan trọng nhất quyết định chất lượng của giấc ngủ. Bên cạnh gối nằm, theo các nhà khoa học, cần đặt gối dưới chân để giúp các cơ bắp được thoải mái, đảm bảo máu lưu thông tốt nhất. Và những chiếc gối vuông chính là để thực hiện nhiệm vụ này, chứ không phải để sử dụng làm gối ôm hay trang trí như nhiều người vẫn thường lầm tưởng. Những lúc chưa nằm, ta cũng có thể tận dụng những chiếc gối vuông để tựa lưng khi xem tivi, đọc sách, lướt điện thoại. Một số lưu ý khác khi sử dụng gối để tốt cho sức khỏe đó là gối nằm không được quá cao cũng không được quá thấp. Theo các nghiên cứu, nếu gối quá cao, bạn có nguy cơ mắc các bệnh về xương, đặc biệt là có thể gây thoái hóa đốt sống cổ, giãn cột sống. Nếu bạn nằm gối mà cằm bị ép xuống dưới cổ tức là bạn đang dùng gối quá cao. Còn nếu gối quá thấp và đặt gối sâu xuống lưng, đầu bạn sẽ bị ngẩng ngược lại đằng sau. Lúc ấy bạn có nguy cơ bị vẹo cột sống và trào ngược dịch trong quá trình hô hấp. Vì vậy, từ chiếc gối nằm hay chiếc gối vuông, bạn nên sử dụng chúng đúng cách, đúng mục đích để đem lại giấc ngủ ngon giấc nhất. Một vật dụng nữa cũng thường xuyên được bắt gặp tại các phòng khách sạn, khu nghỉ dưỡng. Đó là tấm vải, khăn trải ngang giường. Tác dụng thật sự của vật dụng này đó là ngăn không cho bụi hay các chất bẩn dính vào chăn và ga giường. Các chất bẩn có thể kể tới là thức ăn hay vết giày, dép. Nhiều người có thói quen sử dụng đồ ăn, thức uống ở trên giường hay khi nằm, đặt cả giày lên giường. Những việc làm này rất dễ dẫn đến tình trạng đổ hoặc vương thức ăn, làm bẩn ga trải giường, nhất là loại màu trắng tinh. Do đó, trong mỗi lần ăn vặt, uống trà hay thậm chí là ăn sáng tại giường, bạn nên sử dụng tấm khăn này để tránh đồ ăn, thức uống có thể làm bẩn ga giường. Các bụi bẩn khác nữa là bụi trong không khí, bụi từ ba lô, va li hay túi xách khi khách đặt trực tiếp lên giường. Tấm khăn trải sẽ như một vật cách ly, lớp ngăn phần nào vi khuẩn, bụi bẩn từ những đồ đạc như thế lên ga giường. Nhờ có nó, việc vệ sinh ga gối cũng trở nên dễ dàng hơn. Thông thường, chiếc chiếc gối vuông và tấm khăn trải trên giường sẽ có màu sắc tương đồng với nhau. Sự kết hợp này giúp tăng sự đẹp mắt, thẩm mỹ cho cả không gian phòng. Giờ thì bạn đã hiểu rõ tác dụng của những chiếc gối vuông hay tấm khăn trải thường thấy trên giường khách sạn. Vì vậy, hãy lưu ý để sử dụng chúng thật đúng mục đích nhé. Không chỉ ở khách sạn, bạn cũng có thể áp dụng các phương pháp kê gối dưới chân khi ngủ hoặc trang bị tấm khăn trải ngăn bụi trên giường ngay tại nhà mình. Bởi chúng đều vô cùng đơn giản, dễ dàng và mang lại lợi ích tốt cho cuộc sống con người."},{"question":"inona ny lokon'ny akondro ?","answer":"ny lokon'ny akondro dia mavo"},{"question":"Кан таламай деген оюн кандай болот?","answer":"Кан таламай деген оюн мындай болот. Бир топ бала чогулуп алып бир чүкөнүже бир саканы кан деп коет. Ал канга кошуп көп чүкөнү калчашат. Ал чүкөнүкалчаган бала эки бүгө, эки чиге, эки таа, эки алчы болсо бирин бирине атып ала берет. Ал бала атып жатып тийгизе албай же башка чүкөлөргө тийгизип койсо жыдып калат. Жана калчаган бала дагы ошондой тартип менен ала берет. Баякы атып жаткан балдар канча чүкө атса дагы өзүмдүк кылып ала беришет. Кан атып алганы байып калгандай бөлүп турат. Кайсы бир бала жалгыз чүкөнү да атып ала албай тура берет. Эгерде кан алчы түшсө алчы менен атып алат, таа түшсө таа менен, бүгө түшсө бүгө менен, чиге түшсө чиге менен атып ала берет.Канды кандай учурда атып алса да боло берет. Чүкө атып олтуруп баардыгыбүткөндөн кийин ар бир бала чүкөлөрүн санап көрүп, эң аз чүкө алып калганбаланын чүкөсүнө өлчөп салып калчашат. Анда канды атып алган бала кандыжолдошу менен чүкөнүн санатынан башка кылып салат. Калчашаарда анда такыр чүкө албай калган бала оюнга кирбей гана томсоруп олтура берет. Берки чүкө алган балдар калчашып жатканда кан таа түшүп калса сак болуп турган балдар жалпы эле чачылып жаткан чүкөнү талап киришет. Анда кай бирлери көбүн талап алып коет. Баякы чүкөнү көп атып алгандагы көп талап алып байып калат.Кээ бир балдар ошол кан талашмайда дагы жакшы талап ала албай куру калат.Ошентип баякы көп чүкөнүн барын кайсы бала алса ошол бала уткан болупэсептелип берки балдардан кош камчы, бөлчөй, төө матек окшогон сайганбайгесин балдардан алып көтөрүлүп калат. Кандын алчы бүгө, чиге түшкөнү жай оюн болуп атып ойноло берет. Анда канды атып алган бала канды жолдошу менен чүкөнүн сапатынан башка таа түшүп калганда гана талашакей болуп, балдарды тытыштырып салат. Кандын таа түшкөнү кандын жаңылганы деп билинет."},{"question":"Indícame cuál es el evento más importante mencionado en el siguiente texto: \\"Además, se alzó con el Campeonato Sudamericano Sub-20 de 2009, en el que marcó 2 goles. Tiempo más tarde brillo en la Copa Mundial de Fútbol Sub-20 de 2009, donde fue elegido como Balón de Bronce. En este torneo fue el capitán de Brasil, jugó 6 partidos y anotó un gol.\\"","answer":"La Copa Mundial de Fútbol Sub-20 del 2009. "},{"question":"பாடல் அடிகளில் இரண்டாம் எழுத்து ஒன்றுபோல் வரும் (எதுகை) சொற்களை எடுத்து எழுதுக.","answer":"அடிஎதுகை :கொட்டுங்கடி – எட்டுஊழி – ஆழிபொய் – மெய்சீர் எதுகை :எட்டுங்கடி – எட்டிடவேஆழி – அழியாமலே"},{"question":"பிடல் காஸ்ட்ரோவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":" கியூபாவை சேர்ந்த பொதுவுடைமைப் புரட்சியாளரும் பொதுவுடைமை அரசியல்வாதியும் ஆவார்.வரலாறு என்னை விடுதலை செய்யும்.பிடல் காஸ்ட்ரோ (Fidel Alejandro Castro Ruz, (எசுப்பானியம்: [fiˈðel ˈkastro], ஆகஸ்ட் 13, 1926 - நவம்பர் 25, 2016) கியூபாவை சேர்ந்த பொதுவுடைமைப் புரட்சியாளரும் பொதுவுடைமை அரசியல்வாதியும் ஆவார். கியூபாவில் 1959 இல் புரட்சியை வழிநடத்தி புல்ஜென்சியோ பாட்டிஸ்ட்டாவின் அரசை வீழ்த்தி தலைமை அமைச்சர் பொறுப்பை ஏற்ற காஸ்ட்ரோ ,1959 முதல் 1976 வரை கியூபாவின் பிரதமராகவும், 1976 முதல் 2008 வரை ஜனாதிபதியாகவும் பொறுப்பு வகித்தார்.கூபாவின் பொதுவுடைமைக் கட்சியின் முதல் செயலாளராக 1965 இல் பதவியேற்ற இவர் கூபாவை ஒற்றைக் கட்சி சமூகவுடைமைக் குடியரசாக்கினார். 49 ஆண்டுகள் கியூபாவை ஆண்ட காஸ்ட்ரோ பிப்ரவரி 24 2008 அன்று பதவியிலிருந்து விலகினார். உலகத்தில் நீண்ட காலத்துக்கு தலைமைப் பொறுப்பில் இருந்த தலைவர் காஸ்ட்ரோ மட்டுமே. பன்னாட்டளவில், காஸ்ட்ரோ 1979-ல் இருந்து 1983 வரை மற்றும் 2006 முதல் 2008 வரை, அணி சேரா இயக்கத்தின் பொதுச் செயலாளராக இருந்துள்ளார்.[2]அமெரிக்காவில் இருந்து 93 மைல் தொலைவில் இருந்தாலும் கியூபாவை ஒரு சோசலிச நாடாகப் பேணிய பெருமை இவரைச் சாரும். இதைவிட ருசியா-அமெரிக்க பனிப்போர் நடந்த வேளையில் இவர் ருசியாவிற்குச் சாதகமாகப் பல பணிகளைச் செய்தார்."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي السوره اللي ما فيهاش البسمله فالاول ؟","answer":"الإجابة: سوره التوبه وكاتسمى كذلك براءه"},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ awọn Fulani mẹta pẹlu nnkan ija oloro l’Akurẹ","answer":"Ọwọ ileesẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo ti tẹ awọn Fulani mẹta ti wọn ka awọn nnkan ija oloro ati oogun abẹnu gọngọ mọ lọwọ l’Akurẹ.Awọn mẹtẹẹta ọhun, Salisu Abdullahi, Mamuda Adamu àti Tijani Alilu, ni wọn dibọn bi awọn to n fi ọmọlanke sa panti kaakiri adugbo kọwọ too tẹ wọn lagbegbe Ala, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Akurẹ, laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Salisu atawọn ẹmẹwa rẹ la gbọ pe wọn ha sọwọ awọn ọlọpaa tesan Ọda, lasiko ti wọn n ṣayẹwo awọn ọkọ ati ọkada to n gba agbegbe Ala kọja.Ọkada ti wọn gun lawọn agbofinro naa kọkọ da duro, ibi tí wọn si ti n tú ẹru to wa ninu ọmọlanke tí wọn de sẹyin ni wọn ti ṣalabaapade awọn nnkan ija oloro ati ọpọlọpọ oogun laarin awọn panti ti wọn ko sinu rẹ.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, Alukoro ileesẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo, Tee-Leo, Ikoro ni awọn tọwọ tẹ ọhun ko ti i ri alaye to nitumọ ṣe lori awọn nnkan ija oloro tí wọn ba ni ikawọ wọn."},{"question":"A palavra computação tem quantas sílabas?","answer":"A palavra computação tem 4 sílabas: com-pu-ta-ção."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Tollina \\"Tollien\\" Wilhelmina Schuurman, född 20 januari 1913 i Zorgvlied, Drenthe, Nederländerna; död 29 januari 1994 i Apeldoorn, Gelderland; var en","answer":"nederländsk friidrottare med kortdistanslöpning som huvudgren. Schuurman blev silvermedaljör vid den III.e damolympiaden 1930 och var en pionjär inom damidrott."},{"question":"පළමු ලෝක යුද්ධය ආරම්භ කරමින් , මුලින්ම සටන්බිමට පිවිසි රටවල් දෙක මොනවාද ?","answer":"ඔස්ට්‍රෝ -හන්ගේරියාව සර්බියාව ආක්‍රමණය කිරිම"},{"question":"السؤال: كيف نزل القرآن الكريم على رسول الله صلّى الله عليه وسلّم؟","answer":"الجواب: نزل مفرّقًا بواسطة الوحي جبريل عليه السلام."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'berteras keluar bagai pimping'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tampak di luar sahaja bagus (kaya dan lain-lain) tetapi sebenarnya melarat"},{"question":"කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කොටස් වෙළෙඳපොළ යනු කොටස් ගැනුම්කරුවන් සහ විකුණුම්කරුවන්ගේ එකතුවකි. කොටස් වෙලඳපොලවල් රාජ්‍ය හා පෞද්ගලික යන දෙකෙහිම කොටස් ඇතුලත් විය හැක."},{"question":"TRAI વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"TRAI નું પુરુનામ : Telecom Regulatory Authority of India છે.તેની સ્થાપના 1997માં થઈ હતી.TRAIનું મુખ્ય મથક નવી દિલ્લીમાં છે.ટ્રાઈ (TRAI) એ એક વૈધાતિક (નિયમનકારી) સંસ્થા છે.  TRAI ટેલિકોમ ક્ષેત્રે કાર્યરત સંસ્થા છે."},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් කටුමාන  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කාටුව එකතු කිරීමට යොදා ගන්නා උපකරන"},{"question":"Tulis tebak-tebakan lucu","answer":"Burung apa yang suka menolak?Burung gakgak"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు భావం రాయండిశా. ‘ఓపామీ ! యిటువంటి కొండ దరిలో నొంటిం జులుల్ సింగవగాసింబెట్టెడి కుట్ర నట్టడవిలోఁ, గట్టువ్వీ క్రీనీడ, నే ,యాసంగట్టితి వేడిగడ్డ నిలు ? నీ వాలకొన్నచో కూడు నీచేసుట్టంబులు దెచ్చి పెట్టెదరు ? వీకిందేటికే లింగమా !","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :ఓసామీ = ఓస్వామీఇటువంటి = ఇట్టికొండదరి = కొండగుహలోఒంటన్ = ఒంటరిగా ఉంటూపులుల్ = పులులుసింగముల్ = సింహములుగాసింబెట్టెడు = బాధపెట్టుకుట్ర = భయంకరమైనవట్టడవిలో = అరణ్యమధ్యములోకలువ్వి = రావిచెట్టుక్రీవీడ = క్రింది నీడలోఏటిగడ్డన్ = నది ఒడ్డున (సువర్ణముఖి నది)ఆసన్ = ఏ కోరికతోఇలు = గృహము, దేవాలయముకట్టితివి = నిర్మించావునీవు = నీకుఆకొన్నచో = ఆకలిచెందితేకూడునీళ్ళు = ఆహారం, నీరుఏ చుట్టంబులు = ఏబంధువులుతెచ్చి = తీసుకొచ్చిపెట్టెదరు = ఇస్తారునీకున్ = నీకు (శివుడు)ఇందు = ఈ ప్రదేశంలోఏటికే = ఎందుకుండుటలింగమా = ఓ శివలింగమా.భావం :ఓ స్వామీ యిటువంటి కొండపై గుహలో ఒంటరిగా పులులు, సింహములు బాధపెట్టు భయంకరమైన అరణ్యమధ్యంలో రావిచెట్టు నీడన నది ఒడ్డున, ఏ కోరికతో గుడి నిర్మించావు ? నీకు ఆకలి అయినచో ఏ బంధువులు అన్న పానీయములు తెచ్చి యిస్తారు. నువ్వు ఇక్కడ ఎందుకుండాలి లింగమా అని భావం. తిన్నడి ప్రశ్నలలో అతనిలోని నిర్మలత్వం, అమాయకత్వం అతనిలోని ముగ్ధ భక్తిని తెలియజేస్తున్నాయి."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn ti tun ji agbẹ mi-in gbe lọ ni Kwara ","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Monde, ọṣẹ yii, ni awọn agbebọn to dihamọra pẹlu ibọn ati awọn ohun ija oloro tun ji agbẹ kan, Alaaji Ẹlẹfọ, gbe lọ ninu oko rẹ to wa niluu Ballah, nijọba ibilẹ Asa, nipinlẹ Kwara.Iroyin to tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ ni pe ni nnkan bii aago mẹta ọsan ọjọ Aje, Monde, ọṣẹ yii, ni awọn ajinigbe ọhun ya bo oko arakunrin naa, ti wọn si n rọjo ibọn kikankikan. Lasiko naa ni wọn ji agbẹ yii gbe lọ patapata.Awọn olugbe agbegbe naa sọ pe ṣe ni awọn gbọ iro ibọn to n dun leralera, ti ibẹrubojo si gba gbogbo ọkan awọn olugbe agbegbe naa. Titi di igba ta a n ko iroyin yii jọ, wọn o ti i gbọ mo ko o Alaaji Ẹlẹfọ ti wọn ji gbe, ṣugbọn awọn ẹṣọ alaabo Vigilante ati ọlọpaa ti bẹrẹ si i lepa awọn ajinigbe ọhun."},{"question":"من هو صاحب الهجرات الثلاث؟","answer":"\\tأبو موسى الأشعري رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ--ਇਹ  ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਗੋਪੀਚੰਦ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਅਕੈਡਮੀ, ਹੈਦਰਾਬਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਲੈਂਦਾਹੈ। ਉਹ ਇਸ ਵੇਲੇ (27 ਅਗਸਤ, 2014 ਤੱਕ) ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਰਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੀਜਾ ਦਰਜਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਸੌਰਭ ਵਰਮਾ ਦਾ ਭਰਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਗੋ ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਫਾਉਂਡੇਸ਼ਨ, ਬੰਗਲੌਰ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਮਰਥਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ 2012 ਤੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਾਲਰਸ਼ਿਪ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। == ਕਰੀਅਰ ===== 2011 ===ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਲਖਨਊ, ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਯੋਜਿਤ ਏਸ਼ੀਅਨ ਜੂਨੀਅਰ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ, 2011 ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦਾ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਉਸਨੇ 2011 ਦੀਆਂ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਮੰਡਲ ਯੁਵਕ ਖੇਡਾਂ, ਆਈਲ ਆਫ ਮੈਨ ਦੇ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਲੇਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੀ ਜ਼ੁਲਫਾਦਲੀ ਜ਼ੁਲਕੀਫਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਹਾਰ ਕੇ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਸਿੰਗਲਜ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦਾ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ।=== 2012 ===ਜੈਪੁਰ ਵਿੱਚ 36 ਵੀਂ ਜੂਨੀਅਰ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਲੜਕਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਿੰਗਲਜ਼ ਅੰਡਰ -19 ਵਰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿੱਤ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸੇ ਸਾਲ ਵਰਮਾ ਵੀ ਇਰਾਨ ਓਪਨ ਦੇ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।=== 2013 ===2013 ਵਿੱਚ, ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਖਿਤਾਬ  ਜਿੱਤਿਆ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਸਨੇ ਬਹਿਰੀਨ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਸੀਰੀਜ਼ ਅਤੇ ਬਹਿਰੀਨ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਚੈਲੇਂਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੁਰਸ਼ ਸਿੰਗਲਜ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿੱਤ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ।=== 2014 ===ਸਾਲ 2012 ਅਤੇ 2013 ਵਿਚ ਲੜ ਰਹੇ ਸੱਟਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਰਮਾ 2014 ਵਿਚ ਬਰੇਲੀ ਵਿਚ ਆਲ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਰੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ, 2014 ਜਿੱਤ ਕੇ ਜ਼ਬਰਦਸਤ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕੀਤੀ।=== 2016 ===ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਨੀਵਾਰ 26 ਨਵੰਬਰ, 2016 ਨੂੰ ਹਾਂਗਕਾਂਗ ਓਪਨ ਸੁਪਰ ਸੀਰੀਜ਼ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਦੇ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਲਈ ਸਿੱਧੇ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਦੀ ਤੀਜੇਨੰਬਰ  ਜਨ ਓ ਜੋਰਗੇਸਨ ਨੂੰ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਰੋਮਾਂਚਕ ਮੈਚ ਵਿਚ ਡੈੱਨਮਾਰਕੀ ਸਟਾਲਵਰਟ ਨੂੰ 21-19, 24-22 ਨਾਲ ਹਰਾਇਆ। === 2017 ===ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਜਨਵਰੀ 2017 ਵਿਚ ਸੈਯਦ ਮੋਦੀ ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ ਵਿਚ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਈਪ੍ਰਨੀਤ ਨੂੰ 21-19 21-16 ਨਾਲ ਹਰਾਇਆ। ਉਸਨੇ ਉਸੇ ਟੂਰਨਾਮੈਂਟ ਦੇ ਕੁਆਰਟਰ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਉੱਚ ਰੈਂਕ ਦੇ ਹੰਸ-ਕ੍ਰਿਸਟਨ ਵਿਟਿੰਗਸ ਨੂੰ ਹਰਾਇਆ। === 2018 ===ਸਾਲ 2018 ਵਿਚ, ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਵਿਚ ਜਨ ਜੋਰਗੇਨਸਨ (21-15,21-13) ਨੂੰ ਹਰਾ ਕੇ ਸਵਿਸ ਓਪਨ ਦਾ ਖਿਤਾਬ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿਚ ਇਸੇ ਸਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਉਸਨੇ ਹੈਦਰਾਬਾਦ ਓਪਨ ਵੀ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ; ਨਵੰਬਰ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਖ਼ਿਤਾਬ ਦਾ ਬਚਾਅ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇਕ ਸੁਪਰ 100 ਈਵੈਂਟ ਨੇ 2018 ਦੇ ਸਯਦ ਮੋਦੀ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਚੈਂਪੀਅਨਸ਼ਿਪ (ਸੁਪਰ 300) ਵਿਚ ਲੂ ਗੁਆਂਗਜ਼ੂ ਨੂੰ 16-21,21-19,21-14 ਨਾਲ ਹਰਾਇਆ। ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਸੁਪਰ 300 ਈਵੈਂਟ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸਿਰਲੇਖ ਪੂਰਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ, ਸਮੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਨੇ ਗੁਆਂਗਜ਼ੂ ਵਿਚ, ਬੀ.ਡਬਲਯੂ.ਐਫ. ਵਰਲਡ ਟੂਰ ਫਾਈਨਲਜ਼ 2018 ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਯੋਗਤਾ ਦੀ ਪੁਸ਼ਟੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਯੋਗਤਾ ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿਚ 7 ਵੇਂ ਸਥਾਨ 'ਤੇ ਖੜ੍ਹੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਥੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਿਰਫ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੇ 8 ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਨਿਰੰਤਰ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹਨ। ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਦੇ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਤਾਜ ਲਈ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਅਤੇ 1.5 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ ਦਾ ਤਾਜ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਦੀ ਦੌੜ ਹੈ। == ਨਿੱਜੀ ==ਵਰਮਾ ਇਕ ਹੇਠਲੇ-ਮੱਧ-ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਪੇ ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਧਾਰ ਜ਼ਿਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਉਸਦਾ ਪਿਤਾ ਸੁਧੀਰ ਵਰਮਾ ਗਰੇਡ 2 ਦਾ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਨਰਮਦਾ ਵੈਲੀ ਡਿਵੈਲਪਮੈਂਟ ਅਥਾਰਟੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਸੰਗੀਤਾ ਇਕ ਘਰਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਰਾ ਸੌਰਭ ਵਰਮਾ, ਜੋ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਪੱਧਰ 'ਤੇ ਰੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਵਾਲਾ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਵੀ ਹੈ, ਦੇ ਨਕਸ਼ੇ ਕਦਮਾਂ' ਤੇ ਚੱਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਨੂੰ ਖੇਡ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਆ। ਉਹ ਜਲਦੀ ਹੀ ਹੈਦਰਾਬਾਦ ਦੀ ਗੋਪੀਚੰਦ ਬੈਡਮਿੰਟਨ ਅਕੈਡਮੀ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਕੋਚ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਪੁਲੇਲਾ ਗੋਪੀਚੰਦ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਲਈ। "},{"question":"Продовжи речення:  Народився у Меріленді, але незабаром після цього родина переїхала до Делаверу. Навчався у Пенсильванії, вивчав право у Філадельфії. З 1754 року адвокатував у Делавері. Підтримав «величні» протести проти дій британського уряду ","answer":"У 1776 року голосував проти незалежності, проте підписав Декларацію. Під час війни за незалежність займався політикою у межах штату. Поганий стан здоров'я змусив його звільнитися в 1779 році, проте у 1782 році він повернувся на посаду. На Філадельфійському конвенті обстоював права малих штатів і сильну виконавчу владу. Очолив кампанію за ратифікацію Конституції у Делавері. Чотири роки був сенатором США, потім пішов у відставку, щоб стати головою Верховного суду Делаверу. На цій посаді перебував до самої смерті."},{"question":"Tập hợp H gồm các phần tử là: cầu lông, bóng bàn, bóng chuyền, bóng đá, bóng rổ. Hãy viết tập hợp H theo dạng biểu thức toán học: ","answer":"Các phần tử của tập hợp được viết trong hai dấu ngoặc nhọn {}, cách nhau bởi dấu “:”.Tập hợp H gồm các phần tử là: cầu lông, bóng bàn, bóng chuyền, bóng đá, bóng rổNên ta viết tập hợp H như sau:H = {cầu lông; bóng bàn; bóng chuyền; bóng đá; bóng rổ}"},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC tu jade lati ṣeto iforukọsilẹ ni Kwara","answer":"Yatọ si ohun tawọn eeyan n ro ṣaaju akoko yii pe o ṣee ṣe ki wahala ati rogbodiyan bẹ silẹ nibi eto iforukọsilẹ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC ni Kwara, wọọrọwọ ni kinni ọhun bẹrẹ lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, pẹlu bawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ṣe tu jade lọpọ yanturu lọ sibudo idibo wọn.Kaakiri ijọba ibilẹ mẹrindinlogun to wa ni Kwara leto iforukọsilẹ naa ti waye.Lawọn ibudo to wa niluu Ilọrin, witiwiti lawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC jade lati ṣeto naa, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ero ko pọ lawọn ibudo idibo perete to wa laarin igboro, wọrọọwọ lo lọ kaakiri Aarin-Gbungbun Kwara.Ni wọọdu kin-in-ni, ibudo idibo Alapa/Onire/Odegiwa, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC ọgọrun-un kan le mẹtalelogoji lo ti forukọsilẹ laarin aarọ ti eto naa bẹrẹ si ọwọ aago mẹta ọsan.Alaamojuto eto naa, Ọgbẹni Tunde Jimoh Idiagbọn, ṣalaye pe ko si wahala kankan latigba ti eto naa ti bẹrẹ.Bakan naa lọrọ ri nibudo idibo kẹwaa, karun-un ati ikejila ni Isalẹ-Koko, Wọọdu Gambari, ọpọlọpọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ lo jade lati ṣeto iforukọsilẹ naa.Awọn to mojuto eto naa ni Wọọdu Ibagun, Mashood Latifat, Akanbi Teslimat ati Adebayọ Muhammed Qozeem, dupẹ lọwọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ to jade bi wọn ṣe gba alaafia laaye ti wọn si huwa ọmọluabi lati mu ki eto naa lọ wọọrọ.Bakan naa lọmọ sori ni ibudo idibo kẹrin to wa ni Idigba, ni Wọọdu Adewọle, nijọba ibilẹ Ilọrin West, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ṣe jẹẹjẹ lati ibẹrẹ titi de opin.Ọmọ ile-igbimọ aṣoju-ṣofin tẹlẹ, Mashood Mustapha, ṣeto iforukọsilẹ tiẹ ni ibudo rẹ, Aiyelabẹgan, ni Wọọdu Alanamu, nijọba ibilẹ Ila-Oorun Ilọrin.Eto ọhun naa lọ wọọrọ lẹkun Guusu  ati Ariwa Kwara. Senatọ Umar Sadiq to n ṣoju ẹkun Kwara North ṣe iforukọsilẹ tiẹ ni ibudo idibo Osiwera, niluu Kaiama."},{"question":"Gentille Assih","answer":"Gentille Menguizani Assih (tí wọ́n bí ní 2 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀rin, Ọdún 1979) jẹ́ olùdarí eré àti agbéréjáde ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Tógò.Wọ́n bí Assih ní ìlú Kpalimé, orílẹ̀-èdè Tógò ní ọdún 1979. Ó fẹ́ràn ṣíṣe iṣẹ́ sinimá láti ìgbà kékeré rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2001, ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìmọ̀-ẹ̀rọ kọ̀mpútà àti fọ́tòyíyà. Ní ọdún 2006, Assih tún kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìtàn-eré kíkọ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Sẹ̀nẹ̀gàl. Nígbà yìí kan náà ni ó gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ ìbáraẹnisọ̀rọ̀ láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga African Institute of Commercial Studies Ní ọdún 2009, Assih gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ ìṣàkóso àwọn òṣìṣẹ́.Assih ṣiṣẹ́ ní ilé-iṣẹ́ kan tó n rísí bíbáraẹnisọ̀rọ̀ fún ọdún méjì ṣáájú kí ó tó dá ilé-iṣẹ́ tirẹ̀ sílẹ̀ tí ó pe orúkọ rẹ̀ ní “World Films”. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bi olùdarí eré ní ọdún 2004 pẹ̀lú ṣíṣe àwọn fíìmù oníṣókí kan tí àkọ́lé wọ́n jẹ́ Le prix du velo àti La vendeuse contaminee. Ní ọdún 2008, ó ṣe adarí eré Itchombi.Ní ọdún tí ó tẹ̀le, Assih ṣe adarí àti agbéréjáde fún fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Bidenam, l’espoir d’un village ní ìlú Johannesburg, pẹ̀lú ìrànlọ́wọ́ ẹgbẹ́ Goethe Institute. Fíìmù náà dá lóri ayé Bidenam, ẹnití ó padà sí abúlé rẹ̀ lẹ́hìn ọdún mẹ́fà tí ó ti wà láárè, tó sì pinnu láti kọ́ àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀ bí wọ́n ti ń ṣe ètò ọ̀gbìn ní ìlànà ìbomirin. Àbúrò rẹ̀ obìnrin tí ó lọ kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Mòrókò ni ó mú àbá ìtàn eré náà wá. Ní ọdún 2012, Assih ṣe adarí eré ìrírí gígùn kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Le Rite, la Folle et moi.Àṣàyàn àwọn eré rẹ̀2004: Le prix du velo2004: La vendeuse contaminee2008: Itchombi2009: Bidenam, l’espoir d’un village2012: Le Rite, la Folle et moi"},{"question":"Classificeer elk van de titels of ze van Isaac Asimov of Jules Verne zijn: Pebble in the Sky, The Stars, Like Dust, Foundation, The Robots of Dawn, The Naked Sun, Around the World in Eighty Days, From the Earth to the Moon, Martin Paz, Journey to the Centre of the Earth, A Drama in the Air","answer":"De classificatie is:Isaac Asimov: Pebble in the Sky, The Stars, Like Dust, Foundation, The Robots of Dawn, The Naked Sun Jules Verne: Around the World in Eighty Days, From the Earth to the Moon, Martin Paz, Journey to the Centre of the Earth, A Drama in the Air"},{"question":"محاسبه څه شی دی ؟","answer":"ځواب : محاسبه د اقتصاد د علم رشته دی چی د اقتصادی فعالیتونو په فنی توګه ثبت کول ، تصنیف او ګروپ بندی کول ، خالصهکول او د هغی نتیجه راوستل دی"},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: \\"Илгери-илгери бир Абдылда аттуу ото кайрымдуу колу ачык, ээримдүү, берешен, адилеттикти сүйгөн, кадыр-барктуу бай дам жашап, ал эч бир адамды куру-кол калтырбастан, ар дайым адамдарга жардам берчү экен.\\"","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Абдылданын үч уулу жана аларга атаган эки короо менен өтө кооз өстүрүлгөн чоң багы бар эле. Бир күнү Абдылда уулдарын алдына чакырып: — Балдарым мен эми карыдым, бир топ жашка бардым. Көзүмдүн тирүүсүндө бак менен короолорду силерге тапшырмакмын. Өз ара келишип, бирөөнөр бакты, экинчиңер короо жайларды бөлүшүп алгыла, — деди.\\""},{"question":"2018 ஆசிய விளையாட்டுப் போட்டியில் தங்கப் பதக்கம் வென்ற 12 கால்விரல்கள் கொண்ட பிரபலமான தடகள வீரர் யார்?","answer":"ஸ்வப்னா பர்மன் ஒரு இந்திய ஹெப்டத்லெட். 2018 ஆசிய விளையாட்டுப் போட்டியில் தங்கப் பதக்கம் வென்றார்"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو مخترع المذياع ؟","answer":"الإجابة: غولييلمو ماركوني "},{"question":"CUTUBKA KOOWAAD: BAAQA JAMHUURIYADDA FEDERAALKA SOOMAALIYA?","answer":"Qodobka laad. (1) Jamhuuriyadda Federaalka Soomaaliya Soomaaliya waa Jamhuuriyad federaal ah, leh gobannimo, dimograaddi ah, oo ku dhisan matilaadda dadweynaha, loo dhan yahay oo ku salaysan nidaamka axsaabta badan iyo caddaalad bulshadeed."},{"question":"Taura tsumo inoyendererana neinotevera:Chafamba kamwe hachiteyiwi.","answer":"Chapinda kamwe hachiteverwi."},{"question":"Мээнеткеч адам жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Мээнеткеч чыдамкай, сабырдуу болот. Ал өз максатына жетүү үчүн узак жол басат. Ал эми жалкоо баардыгы бат эле болуп калса дейт.Бир акылмандын айтканы бар: \\"Талант - бул 1%, калганы 99% кажыбыс эмгек\\""},{"question":"வினா:  வெப்பம்  கடத்தாப் பொருள் எது ?1.அழைப்பு மணி2.மரம்3.பாதரசம்4.உலோகத்துண்டு","answer":"விடை:மரம்"},{"question":" வினா: ‘வெங்கரி’ என்னும் சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ………………………அ) வெம் + கரிஆ) வெம்மை + கரிஇ) வெண் + கரிஈ) வெங் + கரி","answer":"விடை: ஆ) வெம்மை + கரி"},{"question":"கேள்வி: தெற்கு ஆசியாவின் சாக்ரடீசு என்று ஈ.வெ.ரா வுக்கு பட்டம் வழங்கிய அமைப்பு எது?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ) யுனெஸ்கோ நிறுவனம்ஆ) காமன்வெல்த்இ) தெற்காசிய கூட்டமைப்புஈ) வெளிநாடுவாழ் இந்தியர் கூட்டமைப்பு","answer":"சரியான பதில்: அ) யுனெஸ்கோ நிறுவனம்"},{"question":"அரசின் பொங்கல் விழாவில் சிற்றூர்க் கலைகளைக் காட்சியாக்கியிருக்கிறார்கள். ஒருபுறம் திரைகட்டித் தோற்பாவைக் கூத்து நிகழ்ந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறது. இன்னொருபுறம் பொம்மலாட்டம் ஆடிக்கொண்டிருந்தனர். சற்று நடந்தால் தாரை தப்பட்டை முழங்க ஒயிலாட்டம் ஆடியவாறு மண்ணின் மக்கள் …. இக்கலைகளை நீங்கள் நண்பர்களுடன் பார்த்தவாறும் சுவைத்தவாறும் செல்கிறீர்கள்.இக்கலைகளைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் வளர்க்கவும் மேன்மேலும் பரவலாக்கவும் நீங்கள் செய்யவிருப்பனவற்றை வரிசைப்படுத்துக.","answer":"கலைகளைப் பாதுகாக்கவும் வளர்க்கவும் மேன்மேலும் பரவலாக்கவும் நான் செய்ய விரும்புவன:1. பிறந்த நாள் விழாக்களில் மயிலாட்டம் முதலான கலைகளை நிகழ்த்த முனைவேன்.2. எங்கள் குடும்ப விழாக்களில் பொம்மலாட்டம் நிகழ்த்த ஏற்பாடு செய்வேன்.3. பள்ளி, கல்லூரி விழாக்களில் இக்கலை நிகழ்ச்சிகளை நாங்களே நடத்துவோம்.4. எம் ஊரில் பொம்மலாட்டம் நிகழ்வுக்கு ஏற்பாடு செய்வேன்.5. எங்கள் ஊர் மக்கள் இணைந்து ஒயிலாட்டம் ஆடுவோம்.6. எங்கள் ஊரில் நாட்டுப்புறக் கலையை வளர்ப்போம்."},{"question":"ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"කාබුල් නගරය ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානයේ අගනගරය හා විශාලතම නගරය වන අතර එය කාබුල් පළාතේ පිහිටා ඇත. නවතම දත්ත වලට අනුව එහි ඒ නාගරික ජනගහනය 1925548 ක් පමණ වේ.කාබුල් නගරය ආර්ථික වශයෙන් මෙන්ම සංස්කෘතික වශයෙන් ද ප්‍රධාන තැනක් ගන්නා අතර මුහුදු මට්ටමින් අඩි 5900 ක් (1800m) උසින් පිහිටයි. මෙම නගරය හින්දු කුෂ් කදුවැටිය හා කාබුල් නදිය අතර පිහිටා ඇත. මෙම නගරය අවම කන්දගාර්, හර්ට් හා මසාර් ෂාරිෆ් පිහිටටා ඇති අතර වෘතාකාර අධි‍ෙව්ගී මාර්ග වලින් සම්බන්ද කම් පවත්වයි. ජලාලාබද් හා පාකිස්ථාන‍ේ පෙෂාවාර් නගරයට දිවෙන මාර්ග වල ආරම්භයක් කාබුල් නගරයයි.1978 සිට කාබුල් හි ප්‍රධාන නිෂ්පාදන වන්නේ යුද්දායුද, රෙදිපිළි. ගෘහ භාණ්ඩ හා බිට් සිනි කර්මාන්තයයි. 2001 දි ඇෆ්ගනිස්ථානය ඉස්ලාමිය සමුහාන්ඩුව පිහිටුවීමත් සමගම වෙල  කටයුතු වල නිෂ්පාදනය ඉහළ ගියේය."},{"question":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mélòó ni ó wà ní ìpínlè Anambra?","answer":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mọ́kànlélógún ni."},{"question":"既是法国最大的王宫建筑，又是世界上最著名的艺术殿堂的是？","answer":" 卢浮宫"},{"question":"奧林匹克運動會的發源地是？","answer":"古希臘"},{"question":"विजयनगर साम्राज्याचा सर्वश्रेष्ठ सम्राट कोण होता ?","answer":"कृष्णदेवराय विजयनगर साम्राज्याचा सर्वश्रेष्ठ सम्राट होता."},{"question":"Qui était le peintre Claude Monet ?","answer":"Claude Monet, peintre impressionniste français, est connu pour son dévouement à capturer des moments fugaces de lumière et d'atmosphère dans ses paysages et ses séries de peintures. Ses séries « Nénuphars » et « Meules de foin » mettent en valeur sa fascination pour les qualités changeantes de la couleur et de la lumière. L'engagement de Monet dans la peinture en plein air et l'accent mis sur la perception ont ouvert la voie au mouvement impressionniste."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: രണ്ട് പദപ്രയോഗങ്ങൾ തമ്മിലുള്ള തുല്യത സ്ഥാപിക്കുന്ന ഗണിതശാസ്ത്ര പ്രസ്താവന എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഒരു സമവാക്യം എന്നത് രണ്ട് പദപ്രയോഗങ്ങൾ തമ്മിലുള്ള തുല്യത സ്ഥാപിക്കുന്ന ഒരു ഗണിത പ്രസ്താവനയാണ്, ഇത് പലപ്പോഴും തുല്യ (=) ചിഹ്നത്താൽ പ്രതിനിധീകരിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"MS Office නොමිලේද?","answer":"ඔබට Microsoft Office යෙදුම් නොමිලේ භාවිතා කළ නොහැක. ඒ් වෙනුවට Microsoft 365 භාවිතා කල ‌හැක. Microsoft 365 යනු මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් ඔෆිස් මෙවලම් කට්ටලයේ නවතම අනුවාදය(version) වන අතර, ඔබ දැනටමත් නිවසේ, පාසැලේ හෝ රැකියාවේ භාවිතා කරන වැඩසටහන් එයට ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"س267- ما الجزء الذي يسمى المح من البيضة ؟","answer":"ج267- الصفار"},{"question":"දුරේක්ෂ භාවිතා නොකර ගණිතමය අනාවැකි මඟින් සොයාගනු ලැබූ පළමු ග්‍රහලෝකය","answer":"දුරේක්ෂ භාවිතා නොකර ගණිතමය අනාවැකි මඟින් සොයාගනු ලැබූ පළමු ග්‍රහලෝකය නෙප්චූන් වේ. "},{"question":"السؤال: سورة تسمى بالفاضحة؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة التوبة"},{"question":"No anime Naruto, quem é Shino Aburame?","answer":"Shino Aburame é um ninja da Vila da Folha que é conhecido por suas habilidades de controle de insetos, usando insetos parasitas em suas batalhas."},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta su questa domanda: Chi era il quarterback della squadra che ha vinto Super Bowl LII?","answer":"La risposta corretta su questa domanda è Nick Foles."},{"question":"Göz tansiyonu olan hastalar nelere dikkat etmeli?","answer":"Sağlıklı beslenmek, sigara içmemek, kolestrol kontrolü, egzersiz yapmaya özen göstermek gereklidir. Dar açılı glokomu olanlar, diğer hastalıklar için verilen ilaçları alırken göz doktoruna danışmalı, çok uzun süre karanlıkta oturmalıdırlar."},{"question":"لدي هذا السؤال: ما عدد أجنحة البرغوث؟ ، أجب عليه بطريقة مبسطة.","answer":"حسناً. الإجابة هي لا يوجد أجنحة بل يمشي قفزاً."},{"question":"நீளவால் குதிரையின் வால் ஓடஓடக் குறையும் அது என்ன?","answer":"தையல் ஊசியும் நூலும்"},{"question":"बुकर पुरस्कार प्राप्त विजेत्याला किती हजार पौंड रक्कम मिळते?(A)  ६०(B)  ४०(C)  ५५(D)  ५०","answer":"(D) ५०"},{"question":"ما جنسية الشاعرة نازك الملائكة ؟","answer":"عراقية"},{"question":"サイコロで６の裏は１。では３の裏は何？","answer":"４です。"},{"question":"Bruno Mars ganhou um Grammy Award em 2015?","answer":"Sim"},{"question":"Apakah kebaikan tempe dalam diet harian kita?","answer":"Tempe adalah makanan yang baik untuk kesihatan yang boleh membawa banyak manfaat dalam diet harian kita. Antara kebaikan dań manfaat tempe adalah seperti berikut:1. Kaya Protein: Tempe mengandungi protein yang tinggi, baik untuk pertumbuhan dan pembaikan tisu. 2.Serat Diet Tinggi: Serat dalam tempe membantu sistem pencernaan kita berfungsi dengan lancar dan elakkan masalah sembelit.3. Rendah Lemak: Tempe adalah sumber protein yang rendah lemak, jadi baik untuk yang ingin menjaga berat badan.4. Kaya Nutrien: Ia mengandungi zat besi, kalsium, magnesium, dan vitamin B yang baik untuk kesihatan.5. Indeks Glisemik Rendah: Makan tempe boleh membantu kawal gula darah kita.6. Probiotik Alami: Tempe nagus untuk perut, membantu dalam pencernaan dan juga baik untuk sistem imun kita.7. Alternatif Vegan: Sumber protein yang baik untuk vegetarian dan vegan Bagi yang tidak makan daging.8. Antioksidan: Tempe mengandungi antioksidan yang membantu melindungi sel-sel tubuh kita daripada kerosakan.9. Makanan Versatil: Tempe boleh dimasak dalam pelbagai cara yang mudah dan serasi untuk hidangan pelbagai jenis."},{"question":"बराकपूर येथील लष्करी छावणीत सैनिक असलेला व इंग्रज अधिकाऱ्यावर गोळी झाडणारा क्रांतीकारक कोण होता ?","answer":"बराकपूर येथील लष्करी छावणीत सैनिक असलेला व इंग्रज अधिकाऱ्यावर गोळी झाडणारा क्रांतीकारक मंगल पांडे होता."},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد ولايات الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية؟","answer":"الإجابة: 50 ولاية "},{"question":"માધવ રામાનુજ ની \\"અમે કોમળ કોમળ\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"હળવા તે હાથે ઉપાડજો અમે કોમળ કોમળ,સાથરે ફૂલડાં ઢાળજો એ અમે કોમળ કોમળ.આયખાની આ કાંટ્યમાં રે અમે અડવાણે પગ,રૂંવે રૂંવે કાંટા ઊગિયા એ અમને રૂંધ્યા રગેરગ;ઊનાં તે પાણીડે ઝારજો રે અંગ કોમળ કોમળ,ખેપનો થાક ઉતારજો રે અમે કોમળ કોમળ.પેર્યા ઓઢ્યાના ઓરતા એ છોગે છેલ ઝુલાબી,આંખમાં રાત્યું આંજતા એ અમે ઘેન ગુલાબી;કેડિયે કોયલ ગૂંથજો એ અમે કોમળ કોમળ,ફૂમતે મોર ગે’કાવજો એ અમે કોમળ કોમળ.હાથ મૂકી મારે કાળજે એ પછી થોડુંક લખજો,ભવ ભવ આવાં આકરાં રે અમને જીવતર મળજો;કેવા જીવ્યાના અભરખા રે હતા કોમળ કોમળ,ફૂલના પોઢણ સાથરા રે કેવા કોમળ કોમળ."},{"question":"Sheeg Sababta Kaliftay In Quraanka La Isu Soo Aruuriyo Hadaba Sababta Maxay Ahayd?","answer":"Sababta Waxay Ahayd (Asxaabtii Quraanka Xifdisaney Oo Dagaalada Aad UguDhimanaayey) Sida Dagaalkii Ka Noqoshada Meesha La Yiraahdo Yamaama Markaa Waxaa LagaBaqay In Quraanka Lumo, Sidaas Darteed Baa Dib Loogu Aruurshay Quraanka"},{"question":"Tamin'ny taona firy no lasa zana-tany frantsay tamin'ny fomba ofisialy i Madagasikara?1) 18482) 18853) 1896","answer":"Ny valinny marina dia  3) 1896 - Lasa zana-tany frantsay tamin’ny fomba ofisialy i Madagasikara tamin’ny taona 1896."},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: \\"Aza be anatra imaso, fa ___\\"","answer":"\\"Aza be anatra imaso, fa be fosa ivoho.\\""},{"question":"Nitori ibọn ti wọn yin ni Lẹkki: Wahala ba ijọba atawọn ọga ṣọja","answer":"Bi ọrọ awọn olori ṣọja nilẹ wa ṣe n ṣe segesege lojoojumọ yii, ti ọpọlọpọ aṣiri si n tu, ti fẹẹ ṣe akoba fun awọn ọga ṣọja ati awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba ni Naijiria yii, ọrọ naa si ti ko wahala ba awọn eeyan naa, ere oriṣiiriṣii lawọn paapaa n sa kiri. Awọn ọmọwe kan lo kọkọ ko ara wọn jọ, wọn si le ni ọgọrin ti wọn ṣe bẹẹ, gbogbo wọn si pawọ-pọ, wọn kọwe si aarẹ ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ dibo yan nilẹ Amẹrika, Joe Biden, wọn ni to ba ti gbajọba, ko ma fi oju aanu kankan wo ijọba orilẹ-ede Naijiria, ko ri i pe oun fiya to daa jẹ awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba yii, lori bi wọn ṣe yinbọn pa awọn ọdọ ti wọn n ṣewọde ni Lẹkki. Awọn Purofẹsọ ati ọjọgbọn loriṣiiriṣii ni wọn para pọ kọwe naa, ti wọn si bẹ Joe Biden ati igbakeji ẹ, Kamala Harris, pe ki wọn fofin de gbogbo ẹni to ba lọwọ si ọrọ yii, paapaa awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba, pe wọn ko gbọdọ jẹ ki wọn wọ Amẹrika rara, awọn ati araale wọn.Bi awọn ti kọwe yii, bẹẹ naa ni awọn orilẹ-ede ilẹ Yuroopu n mura, wọn fẹẹ wo ibi ti iwadii to n lọ lọwọ l’Ekoo yoo fi ori sọ, ki wọn too mọ ara ti wọn yoo da gan-an. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe ara daadaa ni wọn fẹẹ da fawọn ti wọn n ṣejọba yii, wọn n wa ibi ti wọn yoo ti mu wọn pẹlu ofin to le koko ni, nitori ohun ti wọn ṣe fawọn ọdọ ni Lẹkki yii, ohun ti gbogbo aye lodi si ni, ti wọn si ni afi ki wọn ri i pe iru rẹ ko gbọdọ ṣẹlẹ nibi kankan lagbaaye mọ. Awọn ara United Kingdom tilẹ ti ṣaaju bayii, nitori lalẹ ana yii, ọrọ Naijiria ati awọn ṣọja ti wọn yinbọn yii ni wọn fi odidi wakati kan sọ nile-igbimọ aṣofin wọn, bi awọn kan si ti n pariwo pe ki wọn tete fiya jẹ Naijiria ati awọn ti wọn ba wa nidii ọrọ yii, awọn diẹ n bẹbẹ pe ki wọn jẹ ki awọn ti wọn n ṣe ijọba naa waa sọ tẹnu wọn.Ohun to jẹ ki ọrọ yii le kari aye bayii ko ju bi ọrọ awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba ati awọn ṣọja ti wọn jade lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ yii ṣe n ṣe segesege lọ. Ohun kan tun ṣẹlẹ lọjọ Satide to kọja yii to mu kọrọ naa tun buru si i. Bẹẹ, ko too di ọjọ naa ni ileeṣẹ oniroyin agbaye, Cable News Network, iyẹn CNN, ti gbe iroyin jade nipa iṣẹlẹ naa, iroyin ọhun si kun fun iwadii ju eyi ti wọn ti n gbọ tẹlẹ lọ. Ninu iroyin naa lo ti han pe loootọ lawọn ṣọja yinbọn nibẹ, wọn ko si yinbọn soke gẹgẹ bi Ọga ṣọja, Ahmed Taiwo, ti wa siwaju igbimọ yii waa sọ. Ọga ṣọja yii ti sọ tẹlẹ niwaju igbimọ naa ni Satide to kọja lọ lọhun-un pe gbogbo awọn ṣọja ti wọn lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ naa, oke lasan ni wọn yinbọn si, ati pe ibọn ti wọn yin naa ko ni ọta ninu, ibọn adẹrubani lasan ni. Ṣugbọn nigba ti iroyin CNN yii jade, fidio fi awọn ṣọja ti ko yinbọn soke han, o si fi han gbangba pe ọta gidi wa ninu awọn ibọn naa.Aṣiri ti CNN tun tu yii bi ijọba Naijiria ninu, minisita fun eto iroyin ijọba, Lai Muhammed, si jade pe awọn yoo fiya jẹ CNN, o ni gbogbo ọrọ ti wọn sọ yii, irọ lo wa nibẹ. Ṣugbọn awọn araaye gba CNN gbọ ju bẹẹ lọ. Wọn mọ pe iroyin ti awọn eeyan naa gbe ba jade, ootọ gidi ni. Yatọ si eyi, ohun ti wọn foju ri nibẹ ninu fidio ko ni irọ ninu nibi kan. Ohun ti Lai Muhammed n sọ ni pe ko si ẹni kankan to ku nibi iṣẹlẹ naa, pe CNN kan fẹẹ ba awọn lorukọ jẹ ni. Ṣugbọn bo ti n sọrọ tan, bẹẹ ni ileeṣẹ igbokuupamọ-si l’Ekoo kede pe ki awọn eeyan wa sọdọ wọn lati waa wo awọn oku to wa nibẹ, iyẹn awọn ti eeyan wọn ba sọnu laarin ọjọ kọkandinlogun, si ọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, bẹẹ ogunjọ, oṣu yii, lawọn ṣọja ya bo wọn ni Lẹkki, ti oku si sun nibẹ daadaa. Itumọ eyi ni pe awọn oku kan wa ti wọn ku loootọ.Yatọ si eyi, awọn eeyan kọọkan ti bẹrẹ si i jade lati sọ pe awọn n wa awọn eeyan awọn, awọn mi-in ti wọn si ti ri oku eeyan tiwọn, ti wọn mọ pe Lẹkki ni wọn ku si naa ti sọrọ, wọn royin iku to pa awọn eeyan wọn lasiko iwọde yii. Nidii eyi, ko si ibi ti ijọba yii fẹẹ sa si lori ọrọ yii mọ, o ti han pe ọpọ ọrọ to n jade ki i ṣe ootọ, ọrọ wọn n tase ara wọn. Bi nnkan si ṣe wa niyi nigba to tun di ọjọ Satide to kọja yii, nigba ti ọga ṣọja ni ọwọ kọkanlelọgọrin tawọn ologun (81 Division), nibi ti awọn ṣọja ti wọn yinbọn yii ti wa, jẹwọ pe ki oun sọ tootọ ki oun sọ tododo, awọn ṣọja ti wọn lọ si Lẹkki yii gbe ibọn dani, ati pe ninu awọn ibọn to wa lọwọ wọn, awọn ibọn kan wa to ni ọta ninu digbidigbi. O ni ko si bi awọn ṣọja yoo ṣe lọ si iru ibi iwọde bẹẹ ti wọn ko ni i gbe ibọn to lọta ninu dani, nitori awọn kan le fẹẹ kọ lu wọn nibẹ.Nigba ti awọn agbẹjọro bẹrẹ si i fi ọrọ wa a lẹnu wo lori ohun to ti sọ tẹlẹ pe ibọn ti awọn ṣọja yin nibẹ ko lọta ninu lo ti tun pada jẹwọ pe awọn ibọn kan wa to lọta ninu o: Birigedia Ahmed Taiwo yii ni: “Dajudaju, awọn ṣọja ti wọn ba n lọ siru ibẹ yẹn, ninu wọn maa gbebọn to ni ọta ninu dani. Nitori boya awọn kan le fẹe kọ lu wọn ni. Ṣugbọn o, awọn ti wọn ṣaaju ti wọn yinbọn yẹn, ibọn ti ko lọta ninu lawọn n yin ni tiwọn!” Bayii ni Taiwo wi, ṣugbọn awọn eeyan ni o ṣoro pupọ lati gba ọrọ naa gbọ, nitori awọn ohun to ti kọja lọ tẹlẹ ti wọn gbọ, nigba ti awọn ṣọja yii ti kọkọ sọ pe awọn ko de Lẹkki, ti wọn tun sọ pe gomina lo ranṣẹ pe awọn, ti wọn si tun sọ pe awọn ko yinbọn, ki wọn too tun ni ibọn ti ko lọta ninu lawọn yin, ki wọn too tun waa sọ pe awọn ṣọja mi-in tun lọ sibẹ pẹlu ibọn to lọta ninu.Nibi ti ọrọ waa de duro yii ni ọkan awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba Buhari yii ko balẹ, ohun to si n ja wọn laya ni pe ọrọ naa le buru ju bayii lọ. Bi ọrọ naa ba buru, to ba ṣe bayii dewaju ile-ẹjọ agbaye, ati awọn ọga ṣọja wọnyi, ati olori ijọba funra rẹ ni wọn yoo de ile-ẹjọ naa kawọ sẹyin, koda ko jẹ ọdun mẹwaa si ogun ọdun lo na wọn. Ohun ti awọn eeyan naa n sa fun ree, nitori wọn mọ pe igbẹyin ọrọ bẹẹ ko le dara. Nidii eyi, gbogbo ohun ti wọn le ṣe lati bo ọrọ naa mọlẹ ni wọn n ṣe, eyi lawọn eeyan ijọba si ṣe n tẹnu mọ ọn lojoojumọ pe ko sẹnikan to ku ni Lẹkki, ti wọn ni ẹni ti eeyan ẹ ba ku ni Lẹkki ko yọju sita. Amọ bi wọn ti n purọ naa, bẹẹ ni irọ ọhun n ja, awọn ti eeyan wọn ku n jade, awọn ti wọn tọju oku pamọ ni ki awọn eeyan waa wo awọn ti wọn ku boya eeyan wọn wa nibẹ, awọn ṣọja paapaa si ti jẹwọ pe loootọ lawọn lọ si Lẹkki pẹlu ibọn to lọta ninu.Ijọba ipinlẹ Eko paapaa ko ti i wi kinni kan, ṣugbọn igbimọ to n ṣewadii ọrọ yii ti ni dandan ni Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu naa wa yọju sawọn, ko si waa sọ ohun to mọ nidii awọn ọrọ yii gan-an. Ṣe gomina naa lo kọkọ sọ pe awọn alagbara to ju oun lọ lo ko ṣọja jade, ki i ṣe oun, oun naa lo si sọ pe awọn oku meji ku nibẹ, bẹẹ lo sọ pe oun wa Buhari ti i ṣe olori ijọba titi, oun o ri i. Gbogbo ohun to sọ yii lo jẹ ki awọn ṣọja binu si i, ti wọn ni awọn ko ro iru ọrọ bẹẹ si i. Ohun ti awọn igbimọ yii ṣe ni afi ki oun naa maa bọ ree, wọn ni oriṣiiriṣii ọrọ to wa nilẹ yii lo da le e lori, bo ba si de ọdọ igbimọ, yoo le sọ gbogbo ohun to mọ sita. Ohun to daju ni pe bi Sanwo-Olu ba dewaju igbimọ yii, pẹrẹpẹrẹ mi-in yoo tun tu jade, nibi ti ọrọ naa yoo si fori sọlẹ si, ko sẹni to mọ. Eyi ni wahala to ba awọn to n ṣejọba l’Abuja, ati awọn ọga ṣọja, nitori ọrọ naa ti di ki olori dori ẹ mu o."},{"question":"පහත තුන් තෙරවිල්ල තෝරන්න.කාරිය බලන්","answer":"කාරිය නම් වැඩ , බලන් නම් බල = වැඩ බල , බඩ වැල"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Com que canção Nicky Minaj recebeu sua primeira indicação para o Grammy?","answer":"A resposta correta é My Chick Bad"},{"question":"No contexto da Matemática, explique brevemente o termo \\"Geometria Analítica\\".","answer":"A geometria analítica é uma área da matemática que combina princípios da álgebra com a geometria para estudar figuras geométricas usando coordenadas."},{"question":"Inona no singa fototra ara-drafitra amin'ny hozatry ny vatana?1-taolana2- ra3-proteinina","answer":"Valiny: 3. Proteinina"},{"question":"Sifu Difẹnsi da bii dokita ni, ko si ẹka iṣẹ aabo ti wọn ko gbọdọ ma mọ – Kọmandanti Abọdunrin","answer":"Ohun ti ẹda ba n ṣe ti ko ṣiwọ, bo pẹ titi, a mọ ni lọwọ jọjọ. Lọdun 1994 ni ọkunrin to waa di olori awọn Sifu Difẹnsi nipinlẹ Ogun bayii, Kọmandanti Ahmed Abọdunrin, darapọ mọ ikọ naa gẹgẹ bii ọmọọṣẹ lasan, gẹgẹ bii ẹni to fẹẹ fara sin lai gbowo, nitori wọn ki i sanwo fawọn Sifu Difẹsi nigba kan, iṣẹ ilu ati iṣẹ ọfẹ ni wọn n ṣe.  Ọdun kẹrindinlọgbọn (26 years) rẹ ree lẹnu iṣẹ naa bayii, ọkunrin naa sọ iriri rẹ lẹnu iṣẹ yii fun akọroyin ALAROYE nipinlẹ Ogun, ADEFUNKẸ ADEBIYI. Kọmandanti Abọdunrin : Emi ni Kọmandanti Ahmed Abọdunrin, apaṣẹ ikọ Nigeria Security and Civil Defence Corps(NSCDC) nipinlẹ OgunALAROYE: O ti pe ọdun kan bayii ti wọn ti gbe yin wa sipinlẹ Ogun gẹgẹ bii ọga patapata, ṣe iwa ọdaran pọ ju ni tabi o mọ niwọnba nipinlẹ yii?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Ki i ṣe pe iwa ọdaran pọ nipinlẹ Ogun ju ti awọn ẹgbẹ rẹ lọ, nnkan to wa nibẹ ni pe ipinlẹ ẹnu iloro (Gateway State) fawọn ilu mi-in ni, ibẹ lawọn ajoji n gba wọle, ti wọn n gba jade. Eyi jẹ ki oriṣiiriṣii eeyan maa  gba ipinlẹ Ogun kọja, ẹlomi-in ko tiẹ ni i lọ mọ, yoo taku sibi ni, ole si ni ẹlomi-in ninu wọn.O tun waa jẹ pe ọpa epo to to kilomita ibusọ mọkandinlọgọrin (79KM) lo gba ipinle Ogun kọja, ọpa afẹfẹ gaasi naa gba ibẹ kọja, awọn onifayawọ naa n gba ibi kọja, gbogbo nnkan wọnyi le mu ki iwa ọdaran pọ niluu, o si wa lara awọn nnkan ti a n koju. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe pe iwa ọdaran pọ nipinlẹ yii ju ti ipinlẹ mi-in lọ.ALAROYE: Awọn agbegbe bii Arepo ti wọn ti maa n bẹ ọpa epo bẹntiroolu sinmi diẹ lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, ọgbọn wo le da si i?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Ko si ọgbọn ta a da si i ju iranlọwọ Ọlọrun ati ifọwọsowọpọ awọn araalu pẹlu ifọkansin awọn oṣiṣẹ mi. Bi mo ṣe sọ lẹẹkan, ibusọ ọpa epo nipinlẹ yii pọ, ṣugbọn ti Ọlọrun ba ran eeyan lọwọ, ti awọn araalu naa n fọwọ sowọ pọ, bo ṣe maa ri naa ree.A ti jade lọ sọdọ awọn araalu, a ṣalaye fun wọn pe ọpa epo ti awọn ole n bẹ ko le ṣe ilu loore, nitori bi epo ba dapọ mọ omi, to ṣan lọ sibi tawọn eeyan wa, ina lo maa fa, ijamba ni yoo ṣẹlẹ. Nigba tawọn naa ko si fẹ wahala, bi wọn ba ti kẹẹfin awọn to n huwakiwa naa, wọn aa ta wa lolobo ni.ALAROYE: Mo ṣakiyesi pe gbogbo ọran ni Sifu Difẹnsi n da si bayii, koda, ẹ n ri si ifipabanilopọ. Ṣe ijọba naa lo gbe iwọnyi le yin lọwọ ni abi ẹ kan n ran awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ ni?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin?Ki i ṣe pe a n da si gbogbo iwa ọdanran bẹẹ yẹn naa, ohun ti ileeṣẹ wa wa fun ni lati daabo bo araalu ati dukia. Ṣe ẹ si mọ pe ẹni to ba ti n da aabo bo araalu ati dukia, ọta gbogbo ọdaran naa ni yoo jẹ.Bi ẹ ba wo orukọ ileeṣe wa, NSCDC. Sikiọriti to wa ninu orukọ wa yẹn, aabo lo tumọ si, Difẹnsi ni lati gbogun ti iwa ọdaran, ẹni to ba si fẹẹ ṣe nnkan meji yii, ko si bi ko ṣe ni i koju bọ gbogbo iwa ọdaran to ba n waye. Iṣẹ eto aabo, bii iṣẹ oniṣegun ni. Ko si dokita ti ko ni i le fun eeyan loogun iba tabi inu rirun. Ṣugbọn to ba waa di pe aisan yẹn n le si i, nigba yẹn ni wọn a maa wa awọn akọṣẹmọṣe eka to jẹ mọ ohun to n ṣe ẹni yẹn.Awọn iṣẹ kan wa ta a n pe ni Core Mandate, to jẹ iṣẹ tiwa gangan, iru ẹ ni ti ọpa epo tẹ ẹ sọ yẹn. To jẹ pe bawọn ologun ba mu wọn gan-an, wọn aa mu wọn wa fun wa ni, nitori wọn mọ pe awa la n ri si pe nnkan kan ko gbọdọ ṣe dukia ijọba. Mi o ni i sọ pe nitori mi o ki i ṣe kọsitọọmu, ki n ri ẹni to n ṣe fayawọ ki n waa dakẹ, ma a mu un, ma a si fa a le awọn kọsitọọmu lọwọ ni, bi ọrọ eto aabo ṣe ri niyẹn.ALAROYE: Nnkan ko fara rọ niluu lasiko yii, iwọde wọọrọwọ ti di wahala siluu lọrun. Ki lẹ ri si eyi?Kọmandanti  Abọdunrin: O ṣe ni laaanu pe iwọde lati fẹhonu han di ohun ti a n pa ara ẹni, ti wọn n pa ọlọpaa, ti wọn n dana sun ileeṣẹ ijọba ati adani, ko daa. Ko sohun to buru lati fi ẹhonu han, keeyan maa ba nnkan jẹ ni ko daa.A gbagbọ pe awọn janduku lo gba kinni naa mọ awọn ọdọ lọwọ, ki i ṣe awọn ọmọ to fẹ daadaa fun ilu ni wọn n ṣe jagidijagan. A rọ wọn ki wọn jawọ nibẹ, niwọn igba tijọba ti ni awọn yoo ṣe ohun ti wọn n fẹ.ALAROYE: Kin waa ni ajọ yin n ṣe si i bayii?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Ipa ti Sifu Difẹnsi n ko lori ọrọ END SARS ko yatọ si eyi tawọn agbofinro yooku n ko. A n ri i pe awọn to n binu pada sile, kawọn eeyan yooku naa le maa ri ọna iṣẹ wọn lọ.A ti da awọn eeyan wa sibi tawọn dukia ijọba wa, awọn dukia to jẹ bi ọwọ ibajẹ ba kan wọn, yoo ko wahala ba tẹru tọmọ ni. A si n ba wọn sọrọ pe ki wọn ma dan ibajẹ kankan wo, nitori  ijọba ti loun yoo ṣe ohun ti wọn n fẹ.ALAROYE: Sifu Difẹnsi naa n gbe ibọn bii ọlọpaa, bawo lẹ ṣe n lo ibọn tiyin?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Bi ko ba di pe awọn ọta doju ibọn kọ wa, a ki i lo ibọn ni tiwa. Awa ki i lo ibọn ti ko ba jẹ pe ohun to n ṣẹlẹ lasiko yẹn gba pe ka lo o.Bi a ba ri i pe ọdaran ṣetan lati yinbọn mọ wa, a le yinbọn mọ ọn lọwọ tabi lẹsẹ, ti ko fi ni i le yinbọn tiẹ. A si maa gbe e lọ sọsibitu.Ọga wa patapata ta a n pe ni Alaaji Abdullahi Gana Muhammadu tiẹ sọ pe oun ko fẹẹ gbọ pe ibọn ṣeeṣi yin lọwọ wa rara ni. Nitori ki ọta ibọn too jade, o to ipele marun-un o. Bawo leeyan yoo ṣe waa to gbogbo ẹ pọ ti yoo ni o ṣeeṣi ni, ko gbọdọ ṣẹlẹ rara.A dẹ tun maa n pada lọọ kẹkọọ si i nipa ibọn lilo, awọn ologun lo n kọ wa, awọn naa ni wọn si kọkọ ko ibọn bii ẹgbẹrun marun-un ta a kọkọ n lo fun wa.ALAROYE: Iriri wo lẹ o le gbagbe ninu iṣẹ yin yii?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Igba ti mo lọ si orilẹ-ede Philipine ni, ti mo foju rinju pẹlu awọn alakatakiti (Rebel). Wọn da bii eeṣin o kọku Boko Haram ta a ni nibi. Emi atawọn ẹgbẹ mi la lọọ kẹkọọ nibẹ, o ba mi lẹru gan-an nitori oriṣiiriṣii ofin ni wọn fun wa.A o gbọdọ tẹju mọ wọn ju, a o gbọdọ ya fọto. Mo ri i pe bo ṣe jẹ pe inu igbo ni wọn n gbe to, wọn ni ọna to daa, wọn si n gbe ni alaafia niwọnba. Wọn ni aṣọ ologun tiwọn, wọn si ni awọn ibọn tiwọn.Wọn ni kawa naa lọọ kọ ẹkọ lọdọ wọn nigba yẹn ni, ka ba wọn sọrọ pe kin ni wọn tun n fẹ lọwọ ijọba ti wọn n ba ja. O wú mi lori, mo si wo o pe iru nnkan bayii naa ṣee ṣe lọdọ wa o, pe ka ba awọn afẹhonu han tabi ajijagbara sọrọ pe kin ni wọn n fẹ. O kan jẹ pe awọn eeyan wa ki i nifẹẹ si ifikunlukun bẹẹ ni.Iriri yẹn jọ mi loju pupọ to bẹẹ to jẹ ko si ọjọ ti mo ji ti mi o ki i ranti ẹ.ALAROYE: Ọmọ ilu wo niyin, awọn ileewo lẹ si lọ?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin:  Ọmọ ilu Ìrẹ̀sì ni mi, nijọba ibilẹ Boluwaduro, nipinlẹ Ọṣun. Mo lọ sileewe pamari St. Judes, n’Irẹsi, ileewe Girama Baptist, mo tun lọ si Ẹdẹkun, ilu Irẹsi ni awọn ileewe yii wa, mo tun waa lọọ ṣe idanwo oniwee mẹwaa l’Oṣogbo Grammar School.Mo lọ si Yunifasiti Eko (Unilag). Mo kẹkọọ nipa irisi ilẹ ati Aato (Geography and Planning). Mo lọ si Yunifasiti Ibadan, mo kẹkọọ nipele Masitaas, mo kọ nipa itọju ọmọniyan ati awọn ogunlende (Humanitarian and Refugee Studies).Mo tun ṣe Masitaas mi-in lori ipẹtu-saawọ (Peace and Conflict Management). Mo tun lọ si Ọlabisi Ọnabanjọ Yunifasiti, mo ṣe Diploma ninu Kọmputa. Mo tun lọ si yunifasiti kan ni Thailand, iyẹn Chulalongkorn University, nipa ipẹtu-saawọ naa ni mo kẹkọọ le lori nibẹ, mo kẹkọọ ni Kofi Annan Yunifasiti, ni Ghana naa.ALAROYE: Ki lo wu yin ninu iṣẹ Sifu Difẹnsi yii tẹ ẹ fi darapọ mọ wọnKọmandanti Abọdunrin:  Mo maa n nifẹẹ si awọn ẹgbẹ to n fi ara sìn (Voluntary Clubs). Nigba ti mo wa nileewe girama, mo wa ninu ẹgbe ‘Boys Scout’.Ni Yunifasiti, mo darapọ mọ ‘Man o war’, mo di alakooso ki n too kuro nileewe yẹn. Nigba ti mo ṣetan ni Unilag, mo maa n ri awọn Sifu Difẹnsi, o dẹ maa n wu mi lati darapọ mọ wọn lati sinru ilu, bi mo ṣe darapọ mọ wọn niyẹn ni 1994.ALAROYE: Awọn ilu wo niṣẹ ti gbe yin de kẹ ẹ too de Abẹokuta?Kọmandanti Abọdunrin: Mo ṣiṣe nipinlẹ Ọṣun, mo ṣiṣẹ nipinlẹ Kwara, mo ṣiṣẹ nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ipinlẹ Plateau naa ko gbẹyin.Lẹyin iyẹn ni mo lọ si olu ileeṣẹ wa l’Abuja, lati ibẹ ni wọn ti gbe mi wa si Abẹokuta gẹgẹ bii ọga agba.Iṣẹ yii ti gbe mi lọ si orilẹ-ede Cuba, Thailand, Philipines, mo lọ si Ghana naa, mo lọọ kọ ẹkọ mọ ẹkọ ni lawọn ilu naa.ALAROYE: Imọran yin fawọn oṣiṣẹ Sifu jakejadoKọmandanti Abọdunrin: Gbogbo iṣe ti kaluku ba n ṣe, ko lọọ nimọ nipa ẹ, ko ma jẹ pe o kan n wọṣọ lasan kiri. Ẹni to ba ti mọ iṣẹ tiẹ, ko ni i ba ẹlomi-in ja pe o n gba iṣẹ oun ṣe.Tojo ba si n pa ikan ọrẹ, gbogbo wa pata leji n pa. Bi wahala ba ṣẹlẹ, kawọn iyawo tabi ọkọ wa too de, awọn oṣiṣẹ wa la maa kọkọ ri lati daabo bo wa. Fun idi eyi, ka maa ri ara wa, ọmọọṣẹ ati ọga bii pe ọkan naa ni wa.Imọran kẹta ni pe ka ma ba ara wa jiyan, ifikunlukun lo daa. Iṣẹ aabo pọ ni Naijiria, a o ti i ṣe e debi kan, ko nilo ka maa ba ara wa ja, ifọwọsowọpọ lo n mu ile duro, ki kaluku sowo pọ, igba naa ni yoo daa. Ẹ ṣeun."},{"question":"O tweet a seguir expressa um sentimento positivo, negativo ou neutro?@user Deixa tempo mostrar, anima mais assim😹😹😹","answer":"Um sentimento positivo."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගම ගංගාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ දිගම ගංගාව මහවැලි ගංගාවයි."},{"question":"日本三名園と呼ばれる３つの公園とは、水戸の偕楽園、金沢の兼六園と、岡山にある何でしょう？","answer":"後楽園です。"},{"question":"Frase 1: Rami Nieminen (nacido el 25 de febrero de 1966) es un futbolista finlandés.Frase 2: Rami Nieminen (nacido el 25 de febrero de 1966) es un ex jugador de fútbol finlandés.Pregunta: ¿Podemos reescribir la frase 1 a la frase 2?","answer":"Sí, podemos reescribir la frase 1 a la frase 2 de la siguiente manera:Frase 2 (reescribiendo la frase 1): Rami Nieminen (nacido el 25 de febrero de 1966) es un ex jugador de fútbol finlandés."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਅਬਿਨਾਸੀ ਤਾ ਕਿਆ ਕਾੜਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਭਗਵੰਤਾ ਤਾ ਜਨੁ ਖਰਾ ਸੁਖਾਲਾ ॥ਜੀਅ ਪ੍ਰਾਨ ਮਾਨ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਤੂੰ ਕਰਹਿ ਸੋਈ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਭਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਰਬਤੁ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਓਲਾ ਤੁਮ ਸੰਗਿ ਲਵੈ ਨ ਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੇਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਿਸੁ ਲਾਗੈ ਮੀਠਾ ॥ਘਟਿ ਘਟਿ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਤਿਨਿ ਜਨਿ ਡੀਠਾ ॥ਥਾਨਿ ਥਨੰਤਰਿ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਇਕੋ ਇਕੁ ਵਰਤਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਸਗਲ ਮਨੋਰਥ ਤੂੰ ਦੇਵਣਹਾਰਾ ॥ਭਗਤੀ ਭਾਇ ਭਰੇ ਭੰਡਾਰਾ ॥ਦਇਆ ਧਾਰਿ ਰਾਖੇ ਤੁਧੁ ਸੇਈ ਪੂਰੈ ਕਰਮਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਅੰਧ ਕੂਪ ਤੇ ਕੰਢੈ ਚਾੜੇ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਦਾਸ ਨਦਰਿ ਨਿਹਾਲੇ ॥ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਹਿ ਪੂਰਨ ਅਬਿਨਾਸੀ ਕਹਿ ਸੁਣਿ ਤੋਟਿ ਨ ਆਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਐਥੈ ਓਥੈ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਰਖਵਾਲਾ ॥ਮਾਤ ਗਰਭ ਮਹਿ ਤੁਮ ਹੀ ਪਾਲਾ ॥ਮਾਇਆ ਅਗਨਿ ਨ ਪੋਹੈ ਤਿਨ ਕਉ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਤੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਕਿਆ ਗੁਣ ਤੇਰੇ ਆਖਿ ਸਮਾਲੀ ॥ਮਨ ਤਨ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਤੁਧੁ ਨਦਰਿ ਨਿਹਾਲੀ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੀਤੁ ਸਾਜਨੁ ਮੇਰਾ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਤੁਧੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਜਾਨਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਜਿਸ ਕਉ ਤੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਭਇਆ ਸਹਾਈ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਤਤੀ ਵਾਉ ਨ ਲਗੈ ਕਾਈ ॥ਤੂ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਰਣਿ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਜਪਿ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਤੂੰ ਊਚ ਅਥਾਹੁ ਅਪਾਰੁ ਅਮੋਲਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਸਾਚਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਦਾਸੁ ਤੇਰਾ ਗੋਲਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਮੀਰਾ ਸਾਚੀ ਠਕੁਰਾਈ ਨਾਨਕ ਬਲਿ ਬਲਿ ਜਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੩॥੩੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 131 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨ ਹੋਵੇ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ) ਅਬਿਨਾਸੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਕੋਈ ਚਿੰਤਾ-ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ।(ਜਦੋਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਨਿਸਚਾ ਹੋਵੇ ਕਿ) ਸਭ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹਰੀ (ਮੇਰਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈ) ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਸੌਖਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਬਿਤੀਤ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਨਿਸਚਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਜਿੰਦ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਖ ਦਾਤਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੇ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਤੂੰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਉਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਮੈਂ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਤੂੰ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਪਰਬਤ (ਸਮਾਨ ਸਹਾਰਾ) ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈਂ । ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਾਣਾ ਮਿੱਠਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਹਰੇਕ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਵੇਖ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ (ਹਰੇਕ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ) ਹੈਂ ।ਹਰੇਕ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ, ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਇਕ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ ।੨।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਮਨ-ਮੰਗੀਆਂ ਲੋੜਾਂ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਤੇਰੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਭਗਤੀ-ਧਨ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਧਨ ਨਾਲ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਭਰੇ ਪਏ ਹਨ ।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਤੇਰੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਦਇਆ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਹੱਲਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਹਨੇਰੇ ਖੂਹ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਕੰਢੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਸੇਵਕ ਅਬਿਨਾਸ਼ੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹਨ) ਆਖਣ ਨਾਲ ਸੁਣਨ ਨਾਲ (ਉਸ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ) ਖ਼ਾਤਮਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ।੪।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਇਸ ਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦਾ) ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈਂ । ਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੇਟ ਵਿਚ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ) ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ) ਦੀ ਅੱਗ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੫।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਕੇਹੜੇ ਕੇਹੜੇ ਗੁਣ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਚੇਤੇ ਕਰਾਂ ? ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਤਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਵੇਖ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈਂ । ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ (ਤੇਰੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਮਿਤ੍ਰ) ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦਾ ।੬।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਤੂੰ ਰਾਖਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ,ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਦੁੱਖ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਰਾਖਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ । ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਤੱਖ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਚ) ਤੰੂ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਤੋਂ) ਉੱਚਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ (ਮਾਨੋ, ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ) ਹੈਂ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਡੂੰਘਾਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦੀ, ਤੇਰੀ ਹਸਤੀ ਦਾ ਪਾਰਲਾ ਬੰਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ, ਤੇਰਾ ਮੁੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ (ਕਿਸੇ ਭੀ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦੇ ਵੱਟੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ) ।ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈਂ । ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਦਾਸ ਹਾਂ, ਗ਼ੁਲਾਮ ਹਾਂ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ (ਮੇਰਾ) ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ, ਤੇਰੀ ਸਦਾ ਮਾਲਕੀ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ ।੮।੩।੩੭।\\""},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Akurumidza kumedza kutsenga kuchada","answer":"kumhanyirira zvinhu"},{"question":"Συμπλήρωσε την πρόταση:  Προς το τέλος του Ρωσικού Εμφυλίου Πολέμου, ο Αντόνοφ-Οβσέγενκο ήταν υπεύθυνος του Κυβερνείου του Ταμπόφ, καταστέλλοντας βίαια την","answer":"Εξέγερση του Ταμπόφ το 1920-1921, μαζί με τον Μιχαήλ Τουχατσέφσκι, με τη χρήση χημικών όπλων."},{"question":"Makine öğrenmesi konusundaki yarı denetimli öğrenme kavramını açıkla.","answer":"Adından da anlaşılacağı gibi bu yöntemde denetimli ve denetimsiz öğrenme bir arada kullanılır. Teknik, küçük miktarda etiketli veri ve büyük miktarda etiketsiz veri kullanarak sistemlerin eğitilmesine bağlıdır. İlk olarak etiketli veriler kullanılarak makine öğrenimi algoritması kısmen eğitilir. Daha sonra, kısmen eğitilen algoritmanın kendisi etiketsiz verileri etiketler. Bu sürece psödo-etiketleme adı verilir. Model daha sonra açıkça programlanmadan ortaya çıkan veri karışımı üzerinde yeniden eğitilir. Bu yöntemin avantajı büyük miktarda etiketli veriye ihtiyaç duyulmamasıdır. İnsanlar tarafından okunup etiketlenmesi çok uzun zaman alacak uzun belgeler gibi verilerle çalışılırken yararlı olur."},{"question":"La domanda: Cosa è la Primavera di Praga?","answer":"La risposta: La Primavera di Praga è stato un periodo storico di liberalizzazione politica avvenuto in Cecoslovacchia all'epoca in cui questa era sottoposta al controllo dell'Unione Sovietica, dopo gli eventi successivi alla seconda guerra mondiale e nell'ambito della guerra fredda. Essa iniziò il 5 gennaio 1968, quando lo slovacco Alexander Dubček divenne segretario del Partito Comunista di Cecoslovacchia, terminando il 20 agosto dello stesso anno, quando un corpo di spedizione militare dell'Unione Sovietica e degli alleati del Patto di Varsavia invase il paese."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 果物のびわの種について、インターネットで「がんがよくなる」などという情報が広がっています。農林水産省によると、果物のびわやあんずなどの種や、熟していない実には「アミグダリン」という物質が入っています。「アミグダリン」が体の中に入ると、青酸という体に悪い物質ができます。たくさん食べると頭が痛くなったりめまいがしたり、吐いたりします。熟したびわの実は安全に食べることができます。農林水産省は、びわの種を粉にした物は、体に悪い物質がたくさん体の中に入る危険があるため、食べないように言っています。国の研究所は、「アミグダリン」でがんが治ったり症状がよくなったりすることはないと言っています。","answer":"農林水産省「びわの種の粉は食べないで」"},{"question":"வினா : தமிழ்நாடு நூலக இயக்கத்தின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : அவினாசி மகாலிங்கம்"},{"question":"Sino si Bernardo Carpio?","answer":"Si Bernardo Carpio ay isang kilalang tauhan sa mitolohiyang Pilipino na kilala dahil sa kanyang angking lakas. Pinaniniwalaan na nasa pagitan siya ng dalawang bato sa isang kweba sa bulubundukin ng Montalban, Rizal. Pinipigilan niya ang pagbangga ng mga bundok sa isa't isa sa ilang bersyon ng kwento, habang tinatangka naman niyang makawala mula rito sa ibang bersyon. Sinasabi na nagkakaroon ng lindol o paggalaw ng lupa dahil sa pagtulak ni Carpio sa mga bato."},{"question":"වින්ස්ටන් චර්චිල් යනු කවුද?","answer":"වින්ස්ටන් චර්චිල් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය රාජ්‍ය නායකයෙක්, හමුදා නායකයෙක්, ලේඛකයෙක් සහ කථිකයෙක් වූ අතර ඔහු බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ඉතිහාසයේ තීරණාත්මක කාල පරිච්ඡේද දෙකක, 1940 සිට 1945 දක්වා දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධයේදී සහ නැවත 1951 සිට 1955 දක්වා අගමැති ලෙස සේවය කළේය. ඔහු දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධ සමයේදී ඔහුගේ නායකත්වය සහ අක්ෂ බලවතුන්ට එරෙහිව ස්ථිරව සිටීමට බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ජනතාව පෙලඹවූ ඔහුගේ කථා සඳහා ප්‍රසිද්ධය."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"baru berlatih hendak berlari, tersembam\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud membuat pekerjaan yang melebihi kebolehan sendiri."},{"question":"پرچم ایران دارای  چند رنگ است؟","answer":"۳ رنگ. پرچم ایران سه نوار افقی رنگی دارد که بترتیب از پایین قرمز، سفید و سبز هستند."},{"question":"Wat is het verschil tussen huisdieren en vee?","answer":"Hoewel beide dieren zijn aan het einde van de dag, komt het belangrijkste verschil gedeeltelijk in de vorm van perceptie en historisch gezien de relatie van mensen met bepaalde dieren. Huisdieren, zoals honden, katten, etc., worden meer gebruikt voor gezelschap en niet voor voedsel. Daarentegen worden vee, zoals koeien, varkens, kippen, etc., voornamelijk gefokt voor voedsel, namelijk vlees, melk, eieren, etc."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'keras ditakik, lunak disudu'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hendaklah diberikan segala perintah dengan bijaksana (dengan lemah lembut kepada yang menurut dan dengan memaksa kepada yang melawan)"},{"question":"Adigunjale ni Saidi, ibọn ibilẹ lo fi n da wọn laamu ni Festac","answer":"Saidi Adewale lorukọ ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogoji yii, ọdọ awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba, lo wa bayii, ibẹ ni wọn ti n ṣe e lalejo latari ibọn ibilẹ ti wọn ba lọwọ ẹ, wọn nibọn ọhun lo fi n daamu awọn eeyan lagbegbe Festac, nijọba ibilẹ Amuwo-Ọdọfin, l’Ekoo.Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, sọ f’ALAROYE lori ikanni wasaapu rẹ pe ọga ọlọpaa tuntun ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ yan si tesan Festac, CSP Fẹmi Iwasokun, lo ko awọn ẹmẹwa ẹ sodi lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, wọn bẹrẹ si i wa awọn ibuba tawọn janduku ati adigunjale n sa pamọ si lagbegbe ọhun kiri, ki wọn le palẹ wọn mọ.Eyi ni wọn n ṣe lọwọ ti wọn fi ri awọn gende mẹta kan lori ọkada ni randabaotu Aboju, lọna marosẹ Badagry, ni wọn ba gba fi ya wọn. Wọn ni bawọn afurasi ọdaran naa ṣe kiyesi i pe awọn ni mọto ọlọpaa to n tẹle wọn yii n le bọ, niṣe ni wọn ṣẹ kọna sinu igbo, wọn bẹ danu lori ọkada, wọn sa lọ.Ṣugbọn ọwọ tẹ ọkan ninu wọn, Saidi Adewale, awọn ọlọpaa si gbe oun ati ọkada ti wọn gun, o di teṣan wọn.Agọ ọlọpaa ni Saidi ti jẹwọ pe oun ko ni ibi pato kan toun n gbe, ibi ti ilẹ ba ṣu oun si loun n sun ni toun, nigba to tiẹ jẹ pe oru niṣẹ tawọn n ṣe maa n bọ si. Nigba ti wọn si beere iṣẹ ti jagunlabi n ṣe, o ni gbewiri lawọn, ole lawọn n ja, irinṣẹ toun si ni ibọn ti wọn ba lapo oun yii.Ibi to sọrọ de niyi ti wọn fi lọọ fa a kalẹ fawọn agbofinro ni Panti.Adejọbi ni iṣẹ iwadii ṣi n lọ lọwọ lori keesi ẹ, ati pe afurasi naa ti n ran awọn agbofinro lọwọ lati le tete ri awọn to sa lọ, atawọn to ku ninu ikọ adigunjale wọn mu, ki gbogbo wọn le lọọ kọgbọn ni kootu laipẹ."},{"question":"قال تعالى في سورة العاديات: ( فالمغيرات صبحا)، ماذا تُعني كلمة المغيرات؟، (الرياح الشديدة، الإبل، الملائكة، الخيل)","answer":"الإجابة: الخيل"},{"question":"كم يبلغ طول جسر الملك فهد ؟","answer":"الإجابة هي : يبلغ 25 كيلو متر ."},{"question":"Pasitọ wọ gau, ọmọ ijọ ni wọn lo lu ni jibiti","answer":"Pasitọ kan, Paul Ojo, ti dero ile-ẹjọ Majisreeti ilu Ado-Ekiti bayii lori ẹsun pe o lu ọmọ ijọ ẹ kan ni jibiti. O  gba owo pe oun yoo ba a ṣe iwe irinna lọ siluu Dubai, ko si mu adehun ṣẹ.Olujẹjọ, ẹni ọdun marundinlaaadọta ọhun, ni Inspẹkitọ Oriyọmi Akinwale sọ pe laarin oṣu keji si ikẹta, ọdun yii, lo huwa naa niluu Isẹ-Ekiti, pẹlu bo ṣe gba ẹgbẹrun lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹrin (N700,000) lọwọ Fakunade Ojo.Akinwale ni lẹyin ti pasitọ gba owo, to si ṣeleri fun Fakunade pe oun yoo ba a ṣe gbogbo eto iwe irinna naa niyẹn ko gbọ nnkan kan mọ, bẹẹ ni Paul ko da owo pada, eyi si pada di wahala laarin wọn.Nigba to han gbangba si ẹni to kowo silẹ pe ọrọ naa ki i ṣe ere rara lo gba ọdọ awọn ọlọpaa lọ pe oun ko ri owo tabi iwe, eyi to fi han pe pasitọ oun ti lu oun ni jibiti.Akinwale ni abala kin-in-ni ati ikẹjọ ofin to gbogun ti jibiti lilu ni olujẹjọ ṣẹ si, oun si ti fi ẹda iwe ẹsun ọhun ṣọwọ si ẹka to n gba ile-ẹjọ nimọran (DPP) ki wọn le sọ igbesẹ to kan.O waa ni ki kootu naa sun igbẹjọ siwaju, ki wọn si fi afurasi naa pamọ sọgba ẹwọn.Pẹlu bi ẹjọ naa ṣe lọ, ko sẹni to beere nnkan kan lọwọ pasitọ ọhun ti Majisreeti-agba Adefunmike Anoma fi ni ki wọn lọọ fi i pamọ sọgba ẹwọn, ati pe kootu naa yoo duro di igbesẹ DPP.Igbẹjọ yoo bẹrẹ lọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu yii."},{"question":"Yawan ma'aikata a sashen kiwon lafiya a Kano, Nijeriya.","answer":"Akwai maikatan lafiya guda 19000 (a shekara ta 2022) a kano, Nigeria."},{"question":"*كم نجمة على علم أستراليا؟","answer":"6 نجوم"},{"question":"Traduci la seguente frase dall'inglese all'italiano:\\"Where is the closest bus stop?\\"","answer":"La traduzione in italiano della frase \\"Where is the closest bus stop\\" è la seguente:\\"Dove si trova la fermata dell'autobus più vicina?\\""},{"question":"ලෝකයේ විශාලතම මිරිදිය විල කුමක්ද?","answer":"කැනඩාවේ සුපීරියර් විල"},{"question":"ما هي الإنفلونزا الإسبانية ومتى بدأت بالإنتشار؟","answer":"جائحة إنفلونزا 1918 أو ما عرف بالإنفلونزا الأسبانية أو الوافدة الإسبانيولية هي جائحة إنفلونزا قاتلة انتشرت في أعقاب الحرب العالمية الأولى في أوروبا والعالم وخلفت ملايين القتلى، وتسبب بهذه الجائحة نوع خبيث ومدمر من فيروس الإنفلونزا (أ) من نوع فيروس الإنفلونزا أ H1N1. وتميز الفيروس بسرعة العدوى حيث تقدر الإحصائيات الحديثة أن حوالي 500 مليون شخص أصيبوا بالعدوى وأظهروا علامات إكلينيكية واضحة، وما بين 50 إلى 100 مليون شخصا توفوا جراء الإصابة بالمرض أي ما يعادل ضعف المتوفيين في الحرب العالمية الأولى.الغالبية العظمى من ضحايا هذا الوباء كانوا من البالغين واليافعين الأصحاء بعكس ما يحصل عادة من أن يستهدف الوباء كبار السن والأطفال والأشخاص المرضى أو ضعيفي المناعة.تسببت الأمراض المعدية في الحد من متوسط العمر المتوقع في أوائل القرن العشرين، ولكن متوسط العمر المتوقع في الولايات المتحدة انخفض بنحو 12 عامًا في السنة الأولى للوباء. تقتل معظم حالات تفشي الإنفلونزا بشكل غير متناسب الصغار جدًا والكبار جدًا، مع ارتفاع معدل النجاة لما بين العمرين، لكن وباء الإنفلونزا الإسبانية أدى إلى معدل وفيات أعلى من المتوقع عند الشباب البالغين."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--उडत्या पाखराची पिसे मोजणे","answer":"अगदी सहज चालता – चालता एखाद्या अवघड गोष्टीची परीक्षा करणे."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny volana jolay 2002?","answer":"Ny volana Jolay 2002 dia nitsidika an’i Madagasikara i Dominique de Villepin, Ministry ny raharahambahiny frantsay. Nanao sonia fifanarahana efatra izy sy ny Ministry ny raharaham-bahiny malagasy Marcel Ranjeva nandritra ny fandalovany. "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Nhiều vùng trên cả nước đón mưa dông kéo dài","answer":"Do ảnh hưởng của rãnh áp thấp kết hợp với vùng hội tụ gió trên cao nên ngày và đêm nay (31/7), khu vực Việt Bắc (Cao Bằng, Bắc Kạn, Hà Giang, Tuyên Quang, Lạng Sơn, Thái Nguyên), khu vực đồng bằng Bắc Bộ, Thanh Hóa và Nghệ An có mưa vừa và dông, có nơi mưa to với lượng mưa phổ biến từ 30-50mm, có nơi trên 70mm. Các nơi khác ở Bắc Bộ có mưa rào và dông, cục bộ có mưa to với lượng mưa từ 20-40mm, có nơi trên 60mm. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nguy cơ cao xảy ra lũ quét, sạt lở đất tại các tỉnh vùng núi Bắc Bộ và ngập úng tại các khu vực trũng, thấp. Hà Nội hôm nay nhiều mây, nắng gián đoạn, có lúc có mưa rào và dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió nam đến đông nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-26 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ. Dự báo mưa dông ở miền Bắc và các tỉnh Thanh Hóa - Nghệ An kéo dài đến hết ngày mai (1/8). Từ 2/8, khu vực này trời nắng, có nắng nóng cục bộ. Các tỉnh Hà Tĩnh - Thừa Thiên Huế hôm nay trời nắng, có nơi nắng nóng, chiều tối có mưa rào và dông rải rác, đêm không mưa. Gió nhẹ. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-27 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, phía Nam có nơi trên 35 độ. Các tỉnh Đà Nẵng đến Bình Thuận ngày mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối có mưa rào và dông rải rác, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 25-28 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, có nơi trên 34 độ. Dự báo từ chiều tối và đêm 1-2/8, miền Trung có mưa rào và dông rải rác, cục bộ có mưa to. Tây Nguyên ngày có mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối và tối có mưa rào và rải rác có dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 20-23 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 29-32 độ, có nơi trên 32 độ. Nam Bộ ngày có mưa rào và dông vài nơi, nắng gián đoạn, riêng chiều tối và tối có mưa rào và rải rác có dông, cục bộ có mưa to. Gió tây nam cấp 2-3. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Nhiệt độ thấp nhất 24-27 độ. Nhiệt độ cao nhất 31-34 độ, có nơi trên 34 độ. Dự báo trong nhiều ngày tới, Tây Nguyên và Nam Bộ tiếp tục có mưa rào và dông rải rác vào chiều tối và tối, cục bộ có mưa to, ngày nắng gián đoạn. Trong mưa dông có khả năng xảy ra lốc, sét, mưa đá và gió giật mạnh. Theo Nguyễn Hoài"},{"question":"සිංහල භාෂාව ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන ජාතිය වන සිංහල ජනයාගේ මව් බස සිංහල වෙයි. අද වන විට මිලියන 20 කට අධික සිංහල සහ මිලියන 3කට අධික සිංහල නොවන ජනගහනයක් සිංහල භාෂාව භාවිත කරති. සිංහල‍ ඉන්දු-යුරෝපීය භාෂාවල උප ගණයක් වන ඉන්දු-ආර්ය භාෂා ගණයට අයිති වන අතර මාල දිවයින භාවිත කරන දිවෙහි භාෂාව සිංහල බසට බොහෝ දුරට සමාන භාෂාවකි. සිංහල ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිල භාෂාවයි.ප්‍රාග් ඓතිහාසික යුගයේ පටන් පැවති හෙළබස ඈත අතීතයේ ඉන්දියානු භාෂා හා යටත් විජිත සමයේ බටහිර භාෂා සමග සම්මිශ්‍රණයෙන් වත්මන් සිංහල භාෂාව බිහිවී ඇත.සින්හල භාෂාවේ ස්වර 18 කි.සිංහල යනු මධ්‍යම ඉන්දු-ආර්ය (එළු ) \\"සිහල\\" යන වචනයට අනුරූප සංස්කෘත පදය වේ. මෙය \\"සිංහ\\" යන සංස්කෘත වචනයේ ව්‍යුත්පන්නයක් වේ. \\"භගවත පුරාණයෙ\\"හි සිංහලය, දිවයිනේ සංස්කෘත නාමය ලෙස සඳහන් කර ඇත. මෙම නම සමහර අවස්ථාවලදී \\"සිංහයන්ගේ වාසස්ථානය\\" ලෙසද හුවා දක්වා ඇත. මෙය අතීතයේ සිංහයන් බහුල වශයෙන් සිටින්නට ඇතැයි යන විශ්වාසය මත යෙදුනක් යැයි කිව හැකසිංහල බසෙහි උප භාෂා ලෙස තදින් බෙදීමක් දක්නට නොහැක. නමුත් ප්‍රදේශික වශයෙන් කතා කරන විලාශය හා ආවේනික වූ වචන හා යෙදුම් භාවිතයේ වෙනස්කම් දැකිය හැක. රජරට (උතුරු මැද පළාත), රුහුණ (දකුණු පළාත), ඌව (උව පළාත) මෙසේ වෙනස්කම් දැකිය හැකි පළාත් කිහිපයකි. නමුත් මෙම විශේෂිත යෙදුම් හා කතා විලාශ අනෙකුත් සිංහලයන්ට බොහෝ විට පහසුවෙන් තේරුම්ගත හැක."},{"question":"Đảo Bình Ba là đảo gì và nằm ở đâu?","answer":"Bình Ba là hòn đảo thuộc thành phố Cam Ranh, tỉnh Khánh Hòa, cách TP Nha Trang 60 km về phía nam. Đảo có diện tích khoảng 3 km2, với bãi biển hoang sơ, nước xanh trong vắt, di chuyển khá thuận tiện. Nhiều năm gần đây, Bình Ba là một trong những điểm đến nổi tiếng của khách du lịch trong nước. Đảo Bình Hưng, cách đất liền chỉ 1 km, là một trong \\"Tứ Bình\\" cùng Bình Ba và hai hòn đảo khác là Bình Lập và Bình Tiên.Trước đó, vào năm 2015, theo quyết định của Thủ tướng về quy chế đảm bảo an ninh, an toàn căn cứ quân sự Cam Ranh, đảo Bình Ba và Bình Hưng cùng khu vực mũi Hời đã không được phép phát triển du lịch. Tuy nhiên, nhiều năm qua các tour nhỏ và khách lẻ vẫn công khai thực hiện."},{"question":"भारताच्या कोरोमंडल किनारपट्टीवर सर्वाधिक पाऊस केव्हा पडतो?(A) जून ते सप्टेंबर(B) जानेवारी ते फेब्रुवारी(C) ऑक्टोबर ते नोव्हेंबर(D) मार्च ते मे=> ","answer":"(C) ऑक्टोबर ते नोव्हेंबर"},{"question":"Python میں موسمی ڈیٹا سیٹ میں دباؤ اور موسم کے درمیان تعلق کو مملکتوں کے لحاظ سے دیکھنے کے لئے بار چارٹس کا استعمال کیسے کیا جاتا ہے","answer":"پہلے، موسمی ڈیٹا سیٹ کو Python میں پڑھیں اور معلوم کریں کہ ہر مملک کا دباؤ اور موسم کے درمیان تعلق کی معلومات دستیاب ہے۔ اگر آپ کا ڈیٹا فرمیٹ ٹیکسٹ یا CSV ہوتا ہے تو، pandas کتابخانے کا استعمال کر کے ڈیٹا کو چھوٹی سی ڈیٹا فریم میں لوڈ کر سکتے ہیں۔اب، آپ کو معلوم کرنا ہوگا کہ کس مملک میں کتنا دباؤ اور موسم ہے۔ آپ ہر مملک کے لئے دباؤ اور موسم کی معلومات کو ایک لسٹ یا ڈیٹا فریم میں جمع کر سکتے ہیں۔ایک بار جب آپ کے پاس معلومات تیار ہوتی ہے، تو آپ matplotlib یا seaborn جیسی Python کی چارٹنگ کتابخانے کا استعمال کر کے ایک بار چارٹ بنا سکتے ہیں۔ بار چارٹ میں ہر مملک کو ایک بار کے ساتھ ظاہر کیا جاتا ہے، جہاں ہر بار کی چوڑائی دباؤ کو ظاہر کرتی ہے اور بار کی لمبائی موسم کو ظاہر کرتی ہے۔ اس طرح، آپ بار چارٹ کی مدد سے ہر مملک کے درمیان دباؤ اور موسم کے تعلقات کو دیکھ کر معلوم کر سکتے ہیں، جو مملکوں کے درمیان موسمی تبدیلی کو سمجھنے کی مدد فراہم کرتا ہے۔"},{"question":"Mẹ tôi thường mua muốt hạt về pha nước muối súc họng. Mẹ tôi nghĩ nước muối mặn mới tốt, giúp tiêu diệt vi khuẩn, còn nước muối sinh lý quá nhạt, không có tác dụng.Vậy có nên tự pha nước muối mặn và súc họng thường xuyên không? ","answer":"Muối có chứa thành phần chủ yếu là natri clorua (NaCl), góp phần hạn chế sự phát triển và tiêu diệt nhiều loại vi khuẩn, virus. Súc họng bằng nước muối thường xuyên có thể phòng nhiều bệnh đường hô hấp, giảm tình trạng viêm họng, cân bằng trạng thái pH của niêm mạc và lớp chất nhầy trên bề mặt niêm mạc họng. Nếu giữ sạch vùng mũi họng có thể tạo thành \\"chốt chặn\\" ngăn nhiều tác nhân gây hại đến đường hô hấp dưới.Nước muối súc họng có thể tự pha tại nhà theo tỷ lệ khoảng 1/2 thìa muối với 250 ml nước sạch. Nước có thể là nước lọc hoặc nước đã đun sôi để nguội. Muối nên chọn loại tinh khiết. Một số người cho rằng pha nước muối mặn súc họng mới tốt, giúp tiêu diệt vi khuẩn; còn nước muối sinh lý quá nhạt không có tác dụng là chưa đúng.Thói quen áng chừng lượng muối rồi pha vào nước, súc họng hàng ngày sẽ không tốt cho sức khỏe. Nếu pha muối quá mặn có thể ảnh hưởng đến niêm mạc họng, làm mất cân bằng độ pH của vùng họng, dùng trong thời gian dài dễ gây khô rát. Người có rối loạn điện giải, tăng huyết áp (thường gặp ở người lớn tuổi) nên lưu ý khi tự pha nước muối súc họng tại nhà. Trường hợp pha nước muối súc họng quá nhạt sẽ không mang đến tác dụng sát khuẩn.Tốt hơn gia đình nên chọn loại nước muối sinh lý pha sẵn, có bán tại các nhà thuốc. Vì nước muối tự pha tại nhà có thể không sạch, khó đạt được nồng độ phù hợp như nước muối sinh lý natri clorid 0,9%. Natri clorid 0,9% còn gọi là dung dịch nước muối đẳng trương, tức trong 100 ml dung dịch có 0,9 g muối; tương đương với nồng độ của dịch cơ thể con người gồm máu, nước mắt... trong tình trạng hoạt động sinh lý bình thường. Nước muối sinh lý được bào chế tại các công ty dược phẩm bảo đảm điều kiện sản xuất, trong đó có vô trùng nên an toàn cho sức khỏe."},{"question":"Joseph Levitch akava nemukurumbira saani?","answer":"Joseph Levitch, anonyanya kuzivikanwa nezita rezita rekuti Jerry Lewis, akave nemukurumbira semutambi weAmerica ane mukurumbira, mutambi, mugadziri wemafirimu, uye anobatsira vanhu. Akawana mukurumbira wakakura nekuda kwezvipo zvake zvevaraidzo uye philanthropy.Jerry Lewis pakutanga akasimuka kuve nemukurumbira sehafu yeane mukurumbira comedy duo \\"Martin naLewis,\\" kwaakabatana naDean Martin. Vaviri vakanakidzwa nekubudirira kukuru pachikuva, terevhizheni, uye mumafirimu muma1950s. Kuita kwavo kwakasimba uye kwakasimba kwakaunza kuseka kune vateereri mhiri kweUnited States nekumhiri.Mushure mekuparadzana naMartin, Jerry Lewis akaenderera mberi nebasa rake rakabudirira semuimbi wega. Akaita nyeredzi mumafirimu akati wandei nemakodhi, achitaridza yake yakasarudzika dhizaini inoratidzirwa nekuseka kweslapstick uye kusetsa kwemuviri. Akanga asiri tarenda rekuseka chete asiwo mutungamiriri ane hunyanzvi, mugadziri, uye munyori, achibatsira kune zvese zvekugadzira uye zvebhizinesi zvevaraidzo.Pamusoro pebasa rake rekuvaraidza, Jerry Lewis aizivikanwa nekuedza kwake philanthropic. Akabata runhare rwepagore rweLabour Day kukwidza mari yeMuscular Dystrophy Association (MDA) kwemakumi emakore akati wandei, zvichibatsira kusimudzira ruzivo nerutsigiro rwevanhu vakabatwa nemhasuru dystrophy nezvimwe zvirwere zvinoenderana.Kukanganisa kwaJerry Lewis muindasitiri yevaraidzo, nhaka yake yekusekesa, uye mabasa ake erupo zvakasiya chiratidzo chisingaperi pane zvese zvakakurumbira tsika nezvikonzero zvekubatsira vanhu."},{"question":"මියන්මාරයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"Naypyidaw"},{"question":"ทำไมรถยนต์ในประเทศไทยถึงวิ่งเลนซ้าย ไม่ใช่เลนขาว","answer":"ประเทศไทยในอดีตนิยมนำเข้ารถยนต์จากญี่ปุ่นกับอังกฤษ ทำให้รถยนต์ส่วนใหญ่ในขณะนั้นใช้พวงมาลัยขวากัน จึงทำให้กฎหมายไทยบังคับให้วิ่งบนเลนซ้ายเป็นหลักตั้งแต่นั้นเป็นต้นมา"},{"question":"Iza amin'ireto no efitra lehibe indrindra any Afrika?a) Ny efitra Saharab) Ny efitra Kalaharic) Ny efitra Namibd) Ny efitr’i Sahel","answer":"Ny efitra Sahara no efitra lehibe indrindra any Afrika."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: గడ","answer":"గడ పదానికి నానార్ధాలు: స్తంభం, సమూహం, పొడుగటి వెదురు కొట్టె"},{"question":"ਮੁੰਡਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਬੰਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੀ ਖਿੜਕੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਇਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਛੱਤ ’ਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੀ ਖਿੜਕੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਇਆ।"},{"question":"Сынган кылыч романдагы Ажыбай датка ким болгон?","answer":"Ажыбай датка – Кокон хандыгына жашынан аралашкан, Таластагы эл башылардын бири, Шералинин атасы Алим хан тарабынан бийлик кызгануу себебинен өлтүрүлгөндө, карындашын балдары менен Ордодон алып чыгып кеткен. Шералины тарбиялап, өстүргөн бир тууган таякеси. Шералинин Алтынбешиктин урпагы экенин санжыра аркылуу далилдеген карыя-даанышман. Шералини хан шайлоо Ажыбай датканын өргөөсүндө чечилет."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Benda ini potong ke tidak juga berguna, kalau potong, kita akan potong ke arah atas?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah seluar"},{"question":"What is the significance of model monitoring in MLOps?","answer":"Model monitoring helps track the performance of deployed models, detect drift, and ensure that models continue to meet their performance criteria over time."},{"question":"नेपालमा \\"परम्परागत निको पार्ने अभ्यासहरू\\" र परम्परागत निको पार्ने (झंक्रिस) को भूमिका वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"परम्परागत निको पार्ने अभ्यासहरूमा हर्बल औषधि र अनुष्ठानहरू समावेश छन्, जसमा झंक्रिसले नेपालको समुदायहरूमा परम्परागत निको पार्ने काम गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Inona ary izaho ?Tsy nify tsy vazana nefa tsy mandà sakafo ","answer":"afo no  tsy mandà sakafo nefa sady tsy nify no tsy vazana"},{"question":"Answer the following question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Question: శరీరంలో ఎన్ని ఎముకలు ఉంటాయి?Topic: మానవ శరీరముArticle: మానవ శరీరము బాహ్యంగా కనిపించే నిర్మాణము. మానవుని శరీరములో తల, మెడ, మొండెం, రెండు కాళ్ళు మరియు రెండు చేతులు ఉంటాయి. సరాసరి మానవుని పొడవు 1.6 మీటర్లు (5.6 అడుగులు). ఇది వారివారి జన్యువులమీద ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది.మానవ శరీరము వివిధరకాలైన వ్యవస్థలు (systems), అంగాలు (organs), కణజాలాలు (tissues) మరియు కణాలు (cells) తో చేయబడివుంది. శరీర నిర్మాణ శాస్త్రము (anatomy) వీటన్నింటి గురించి తెలియజేస్తుంది. మానవ శరీరము పనిచేసే విధానాల్ని తెలియజేసేది శరీర ధర్మ శాస్త్రము (physiology).జీవమున్నంత వరకు మానవున్ని 'శరీరము' అని, మరణము తర్వాత 'శవము' అని అంటారు.మానవ శరీరములోని వ్యవస్థలుజీర్ణ వ్యవస్థమూత్ర వ్యవస్థరక్త ప్రసరణ వ్యవస్థనాడీ వ్యవస్థశ్వాస వ్యవస్థపురుష జననేంద్రియ వ్యవస్థస్త్రీ జననేంద్రియ వ్యవస్థశోషరస వ్యవస్థఅస్థిపంజర వ్యవస్థమానవ శరీరములోని భాగాలుతల మరియు మెడమెదడుముఖంచెవులుకళ్ళునోరునాలుకపళ్ళుముక్కుస్వరపేటికగొంతులాలాజల గ్రంధులుపియూష గ్రంధిఅవటు గ్రంధి (థైరాయిడ్)పారాథైరాయిడ్ గ్రంధివీపు (వెనుకభాగం)వెన్నెముకవెన్నుపూసలువెన్నుపాముఛాతీవక్షోజాలుఊపిరితిత్తులుగుండెఅన్నవాహికఉదరవితానము (డయాఫ్రం)బాలగ్రంధిఉదరముజీర్ణకోశంపేగులు (చిన్న ప్రేగు+పెద్ద ప్రేగు)కాలేయంప్లీహముక్లోమముమూత్రపిండాలుఅధివృక్క గ్రంధి (అడ్రినల్ గ్రంధి)ఉండుకము (అపెండిక్స్)నాభికటికటి (పెల్విస్)త్రికాస్థి/ త్రికము (శాక్రం)గుదాస్థి/ అనుత్రికము (కాకీక్స్)అండాశయాలుఫెలోపియన్ నాళాలుగర్భాశయంయోనిక్లైటోరిస్మూత్రాశయంవృషణాలుశుక్రకోశంశుక్రవాహికలుపౌరుష గ్రంథిపురీషనాళముగుదముశిశ్నముకాళ్ళు మరియు చేతులుకండరాలుఎముకలుకీళ్ళురక్తనాళాలునాడులుభుజందండచేయిమోచేయిముంజేయిమణికట్టుచేయిచేతివేళ్లుతొడమోకాలుముంగాలుమడమపాదముకాలివేళ్లుమానవ శరీరములోని కణజాలాలుఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసరళ ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసరళ శల్కల ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసరళ ఘనాకార ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసరళ స్తంభాకార ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసరళ స్తంభాకార శైలికా ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుమిధ్యాస్త్వరిత ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసంయుక్త ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుస్తరిత ఘనాకార ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుస్తరిత స్తంభాకార ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుస్తరిత కేరాటిన్ సహిత శల్కల ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుస్తరిత కెరాటిన రహిగ ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుఅవస్థాంతర ఉపకళా కణజాలాలుసంయోజక లేదా ఆధార కణజాలాలువాస్తవిక సంయోజక కణజాలాలుమాత్రిక పలచగా ఉన్న (అసాంద్రీయ) సంయోజక కణజాలాలుఅరియోలర్ సంయోజక...","answer":"216. "},{"question":"\\"ලංකා  ලංකා  පෙම්බර ලංකා\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"ලංකා ලංකා පෙම්බර ලංකා පිනවමු ඔබ ලංකාහොබවමු ඔබ ලංකා දිවි දී සුරකිමු ඔබ ලංකාබලිතරු රාවණ ගැමුණු විජයබා නිරිඳුන් ලද ලංකාපුලතිසි දැමි සිරි රහල් කුමරතුඟු පඬුවන් ලද ලංකාවිදු සක්විති මහ පැරැකුම් කිවිසුරු කිවියන් ලද ලංකාඔබ රැකුනොත් ලෝ කුඹුවද අප හට සීත ගඟුල ලංකාමහවැලි කළු කැළණි වලවේ අත් හතරක් ඇති ලංකාසමනොළ කිරිගල් පිදුරුතලා නෙක කෙහෙ ගැට බැඳි ලංකාතේ වතු පොල් වතු කෙත් වතු පෙළ උකුලේ නලවන ලංකාමුහුදින් අඟලක් ඔබ වැව හොත් එහි පනිමු පනිමු ලංකාහෙළ මුතු මිණි වැල් එකට දමාලා ඔබ සරසමු ලංකාගස් වැල් වලැ මල් එකට ගොතාලා ඔබ පළඳමු ලංකාරුහුණේ කිරි පැණි එකට අනාලා ඔබ පිනවමු ලංකාඔබ වෙනුවෙන් එන වෙඩි සැර මල් පෙති සේ සලකමු ලංකාඔබ හට අත පොවනට උන් මුන් හට ඉඩ නොතබමු ලංකාඅවහොත් මෙහි උන් ලුහුබඳවා ගොළු මුහුද ගෙවමු ලංකාගොඩ දිය අහසේ හැමතැනැ ඔබගේ නම කියවමු ලංකාඅවසනැ ඔබට මැ පොහොරට මේ කය මෙහි මැ හොවමු ලංකාසුනිල් ශාන්ත, අයිවෝ ඩෙනිස්අරිසෙන් අහුබුදුසුනිල් ශාන්ත "},{"question":"Isikan tempat kosong berikut dengan jawapan yang sesuai: \\"Mak Cik Hasnah sedang ___________bawang di dapur.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah menumbuk."},{"question":"أعطني مثالاً على المعلومات العامة في هذه الفئة: الكتب.","answer":"ما الكتاب الذي ألفه هانتر تومسون وصدر في عام 1971؟ Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  ubadka aan Aabe mooyee Awoowe Laheyn?","answer":"Waa ilma Aadan (CS)."},{"question":"በግራኝ መሃመድ ወረራ ምክንያት ኢትዮጵያ ከየትኛው የአውሮፓ ሀገር ጋር ግንኙነት ፈጠረች?","answer":"ከፖርቱጋሎች"},{"question":"أريد أن أتعلم الشعر. أنشيء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الطويل.","answer":"حسناً بالتأكيد: وَلا قِرنَ إِلّا أَدمَعَ الطَعنُ نَحرَهُوَما غَسَلَتهُ بِالدُموعِ مَدامِعُهوَيَومٍ كَأَنَّ السَمهَرِيَّ عُيونُهُإِلى المَوتِ وَالنَقعِ المُثارُ بَراقِعُهيُخَرَّقُ مِنهُ كُلُّ جِلبابِ مُهجَةٍعَلى أَنَّهُ في مَنظَرِ العَينِ راقِعُه."},{"question":"வினா:இந்தியாவின் தேசிய பாடல்?","answer":"விடை: வந்தே மாதரம்"},{"question":"వ్యాపార లక్ష్యాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"వ్యాపార ధ్యేయాలను ఆర్థిక ధ్యేయాలు, సాంఘిక ధ్యేయాలు, మానవ ధ్యేయాలు, జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలుగా విభజించవచ్చును.ఆర్థిక ధ్యేయాలు: వ్యాపారము యొక్క ఆర్థిక ధ్యేయాలు దిగువ వివరించబడినవి.1) లాభార్జన: వ్యక్తులు వ్యాపారములో ప్రవేశించడానికి ముఖ్య కారణము లాభార్జన. వ్యాపారము నడుపుటకు లాభమే ముఖ్యమైన ప్రోత్సాహకము. ఒక వ్యాపారము నిలబడవలెనంటే లాభాలు ఆవశ్యకము. లాభాలు వ్యాపార సంస్థ ఉనికికే కాక, వ్యాపార వృద్ధికి, విస్తరణకు కూడా అవసరము.2) వినియోగదారులను పొందుట: వినియోగదారులు తమ అవసరాలను, కోర్కెలను తీర్చుకొనడానికి వస్తు సేవలను కొనుగోలుచేసి, చెల్లించడానికి తగినంత మంది వినియోగదారులు ఉన్నప్పుడే వ్యాపారము లాభాలను ఆర్జించ గలదు. వినియోగదారులకు నాణ్యమైన వస్తువులను, సమంజసమైన ధరలకు అందించవలెను. కాబట్టి వినియోగదారులను పొందటమే ముఖ్యమైన ఆర్థిక ధ్యేయము.3) సాంకేతిక అభివృద్ధి: ప్రస్తుత పోటీ ప్రపంచములో ప్రతి సంస్థ నాణ్యమైన సరుకును సమంజసమైన ధరలకు అమ్మడానికి ప్రయత్నము చేస్తుంది. వ్యాపార సంస్థ విజయవంతము కావలెనంటే కొత్త డిజైన్లు, మంచి యంత్రాలు, కొత్త కొత్త వెరైటీలు అవసరము. అంతేగాక నూతన సాంకేతిక పద్ధతులను ఉపయోగించి ఉత్పత్తిని పెంచుట ద్వారా వ్యయాలను తగ్గించుకోవచ్చును.సాంఘిక ధ్యేయాలు: హెన్రీ ఫోర్డ్ ఉద్దేశ్యము ప్రకారము వ్యాపారము యొక్క ప్రాథమిక ధ్యేయము సేవలనందించుట మరియు అనుబంధ ధ్యేయము లాభాలను సంపాదించుట. సాంఘిక ధ్యేయాలను దిగువ విధముగా చెప్పవచ్చును.1) నాణ్యమైన సరుకు అందుబాటులో ఉంచి సరఫరా చేయుట: సంఘానికి అవసరమయ్యే వస్తువులను వ్యాపారము అందజేయవలెను. నాణ్యమైన సరుకు, సరసమైన ధరలకు అందజేయుట వ్యాపారము యొక్క సాంఘిక బాధ్యత.2) ఉద్యోగులకు న్యాయమైన ప్రతిఫలము: వేతనాలు, జీతాలకు అదనముగా లాభాలలో సమంజసమైన భాగాన్ని ఉద్యోగులకు బోనస్ రూపములో పంపిణీ చేయాలి. పనిచేయడానికి సుముఖమైన వాతావరణాన్ని ఏర్పాటుచేయుట యజమాని యొక్క విధి.3) ఎక్కువ ఉద్యోగావకాశాలు కల్పించుట: వ్యాపారాన్ని విస్తరించుట ద్వారా ఎక్కువ ఉద్యోగ అవకాశాలు కల్పించి, సంఘానికి సేవ చేయవచ్చు. సంపూర్ణ ఉద్యోగిత అనేది సంఘానికి చేసే ముఖ్యమైన సేవగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు.4) ప్రభుత్వానికి సహకరించుట: జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలను సాధించుటకు వ్యాపారము ప్రభుత్వముతో సహకరించవలెను. వ్యాపారము పన్నులను సకాలములో చెల్లించాలి. ప్రజాహిత సంక్షేమ కార్యములకు, ప్రభుత్వానికి ఇది రాబడిని ఏర్పరుస్తుంది.5) సాంఘిక సంక్షేమము: వ్యాపారము సాంఘిక, కల్చరల్ మరియు మతపరమైన వ్యవస్థలకు సహాయము చేయాలి. ఇవి స్కూళ్ళు, ఆసుపత్రులు, లైబ్రరీలు, వ్యాయామ సంఘాలు, ప్రయోగ సంస్థలను నిర్మిస్తాయి.మానవతా ధ్యేయాలు: మానవతా ధ్యేయాలు పనివారి బాగోగులు, వినియోగదారులు, వాటాదారుల సంతృప్తితో ముడిపడి ఉన్నది..1) యాజమాన్యము, పనివారి మధ్య సహకారము: పనిచేసేవారు కూడా మానవులేనని యాజమాన్యము గుర్తించాలి. ఉద్యోగుల కృషి ద్వారానే లాభదాయకత పెరుగుతుంది. కాబట్టి, వారుపడ్డ కష్టానికి ప్రతిఫలమును అందించాలి.2) పనివారి సంక్షేమము: పనివారికి భౌతిక అవసరాలు, గుర్తింపు, గౌరవాన్ని కాపాడుట మరియు పనిచేయడానికి తగిన వాతావరణాన్ని కల్పించుట ద్వారా వారు కష్టపడి పనిచేస్తారు. పనివారి ఆరోగ్యము, రక్షణ మరియు సాంఘిక భద్రతకు తగిన ఏర్పాట్లు చేయవలెను.3) మానవ వనరుల అభివృద్ధి: మానవ వనరులు వ్యాపారములో విలువగల ఆస్తి. వాటిని అభివృద్ధిచేయుట ద్వారా వ్యాపార వృద్ధి జరుగుతుంది. పనివారికి శిక్షణ, వైఖరి, నైపుణ్యాల అభివృద్ధికి వర్క్షాపులు నిర్వహించుట ద్వారా ఇది సాధ్యపడుతుంది.4) పనివారికి యాజమాన్యములో చోటు: పనివారిని నిర్ణయాలు తీసుకునే ప్రక్రియలో పాల్గొనేటట్లు చేయుట ద్వారా వారి వ్యక్తిగత వికాసము అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుంది.జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలు: వ్యాపారము యొక్క జాతీయ ధ్యేయాలను దిగువ విధముగా వివరించవచ్చును.1) జాతీయ అవసరాలు: వ్యాపారము వస్తువులను జాతీయ అవసరాలు, ఆసక్తులను దృష్టిలో ఉంచుకొని ఉత్పత్తి చేయవలెను. అరుదుగా లభ్యమయ్యే సహజ వనరుల వృథాను తగ్గించవలెను.2) వనరుల అభిలషణీయమైన వినియోగము: వనరుల సక్రమమైన కేటాయింపు, అరుదుగా లభ్యమయ్యే వనరుల అభిలషణీయమైన వినియోగము ద్వారా దేశము త్వరితగతిన ఆర్థికాభివృద్ధిని సాధించగలదు.3) వెనుకబడిన ప్రాంతాల అభివృద్ధి: అన్ని ప్రాంతాలు సమానముగా అభివృద్ధి చెందవలెనంటే పరిశ్రమలను వెనుకబడిన ప్రాంతాలలో స్థాపించవలెను. దీనివలన ఆ ప్రాంతములో జీవన ప్రమాణము పెరగడానికి తోడ్పడుతుంది.4).ఎగుమతులను పెంచుట: ఎగుమతులను పెంచడానికి, దిగుమతులపై ఆధారపడుట తగ్గించడానికి వ్యాపారము ప్రభుత్వానికి సహాయపడవలెను.5) చిన్నతరహా పరిశ్రమల అభివృద్ధి: ఉద్యోగ అవకాశాలు కల్పించుటకు, పెద్దతరహా పరిశ్రమలకు అవసరమయ్యే ఇన్పుట్లను ఏర్పాటు చేయడానికి చిన్నతరహా పరిశ్రమల ఆవశ్యకత ఎంతైనా ఉన్నది."},{"question":"Qual é a capital de Portugal?","answer":"Lisboa"},{"question":"Quels sont les 5 termes clés que je devrais connaître sur le solfège en tant que pianiste ? Définissez-les de manière concise.","answer":"Voici 5 termes clés de la théorie musicale pour les pianistes ainsi que des définitions concises :1. Gamme : série de notes musicales disposées par ordre croissant ou décroissant, souvent utilisées comme base pour les mélodies et les harmonies.2. Accord : trois notes ou plus jouées ensemble pour créer une harmonie. Les accords courants incluent les accords majeurs, mineurs et diminués.3. Signature de clé : un ensemble de dièses ou de bémols au début d'un morceau de musique indiquant la tonalité (centre tonal) et les notes qui seront modifiées tout au long du morceau.4. Signature rythmique : symbole numérique placé au début d'un morceau qui indique le nombre de temps dans chaque mesure et le type de note qui obtient un temps.5. Dynamique : symboles qui indiquent le volume ou la douceur d'un passage musical. Les dynamiques courantes incluent le pianissimo (très doux), le piano (doux), la forte (fort) et le fortissimo (très fort)."},{"question":"Nêu những dòng thơ có cấu trúc giống nhau trong khổ thơ cuối trong bài thơ Tiếng gà trưa Ngữ văn lớp 7?","answer":"- Những dòng thơ có cấu trúc giống nhau:+ Vì lòng yêu Tổ Quốc+ Vì xóm làng thân thuộc+ Vì bà+ Vì tiếng gà cục tác"},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Dragon Ball Z\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Dragon Ball Z\\" dia Akira Toriyama."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සිල් ගත් දෝතට පියුම් පිපෙනවාපින් හිත පුර හඳ බුදුන් වඳිනවාමිත්තණියේ නුඹ සිල් රෙදි පොරවාපන්සල් ගිය හැටි හිතේ මැවෙනවා","answer":"සිල් ගත් දෝතට පියුම් පිපෙනවාපින් හිත පුර හඳ බුදුන් වඳිනවාමිත්තණියේ නුඹ සිල් රෙදි පොරවාපන්සල් ගිය හැටි හිතේ මැවෙනවාබෝසත් සිරිතේ කතා කියා දීබෝසත් ගති ගුණ පුරුදු කළාබෝසත් දරුවන් රටකට බිහි කළමිත්තණියේ නුඹ නිවන් දකිනවාබාලේ සිට අප තුරුලට අරගෙනආල වැඩූ අම්මා වාගේපෑ සෙනෙහස රන් රුවන් වටිනවාමිත්තණියේ නුඹ නිවන් දකිනවාඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිරඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමිරෝහණ වීරසිංහ"},{"question":"Inona no iantsoanao an’ilay olona renin’ny reninao na ny rainao?a) ny rafozambavinyb) Rahavavyd) Nenitoae) Bebe","answer":"e) Bebe no iantsoanao an’ilay olona renin’ny reninao na ny rainao"},{"question":"Sókótó","answer":"Sokoto je ilu pataki kan ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria, nitosi idapomora Odo Sokoto ati Odo Rima. Ni Odun 2006, olugbe ti o wa ni be ju 427,760. Sokoto ni oluilu Ipinle Sokoto, o si je oluilu awon ipinle ti o wa ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria tele.Oruko Sokoto (oruko atijo re ni Sakkwato) ni ipilese Larubawa, je sooq ti o tunmo si oja ni Yoruba. Atun mo si Sakkwato, Birnin Shaihu da Bello tabi \\"Sokoto, Oluilu Shaihu ati Bello\\" Bello Umar Maikaset.Ibujoko Kalifu Sokoto teleri, esin musulumi ni o bori ni ilu naa ti o si je ibujoko pataki ti won ti n ko eko Islam. Sultanu ti o je oludari Kalifu ni adari elesin awon Musulumi Naijiria.Sokoto ni oju ojo ologbele-ogbele (Isori oju ojo Köppen BSh). O wa ni apa Sahel to gbe, Savana oniyanrin ati oke die si yiika. Pelu iwon igbona tabi otutu odoodun to saba ma n je 28.3°C (82.9°F), Sokoto je ikan lara awon ilu to gbona julo ni Naijiria, sibesibe iwon igbona tabi otutu ni osan saba ma n je 40°C (104.0°F) fun pupo igba lodun, gbigbe re kii je ki ooru poju. Osu keji titi de Osu kerin ni o ma n gbona julo, ti gbigbona re le ju 40°C lo. Iwon igbona tabi otutu ti o ga julo ni 45°C. Igba ojo beere lati Osu kefa titi de Osu kewa, nigbati ojo ma n ro lojoojumo. Ojo naa kii saba ma n pe, oyato si bi ojo ti ma n ro ni awon agbegbe ti ojo ti man ro daradara. Lati opin Osu kewa de Osu keji, ni 'igba otutu', ategun oye ti o n fe eruku Sahara ma n bo oju ojo. Eruku yii ma n bo oorun, o si ma n di iwon igbona tabi otutu ku lopolopo.Anfani ti agbegbe naa ni lati gbin irugbin ni ibi isan omi odo Sokoto-Rima, ti o ni ile olora. Awon irugbin ti won ma n gbin ni Sokoto ni jero, oka baba, ewa to fere poju, leyin re ni agbado, iresi, yamati/eeku, awon irugbin oka ati ewebe miran ni alubosa, tomati, ata, igba/ikan, letusi, ati kabeeji. Yato si jero, Sokoto ni o n pese alubosa julo ni Naijiria. Ni ti eweko, Sokoto bosi agbegbe Savana. Eyi jẹ ilẹ-koriko ti ko ni eṣinṣin tse-tse, o dara fun ogbin awọn irugbin ọkà ati osin ẹran. Òjò máa ń pe bẹ̀rẹ̀ ó sì ma n tete dawoduro pẹ̀lú ìwọ̀n idaji òjò odoodun láàárín 500mm ati 1,300mm. Awọn igba meji pataki lo wa ni Sokoto, igba otutu ati ogbele. Ogbele ma n bẹrẹ lati Oṣu Kẹwa titi di Oṣu Kẹrin ni awọn apa kan o si le di Osu Karun tabi Osu Kefa ni apa miiran. Igba otutu ni apa keji bẹrẹ ni Osu Karun titi di Oṣu Kẹsan tabi Oṣu Kẹwa ni opo ibi ni ipinle naa. Oye, gbigbẹ, otutu, ati afẹfẹ eruku ni iriri ipinle naa laarin Oṣu Kọkanla ati Osu keji. Ooru ma n po ni ipinlẹ naa ni Oṣu Kẹta ati Oṣu Kẹrin. Ṣugbọn oju ojo ni ipinle naa ma tutu ni owurọ o si ma n gbona ni awọn ọsan, yato si igba oye lile. Petele ti o wopo ni ile Hausa, apa ariwa Naijiria ni o poju ni ipinle naa. Ilẹ fadama ti o tobi pupo ti awọn ọna Odo Sokoto-Rima wa ni pẹtẹlẹ ti o si pese ilẹ olora ti o dara fun ogbin ọpọlọpọ irugbin ni ipinle naa. Awọn oke ati oke-nla wa kaakiri ipinlẹ naa.Shehu Usmanu Dan Fodiyo ti lo Sokoto ni ibere osu kewaa odun 1804 gege bi ibi ipade pelu Galadima, Yunfa's Vizier. Lẹyin naa, Muhammad Bello lo o gẹgẹbi ibi ikọlu Dufua ni ibere ọdun 1806. Bovil daba pe won ti mo agbegbe naa si Sokoto lati ibẹrẹ awon ọdun kẹtadinlogun. Ni iwoye itan, Sokoto ni a da sile bi agọ ologun ni ọdun 1809, nigbati Shehu Usmanu wa ni Sifawa. Lẹhinna o di olu-ilu kalifu lẹhin iku Shehu.Ni awọn ọdun 1820, Sokoto wa ni ipo giga rẹ ti aisiki ni ibamu pẹlu ipo giga ti awọn agbara 'awọn alaṣẹ' ni aarin kalifu, ti o n gba isakole lododun lati ọdọ gbogbo awọn fiifu ṣaaju ki agbara won to dinku. Oluwakiri Hugh Clapperton (1827) ni iwunilori pupọ nipasẹ aisiki yii ati awọn ipa rẹ lori ilu naa.Clapperton ṣe akiyesi pataki bi agbegbe Sokoto se sunmora won: awọn odo, dipo iṣowo jijinna, ni ọrọ-aje ilu naa. Ṣugbọn iṣowo Sokoto ko da bii ti tele mo, nitori ipo idamu ti orilẹ-ede ti o sunmo wa.Ni akoko ti oluwakiri Heinrich Barth de ni 1853, die eniyan lo n gbe Sokoto o si ti bajẹ pupọ. Barth ni 1857 ṣe iṣiro awọn olugbe ni 20,000-22,000, ṣugbọn ọja naa si n se daadaa, ati agbegbe eyin odi ti o dara ju Sokoto funrararẹ.Bovil ṣapejuwe ni deede Sokoto gẹgẹbi ipo ti o lagbara, pẹlu awọn apata giga lati ila-oorun si ariwa-iwọ-oorun ati afonifoji kekere kan ni iwọ-oorun ati guusu iwọ-oorun ti o daabobo lodi si awọn ikọlu alagbara aimotele. Ilu naa jẹ gaba lori ilẹ pẹtẹlẹ ti o gbooro nibiti awọn odo meji, Rima ati Sokoto pade, ti o jẹ ipade ọna lati Gobir ni ariwa, Kebbi ni guusu ati Burmi Zamfara ni ila-oorun.Ni ibẹrẹ orundun kọkandinlogun, ilu naa (Sokoto) ti pin si awọn eka. Irú àwọn eka bẹ́ẹ̀ ni ẹ̀ka Magajin Gari, ẹ̀ka Waziri, ẹ̀ka Sarkin Musulumi, ẹ̀ka Sarkin Adar, ẹ̀ka Magajin Rafi, àti eka Sarkin Zamfara. Ni akoko yii awọn wọọdu naa jẹ kekere ti wọn si fi odi yi wọn ka, pelu eyiti o wa ninu mọṣalaṣi Sultan Bello ati Shehu, Aafin Sultan ati awọn ile miiran ati agbo ile Shehu.Ni ọdun 1818, won fe odi naa si iwọn ti o ni awọn ẹnu-ọna ti o wọle ati jade lati odi Birni. Iru ibode ni Kofar-Kade, Kofar-Kware, Kofar-Rini, Kofar-Dundaye, Kofar-Taramniya, Kofar-Aliyu Jedo, ati Kofar-Marke.Agbegbe Sokoto ti o wa lọwọlọwọ jẹ ile ti ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba ti ìwọ̀ oòrùn Sudan ṣaaju ikonileru. Awọn yii ni ijọba Gobir ati Kebbi pẹlu kalifu olokiki agbaye ti olu-ilu ti ẹmi ati ti iṣelu jẹ olu-ilu ipinlẹ naa.Lẹ́yìn ìṣẹ́gun kalifu látọwọ́ àwọn Gẹ̀ẹ́sì lọ́dún 1903, oríṣiríṣi ẹ̀yà ara rẹ̀ ni wọ́n fi ṣe àdáṣe tí wọ́n sì darapọ̀ mọ́ ìjọba Àríwá Nàìjíríà. Ẹkùn àríwá tipa bẹ́ẹ̀ jẹ́ apá kan kalifu Sokoto àti ijoba Kanem-Bornu. Eyi tẹsiwaju titi di Oṣu Kini ọdun 1967 nigbati a ṣẹda awọn ipinlẹ lati rọpo awọn ijọba agbegbe nipasẹ Ajagun Yakubu Gowon. Sokoto di olu-ilu ipinlẹ àríwá ìwọ̀ oòrùn ti a ṣẹda ni ọdun 1967. Ni ọdun 1976 lẹyin idasile ipinlẹ Niger kuro ni ipinlẹ àríwá ìwọ̀ oòrùn, ipinlẹ Sokoto farahan pẹlu olu ile rẹ. Sibẹsibẹ ni Sokoto, ipinle Kebbi ati Zamfara ni won yo kuro ni Sokoto, ni 1991 ati 1996 lẹsẹsẹ.Ilu Sokoto ti jẹ olu-ilu fun ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba lati igba idasile rẹ nipasẹ Kalifu Muhammad Bello ni ọdun 1809.Ipinle Sokoto ni iye eniyan bii 3.7 milionu ti o da lori ikaniyan ọdun 2006 ti ẹya meji ti o jẹ Fulani ati Hausa . Ilu Sokoto, olu ilu ipinle Sokoto, ni iye eniyan ti o to 2.5 milionu. Yatọ si Fulani ati Hausa, eya kekere Zabarmawa ati Tuareg wa ni awọn aala ti ijọba ibilẹ. Gbogbo awọn ẹgbẹ wọnyi n sọ Hausa gẹgẹbi ede ti o wọpọ. Fulfulde ni awọn Fulani n sọ.Awon Hausa ni ipinle naa je Gobirawa, Zamfarawa, Kabawa, Adarawa ati Arawa. Awọn Fulani ni apa keji jẹ ti awọn ẹgbẹ pataki meji; ilu Fulani (Hausa: Fulanin Gida; Fula: Fulbe Wuro) àti awon awọn alarinkiri. Awọn akoko ni Torankawa, awọn idile ti Shehu Usmanu Danfodiyo, Sullubawa ati Zoramawa. Awon Torankawa jẹ kilasi aristocratic lati ọdun 1804.Ni aṣa, ipinle na jẹ isokan. Awọn eniyan ti ipinle na jẹ Musulumi, ati pe ẹsin Islam n fun wọn ni eto ti iwa ati ihuwasi. Ilana imura wọn tun jẹ ti orisun Islam. Awọn ayẹyẹ pataki meji ti o jẹ, Eid-el-Fitri ati Eid-el-Kabir ni won ma n se ni ipinle na ni odoodun. Ayeye akoko duro fun opin awe Ramadan, nigba ti ikeji wa fun pipa àgbo ni iranti ise Anabi Ibrahim (Abraham).Ijakadi ibilẹ (Kokawa) ati ese (Dambe) ni ere idaraya meji ti Hausa n gbadun nigba ti Fulani ati Sullubawa ma n daraya pẹlu Sharo ati Doro lẹsẹsẹ. Awọn alejo ti o ṣe pataki si ipinlẹ naa ni won ma n pe si ibi ayeyedurbar nla tabi kekere, ayeye ti o wa fun iwode ẹṣin ti a ṣe lọṣọ daradara ati awọn ibakasiẹ ti awọn ọkunrin ti o wo aso ogun ibile ati aso asa maa n gun.O ju ọgọrin ninu ọgọrun (80%) awọn olugbe ilu Sokoto ti o n ṣe iru iṣẹ-ogbin kan tabi omiran. Wọ́n ń pese irúgbìn bii jéró, okababa, àgbàdo, ìrẹsì, anoman, ege, ẹ̀pà, àti ẹ̀wà fún oúnjẹ, wọ́n sì ń pese àlìkámà, òwú, àti ẹfọ̀ jáde fún owó. Iṣẹ́ ọnà abẹ́lẹ̀ bíi alágbẹ̀dẹ, aso híhun, pipa aso laro, gbígbẹ́ ona àti iṣẹ́ áwọ̀ tún kó ipa pàtàkì nínú ètò ọrọ̀ ajé àwọn ará Sokoto; nitori eyi, awọn agbegbe oriṣiriṣi bii Makera, Marina, Takalmawa ati Majema di pataki. Sokoto tun jẹ ọkan ninu awọn agbegbe ti o n pese ẹja ni orilẹ-ede. Nitori naa, opolopo eniyan lẹba agbada odo ma n peja pẹlu.Bakanna ni Sokoto ni awọn ohun elo adayeba ati erupẹ. Awon ile ise ogbin ti o n lo owu, epa, oka, goomu, agbado, iresi, ireke, alikama, ege, goomu Arab ati taba bi awọn ohun elo ise ni won le dasilẹ ni agbegbe naa. Ogbin aladanla ni won tun le ṣe ni ipinlẹ na nipa lilo omi irigeson lati Daamu Goronyo, Lugu, Kalmalo, Wammakko ati adagun Kwakwazo laarin awọn miiran.Awọn ohun alumọni bii kaolini, gipisum, okuta-efun, lateraiti, awọn ọlọ pupa, fosifeti mejeeji ofeefee ati alawọ ewe, amọ iboji, iyanrin ati bẹbẹ lọ, wa ni awọn iwọn iṣowo. Awọn ile-iṣẹ ti o nlo awọn ohun elo ise wọnyi le ti fi idi mulẹ ni ipinlẹ naa.Àìsí esinsin tse-tse lórí ilẹ̀ pápá oko tí ó ṣí sílẹ̀ ní èrè fun àwọn ẹranko igbó àti ẹran agbéléjẹ̀. Sokoto wa ni ipo keji ni ipese ẹran-ọsin ni iye ẹranko ti orilẹ-ede ti o ju miliọnu mẹjọ lọ.Wiwa awọn agbara eto-aje wọnyi n pese awọn anfani idoko-owo to dara, ni pataki ni awọn ile-iṣẹ ogbin gẹgẹbi bii ọlọ iyẹfun, ṣiṣe awọn tomati, isọdọtun suga, awọn aṣọ, goomu, soradi, ẹja agolo, ati bẹbẹ lọ.Sokoto ko ni eto irinna gbogbo eniyan. Gbigbe laarin ilu naa (nigbati kii ṣe nipasẹ ẹsẹ) ni nipasẹ okada eyiti o ṣiṣẹ bi takisi eniyan kan ati nigbamiran awọn kẹkẹ ẹlẹsẹ mẹta ma n gbe eniyan lati ibi kan si ekeji; eyi ngbanilaaye fun gbigbe eniyan diẹ sii ju ọkan lọ ni akoko kan (sibẹ ni idiyele olowo poku bi awọn okada). Awọn ọkọ akero ati awọn takisi kii ṣe loorekoore ati pe wọn lo fun gbigbe laarin awọn ilu.Papa ọkọ ofurufu agbaye pẹlu asopọ deede si Abuja, Kano ati Eko wa ni kilomita mewa guusu si Sokoto.Ni Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 2008, won se adehun fun kikọ awọn iṣẹ simenti ni Sokoto.Didi ilu nla ni Ìtàn tó ti pẹ́ gan-an ní ilẹ̀ Hausa. Eto naa bẹrẹ nigbati awọn agbegbe ilana kan ti ilẹ Hausa ni idagbasoke lati Kauyuka si Birane. Sibẹsibẹ ọkan ninu awọn abajade pataki ti jihadi ni iyara ti iṣẹlẹ yii kii ṣe ni ilẹ Hausa nikan ṣugbọn ni gbogbo awọn agbegbe ti iṣakoso kalifu. Awọn ilu tuntun dide ati ilu Birane to ti pe wọ inu akoko idagbasoke ti a ko ri tẹlẹ, diẹ ninu won bi awọn agbegbe tuntun ti awọn iṣẹ iṣowo, awọn miiran bi awọn olu-ilu Emirati ati aarin gungun iṣakoso ati iṣowo.Ọkan ninu awọn ẹya olaju ninu itan kalifu Sokoto bẹrẹ pẹlu idasile ilu Sokoto (olu-ilu kalifu). Ki jihadi to sele, agbegbe laarin Ijọba Gobir ati Kebbi ni agbegbe ti a n pe ni “ilẹ awon arinkiri”. Sugbon pelu aseyori jihad ti Shehu Usmau dan Fodiyo (1804–1808) dari ati isegun ti awon jihadi lori awon olori ile Hausa, ilu Sokoto (olori ile ijoba kalifu) ni Muhammad Bello ko. Pẹlupẹlu, gẹgẹbi Abdul-Razaq Shehu ṣe akiyesi ninu iwe rẹ Sakkwato Birnin Shehu ), won ti ya aworan ilu Sokoto lori iwe nipasẹ Muhammad Bello paapaa ṣaaju ki won to kọ ọ. Bello, ọmọ Sheikh, wa ninu awọn ogagun baba rẹ ati awọn adari ogun. O ja ogun ti o lera julo ti o si gun julo, o si je ayaworan kalifu Sokoto Birnin Shehu.Ilu Sokoto gẹgẹ bi a ti ya aworan re nipasẹ ayaworan Muhammad Bello ni gbogbo awọn ẹya ara ti ilu ode oni pẹlu awọn ọna, awọn afara, ọja, ganuwa (awọn ibi agbara kaakiri ilu) ati pẹlu awọn ile-iṣẹ iṣakoso ati iṣowo. Lara awọn ile-iṣẹ iṣakoso ti Muhammad Bello ṣe ni Kanwuri, Binanchi, Galadanci, Alkalanci, Dogarawa ati bẹbẹ lọ. Sibesibe, yato si ọja aarin ti a mọ si Yardole, awọn agbegbe iṣowo miiran ti a ṣe nipasẹ Muhammad Bello ni Makera, Madinka, Marina, Siriddawa, Takalmawa, Runji ati Jirgawa. Ni afikun, ninu awọn ohun miiran ko si ilu ni boya ṣaaju jihadi tabi orundun kokandinlogun ile Hausa ti o le di ilu nla laisi odi ti o munadoko (ganuwa). Eyi ni a kọ pẹlu ọpọlọpọ awọn ibi agbara bi Kofar Aliyu Jedo, Kofar Dundaye, Kofar Marke, Kofar Rini, Kofar Kware, ati Kofar Taramniya, ati pe idagbasoke pataki yii fa ọpọlọpọ eniyan lati lọ kuro ni agbegbe wọn si ilu Sokoto fun iwalaaye.Lati akiyesi ti o wa loke lori bi kalifu Muhammad Bello ṣe ya aworan ilu Sokoto, a o ri pe Sokoto jẹri sii awọn aṣikiri ti o ni ifẹ si awọn iṣẹ alagbẹdẹ, ise awo, ohun elo amọ ati bẹbẹ lọ. Fun apẹẹrẹ, diẹ ninu awọn eniyan wọnyi ṣe iṣowo ti alagbẹdẹ tabi ni iṣowo miiran ti o jọmọ bi Makera Assada. Awon eniyan kan wa ti won maa n rin irin ajo lo si orisiirisii ilu Naijiria ati awon orile-ede to wa nitosi lati ra awon ohun elo irin to baje bii oko to yonu, oko ayokele, oko nla, oko ofurufu ati beebee, paipu irin, ati tanki epo ki won le tu won ka, ti won si n ta won fun ẹnikẹni ti o fẹ lati loo tabi yi wọn pada si ọja miiran."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Papagaio que acompanha João-de-Barro vira ajudante de pedreiro\\"?","answer":"A frase nos diz que se andarmos com uma pessoa, as ações dela podem acabar nos influenciando, seja de forma positiva ou negativa.Exemplo: “Aquele senhor não me passa confiança, é papagaio que anda com João-de-barro…”"},{"question":"أجب عن السؤال التالي: \\"كم يبلغ طول جسر الملك فهد ؟\\"","answer":"حسنا إجابة السؤال هي: \\"25 كم\\"."},{"question":"画框材质的种类有哪些","answer":"画框材质最为普见得是实木材质和PS发泡材质，主要的分类如下：实木。实木相框是最普遍的，而且比较百搭，非常自然的感觉卡纸。卡纸比较细致和平滑，是介于纸和纸板之间的一种厚纸，同时耐水性很不错。塑料。塑料比较轻便，不容易被腐蚀，但比较容易老化，所以并不适合长久性装饰亚克力。亚克力也教有机玻璃，硬度和透明度都不错的。树脂。基本上和塑料差不多金属。用金属来做照片墙，很独特，光泽度非常好，一般适合现代化的家居风格。铝。铝集合了塑料和金属的优点，轻便有质感。玻璃。玻璃相框是很漂亮的，家中有一组玻璃相框的照片墙很也表达出主人的品味，但唯一的缺点就是易碎。水晶。水晶相框比玻璃相框更上一层楼，有一种高贵典雅的气质。皮。皮质的相框很复古，有时可以和实木相框结合铜。铜质的相框也和皮质一般，显得比较复古，沧桑。"},{"question":"Koks yra klausimas: \\"2011 m. Bendrovė užregistravo 2,1 mlrd. JAV dolerių metines pajamas, todėl ji tapo 20-ąja didžiausia programinės įrangos kompanija pagal tų metų pajamas\\". Tema yra \\"BMC Software\\".","answer":"\\"Kokio dydžio yra \\"BMC Software\\"?\\""},{"question":"എന്താണ് അപ്പലാച്ചിയൻ ട്രയൽ?","answer":"കിഴക്കൻ യുണൈറ്റഡ് സ്റ്റേറ്റ്സിലെ പ്രശസ്തമായ ദീർഘദൂര ഹൈക്കിംഗ് പാതയാണ് അപ്പലാച്ചിയൻ ട്രയൽ, 14 സംസ്ഥാനങ്ങളിലൂടെ 2,190 മൈലുകൾ വ്യാപിച്ചുകിടക്കുന്നു. വൈവിധ്യമാർന്ന ഭൂപ്രകൃതി, പ്രകൃതി സൗന്ദര്യം, വെല്ലുവിളി നിറഞ്ഞ കാൽനടയാത്ര അനുഭവം എന്നിവയ്ക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട ഇത് ലോകമെമ്പാടുമുള്ള ഹൈക്കർമാരെയും പ്രകൃതി സ്‌നേഹികളെയും ആകർഷിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Een gerecht van ossenhaas, ganzenleverpastei en fijngehakte paddenstoelen, in bladerdeeg verpakt en in de oven gegaard. Over welk gerecht, genoemd naar een Engelse hertog, hebben we het? Graag de volledige naam.","answer":" Beef Wellington "},{"question":"Кайсы байыркы инсан көбүнчө Батыш философиясынын негиздөөчүсү деп эсептелет?","answer":"Батыш философиясынын негиздөөчүсү деп Сократты айтып келишет."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"પલંગ પાયે તને કુસુમમાળાવડે\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"પલંગ પાયે તને કુસુમમાળાવડે, બેહુ કર બાંધ્યો લાજ લોપી;માહરે મંદિરથકિ કોણ મૂકાવશે, શું કરશે સહુ શોક્ય કોપી.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"પલંગ પાયે તને કુસુમમાળાવડે, બેહુ કર બાંધ્યો લાજ લોપી;માહરે મંદિરથકિ કોણ મૂકાવશે, શું કરશે સહુ શોક્ય કોપી.તું વનમાળી કાહાવે, હું કુસુમ વનવેલડી, નીર નિત સીંચતો કાં અરોપી;ભ્રમર જાએ ફુલ, ફુલ મકરંદ વશ, કમળમાં હેત ન રહ્યોરે રોપી.પ્રીતનો કરનાર પ્રેમના પાત્રશું, તન મન પ્રાણ ત્યાં મેલે સોંપી;ભણે નરસઈઓ જેમ રીસ ઊતરે, ત્યમ તું શિખ શાણી દે રે ગોપી."},{"question":"Виріши математичну задачу: \\"Ціна товару становила 500 гривень. Через деякий час вона зросла на 10%, а потім знизилась на 10%. Визначте нову ціну товару.\\"","answer":"Оскільки початкова ціна товару становила 500 гривень, то після підвищення на 10% ціна товару становитиме 500 + 500 * 10 /100 = 550 гривень. Після зниження (проміжної) ціни товару на 10% нова ціна товару становитиме 550 - 550 * 10 / 100  = 495 гривень. Відповідь: 495 гривень. "},{"question":"Чыңгыз Айтматовдун учкул сөзүнөн жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Эң ириде өзүңдүн киндик кан тамган жериң тууралуу ойлонгондо, жалпы дүйнө тууралуу акыл калчайсың."},{"question":"Wọn ba oku ọmọbinrin kan nibi tawọn ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ ju u si l’Akurẹ","answer":"Oku ọmọbinrin kan ni wọn ba pade lẹgbẹẹ ṣọọsi nla kan to wa lagbegbe Oke-Ijẹbu, niluu Akurẹ, laaarọ kutukutu ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.Oku ọmọbinrin ọhun ti ko sẹni to ti i mọ ibi to ti wa la ri ti wọn fi aṣọ funfun we, ti wọn si tun ko awọn nnkan mi-in si ẹgbẹ rẹ nitosi oju titi ti wọn tẹ ẹ si.Ọkan ninu awọn to wa nibi iṣẹlẹ ọhun ta a fọrọ wa lẹnu wo ni ko sẹni to le sọ pato asiko ti wọn gbe oku ọmọbinrin ta a n sọrọ rẹ yii wa si agbegbe naa.O ni akiyesi ti awọn ṣe ni pe o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ awọn ọmọ Yahoo kan ni wọn lo o, ti wọn si fi oru boju waa ju oku rẹ sibi tawọn eeyan ti ba a nigba ti ilẹ mọ.Oku ọhun si wa nibẹ ti ko sẹni to ti i fọwọ kan an ni gbogbo asiko ta a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ lọwọ."},{"question":"Sobre qual evento importante esse texto é sobre: Em sua estreia na Fórmula 1, no dia 26 de julho de 2009, no Grande Prêmio da Hungria pela equipe Toro Rosso, Alguersuari completou a prova na 15ª posição. Os primeiros pontos na categoria foram conquistados no Grande Prêmio da Malásia, quando terminou a corrida na nona colocação.","answer":"Carreira do corredor de F1 Alguersuari, sua primeira corrida e seu primeiro ponto."},{"question":"Siapakah Ho Yuhang? Huraikan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 190 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Ho Yuhang (lahir 11 April 1971) ialah seorang pelakon, pengarah dan penulis skrip Malaysia.Dilahirkan dan dibesarkan di Petaling Jaya, Selangor, Yuhang mengambil jurusan kejuruteraan di Universiti Negeri Iowa di Amerika Syarikat, tetapi memilih kerjaya dalam penerbitan TV sebaik sahaja pulang ke Malaysia. Beliau dilatih sebagai jurutera tetapi menceburkan diri dalam pembikinan filem kerana minat dengan filem vintaj. Yuhang memulakan kerjaya dengan menerbitkan iklan pada pertengahan tahun 1990-an. Pada tahun 2000, beliau mengarahkan dokumentari Semangat Insan: Masters of Tradition yang menonjolkan keperluan untuk memelihara bentuk kesenian tradisional Malaysia. Beliau kemudian menduduki kerusi pengarah menerusi filem Min pada 2003.Beliau menerima pengiktirafan antarabangsa untuk filem Rain Dogs. Yuhang memenangi Anugerah Bakat Baru di Festival Filem Asia Hong Kong 2006 dan juga mengetuai pengarah terbaik di Festival Tiga Benua (acara tahunan yang diadakan di Nantes, Perancis, untuk meraikan panggung wayang Asia, Afrika dan Amerika Latin) pada tahun 2006. Pada tahun 2010, Ho mengambil bahagian dalam inisiatif IFFR Cinema Reloaded menerusi Untitled Project.Pada tahun 2020, Yuhang mengarahkan sebuah filem pendek bertajuk Kita yang dirakamkan menggunakan telefon pintar Vivo X50 Pro mengikut perspektif beliau."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم ابن عم خديجة بنت خويلد الذي ذهب الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم إليه عند أول نزول الوحي للرسول ؟","answer":"الإجابة: ورقة بن نوفل"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සරසවියෙදි හෙට විතරයි හමුවන්නේකිමද කුමරි නෙතු කඳුලැලි පුරවන්නේ","answer":"සරසවියෙදි හෙට විතරයි හමුවන්නේකිමද කුමරි නෙතු කඳුලැලි පුරවන්නේදොඹ සූරන මහ වැස්සේ තනි කුඩයේඅප තනි වී දොඩමළු වූ හැටි දෙණියේකොමල පපා මුකුළු හිනා පෑ දෙතොලේමතකද මහවැලි දෑලේ සපු සෙවණේකලා ශිල්ප රාජ ඉසුරු මල් යහනේඑදා ලපළු හෙවණේ සරතැස නිවුණේඅපේ මියුරු සීන පිරුණු රජ දහනේමෙදා සුවඳ පමණි ඉතිරි හන්තානේකෝල බැලුම් හෙලා රඟන පරෙවියනේමාල බැඳුණු ගෙල කුමරිගෙ හඳපානේහීනෙන් දැකුමට විතරයි ඉතිරි වුනේහන්තානේ කුමරියෙ නාඬන් ළසඳේගායනය: දයාරත්න රණතුංගසිරිසමන් විජේතුංගදයාරත්න රණතුංග "},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Tổng của hai số – 313 và – 211 là:A. 534.     B. 524     C. – 524     D. – 534","answer":"Lời giảiTổng của hai số – 313 và – 211 là: (– 313) + (– 211) = –  (313 + 211) = – 524.Chọn đáp án C."},{"question":"São Tomé moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"São Tomé moy péeyu réwum São Tomé et Príncipe"},{"question":"Aunti Sikira jẹwọ fun mi, o ni loootọ lọkunrin yẹn boun ṣe aṣemaṣe","answer":"Eke niyaale mi, Iya Dele. Eke gidi ni. Abi bawo lo ṣe mọ pe panti ti wọn mu wa sile wa, panti Aunti Sikira ni. Inu ile ni kaluku n sa panti ẹ si nigba taye ti daye ka maa ji ara ẹni ni pata kiri yii, ko sẹni to n sa pata ẹ sita ninu wa, emi o tiẹ ṣe e ri. Bi Iya Dele ṣe waa mọ pe panti toun ri lọwọ ẹni to waa fi ẹjọ sun Alaaji, panti Aunti Sikiria ni, iyẹn lemi tubọ fẹ ko ṣalaye. Ṣugbọn Safu to wa nibi to ti n sọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ fun wa ko le jẹ ki n maa lọ ọ nifun. Bo ba jẹ emi ati ẹ ni, mo mọ bi mo ṣe n mu un. Ṣebi Iyaale mi ni, Aunti Alakẹ Lakonko, mo mọ bi mo ṣe n mu un.Ṣugbọn iyẹn gan-an tiẹ kọ lọrọ to wa nilẹ yii. Ohun to wa nilẹ ti le ju bẹẹ lọ. Ọrọ to ba ti di ti famili Alaaji, o ni bi mo ṣe maa n da si i, nitori mi o ki i fẹ wahala gbogbo wọn. Mo mọ wọn daadaa. Aunti Sikira lo si ti duro to n bẹ mi yii, latigba to ti gbọ pe awọn eeyan yii n bọ lo ti n waa bẹ mi, to n pe ki n gba oun, yeye ọmọ ni i gb’ọmọ, irukẹrẹ ni i gb’ọmọ Ọrunmila. Emi o kuku mọ ibi to ti n gbọ awọn ohun Ifa to maa n ju lulẹ nigba mi-in, boya owe lasan si ni, abi ki lo kan ọmọ Ọrunmila ninu gbogbo ohun to wa nilẹ yii.Kinni kan ti mo laiki lọrọ ẹ, iyẹn Aunti Sikira naa ni pe bi ọrọ ba ti da bayii, yoo jẹwọ ni gbangba ni, ko si bi kinni naa ti le le to, yoo sọ pe loootọ ni, bi wọn yoo ba pa oun ki wọn kuku pa oun. Ko ju bẹẹ lọ. Ko si lojuti kan bayii, eyi ti n ko fẹ ninu ọrọ ẹ niyẹn. Bi eeyan ko ba ti lojuti, ko si ohun ti ko le ṣe. Aunti Sikira ko lojuti, ohun to si ṣe n ṣe bo ti n ṣe n kiri naa ree. Ṣugbọn emi ni kinni kan, iyẹn naa si ni pe aanu eeyan ki i pẹẹ ṣe emi, emi ki i fẹ ki aye da yẹyẹ eeyan silẹ, paapaa ẹni to ba ti mọ pe ohun toun ṣe ko dara, to si mura lati ṣe atunṣe. Bi ọrọ yẹn ṣe ri niyẹn.Ko pẹ ti Iya Dele kuro ni ṣọọbu ti Aunti Sikira funra ẹ fi de, bo ti ri mi lo sare wọle, nigba ti mo si ni ko jokoo, bo ṣe n jokoo bayii, o bu sigbe ni. ‘Iyaa wa, temi ti bajẹ o! O ti bajẹ gan-an! Ti ẹ o ba ran mi lọwọ lasiko yii, aye mi maa bajẹ patapata ni! Bobinrin yẹn ma ṣe n wi niyẹn. Emi o si fẹẹ bẹ ṣaaju, n ko fẹẹ sọ fun un pe Iya Dele ṣẹṣẹ lọ ni, mo fẹ ko fi ẹnu ẹ sọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ, nitori bo ba mọ pe Iya Dele ti waa ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ ni ṣọọbu, ko ni i fẹ bẹẹ rara, iyẹn si tun le dija tuntun. Nitori ẹ ni n ko ṣe sọ fun un, oju lagba i ya, agba ki i yanu.Funra ẹ lo si tẹnu bọrọ, o ni obinrin oloriburuku kan lo waa ba oun nile to n pariwo pe ọkọ oun n ba oun sun, to si mu panti kan dani to waa fi han Alaaji pe panti toun ni. Ohun ti mo kọkọ beere ni pe ta lo ni panti, lo ba n wolẹ. Mo waa ni, Aunti Sikira, lo ba gboju soke lo wo mi, mo ni ṣe loootọ lọkọ obinrin naa ba ẹyin naa sun. Lo ba ni loootọ ni, ṣugbọn ẹẹkan naa ni, pe ọjọ to ba oun sun yẹn naa ni iyawo ẹ ka awọn mọ, nitori ọkunrin naa loun o le gba otẹẹli, ati pe iyawo oun ti lọ si Ibadan, o maa pẹẹ de, afi bawọn ṣe wa lori moṣan ti iyawo ẹ de.Ninu gbogbo ọrọ yii, eyi to pa mi lẹrin-in ju niyẹn: Aunti Sikira funra ẹ lo fẹnu ara ẹ sọ pe nigba ti awọn wa lori moṣan lobinrin yẹn de, ori moṣan yẹn lo si n pa mi lẹrin-in nibẹ. Inu bi mi nigbẹyin ṣa, nitori mo beere ohun to fa a, mo ni ki lo n wa kiri, ki lo kuku de ti oun obinrin agbalagba bẹẹ maa maa ṣe iṣekuṣe. O ni oun ti mọ ọkunrin yẹn tipẹ, pe ki i ṣe pe awọn ṣẹṣẹ mọra, maanu-furẹndi toun n tẹle koun too pada si ọdọ Alaaji ni. Mo ni bo ba jẹ bẹẹ, ko yẹ ko tun sun mọ ọn mọ, gbogbo ohun to ṣe nigba ti ko ti i lọkọ, iyẹn ti lọ niyẹn, asiko to ti lọkọ, ko tun gbọdọ ya sibẹ yẹn mọ.Lo ba ni misiteeki ni, oun ko ni i ṣe bẹẹ mọ, ki n ṣaa jẹ ki wọn dariji oun, ki wọn fi eleyii fa oun leti, oun o tun jẹ ṣe bẹẹ mọ. Lo ba bu sigbe, o n ke. Ẹkun to n sun yẹn lo jẹ ki aanu ẹ ṣe mi, nitori bi mo ṣe n wo o to n sunkun yii, niṣe lo darugbo wa loju mi, gbogbo faari ati akọ to maa n ṣe ko si nibẹ mọ, emi to si jẹ emi ni igba ikolẹ ẹ, to jẹ emi lo maa n ditẹ mọ, emi naa lo waa sa ba yii, emi lo n bẹ pe ki n ma jẹ ki wọn le oun nile ọkọ yii. Mo waa ri i pe yatọ si pe o fẹran iṣekuṣe, o laiki Alaaji gan-an ni, ko fẹẹ fi i silẹ rara, ko si fẹ ko foun silẹ, aye ẹ niyẹn.Ẹni to ba ti fẹran ọkọ mi denudenu, ọrẹ mi ni o. O pẹlu ohun to jẹ ki n ran an lọwọ. Mo mọ pe Iya Dele fẹ ko ṣẹsin ni gbangba ni, bẹẹ tiẹ naa wa lara ẹ, abi oju wa nibi kọ loun ati wolii Sẹlẹ n fa a, ati ọkunrin to fẹẹ maa ra ọja lọwọ ẹ, ti iyẹn n jin in mọ ṣọọbu kan to wa nisalẹ Brown nigba yẹn. Tiẹ wa lara ẹ jare. Ohun ti mo ṣe kọkọ bu Aunti Sikira naa niyi, mo ni ko yee sunkun eke ati ẹkun iranu niwaju mi, pe ṣe bo ṣe dagba to yii, o fẹẹ sọ fun mi pe oun ko mọ pe agbere ko daa ni. Mo ni ti mo ba ti ran an lọwọ eleyii, lọjọ to ba tun ṣe bẹẹ, funra mi ni mo maa le e nile Alaaji. O loun fara mọ ọn, bi oun ba tun ṣe bẹẹ ki n le oun.Mo fẹẹ fi oko kan pa ẹyẹ meji ni, nitori ẹ ni mo ṣe sọ fun un pe Safu lo maa ṣiṣẹ ọrọ to wa nilẹ yii o, mo ni mo maa ran an lọ sọdọ awọn famili Alaaji, pe oun lo maa lọọ da wọn duro ti wọn ko fi ni i wa mọ, nitori ti wọn ba pe famili le e lori ko ni i daa. Loun naa ba ni ki n ṣe bẹẹ, pe aburo oun kuku ni Safu, owu loun fi n ba a ja lẹẹkọọkan. Ni mo ba pe Safu, mo ni iyaale ẹ ni iṣẹ kan to jẹ oun lo maa ba a ṣe e. Ọmọ yẹn loun ti ṣetan to ba ti jẹ iṣẹ iyaale oun ni.Ni mo ba ran Safu lọ si Agege ni ọjọ Jimọ, mo ni ko fun baba lowo, ko fun awọn Bọọda Lasisi ati awọn to ku ẹ lowo, pe ko waa ni ki Iya Walia waa ri mi. Ohun ti mo ni ko sọ fun wọn ni pe ipade ile Alaaji ko bọ si i mọ, mo ni ko ṣalaye fun baba pe ọrọ kekere gbaa ni, mo ni ma a yanju ẹ funra mi. Ọjọ yẹn naa ni mo pe Iya Walia pe ko waa ri mi. Asiko ti Safu wa l’Agege, Iya Walia wa lọdọ mi, mo dẹ ṣalaye fun un pe ko ma lọ sile ẹgbọn ẹ, ko dẹ ri i pe ko ṣeni to wa sipade kankan nile wa. Ni mo ba fun un lowo ọkọ, lo ba lọ. Bo ṣe jẹ pe lọjọ Satide, ko si famili kan to wa sile niyẹn o."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai cendawan tumbuh\\"?","answer":"Terlalu banyak pada sesuatu masa."},{"question":"What ethical considerations should be taken into account in data analytics?","answer":"Ethical considerations in data analytics are crucial, as the way data is collected, analyzed, and used can have significant impacts on individuals, communities, and society as a whole. Here are key ethical considerations to be mindful of:1. Privacy and Consent: Respecting the privacy of individuals whose data is being collected and analyzed is paramount. It is essential to obtain consent, where feasible, especially for sensitive data. Users should be informed about what data is being collected, how it will be used, and who will have access to it.2. Data Security: Ensuring the security of data to prevent unauthorized access and breaches is critical. This includes implementing robust security measures to protect data from cyber threats and ensuring that only authorized personnel have access to sensitive information.3. Bias and Fairness: Data analytics can perpetuate and amplify biases if the underlying data is biased or if the analytical methods are flawed. It's important to critically evaluate data sources for potential biases and design algorithms that are fair and impartial. Efforts should be made to mitigate any form of discrimination that could arise from biased data analysis.4. Transparency and Accountability: The processes and methodologies used in data analytics should be transparent. This means being open about how data is collected, analyzed, and interpreted, as well as the limitations of the data and the analyses. There should also be accountability for the decisions made based on data analytics, especially in high-stakes areas like healthcare, criminal justice, and finance.5. Data Accuracy and Quality: Ensuring the accuracy and quality of data is essential. Decisions based on poor-quality or inaccurate data can lead to harmful consequences. Regular checks and balances should be in place to verify the quality and accuracy of the data.6. Informed Decision-Making: Data analytics should be used to supplement human decision-making, not replace it. It's important to understand the context and the qualitative aspects that data might not capture. Over-reliance on data analytics without considering the broader context can lead to flawed decisions.7. Impact on Society and Individuals: Consideration should be given to the broader impacts of data analytics on society and individuals. This includes thinking about the long-term consequences and potential unintended effects of data-driven decisions, particularly in terms of social inequality, economic impacts, and individual rights.8. Compliance with Laws and Regulations: Adhering to relevant laws and regulations related to data protection, such as the GDPR in Europe, is crucial. These legal frameworks are designed to protect individual rights and ensure ethical handling of data.9. Sustainability and Environmental Impact: The environmental impact of large-scale data analytics, which often requires substantial computational resources, should be considered. Efforts should be made to minimize the carbon footprint of data storage and processing operations.10. Respect for Cultural Differences: Data analytics should respect cultural differences and norms, especially when dealing with data from diverse populations. Sensitivity to cultural contexts can prevent misinterpretations and misuse of data.By addressing these ethical considerations, data analytics can be conducted in a responsible and socially beneficial manner. This approach not only protects individuals but also enhances the credibility and public trust in data analytics practices."},{"question":"Pregunta: ¿ Quien escribió la canción de un río perezoso? Respuesta:","answer":"Fue escrita por Sídney Arodin "},{"question":"ਓਜ਼ੋਨ ਪਰਤ ਦੀ ਹਾਨੀ ਸਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਹਾਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਘੱਟ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕੀ ਕਦਮ ਉਠਾਏ","answer":"ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਰਸਾਇਣ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਓਜ਼ੋਨ ਪਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਨੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ । ਕਲੋਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ ਕਾਰਬਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਾਧੇ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਓਜ਼ੋਨ ਪਰਤ ਵਿਚ ਛੇਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਸੂਰਜੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਪਰਾਬੈਂਗਣੀ ਵਿਕਿਰਣਾਂ ਸਿੱਧੇ ਧਰਤੀ ਤੇ ਆਉਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਈਆਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਕੈਂਸਰ, ਮੋਤੀਆ ਬਿੰਦ ਅਤੇ ਚਮੜੀ ਰੋਗਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਣ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ । ਓਜ਼ੋਨ ਪਰਤ ਪਰਾਬੈਂਗਣੀ ਵਿਕਿਰਣਾਂ (UV-Rays) ਦਾ ਅਵਸ਼ੋਸ਼ਣ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।ਇਸ ਹਾਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਘੱਟ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ 1987 ਵਿਚ ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ (UHEP) ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹੀ ਸਰਬਸੰਮਤੀ ਬਣੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਲੋਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ-ਕਾਰਬਨ (CFCs) ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਨੂੰ 1986 ਦੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਤੇ ਸੀਮਿਤ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਵੇ । ਮਾਂਟਰੀਅਲ ਪ੍ਰੋਟੋਕੋਲ ਵਿੱਚ 1987 ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਲ 1998 ਤੱਕ ਕਲੋਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ ਕਾਰਬਨ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਵਿਚ 50% ਦੀ ਕਮੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਹੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ । ਸਾਲ 1992 ਵਿਚ ਮਾਂਟਰੀਅਲ ਪ੍ਰੋਟੋਕੋਲ ਦੀ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ 1996 ਵਿਚ (CFCs) ਤੇ ਹੌਲੀ-ਹੌਲੀ ਰੋਕ ਲਗਾਉਣ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਗਿਆ । ਹੁਣ ਕਲੋਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ-ਕਾਰਬਨ ਦੀ ਜਗਾ ਹਾਈਡਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ ਕਾਰਬਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਓਜ਼ੋਨ ਪਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਹਾਨੀ ਪਹੁੰਚਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਲੋਰੀਨ ਜਾਂ ਬੋਮੀਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ । ਆਮ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਇਸਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਲਗਭਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਭਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਰਕਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਕਾਰਜ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਨੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ-1. ਸੁਪਰ ਸੱਨਿਕ (Supersonic) ਜਹਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ।2. ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਵਿਸਫੋਟਾਂ ਤੇ ਕਾਬੂ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ।3. ਕਲੋਰੋਫਲੋਰੋ-ਕਾਰਬਨ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਨੂੰ ਸੀਮਿਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।4. CFCs ਦੇ ਵਿਕਲਪ ਦੀ ਤਲਾਸ਼ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Performance කියන එක \\"කාර්ය සාධනය\\" කියලා ගොඩක් තැන්වල නිල වශයෙන්ම පරිවර්තනය කරලා තියෙනවා. ඒක හරිද? ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු ගේ performance එක ගැන කතාකරන කොට, \\"He performed well\\" කියන එක \\"ඔහු හොඳින් කාර්ය සාධනය කලා\\" කිව්වොත් නිකං කුණුහරපයක් වගේ නේ. අනික මම දැකලා තියෙනවා \\"ජනාධිපති කාර්ය සාධන බලකාය\\" කියන එක \\"Presidential task force\\" කියලා පරිවර්තනය කරලා තියෙනවා. Performance කියන එකට, ඒ අදහස හරියටම කියවෙන සිංහල වචනයක් තියෙනවද? තියෙනවා නම් ඒ වචනය හරි, නැත්තම් හොඳ ගැලපෙන වචනයක් හරි කරුණාකරලා ලබාදෙන්න. ස්තුතියි!","answer":"වචනයක් තේරුම් ගත යුත්තේ සන්දර්භය අනුව ය. බොහෝ වචන වලට තේරුම් එකකට වඩා ඇත. එනිසා භාෂා දෙකක වචන දෙකක් සමපාත නොවේ.මතක හිටින උදාහරණයක් දෙන්නම්.Ass: බූරුවා, පස්සා පැත්ත.බූරුවා: එනම් සත්ත්වයා, ගෙවල් හැදීම වැනි වැඩ වලදී උඩ නැග සිටීමට සාදා ගන්නා, එහා මෙහා ගෙන යා හැකි අට්ටාලය.Kick him the ass යන්න \\"ඔහුගේ බූරුවාට පයින් ගසන්න\\" යනුවෙන් තේරුම් ගෙන අට්ටාලයට පයින් ගැසූ විට උඩ නැඟ සිටින මේසන් බාස් බිම වැටේ.ඉහත කියා ඇති පරිදි, Performace  යන වචනයේ අර්ථය තීරණය වන්නේ සන්දර්භය අනුවයි. ක්‍රීඩකයෙක් සඳහා  නම් \\"ඔහු මනා  ක්‍රීඩා  කෞෂල්‍යයක් දැක්වූයේය\\" වගේ කියන්න පුළුවන්. Performace report එකක් \\"කාර්‍ය සාධන වාර්තාව\\" වෙන කොට, theatre performance කියන එක නාට්‍ය සන්දර්ශනය වෙනවා."},{"question":"கேள்வி : சரியான விடையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக.பின்வருவனவற்றுள் தோல் கருவிகள் எவை?1) மிருதங்கம்2) பறை3) ஜால்ரா4) தவில்","answer":"பதில் :தோல் கருவிகள்1) மிருதங்கம்2) பறை4) தவில்மிருதங்கம்:மிருதங்கம் அல்லது தண்ணுமை என்பது தென்னிந்தியாவில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் ஒரு தாள வாத்தியமாகும். மிகப்பெரும்பாலான கருநாடக இசை நிகழ்ச்சிகளில், சிறப்பாக வாய்ப்பாட்டு நிகழ்ச்சிகளில், மிருதங்கம் முக்கியமாக இடம்பெறும். மிருதங்கம் தொன்மையான வரலாற்றைக் கொண்ட ஓர் இசைக்கருவி எனக் கருதப்படுகிறது. இதையொத்த இசைக்கருவி சிந்துவெளி நாகரீக காலத்திலும் புழக்கத்திலிருந்ததற்கான ஆதாரங்கள் உள்ளன.'மதங்கம்' என்னும் பழந்தமிழ்ச் சொல்லின் திரிபே 'மிருதங்கம்' என்னும் வடமொழிச் சொல் எனக் கருதுகிறார்கள். தமிழின் 'மெது' என்பதே 'மிருது' எனத் திரிந்தது.பெரும்பாலும் பலாமரக் குற்றியைக் குடைந்து இக்கருவி செய்யப்படுகிறது. இது, இதன் வட்டவடிவ முனைகளில், ஒருமுனை, மற்றமுனையிலும் சற்றுப் பெரிதாகவும் நடுப்பாகம் இவ்விரு முனைகளின் அளவிலும் சற்றுப் பெரிய விட்டமுள்ளதாகவும் அமைந்த ஒரு பொள் உருளை வடிவினதாக அமைந்துள்ளது. திறந்த இரண்டு முனைகளும் தோலினால் மூடப்பட்டிருக்கின்றன. இத் தோற்பகுதிகள் இரண்டும் தோலினாற் செய்த வார்களினால் ஒன்றுடனொன்று இழுத்துப் பிணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. வலது பக்கத்தோலில் \\"சோறு\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படும் ஒரு கரு நிறப் பதார்த்தம் நிரந்தரமாக ஒட்டப்பட்டிருக்கும். மறுபக்கத்தில் வாத்தியத்தை வாசிப்பதற்குச் சற்று முன்னர், மாவும் நீரும் கலந்த ஒரு கலவை தடவப்படும். நிகழ்ச்சி முடிவடைந்ததும் இது நீக்கப்படும். மிருதங்கம் இருந்த நிலையிலேயே வாசிக்கப்படுவது வழக்கம். பறை:பறை ஒரு தமிழிசைக் கருவியாகும். இது தோலால் ஆன மேளமாகும். 'பறை' என்ற சொல் பேச்சைக் குறிப்பதாகும். 'பேசு' எனப்பொருள்படும் 'அறை' என்ற சொல்லினின்று 'பறை' தோன்றியது. (நன்னூல் : 458). பேசுவதை இசைக்கவல்ல தாளக் கருவி 'பறை' எனப்பட்டது. பன்னெடுங்கால வரலாற்றைத் தன்னகத்தே கொண்டுள்ள பறை, ஓர் இசைக் கருவி மட்டுமல்ல தொல்குடித் தமிழ்ச் சமூகத்தின் சொத்து, தோலிசைக் கருவிகளின் தாய். தமிழினத்தின் தொன்மையான அடையாளம். உழைக்கும் மக்களின் இசைக் களஞ்சியம். தமிழர் வாழ்வியலின் முகம் என வருணிக்கப்படுகிறது. \\"பறை\\" என்பது ஓடும் இசையை ஒழுங்கு பெற நிறுத்தி ஓர் அளவோடு சீரோடு, ஒத்த அழகோடு நடக்க, இசைக்கு நடை கற்பிக்கும் கருவி என முனைவர் வளர்மதி தன்னுடைய \\"பறை' ஆய்வு நூலில் விளக்குகிறார். தவில்:தவில் என்பது நாதஸ்வரத்திற்குத் துணையாக வாசிக்கப்படும் தாள இசைக்கருவியாகும். கர்நாடக இசைக்கும் கிராமிய இசைக்கும் இது பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. இது தோம்பு உருவத்தில் மரத்தால் செய்யப்பட்டிருக்கும். விழாக்காலங்களிலும்,திருமணம், குழந்தைக்குக் காது குத்தல் போன்ற நன்நிகழ்ச்சிகளிலும் இதன் பயன்பாடு அதிகம். விலங்கின் தோலால் இழுக்கப்பட்டு வளையத்தைக் கொண்டு ஓட்டில் கட்டப்படிருக்கும் இந்தக் கருவியில் ஒரு பக்கம் மறு பக்கத்தைவிடச் சற்று பெரியதாக இருக்கும். தவில் வாசிப்பவர் ஒரு தோல் கயிற்றால் தனது தோளின் மீது தவில் கருவியை மாட்டி முழக்குவார். சிறிய பக்கத்தில் மரத்தால் செய்யப்பட்ட குச்சியினாலும் பெரிய பக்கத்தை விரல்களாலும் முழக்குவர். விரல்களில் அரிசிக் கூழால் செய்யப்பட்டு உலர்த்தப்பட்ட கவசங்கள் அணிந்திருப்பார்கள். பெரும்பாலான தவில் கலைஞர்கள் சிறிய பக்கத்தை வலது கையால் குச்சி கொண்டும் பெரிய பக்கத்தை இடது கையால் கவசம் அணிந்த விரல்களைக் கொண்டும் முழக்குவர். எனினும், இடது கையால் குச்சியையும் வலது கையால் விரல்களையும் பயன்படுத்தும் கலைஞர்களும் இருக்கிறார்கள்."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Tại cơ sở 2 Bệnh viện Bệnh Nhiệt đới Trung ương, ghi nhận trong khoảng 2-3 tuần gần đây, các trường hợp nặng tăng gấp 4-5 so với các tháng trước. Khoa Hồi sức tích cực hiện đang điều trị cho 25 bệnh nhân, đa số phải thở máy, oxy nồng độ cao; trong khi hai tháng trước chỉ tiếp nhận vài ba ca một tuần. Bác sĩ Phạm Văn Phúc - Phó trưởng Khoa Hồi sức tích cực, Bệnh viện Bệnh Nhiệt đới Trung ương cho biết: \\"Những bệnh nhân nặng ở đây đa phần có tình trạng suy giảm miễn dịch, tuổi cao hoặc mắc các bệnh nền nặng. Thứ hai là những bệnh nhân đã tiêm mũi 3, đã mắc nhưng thời gian mắc đã lâu khoảng 4 - 5 tháng, mũi 3 đã trên 6 tháng, vì thế miễn dịch bị giảm sút, có nguy cơ mắc và trở nặng''. Để đáp ứng nhu cầu điều trị tăng cao trong thời gian gần đây, bệnh viện đã thiết lập đơn nguyên điều trị COVID-19 tách","answer":"biệt với khu điều trị bệnh nhân thông thường tại Khoa Hồi sức tích cực và Khoa Virus - Ký sinh trùng. ''Chúng tôi đang đồng thời đối mặt với COVID-19 và vẫn duy trì việc điều trị các bệnh nhân thông thường. Chuẩn bị ứng phó với sự bùng phát của dịch cúm, sốt xuất huyết nên có những áp lực về giường bệnh nhất định'', bác sĩ CKII Nguyễn Trung Cấp - Phó Giám đốc Bệnh viện Bệnh Nhiệt đới Trung ương cho biết thêm. Áp lực về giường bệnh đang có nguy cơ trở lại khi tại Bệnh viện Đại học Y Hà Nội, số lượng bệnh nhân điều trị COVID-19 cũng tăng khoảng 30% trong những tuần gần đây. Hiện làn sóng dịch lần thứ 4 ở nước ta đã qua khoảng hơn 4 tháng, đây cũng là thời điểm hiệu lực vaccine suy yếu. Do đó, việc tiêm vaccine COVID-19 mũi 3, mũi 4 có ý nghĩa rất quan trọng để bổ sung lá chắn trước dịch bệnh, đồng thời hạn chế nguy cơ quá tải giường bệnh khi số bệnh nhân nặng tăng lên. Theo TS.BS Phạm Quang Thái - Phó trưởng Khoa Kiểm soát bệnh truyền nhiễm, Viện Vệ sinh dịch tễ Trung ương: ''Việt Nam đã mở cửa, mọi người đã quay trở lại cuộc sống bình thường và chấp nhận một tỷ lệ mắc ở trong cộng đồng. Tuy nhiên, để có thể hoàn toàn sống một cách thoải mái thì cần phải nỗ lực hơn nữa trong việc bao phủ vaccine, có các phương án dự phòng để tránh các ổ dịch bùng phát cũng như tránh quá tải bệnh viện''. Các chuyên gia dự báo trong thời gian tới, số ca nhập viện có thể tiếp tục gia tăng. Người dân nên tiếp tục thực hiện các biện pháp dự phòng cá nhân như khử khuẩn, đeo khẩu trang khi ở môi trường kín hoặc nơi đông người. Đồng thời, nên tiêm vaccine mũi 3, 4 để hạn chế số ca mắc và trở nặng. * Mời quý độc giả theo dõi các chương trình đã phát sóng của Đài Truyền hình Việt Nam trên TV Online và VTVGo! Từ khóa:"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：中國四大菜系中，以麻辣聞名的是哪一個菜系？","answer":"答案：以麻辣聞名的是川菜。川菜是中國四大菜系之一，以其辣椒和花椒的獨特風味而聞名，喜愛麻辣口味的人常常喜歡品嚐川菜。"},{"question":"සිංහල ජන කතාවක් කියන්න ","answer":"යහපත් වැඩට යහපත් විපාකඑක ගමක ගැමියන් නිතර ගමන් ගන්නා පාරක මැදට වන්නට විශාල ගලක් පෙරළී තිබුණා. නිතරම ගැමියන් පාරේ එහෙට මෙහෙට ඇවිද ගිය ද සියල්ලෝම ගල දෙස බලා, එය පිළිබඳව සැලකිල්ලක් නොදක්වා ම තම තමන්ගේ ගමන් බිමන් වල යෙදුණා.කිසිවෙකුට ත් එය ඉවත් කිරීමට සිතුණේ නෑ. ඔන්න එන්න එන්නම රෑ බෝවීගෙන ආවා. රාත්‍රී කාලයේ ගමන් ගන්නා විට ගලක් ඇති බව අමතක වීම නිසා, බොහෝ අය ගලේ හැපී බිම වැටී තුවාල සිදු වුණා.වැටුණු පිරිසද ඉක්මනින්ම නැගිට, තමාට තුවාල සිදු වී ඇති ද යන්න බැලුවා මිස ගල ඉවත් කර දැමීමට සිතුවේ නෑ. දින කිහිපයක් ගත වුණා. දිනක් දුප්පත් ගොවියෙක් කුඹුරු වැඩ නිම කර, රෑ බෝවී, නිවස වෙත යමින් සිටියා. හාත්පසම අඳුරු වී තිබුණු බැවින් පෙරලී ඇති ගල් ගෙඩිය මේ ගොවියාට පෙනුනේ නෑ.ඔහු ද ගලේ හැපී වැටෙන්නට ගියා.\\"මේ ගල මෙතන තිබුනොත් බොහෝ දෙනෙක්ට අනතුරු විය හැකි\\" සිතා, ගල පෙරලා පාරෙන් ඉවතට දැමුවා. ගල පෙරලන විට ගල ලෝහයකට වැදීමෙන් නැගෙන ශබ්දයක් ඇති වුණා. ඔහු ගල ඉවත් කළ තැන පිරික්සුවා. සඳ එළියට දිලිසෙන යමක් එහි තිබෙනු දුටු ඔහු එය අතට ගෙන බැලුවා.රනින් තැනූ බරැති පෙට්ටියක් එහි තිබුණා. එහි කොටා තිබුණේ \\"ගල පෙරලන්නා ට තෑග්ගක්\\" යනුවෙනි. ගොවියා ඉතා සතුටින් රන් පෙට්ටියත් ගෙන නිවසට ගියා."},{"question":"إيش أكثر مسلسل سعودي سوى جدل كثير من زمان","answer":"طاش ما طاش، مثل فيه ناصر القصبي."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hisap darah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud memeras keuntungan yang terlalu banyak. Contoh ayat: Penjual itu menghisap darah pelanggan-pelanggannya."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Bu ngeen ko deful, te du ngeen ko mën a def mukk, na ngeen ragal safara soo xam ne matt ma koy xamb nit la ak i xeer, te way weddi ya la ñu koy xaaroo.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Bu ngéen ko deful, te du ngéen ko man a def mukk, na ngéen ragal safara soo xàm ne matt ma ko'y xamb nit la ak i xeer, te wayweddi ya la ñu ko'y xaaroo."},{"question":"በጆን ሎጂ ቤርድ የመጀመሪያውን የቴሌቪዥን መግለጫ የተሰጠው መች ነበር?","answer":"1918 ዓ.ም. ( 1926 እ.ኤ.አ.)"},{"question":"Kızılay devlet mi özel mi?","answer":"Kızılay, tüzel kişiliğe sahip, özel hukuk hükümlerine tâbi, kâr amacı gütmeyen, yardım ve hizmetleri karşılıksız olan ve kamu yararına çalışan bir gönüllü sosyal hizmet kuruluşudur."},{"question":"Jakie są zalety lasów?","answer":"Lasy łagodzą klimat, gromadzą wodę, oraz poprawiają czystość powietrza. Dodatkowo spacer po lesie dla ludzi może redukować stres i zmęczenie, oraz poprawiać nastrój."},{"question":"Jimoh Ibrahim darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC l’Ondo","answer":"Ọgọọrọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC loriẹ-ede yii ni wọn peju peṣẹ siluu Igbotako, nijọba ibilẹ Okitipupa, lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọṣẹ to kọja, nibi ti gbajugbaja oniṣowo ni, Dokita Jimoh Ibrahim, ti kede ipinnu rẹ pe oun ko ba wọn ṣe ẹgbẹ PDP mọ, o ni oun ti darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC to n ṣejọba ipinlẹ Ondo lọwọ lati ọjọ naa lọ.Ojulowo ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP lọkunrin agbẹjọro ọhun tẹlẹ, ni kete ti Gomina ana nipinlẹ Ondo, Dokita Oluṣẹgun Mimiko ti sa kuro ninu ẹgbẹ Labour to wa, to si lọọ darapọ mọ PDP ni nnkan ko ti lọ deedee mọ laarin awọn mejeeji.Ninu ẹgbẹ yii kan naa ni Ibrahim ti dije ta ko Eyitayọ Jẹgẹdẹ ti Mimiko fa kalẹ ninu eto idibo gomina to waye lọdun 2016, eyi to ṣokunfa bi ẹgbẹ ọhun ṣe fidi–rẹmi latari ọkan-o-jọkan ẹjọ ti wọn pe ara wọn lori ẹni to yẹ ko dije.Eto idibo ku bii ọjọ meji pere nile-ẹjọ sẹṣẹ da Jẹgẹdẹ lare, ti adajọ si kede rẹ nigba naa pe oun lẹni to lẹtọọ ati dije lorukọ ẹgbẹ PDP.Ọrọ to kọkọ ti ẹnu ọkunrin yii jade lẹyin idajọ naa ni pe ko dun oun rara bi wọn ṣe da alatako oun lare, nitori pe ọbẹ ge ọmọ lọwọ, ọmọ sọ ọbẹ nu, ọbẹ ti ṣe ohun to fẹẹ ṣe.O ni inu oun dun pe erongba oun lori eto idibo to fẹẹ waye naa ti di mimusẹ ki wọn too da Jẹgẹdẹ lare.Loootọ lọmọ bibi ilu Igbotako ọhun ko duro sibi kan sọ fawọn eeyan pe oun ti kuro ninu ẹgbẹ PDP, sibẹ, ko ba wọn da sohunkohun lati ọdun bii mẹrin sẹyin, bẹẹ ni ko si fi bo rara pe Gomina to wa lori oye, Arakunrin Rotimi Akeredolu loun n ṣatilẹyin fun.Idi ree ti ipinnu to ṣe lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee ọsẹ to kọja ko ṣe fi bẹẹ jọ awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo loju pẹlu bo ṣe jẹ pe ọpọ wọn lo ti mọ ẹni to n ṣiṣẹ fun tẹlẹ ko too ṣẹṣẹ waa kede erongba rẹ lati darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC."},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਫਰਹਾਨ ਅਖਤਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ।","answer":"ਫਰਹਾਨ ਅਖਤਰ (ਜਨਮ - 9 ਜਨਵਰੀ 1974), ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ, ਪਟਕਥਾ ਲੇਖਕ, ਐਕਟਰ, ਪਲੇਬੈਕ ਗਾਇਕ, ਗੀਤਕਾਰ, ਫਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ, ਅਤੇ ਟੀਵੀ ਹੋਸਟ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- ሪቻርድ ብራንሰን የየትኛው አየር መንገድ ባለቤት ነው? መልስ፡- ","answer":"ድንግል አትላንቲክ"},{"question":"MUSKAZON hap diş ağrısına iyi gelir mi?","answer":"Oct 28, 2021 User 1: Diş ağrısı için en etkili ilaç. 10 dakikada etkisini gösteriyor."},{"question":"Awọn agbanipa yinbọn pa Abdulfatai to n dupo Magaji niluu Ballah, ni Kwara","answer":"Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Ajayi Ọkasanmi, ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe loootọ ni awọn kan ti wọn ko ti i mọ pa Abdulfatai Mọgaji, ẹni to n dupo Magaji Zeni. O ni Ọga ọlọpaa, Muhammed Bagega, ti paṣẹ pe ki iwadii to peye lori iku ọkunrin naa waye, ati pe ọwọ gbọdọ tẹ awọn to ṣeku pa a.Awọn agbebọn kan ti wọn fura si pe wọn jẹ agbanipa ni wọn yinbọn pa ọkunrin yii lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, niwaju ṣọọbu rẹ ni Ballah, lagbegbe Ẹyẹnkọrin, nipinlẹ Kwara.Awọn tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣoju wọn ṣalaye pe iwaju ṣọọbu rẹ ni Abdulfatai jokoo si lọjọ iṣẹlẹ naa, nibi tawọn gende mẹrin kan ti de lori ọkada, bi wọn si ṣe bọ silẹ, ọdọ rẹ ni wọn lọ taara, ti wọn si gbebọn fun un.Ọkunrin ọhun lawọn eeyan mọ daadaa gẹgẹ bii ẹni to n ta ilẹ lagbegbe naa.Wọn ni nigba tawọn yẹn de ibi toun pẹlu ẹnikan jokoo si, wọn ko tiẹ beere ọrọ kankan lọwọ rẹ, oju ẹsẹ ni wọn yinbọn fun un, ti wọn si poora kiakia. Ọkunrin naa ko lo iṣẹju kan to fi dagbere faye.ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn ti sinku oloogbe naa nilana Musulumi nile mọlẹbi rẹ to wa lagbegbe Alanamu.Ṣaaju asiko ti wọn pa a, Abdulfatai ti gba kootu lọ lati pẹjọ ta ko ẹni to wa nipo Magaji Zeni, Alhaji Sulaiman, ẹni toun pẹlu ẹ jọ dupo naa bii ọdun diẹ sẹyin.Ile-ẹjọ giga tilu Ilọrin to gbọ ẹjọ naa ti da a lare ninu idajọ rẹ, ṣugbọn eyi ko dun mọ Alhaji Sulaiman ninu, idi toun naa fi gba ile-ẹjọ ko-tẹmi-lọrun lọ niyẹn, ibi ni ile-ẹjọ ti kede pe oun ni ipo naa tọ si.Abdulfatai ko waa duro sibẹ, oun naa gbe ẹjọ lọ si ile-ẹjọ to ga ju lọ, ibẹ lẹjọ ọhun ṣi wa titi digba ti wọn fi gbẹmi rẹ.Ko sẹni to le sọ ibi ti iku ọkunrin naa ti wa, ṣugbọn iwadii awọn ọlọpaa ti n lọ lọwọ lori iku to pa a ati awọn to wa nidii rẹ."},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan langkah-langkah mengatasi masalah penderaan kanak-kanak. ","answer":"Dalam meniti arus modenisasi pada hari ini, pelbagai kemajuan dan kejayaan yang telah dicapai oleh tamadun manusia. Namun, kemajuan dan kejayaan tersebut tidak memberikan makna jika nilai kemanusiaan kita kekal ditakuk lama. Kita kadang kala digemparkan dengan kes penderaan khususnya yang melibatkan kanak-kanak berlaku dan menyebabkan kanak-kanak tersebut menanggung kesakitan atau meninggal dunia. Perilaku yang tidak waras ini sering berlaku kerana pelaku hilang pertimbangan dan bertindak untuk melepaskan amarah kepada insan yang tidak mengenal erti kehidupan lagi. Ketidak adilan ini perlu dihentikan dan dicegah agar masyarakat kita menjadi lebih baik daripada sebelum ini. Ibarat peribahasa, kerana nila setitik, rosak sesusu sebelanga. Maka, sebagai orang awam yang bertanggungjawab, wajar untuk kita bincangkan langkah-langkah mengatasi masalah penderaan kanak-kanak demi manfaat kita bersama.Pertama sekali, masalah penderaan kanak-kanak boleh diatasi dengan memberikan pendidikan tentang penderaan kanak-kanak kepada orang ramai. Untuk makluman semua, penderaan ini boleh berlaku dimana-mana sahaja samada semasa mereka bersama keluarga, di pusat jagaan atau di sekolah. Oleh yang demikian, pendidikan melalui media massa dan juga media sosial adalah mustahak untuk memberi kesedaran tentang perkara ini. Sebagai contoh, pesanan khidmat masyarakat di ruangan iklan siaran televisyen oleh animasi terkenal Upin dan Ipin yang memberitahu kanak-kanak apa itu penderaan dan bagaimana cara untuk membuat aduan. Kaedah ini sedikit sebanyak dapat mencapai golongan yang berisiko seperti kanak-kanak untuk tahu bahawa mereka sebenarnya didera dan boleh meminta pertolongan. Tuntasnya, memberi pendidikan tentang penderaan kepada kanak-kanak dapat membendung penderaan daripada berlaku kepada mereka.Langkah seterusnya untuk mengatasi masalah penderaan kanak-kanak adalah dengan membudayakan perkhidmatan kaunseling untuk semua lapisan umur masyarakat. Jika dinilai, kebanyakan kes penderaan berlaku disebabkan oleh pendera mempunyai masalah kesihatan mental atau tekanan jiwa. masyarakat kita masih mempunyai stigma seperti golongan lelaki perlu bekerja keras untuk menampung keluarga tanpa memikirkan kesihatan jiwa dan raganya. Akibat daripada memendam masalah dan tekanan pada diri sendiri, individu tersebut boleh bertindak di luar tabiatnya oleh kerana tidak mampu lagi untuk berfikir secara rasional atau waras. Justeru, setiap kita sebenarnya berhak untuk mendapatkan perkhidmatan kaunseling untuk meluahkan masalah dan tekanan yang ditanggung oleh diri sendiri. Dengan kepakaran seorang kaunselor, pastinya fikiran seseorang yang berada dalam tekanan dapat ditenangkan dan menjadi lebih rasional dalam setiap tindakan yang diambil. Izharnya, jika setiap diantara kita mempunyai ruang dan orang untuk mendengar dan memahami setiap permasalahan yang dihadapi, pasti masalah seperti mendera dapat dielakkan.Pada masa yang sama, masalah penderaan dalam kalangan kanak-kanak boleh diatasi dengan menjadi anggota masyarakat yang peka dengan keadaan sekeliling. Kita merupakan mata-mata kepada pihak berkuasa untuk melaporkan sebarang aktiviti atau perkara yang mencurigakan berlaku dalam kawasan tempat tinggal kita. Bukan untuk menjaga tepi kain orang tetapi budaya mengambil berat sesama jiran perlu disemai kembali. Masyarakat hari ini lazimnya menghabiskan masa di tempat kerja dan tidak gemar untuk meluangkan masa mengenali jiran tetangga. Namun, kelebihan yang kita dapati masa ini iaitu dengan adanya media sosial, wajar untuk kita manfaatkannya untuk kepentingan komuniti setempat kita. Menyertai atau mewujudkan sebuah kumpulan dalam aplikasi “Whatapps” yang terdiri daripada jiran tetangga dapat merapatkan ukhuwah dan menjamin keselamatan. Apabila sebuah komuniti yang prihatin dibina, tiada ruang untuk pendera melakukan penderaan dalam keadaan yang berisiko untuk mereka. Jelaslah bahawa dengan menjadi masyarakat yang peka dengan keadaan sekeliling, ia membantu membendung penderaan kanak-kanak daripada berlaku.Dari sudut pandang yang lain, masalah penderaan kanak-kanak boleh diatasi dengan mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat. Apabila masyarakat kita mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat pastinya perlakuan yang tidak mempunyai perikemanusian ini akan berlaku. Tamsilnya, masyarakat yang mengamalkan gaya hidup sihat akan mempunyai fikiran yang rasional dan mengelakkan diri daripada melakukan perkara yang sia-sia dan memudaratkan. Apabila seorang individu mampu menjaga kesihatan diri secara fizikal, mereka juga mampu menjaga kesihatan mental dan rohani mereka. Persis kata mutiara, badan cergas, otak cerdas yang bermaksud badan yang sihat akan melahirkan pemikiran yang sempurna akalnya. Selain itu, masyarakat yang sihat pastinya akan mengutamakan nilai-nilai murni dalam kehidupan khususnya nilai kasih sayang dan tanggungjawab dalam keluarga. Intihannya, masalah penderaan kanak-kanak dapat diatasi sekiranya masyarakat mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat.Sebagai kesimpulan, banyak langkah yang boleh digarap untuk membendung masalah penderaan kanak-kanak daripada berlaku dalam masyarakat kita. Sesungguhnya, institusi kekeluargaan penting dalam memebentuk keperibadian nusa bangsa kita. Jika insan madani dapat dihasilkan, masyarakat yang berminda kelas pertama dan ketrampilan tinggi akan dibentuk. Kejayaan membentuk modal insan yang cemerlang akan membawa negara kita ke tahap yang lebih baik dan duduk sama rendah dan berdiri sama tinggi dengan negara lain. Setiap pihak bertanggungjawab menjalankan obligasi masing masing dan memastikan anak-anak dan seluruh komuniti menetang penderaan dan berusaha mewujudkan masyarakat yang penyayang."},{"question":"வினா :தமிழ்நாட்டின் சுதேசி இயக்கத்தின் தந்தை எனப்படுபவர்A. வ.உ.சிதம்பரம்பிள்ளைB. இராஜகோபாலாச்சாரியார்C. சத்திய மூர்த்திD. சுப்ரமணிய சிவா","answer":"விடை :A. வ.உ.சிதம்பரம்பிள்ளை.வ. உ. சி என்றழைக்கப்படும் வள்ளியப்பன் உலகநாதன் சிதம்பரம் பிள்ளை, செப்டம்பர் 5 1872 – நவம்பர் 18 1936). ஒரு இந்தியா விடுதலைப் போராட்ட வீரர். பிரித்தானியக் கப்பல்களுக்குப் போட்டியாக முதல் உள்நாட்டு இந்திய கப்பல் நிறுவனத்தைத் தொடங்கியவர். இவர் தொடங்கிய சுதேசி நீராவிக் கப்பல் நிறுவனம் தூத்துக்குடிக்கும் கொழும்புக்கும் இடையே கடல்வழிப் போக்குவரத்தை மேற்கொண்டது. "},{"question":"“Obinrin Ti Kò Ni Orogún, Kò Ti Mọ Àrùn Ara Rẹ̀”: A Woman Who Has No Co-Wife Cannot Yet Identify Her Disease","answer":"Òwe yi fi ara han ni itan iyàwó Aṣojú-ọba, ti a ò pè ni Tinumi pẹ̀lú ọmọ rẹ̀ kan ṣoṣo, ọkùnrin ti a mọ̀ si Mofẹ́.  Mofẹ́ dàgbà lati fẹ obinrin.  Ó̀ yan obinrin ti à ńpè ni Àyànfẹ́ ni iyàwó àfẹ́sọ́nà.  Nigbati ó mú Àyànfẹ́ lọ han àwọn òbi rẹ, Bàbá Mofẹ́ gba Àyànfẹ́ tọwọ́-tẹsẹ̀, ṣùgbọ́n iyá Mofẹ́ fi àáké kọ́ri pé ọmọ ohun kò ni fẹ́ Àyànfẹ́.  Wọn bẹ̀rẹ̀ idi ti kò ṣe fẹ́ ki ọmọ ohun fẹ ẹni ti ó múwá, Tinumi kò ri àlàyé ṣe ju pé ohun kò fẹ́ ki ọmọ ohun fẹ́ “Àtọ̀hún rin wa – ọmọ ti kò ni iran”.  Ọmọ rẹ naa fi àáké kòri pé ẹni ti ohun ma fẹ ni Àyànfẹ́.Tinumi sọ àfẹ́sọ́nà ọmọ rẹ di orogún, gbogbo ibi ti ó bá ti pàdé Àyànfẹ ni ibi àjoṣe ẹbi ni ó ti ḿbajà pé ki ó dẹ̀hin lẹhin ọmọ ohun.  Àyànfẹ́ lé ọmọ rẹ titi ṣùgbọ́n ó kọ̀ lati dẹhin.Lẹhin ọdún marun ti Mofẹ́ àti Àyànfẹ́ ti ńṣe ọ̀rẹ́, iwé jade pé wọn gbé Bàbá Mofẹ́.  Gẹgẹ bi Aṣojú-Ọba lọ si Òkè-òkun.  Bàbá ṣètò bi ọmọ àti iyàwó ti ma tẹ̀lé ohun.  Ọmọ kọ̀ pé ohun kò lọ pẹ̀lú òbi ohun ti àfẹ́sọ́nà ohun kò bá ni tẹ̀lé àwọn lọ.  Bàbá gbà pé ọmọ ohun ti tó fẹ́ iyàwó, wọn ṣe ètò igbéyàwó fún Mofẹ́ àti àfẹ́sọ́nà̀ rẹ.  Lẹhin ti Mofẹ́ àti Àyànfẹ́ ṣe iyàwó tán, wọn tẹ̀lé Bàbá àti Ìyá wọn lọ si Òkè-okun lati má jọ gbé.Àrùn ara Tinumi, aya Aṣojú-ọba bẹ̀rẹ̀ si han nitori ó sọ iyàwó ọmọ rẹ di orogún.  Nigbati ọkọ rẹ ri àlébù yi, ó pinu lati wa orogún fun Tinumi nitori ai ni orogún ni ó ṣe sọ aya ọmọ rẹ di orogún.  Gẹgẹ bi a ti mọ, igbéyàwó ibilẹ̀ kò ni ki ọkùnrin ma fẹ iyàwó keji.  Nigbati Bàbá Mofẹ́ fẹ́ iyàwó kékeré, ọmọ àti iyàwó kó kúrò lọ si ilé tiwọn, inú rẹ bàjẹ́ nigbati o kũ pẹ̀lú orogún rẹ.  Ó jẹ èrè iwà burúkú àti ìgbéraga."},{"question":"Waa maxay Toxicology?","answer":"waa  barashada  waxyeelada  sunta  ah  ee  kujirta daawada. Pharmacolgist Wuxuu qiimeen kusameyaa waxyaabaha kala ah \\u0002Waxtarka iyo wax yeelada dawada kor meero sida saxda ah ee daawada loo isticmaalayo Daawadaan sida ay ushaqeyso iyo waxyaaba ay daweyneyso Ilaha dawada laga soosaaro(Source of  Drugs) ."},{"question":"ආහාරයට ගත හැකි මේදයන් මොනවාද?","answer":"ආහාරයට ගත හැකි සත්ව මේදයන් වනුයේ ඌරු තෙල්, මත්ස්‍ය තෙල්, බටර් හෝ එළගිතෙල්ය. ඒවා කිරිවලින් , මස්වලින් සහ සතුන්ගේ සමට යටින් ඇති තෙල් මගින් ලබාගනී. ශාකවලින් ලබා ගන්නා ආහාරයට ගත හැකි මේද වර්ග වනුයේ රටකජු, සෝයා, සූරිය කාන්ත තෙල්, තලතෙල්, පොල්තෙල්, ඔලිව්තෙල් සහ එළවළු තෙල්ය. මාජරින් සහ අනෙකුත් එළවළු තෙල් වර්ග ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍ය පිලිස්සීම සදහා භාවිතා කරනු ලබයි. මේදය සදහා ලබාදී ඇති මෙම නිදසුන් සංතෘප්ත මේද සහ අසංතෘප්ත මේද ලෙස වර්ගීකරණය කරයි."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn ji gbajumọ onisowo kan gbe n’llọrin","answer":"Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọṣẹ yii, lawọn agbebọn to dihamọra pẹlu ibọn ji gbajugbaja oniṣowo kan, Arabinrin Asiat Ishao, gbe lọ ni agbegbe Okoolowo, nijọba ibilẹ Guusu Ilọrin (South) nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ pe ni nnkan bii alẹ ti arabinrin naa fẹẹ kuro lọọfiisi rẹ to wa ni adojukọ Bioraj Pharmacy, Okoolowo Ilọrin, ni awọn ajinigbe naa yọ si i, wọn n yinbọn soke lera lera titi ti wọn fi le obinrin naa jade ninu mọto rẹ, ti wọn si ji i gbe sa lọ.Sikin tutu ati ẹja ni wọn sọ pe Asiat n ta ni ọfiisi rẹ. Titi di igba ta a fi pari akojọ iroyin yii, wọn o ti i gburoo awọn agbebọn naa. Bẹẹ ni wọn ko ti i pe mọlẹbi obinrin yii lati sọ iye ti wọn fẹẹ gba.Ṣugbọn awọn mọlẹbi ni awọn ti fọrọ naa to awọn ọlọpaa leti, wọn si ti fi awọn lọkan balẹ pe awọn yoo doola ẹmi arabinrin naa."},{"question":"કેપ્ટન અમેરિકા વિશે વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"કેપ્ટન અમેરિકા: સિવિલ વોર એ 2016 ની અમેરિકન સુપરહીરો ફિલ્મ છે જે માર્વેલ કોમિક્સના પાત્ર કેપ્ટન અમેરિકા પર આધારિત છે, જે માર્વેલ સ્ટુડિયો દ્વારા બનાવવામાં આવી છે અને વોલ્ટ ડિઝની સ્ટુડિયો મોશન પિક્ચર્સ દ્વારા વિતરિત કરવામાં આવી છે.તે કેપ્ટન અમેરિકાની સિક્વલ છે: ફર્સ્ટ એવેન્જર (2011) અને કેપ્ટન અમેરિકા: ધ વિન્ટર સોલ્જર (2014), અને માર્વેલ સિનેમેટિક યુનિવર્સ  માં 13 મી ફિલ્મ.આ ફિલ્મનું દિગ્દર્શન એન્થોની અને જ R રુસો દ્વારા ક્રિસ્ટોફર માર્કસ અને સ્ટીફન કફિલીની લેખન ટીમ દ્વારા સ્ક્રીનપ્લેથી કરવામાં આવ્યું હતું, અને સ્ટીવ રોજર્સ / કેપ્ટન અમેરિકા તરીકે ક્રિસ ઇવાન્સની સાથે રોબર્ટ ડાઉની જુનિયર, સ્કારલેટ જોહાનસન, સેબેસ્ટિયન સ્ટેન, એન્થોની સહિતના એક કાસ્ટની સાથે છે.મેકી, ડોન ચેડલ, જેરેમી રેનર, ચેડવિક બોઝમેન, પોલ બેટ્ટેની, એલિઝાબેથ ઓલસન, પોલ રડ, એમિલી વેનકમ્પ, મેરિસા ટોમેઇ, ટોમ હોલેન્ડ, ફ્રેન્ક ગ્રિલો, માર્ટિન ફ્રીમેન, વિલિયમ હર્ટ અને ડેનિયલ બ્રહલ.કેપ્ટન અમેરિકામાં: સિવિલ વોર, એવેન્જર્સની આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય નિરીક્ષણ અંગેના મતભેદને ટીમને બે વિરોધી જૂથોમાં અસ્થિભંગ કરે છે - એક સ્ટીવ રોજર્સની આગેવાની હેઠળ અને બીજું ટોની સ્ટાર્ક (ડાઉની) દ્વારા."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Burkina Faso","answer":"Péeyum réwum Burkina Faso mu ngi tudu Ouagadougou"},{"question":"Um boneco de madeira ganha vida e busca se tornar um menino de verdade. Qual é o filme? Dica: É da Disney.","answer":"o personagem em questão é o Pinóquio."},{"question":"வினா: மூன்றடிச் சிற்றெல்லையும் ஆறடிப் பேரெல்லையும் கொண்ட அகவற்பாக்களால் ஆன நூல் எது?(1) ஐங்குறுநூறு(2) குறுந்தொகை(3) கலித்தொகை(4) புறநானூறு.","answer":"விடை: (1) ஐங்குறுநூறு.1.   ஐங்குறுநூறு எட்டுத்தொகை என வழங்கும் தொகுப்பு நூல்களுள் ஒன்று.  2.  இதிலுள்ள பாடல்கள் கடைச்சங்க காலத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவை.  3.  அன்பின் ஐந்திணையான குறிஞ்சி, முல்லை, மருதம், நெய்தல், பாலை, என்னும் ஐந்து நிலம் சார்ந்த       திணைகள் ஒவ்வொன்றிற்கும் நூறு பாடல்கள் வீதம் இந்நூலில் ஐந்நூறு அகத்திணைப் பாடல்கள்        உள்ளன.  4. ஆசிரியப்பாவில் அமைந்த 3 அடி சிற்றெல்லையும் 6 அடி பேரெல்லையும் கொண்டதாக விளங்குகிறது.  5.  இந்நூல் குறைந்த அடியெல்லை கொண்ட பாக்களால் அமைந்தமையால் ஐங்குறுநூறு எனப் பெயர்       பெற்றது.   6.    இந்நூலுக்குக் கடவுள் வாழ்த்து பாடியவர் பாரதம் பாடிய பெருந்தேவனார் ஆவார்.  7.   அந்தப் பாடல் சிவபெருமானின் விரிவாக்கத் தன்மையை ஒன்று, இரண்டு, மூன்று என்று எண்ணிக்        காட்டுகிறது என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. "},{"question":"दिये गये गीत गीत के बोल पूरे करें:\\"गुलाबी आँखें, जो तेरी देखी, शराबी ये दिल हो गयासम्भालो मुझको, ओ मेरे यारों, सम्भलना मुश्किल हो गया\\"","answer":"\\"दिल में मेरे, ख़्वाब तेरे, तस्वीरें जैसे हों दीवार पेतुझपे फ़िदा, मैं क्यूँ हुआ, आता है गुस्सा मुझे प्यार पेमैं लुट गया, मान के दिल का कहामैं कहीं का ना रहा, क्या कहूँ मैं दिलरुबाबुरा ये जादू तेरी आँखों का, ये मेरा क़ातिल हो गयागुलाबी आँखें जो तेरी देखी...मैंने सदा, चाहा यही, दामन बचा लूं हसीनों से मैंतेरी क़सम, ख़्वाबों में भी, बचता फिरा नाज़नीनों से मैंतौबा मगर, मिल गई तुझसे नज़रमिल गया दर्द-ए-जिगर, सुन ज़रा ओ बेख़बरज़रा सा हँस के, जो देखा तूने, मैं तेरा बिस्मिल हो गयागुलाबी आँखें जो तेरी देखी...\\""},{"question":" भारताचे पहिले गृहमंत्री कोण होते?(A) सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल(B) श्री बेनी प्रसाद वर्मा(C) विष्णू देव साई(D) यांपैकी नाही=> ","answer":"(A) सरदार वल्लभभाई पटेल"},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me donner la poème \\"Rosa fâchée\\" par Victor Hugo?","answer":"Titre : Rosa fâchéePoète : Victor Hugo (1802-1885)Recueil : Les chansons des rues et des bois (1865).Une querelle. Pourquoi ?Mon Dieu, parce qu'on s'adore.À peine s'est-on dit ToiQue Vous se hâte d'éclore.Le coeur tire sur son noeud ;L'azur fuit ; l'âme est diverse.L'amour est un ciel, qui pleutSur les amoureux à verse.De même, quand, sans effroi,Dans la forêt que juin dore,On va rôder, sur la foiDes promesses de l'aurore,On peut être pris le soir,Car le beau temps souvent triche,Par un gros nuage noirQui n'était pas sur l'affiche.À découvrir sur le site https://www.poesie-francaise.fr/victor-hugo/poeme-rosa-fachee.php"},{"question":"もともとは力士が食べる食事全般を意味していた、相撲部屋で昼食として作られる鍋料理のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"ちゃんこです。"},{"question":"ඔන්චිල්ලා වාරමක් කියන්න ","answer":"ප දි නා ලෙස තරුණන් ඔන්චි ල්ලාඅ ඳු නා වත තද කර ඇඳග ල්ලාප ඳි නා වැල් දෙක බුරුල නොදෙ ල්ලාසොඳිනා ගී කියමින් පැද ප ල්ලාමි තු රු මෙනුඹ අප එක්ව සිය ල්ලාක තු රු ලෙසට බැඳි රන් ඔන්චි ල්ලාන ත ර ලමින් ගුවනේ ඔන්චි ල්ලාමෙවර පදිමු අපි රන් ඔන්චි ල්ලාඉ ඳ ගත්තෙමි උස පුටුවක ගුව නාබැ ඳ ගත්තෙමි ජය කොන්ඩේ මුදු නාඇ ඳ ගත්තෙමි වතකුත් ආබර නාවැ ඳ ගත්තෙමි නාරායන සර නාතු ටු ව උඩින් සිට බැඳි ඔන්චි ල්ලාපි ට පි ට පෑගුවෙ එකර කැවි ල්ලාව ට පි ට සිටි අය බලා සිටි ල්ලාඅ ට දෙන අට කොණ වාඩි වෙය ල්ලාව ට් ටු සතර හා ලී දඬු වැල් ගෙ නකි ට් ටු නොකර එහි බඳිමින් තැන තැ නඔ ට් ටු කරති සැම දෙන මග යන එ නගැ ට් ටු නැතුව අපි පදිමුව අට දෙ නසු න් ගා ඩ න් කර බැඳි ඔන්චි ල්ලාප න් ගා ඩ න් කර මෙගම සිය ල්ලාන න්ගා කු ඩ පිට මෙකර කැවි ල්ලානැන් දා ව රු නේ තෑගි දිය ල්ලාපී නා එන කල තිසරුන් ගො ල්ලාබා නා වැල ගෙඩි මෙන් සුවි පු ල්ලාඕ නෑ රඟවට සැරසී ග ල්ලානෑනා වරුනේ තෑගි දිය ල්ලාදු ක් කාටත් එක සරිය බොල න්නේම ක් කා දැයි දැන් බලා සිටි න්නේරි ක් කා රුපියල් සුරතට ග න්නේඅ ක් කා වරුනේ තෑගි දිය න්නේ"},{"question":"p(x) = g(x) . q(x) + r(x) లో p(x) పరిమాణం 5 మరియు q(x) పరిమాణం 3 అయిన g(x) పరిమాణము ఎంత?","answer":"g(x) పరిమాణం = 5 – 3 = 2"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: కరి","answer":"నిదర్శనం, ఏనుగు, కోతి "},{"question":"नेपालमा गुन्द्रुक खानेकुरा के हो ?","answer":"गुन्द्रुक को झोल एक सामान्य सूप हो जुन परम्परागत रूपमा किण्वित र सुकेको हरियो पातदार तरकारीहरूसँग तयार गरिन्छ। नेपालको राष्ट्रिय परिकारमध्येको एक गुन्द्रुक देशैभर खाने गरिन्छ। स्वादमा अमिलो सुपको रूपमा खाँदा यसले स्वाद र स्वास्थ्य दुवै एकैपटक प्रदान गर्छ। गुन्ड्रुकले शरीरमा प्रोबायोटिक्स आपूर्ति गर्न, पाचन र चयापचयमा मद्दत गर्ने र धेरै भिटामिन र खनिजहरू आपूर्ति गर्न जानिन्छ।"},{"question":"Karuur?","answer":"Karuur Waa Caano Geel oo Dhanaan."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai buah keras di dalam sekul\\"?","answer":"Bercakap dengan tergopoh-gopoh"},{"question":" Iza no anaran'ilay mpanao sary sokitra frantsay malaza namorona ny sarivongana \\"The Thinker\\"?","answer":" Auguste Rodin ilay mpanao sary sokitra frantsay malaza."},{"question":"હેરી પોટરમાં ડિમેન્ટર્સનું શું મહત્વ છે?","answer":"ડિમેન્ટર્સ એ આત્માને ચૂસનારા જીવો છે જે અઝકાબાન જેલની રક્ષા કરે છે, જે જાદુની કાળી બાજુ અને ખુશી અને આશા ગુમાવવાના ડરનું પ્રતિનિધિત્વ કરે છે. તેઓ આઘાતની વિલંબિત અસરો અને નિરાશા સામેના સંઘર્ષનું પ્રતીક છે."},{"question":"Solve for 'y' in the equation: 4y - 2 = 14.","answer":"To isolate 'y', add 2 to both sides of the equation: 4y = 14 + 2, which simplifies to 4y = 16. Finally, divide both sides by 4: y = 16 / 4, which equals 4."},{"question":"Sau nhiều năm kinh doanh, bố mẹ tôi dành dụm được 10 tỷ đồng, dự định xây một căn biệt thự ở ngoại ô để dưỡng già. Ông bà thích trồng cây và rau xanh, cuối tuần cũng có thể đón con cháu về chơi.Sau khi tìm hiểu, tôi có góp ý bố mẹ nên mua 2 căn hộ chung cư gần nhà con cái, một để ở, còn lại cho thuê để có thêm thu nhập. Phần vì ông bà đã có tuổi, ở chung cư sẽ đỡ vất vả khoản đi lại, lên xuống cầu thang.Rất mong được tư vấn để gia đình tôi có thể tìm được phương án phù hợp.","answer":"Bạn nên tôn trọng quyết định của bố mẹ. Những người có tuổi thích cuộc sống an yên, tránh xa khói bụi thì việc mua 1 mảnh đất, cất 1 căn nhà, còn lại làm vườn trồng rau, nuôi gà,...an dưỡng tuổi già là quyết định rất hợp lí. Người già không thích hợp sống ở chung cư vì không khí ngột ngạt và rất ít không gian để họ có thể vận động và tận hưởng những ngày cuối cùng của cuộc sống.Lời khuyên: hãy đồng hành cùng quyết định của bố mẹ là: có thể dùng 5 tỷ mua đất ngoại ô và cất nhà để dưỡng già, khu đất phải đảm bảo cất xong căn nhà còn hơn trăm mét vuông để ông bà trồng rau, chơi kiểng. Số tiền còn lại 5 tỷ, mở số tiết kiệm để hàng tháng ông bà lấy tiền lãi mà chi tiêu, du lịch, hoặc để có tiền đề phòng bệnh tật."},{"question":"Em qual time o Pelé jogou no Brasil?","answer":"Pelé jogou no Santos."},{"question":"ਆਦੀਸ ਅਬਾਬਾ: ਇਥੋਪੀਅਨ ਏਅਰਲਾਈਨਜ਼ ਦੇ ਤਬਾਹ ਹੋਏ ਬੋਇੰਗ 737 ਮੈਕਸ 8 ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਦਾ ਬਲੈਕ ਬੌਕਸ ਪੈਰਿਸ ਲਿਜਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਹਾਦਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਰ ਭਾਰਤੀਆਂ ਸਣੇ 157 ਮੁਸਾਫਿਰ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਸਨ। ਹਾਦਸਾ ਜਾਂਚ ਬਿਊਰੋ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਥੋਪੀਆ ਦਾ ਵਫ਼ਦ ਫਲਾਈਟ ਡਾਟਾ ਰਿਕਾਰਡਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੌਕਪਿਟ ਵੌਇਸ ਰਿਕਾਰਡਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਪੈਰਿਸ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਏਅਰਲਾਈਨ ਨੇ ਟਵਿੱਟਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ।-ਪੀਟੀਆਈਹਾਦਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਯਾਤਰੀ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਸਨ?","answer":"ਇਸ ਹਾਦਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ 157 ਯਾਤਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"地方から東京へ出ることを「上京」といいますが、地方から京都へ出ることを何といったでしょう？","answer":"上洛"},{"question":"Mikä on zikavirus?","answer":"Zikavirus kuuluu flavivirusten sukuun, johon kuuluvat myös muun muassa TBE-virus, denguevirus sekä Länsi-Niilin virus. Flavivirusten isäntinä toimivat ihmiset sekä muut nisäkkäät, mutta ne leviävät usein isännästä toiseen esimerkiksi hyttysten välityksellä."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਏਕੋ ਜਪਿ ਏਕੋ ਸਾਲਾਹਿ ॥ਏਕੁ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਏਕੋ ਮਨ ਆਹਿ ॥ਏਕਸ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ ਗਾਉ ਅਨੰਤ ॥ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਜਾਪਿ ਏਕ ਭਗਵੰਤ ॥ਏਕੋ ਏਕੁ ਏਕੁ ਹਰਿ ਆਪਿ ॥ਪੂਰਨ ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹਿਓ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਬਿਆਪਿ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਬਿਸਥਾਰ ਏਕ ਤੇ ਭਏ ॥ਏਕੁ ਅਰਾਧਿ ਪਰਾਛਤ ਗਏ ॥ਮਨ ਤਨ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਏਕੁ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਰਾਤਾ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਇਕੁ ਜਾਤਾ ॥੮॥੧੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 289 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਜਪ, ਤੇ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ ਕਰ, ਇਕ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, ਤੇ, ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਮਿਲਣ ਦੀ ਤਾਂਘ ਰੱਖ ।ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਹੀ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ, ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਇੰਦ੍ਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਇਕ ਭਗਵਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਜਪ ।(ਸਭ ਥਾਈਂ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।(ਜਗਤ ਦੇ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਖਿਲਾਰੇ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਪਾਪ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਤੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਪਰੋਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਸ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।੮।੧੯।\\""},{"question":"Inona ny volana aorian'ny volana aprily?","answer":"Ny volana mey ny volana aorian'ny volana aprily."},{"question":"உலக உணவு தினம் எப்போது கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது?","answer":"உலக உணவு தினம் அக்டோபர் 16 அனஂறு கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"\\"Чоочун киши\\"- романы кимге таандык?","answer":"Зуура Сооронбаеванын эң мыкты чыгармаларынын бири катары эсептелинген \\"Чоочун киши\\" романы 1988-жылы басмадан чыгат. Бир үй-бүлөдөгү эркек менен аялдын жүрөктү өйүткөн мамилесин кылдаттык менен түшүндүргөн чыгарма жазуучуга экинчи жолу олуттуу ийгилик алып келип, эл сүймөнчүгүнө айланат. Көпчүлүктүн суранычы менен романдын уландысы 2002-жылы жарык көрүп, азыркы күндө да актуалдуулугун жогото элек."},{"question":"Scrivi un esempio di trivia in questa categoria: \\"musica\\".","answer":"Elvis è il solista più di successo di sempre? Sì"},{"question":"Sobre qual evento histórico o texto a seguir se refere?Texto: Em 1836 serviu de prisão ao líder revolucionário Farroupilha Bento Gonçalves e a Pedro Boticário. Em 15 de março de 1837, ambos tentaram uma fuga, mas Pedro Boticário, por ser muito gordo, não conseguiu passar por uma janela. Em solidariedade Bento Gonçalves também desistiu da fuga, sendo ambos transferidos, logo após, para outras prisões.","answer":"Farroupilha"},{"question":"Жакынкы ___ кийинки тасмамды тартууга киришебиз. Тасма таенесинин колунда чоңойгон 7 жашар Бала тууралуу. Чет элден кайтып келген ата-энеси Баланы шаардагы жаңы үйүнө алып кетишет. Бирок Балага жаңы үй да, жаңы ата-эне да чоочун, алар Бала үчүн жөн эле Эркек жана Аял.Үч сызыктын ордунда эмне сөз болушу мүмкүн?","answer":"Үч сызыктын ордунда \\"айларда\\" болушу мүмкүн. Ошондо толук сүйлөм мындай болуп калат: \\"Жакынкы айларда кийинки тасмамды тартууга киришебиз\\"."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy matiko lolo ilay olona mipetraka ao ambadika ao io fa olona efa nigadra hoe io.\\"","answer":"Ity fanambarana ity dia maneho tahotra. Matahotra ianao satria olona tsy azonao antoka no mipetraka ao ambadiky ny hefitra misy anao."},{"question":"السؤال: في أي عام تولى هارون الرشيد الخلافة؟","answer":"الإجابة: في ربيع الأول عام 170ه"},{"question":"Anisan'ny baobab lehibe indrindra misy ny baobab fanta-daza hita ao Mahajanga. Firy taona no nomina io baobab io ?","answer":"Ny baobab ao Mahajanga dia eo amin'ny 275 taona .( mety latsaka na mahery)."},{"question":"Ini Edo","answer":"Ini Edo (ti a bi ni ọjọ matelogun, osu kerin ni odun 1982) jẹ oṣere ọmọ Nàìjíríà.[4][5][6] O bẹrẹ iṣẹ fiimu rẹ ni ọdun 2000, [7] ati pe o ti ṣe ifihan ni diẹ sii ju awọn fiimu ogorun lati igba akọkọ rẹ. Ni ọdun 2013, o jẹ adajọ fun Miss Black Africa UK Pageant. Ni ọdun 2014, Ajo Agbaye yan Iyaafin Edo gẹgẹ bi Aṣoju Agbaye Awọn Eto Ibugbe ti Ajo Agbaye.Ini Edo jẹ omo Ibibio lati ipinlẹ Akwa Ibom ni apa guusu-guusu ti Naijiria, ko jinna si Calabar. Olukọ ni iya rẹ, baba rẹ si jẹ alàgba ijọ. O ni idagbasoke ti o muna, ekeji ti awọn ọmọ mẹrin, awọn ọmọbinrin mẹta, ọmọkunrin kan. O lọ si Ile-ẹkọ giga Cornelius Connely ni Uyo . O pari ile- ẹkọ giga ti Yunifasiti ti Uyo nibiti o ti gba Iwe-ẹkọ giga ni Theatre Arts. O tun pari eto ẹkọ bachelors ni University of Calabar nibi ti o ti kọ Gẹẹsi. Ni ọdun 2014 o gba sikolashipu lati kawe ofin ni National Open University of Nigeria .Iṣẹ oṣere rẹ bẹrẹ ni ọdun 2003 [10] pẹlu iṣafihan akọkọ rẹ ni Thick Madam. Olupilẹṣẹ ṣe awari rẹ ni afẹnuka ti o lọ. Aṣeyọri rẹ wa ni 2004 nigbati o ṣiṣẹ ni World Apart . O ti han ni awọn fiimu ti oju ogorun lo ; o jẹ ọkan ninu awọn oṣere ti o ṣaṣeyọri julọ ni Nigeria. O ti ṣe yiyan \\"Oṣere Ti o dara julọ \\" ni Awọn Awards Awards ile Afirika elekankala fun iṣẹ rẹ ninu fiimu “While You Slept”Ni ọdun 2008, Ini Edo ni iyawo Philip Ehiagwina okunrin oniṣowo kan ti o da lori ile de Amẹrika. Igbeyawo pari ni Oṣu Kẹsan ọdun 2014 lẹhin ọdun mẹfa.• Arabinrin GLO ni o jẹ fun ọdun mẹwa lati ọdun 2006 si 2016. [14]• Ni ọdun 2010 o lorukọ lati jẹ aṣoju iyasọtọ ti Noble Hair. [15]• Ini Edo jẹ aṣoju iyasọtọ ti Slim Tea Nigeria.• Ni ọdun 2019 o ti fowo si bi aṣoju fun ami iyasọtọ @MrTaxi_NG.Ini Edo ni a yan gege bi Oluranlọwọ pataki si Gomina Ipinle Akwa Ibom lori Asa Ati Irin-ajo nipasẹ Udom Gabriel Emmanuel ni ọdun 2016."},{"question":" Sheeg asxaabigii hogaaminaayey dagaalkii mu'ta?","answer":" Asxaabigii hogaaminaayey dagaalkii mu'ta waa Zeyd Bin Xaarith (RC)."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు భావం రాయండిమ. ఒడలందెల్ల విభూతిపూత, పులితోలొడ్డాణ మల్లాడు కెంజడ అల్మైక విచార నిశ్చలదృగబా తంబు, లచ్చెన కచ్చడ మంసంబున, రుండమాల గళదేశస్థాణువుం గొలఁగానోడయం డొక్కరుఁ డక్కుమారుకలలో సుద్యత్కృపా మూర్తియై","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :ఒడలందున్ + ఎల్లన్ = దేహమంతటావిభూతిపూత్ర = విభూతి లేపనము (రాసుకొనగా)పులితోలు = పులిచర్మంఒడ్డాణము = కటిసూత్రము (నడుముకు ధరించు పట్ట)అల్లాడు = కదిలెడు (చలించెడు)కెంజడలు = ఎర్రని జటలు కలవాడుఆత్మ = జీవుడు; బుద్ధి; బ్రహ్మము; మనసుఏకవిచార = ఒకే ఆలోచన చేత (ఏకాగ్రత)నిశ్చల = స్థిరమయినదృక్ + అజ్ఞాతంబులు = పద్మముల వంటి కనులు గలఅచ్చు + ఐన = శరీరమునకు సరిపోయినకచ్చడము = ధోవతి (గోచి వలె)అంసంబునన్ = మూపు; భుజశిరమురుండమాల = పూర్రెల దండ; తెగిన తలల దండగళదేశస్థాణువు = కంఠ ప్రదేశములో శివలింగమునుకాలంగా = ఒప్పగా; ఉండగాఒడయండు = ప్రభువు (జంగమదొర)ఒక్కరుఁడు = ఒకడుఉద్యత్ = ప్రకాశించే; ఉదయిస్తున్న; పైకివస్తున్నకృపామూర్తియై = దయామూర్తి వలెఅక్కుమారు = ఆ బాలుని యొక్క (తిన్నడు)కలలో = స్వప్నమునందు కనిపించాడు.భావము :దేహమంతటా విభూతి పూసుకుని, పులిచర్మాన్ని ఒడ్డాణము వలే నడుముకు చుట్టుకొని, కదులుతున్న ఎర్రటి జటలు కలిగినవాడు, ఆత్మ (బ్రహ్మము) గురించి ఏకాగ్రతతో ఆలోచన చేసినట్టి స్థిరమయిన చూపులు’ గలవాడు, పద్మనయనముల వాడు, శరీరానికి సరిపోయిన గోచి ధరించినవాడు, భుజముల మీద పుర్రెల దండ కలవాడు, కంఠస్థానంలో శివలింగాన్ని కలిగిన ప్రకాశించే దయామూర్తి అయిన జంగమదేవుడు (శివుడు) ఆ తిన్నడికి కలలో కనిపించాడు."},{"question":"Uzupełnij następujące zdanie: Pearce dołączył do zespołu \\"Mecz Dnia\\" BBC w 2004 roku.; jest jednym z czołowych komentatorów BBC, obok Guy'a Mowbray'a, Steve'a Wilsona i Simona Brothertona. W ciągu piętnastu lat pracy w BBC Sport, Pearce komentował na żywo mecze Pucharu Anglii, Pucharu Ligi i Mistrzostw, a także obejmował cztery Puchary Świata (2006, 2010, 2014 i 2018), cztery Mistrzostwa Europy (2008, 2012, 2016 i 2018) i cztery ","answer":"Mistrzostwa Europy (2016)."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Helmi bertanggungjawab memelihara __nya sejak pemergian kedua-dua orang tua mereka. Pilihan:  A) rakan-rakanB) adik-adikC) ibu-ibuD) jiran-jiran","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah B) adik-adik"},{"question":"Firy ny firenena mandrafitra an'Etazonia?","answer":"Etazonia dia misy fanjakana 50. Samy manana ny governemantany sy ny lalànany avy ireo fanjakana ireo, saingy miray hina eo ambany governemanta federaly foibe izy ireo. Ny Etazonia dia tsy mizara ho \\"firenena\\" amin'ny heviny mahazatra, fa amin'ny fanjakana izay manana fizakan-tena ary mivondrona mba hamorona firenena."},{"question":"මෙම ප්‍රකාශය හරිද වැරදිද?\\"විෂමජාතීය මිශ්‍රණයක, මිශ්‍රණය පුරා තැනින් තැනට සංඝටක අංශුවල පැතිරීම වෙනස් නොවේ\\"","answer":"මෙම ප්‍රකාශය වැරදි ප්‍රකාශයකි. විෂම ජාතීය මිශ්‍රණයක සංඝටක අක්‍රමවත්ව පැතිරී ඇත."},{"question":"नेवार समुदायमा \\"रोपाई जात्रा\\" पर्वको सांस्कृतिक महत्वबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"रोपाई जात्राले नेवार समुदायको कृषि सम्पदालाई झल्काउने परम्परागत संगीत, नृत्य र अनुष्ठानका साथ धान रोप्ने मौसम मनाउँछ।"},{"question":"​ශ්‍රී ‍ලංකාවේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයෙකුවූ හෙන්‍​රි මන්ක් මේසන් මුවර් (Henry Monck-Mason Moore) තවත් රටවල් දෙකක එම තනතුර දරා ඇත. එම රටවල් දෙක මොනවා ද?","answer":"හෙන්‍​රි මන්ක් මේසන් මුවර් (Henry Monck-Mason Moore) කෙන්යා​ව සහ සියෙරාලියොන් යන රටවල් වලද බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයෙකුවූ ලෙස කටයුතු කර ඇත."},{"question":"3: Waxaad sheegtaan haweeneydii ka qeeb gashay dagaalkii uxud, waxaana leeb ku dhuftay nin mushrik ah dhulka ayay ku dhacday oo coowradeedii ayaa feeydantay, gaalkiina wuu ku qoslay gabadhii, NABIGA SCW aad ayuu uga murugooday oo wuxuu udhiibay leeb aan bir kujirin Sacad Inbu Abii Waqaas wuuna ku dhuftay mushrigii, Isagana dhulka ayuu ku dhacay oo coowradiisa ayaa feydantay Nabiga SCW Aad ayuu ugu qoslay oo wuxuu yiraahday NABIGA SCW waxaa u abaal guday gabadha Sacad, ee waxaad sheegtaanb    haweeneeydas magaceeda?","answer":"3: Waa Umu Ayman    "},{"question":"भारताचे राष्ट्रीय फळ कोणते?","answer":"आंबा"},{"question":"بی بی سی اردو کی پرائیویسی پالیسی کیا ہے؟","answer":"نجی معلومات کی پالیسیآپ کے متعلق حاصل کی گئیں نجی معلومات کے بارے میں ہماری پالیسی درج ذیل ہے۔1: سٹیٹ مینٹ آف انٹینٹ2: وزیٹرز کے بارے میں معلومات3: 'کوکیز' کیا ہے؟4: نجی معلومات داخل کرنا5: نجی معلومات تک رسائی6: سولہ سال سے کم عمر کے انٹرنیٹ استعمال کرنے والے7: اپنے کوکیز کوڈ کو کیسے دیکھا جائے؟1: سٹیٹ مینٹ آف انٹینٹفارمز میں دیےگئے خانوں میں اپنے بارے میں تفصیلات درج کرنے سے بی بی سی آپ کو وہ خدمات مہیا کر سکے گا جو آپ کو مطلوب ہیں۔ جب بھی آپ ہمیں نجی معلومات فراہم کریں گے ہم ان معلومات کو اپنی اس پالیسی کے مطابق استعمال کریں گے۔ ہماری خدمات کا مقصد آپ کو وہ معلومات فراہم کرنا ہے جو آپ موصول کرنا چاہتے ہیں۔ انٹرنیٹ کے موجودہ قوانین کا احترام اور بیسٹ پریکٹس کا حصول بی بی سی کی اولین ترجیح ہیں۔2: وزیٹرز کے بارے میں معلوماتآپ جب بھی بی بی سی آئی کی ویب سائٹ پر آئیں گے تو آپ جن صفحات تک پہنچیں گے وہ کوکیز سمیت آپ کے کمپیوٹر پر ڈاؤن لوڈ ہو جائیں گی۔ (مزید معلومات کے لیے پوائنٹ نمبر تین ملاحظہ فرمائیں)۔ اگر تمام نہیں تو زیادہ تر ویب سائٹس کوکیز استعمال کرتی ہیں کیونکہ کوکیز ویب سائٹ شائع کرنے والوں کو مفید کام سرانجام دینے میں مدد فراہم کرتی ہیں جیسے کہ یہ معلوم کرنا کہ کسی کمیوٹر یا اسے استعمال کرنے والے نے پہلے اس ویب سائٹ کو وزٹ کیا ہے یا نہیں۔ بار بار اس ویب سائٹ کو وزٹ کرنے والے کمپیوٹر میں دیکھا جاتا ہے کہ آیا اس کمپیوٹر پر پہلے سے اس سائٹ کے حوالے سے کوئی ککی موجود ہے یا نہیں جو آپ کے پچھلے وزٹ کے دوران آپ کے کمپیوٹر میں داخل کی گئی تھی۔کوکیز کا مقصد کمپیوٹر استعمال کرنے والے کے متعلق مفید معلومات فراہم کرنا ہوتا ہے جو ویب سائٹ بنانے والوں کو اپنی خدمات کو ان کی ضروریات کے مطابق بہتر بنانے میں مدد فراہم کرتی ہیں اور استعمال کرنے والے کے پروفائل کا تجزیہ کرنے میں مدد دیتی ہیں۔ مثال کے طور پر اگر آپ اپنے پچھلے وزٹ پر ہمارے تعلیمی صفحات پر گئے تھے تو کوکیز ہمیں یہ بتا سکتی ہیں اور اس سے ہمیں آپ کے اگلے وزٹ کے دوران اپنی تعلیم کے متعلق معلومات کو آپ کے لیے واضح کرنے میں مدد مل سکتی ہے۔ریڈ شیرف انٹرنیٹ کے استعمال پر ایک تحقیقی اور رائے شماری کرنے والی کمپنی ہے جو ہمارے لیے ہماری ویب سائٹ پر آنے والوں کے بارے میں غیر نجی معلومات ان کوکیز اور کوڈ کے ذریعے اکٹھا کرتی ہے جو ہماری سائٹ میں ایم بیڈڈ ہوتی ہیں۔ یہ کوکیز اور کوڈ دونوں ایسے غیر نجی اعداد و شمار فراہم کرتے ہیں جیسے کہ استعمال کرنے والا کن مختلف پیجز تک گیا، کتنی دیر تک ان پر رہا، کن کن پیجز اور راستوں سے گزرتے ہوئے کسی پیج تک پہنچا، استعمال کرنے والوں کی سکرین سیٹنگ کیا ہے اور اسی طرح کی دیگر عمومی معلومات۔ اس سے بی بی سی کو اس کی سائٹ تک آنے والوں کے لیے اپنی خدمات کو بہتر سے بہتر بنانے میں مدد ملتی ہے۔اگر ریڈ شیرف کی کوکیز اپنے سسٹم پر نہیں چاہتے تو آپ پوائنٹ نمبر سات کے طریقہ کار کے تحت ایسا کر سکتے ہیں۔ ہماری ویب سائٹ پر موجود ایم بیڈڈ کوڈ کے بارے میں آپ براہ راست ریڈ شیرف سے درج ذیل ای میل کے پتے پر رابطہ کر سکتے ہیں۔privacy@redsheriff.comاس سلسلے میں ریڈ شیرف کی اپنی نجی معلومات کے بارے میں پالیسی پر مزید معلومات کےلئے درج ذیل ویب سائٹ سے رجوع کریں۔http://www.redsheriff.com/6.0.0.htm3:' کوکیز' کیا ہیں؟جب آپ کسی بھی سائٹ میں داخل ہوتے ہیں تو آپ کے کمپیوٹر کو خودکار طور پر کوکیز جاری کر دی جاتی ہیں۔ کوکیز ایسی ٹیکسٹ فائلز پر مشتمل ہوتی ہیں جن کے ذریعے ہمارا سرور آپ کے کمپیوٹر کی شناخت کرتا ہے۔ کوکیز بذات خود مختلف استعمال کرنے والوں کی شناخت نہیں کرتیں بلکہ ان کا کام صرف کمپیوٹر کی شناخت تک ہی محدود ہوتا ہے۔ یہ کوکیز زیادہ تر سائٹس جاری کرتی ہیں جس کا مقصد ان کی سائٹ پر آنے والی ٹریفک کے بارے میں اعدادو شمار اور معلومات کا حصول ہوتا ہے۔کوکیز بذات خود صرف سائٹ کے ان حصوں اور دورانیے کے بارے میں ہی ریکارڈ جمع کر پاتی ہیں جن تک کوئی کمپیوٹر پہنچتا ہے۔ کمپیوٹر استعمال کرنے والوں کو مکمل اختیار حاصل ہوتا ہے کہ وہ اپنے کمپیوٹرز کی سیٹنگ میں ان کوکیز کو بغیر اطلاع کے اندر آنے کی اجازت دیں، اندر آنے دینے سے پہلے مطلع کیا جانا ضروری قرار دیں یا کوکیز کو اپنے کمپیوٹر میں آنے سے مکمل طور پر روک دیں۔ تاہم کوکیز کو مکمل طور پر روکنے کا مطلب یہ بھی ہے کہ کچھ ویب سائٹس پر خاص طرح کے پیجز تک آپ رسائی حاصل نہیں کر پائیں گے۔اگر آپ کے کپمیوٹر کی سیٹنگ کوکیز مسترد نہیں کر رہی تو بھی آپ نامعلوم کمپیوٹر کے طور پر ہماری ویب سائٹ براؤز کر سکتے ہیں جب تک کہ آپ بی بی سی آئی کی خدمات کے لئے رجسٹر نہیں کرتے۔4: آپ کی نجی معلومات کی حفاظت اور اس کا استعمالآپ مقابلوں میں شرکت یا بی بی سی آئی کمیونٹی کی رکنیت کے لیے بی بی سی آئی کو جو بھی نجی معلومات فراہم کریں گے ہم ان کے استعمال کے لیے قانونی طور پر آپ کو جواب دہ ہیں۔ ہم پر لازم ہے کہ ہم آپ پر واضح کریں کہ ہم ان معلومات کو کیسے استعمال کریں گے اور یہ معلومات کسی کو بھی فراہم کرنے سے پہلے آپ کو مطلع کریں (یہ جاننے کے لیے کہ ہم ان معلومات کے لئے درخواست کیوں کرتے ہیں متعلقہ ویب پیجز پر جائیں)۔ عام طور پر آپ بی بی سی کو جو بھی معلومات فراہم کریں گے وہ بی بی سی کے اندر اور اس کے سروس پرووائیڈرز کے لیے ہی استعمال کی جائیں گی۔ یہ معلومات کبھی بھی آپ کی رضامندی حاصل کیے بغیر باہر کسی کو فراہم نہیں کی جائیں گی جب تک کہ ہم پر یہ قانونی طور پر لازم نہ ہو کہ ہم یہ معلومات ظاہر کریں۔ اثنا دریں اگر آپ نامناسب اور ناشائستہ مواد بی بی سی کو پوسٹ کریں یا بھیجیں اور بی بی سی کے خیال میں یہ رویہ قابل گرفت ہے اور دہرایا جا رہا ہے تو بی بی سی اسے روکنے کے لیے آپ کے متعلق جو بھی معلومات موجود ہیں استعمال کر سکتا ہے۔ اس میں آپ کو ملازمت فراہم کرنے والے ادارے، آپ کی تعلیمی درس گاہ اور آپ کو ای میل کی سروس مہیا کرنے والی کمپنیوں تک آپ کے رویے کے بارے میں اطلاعات کی فراہمی شامل ہے۔ہم ان معلومات کو صرف اس وقت تک اپنے پاس رکھیں گے جب تک کہ آپ ہماری خدمات سے استفادہ حاصل کرتے رہتے ہیں اور اس کے بعد جیسے کہ بی بی سی آئی کی رکنیت ختم کر دینے کے بعد اسے ضائع کر دیں گے۔ تاہم تحفظات کے پیش نظر ہم بی بی سی آئی کمیونٹی سروسز میں شرکت کےحوالے سے آپ کے پیغامات، ان کا متن، رکن کا نام، وقت اور تاریخ جیسی دستاویزات چھ ماہ تک آپنے پاس رکھ سکتے ہیں۔ جہاں ایسے افراد کی نجی معلومات رکھی جائیں گی جنہوں نے ابھی تک بی بی سی آئی کی رکنیت کے لیے نام درج نہیں کرایا لیکن دوسری خدمات میں حصہ لیا ہے (جیسے کہ مقابلے) ان کی نجی معلومات صرف اس وقت تک محفوظ کی جائیں جب تک کہ وہ ان سہولیات کی اطمینان بخش فراہمی کے لیے ضروری ہوں گی۔ ہم ڈیٹا پروٹیکشن ایکٹ انیس سو اٹھانوے کے تحت فراہم کی گئی تمام نجی معلومات کا تحفظ یقینی بنائیں گے۔اگر آپ کو بی بی سی آئی کی کسی بھی سائٹ سے یہ بتایا جائے کہ آپ کی معلومات کے ذریعے بی بی سی 'خدمات کے انتظامی مقاصد' کے تحت آپ سے رابطہ کرے گی تو اس کا مطلب ہے کہ بی بی سی آپ سے ایسے تمام مقاصد کے لیے رابطہ کر سکتی ہے جو ان خدمات سے متعلقہ ہیں جس کے لیے آپ نے درخواست دی ہے۔ مثال کے طور پر ہم آپ کو 'پاس ورڈ' فراہم کرنے کے لیے یا یہ بتانے کے لیے کہ سروس انتظامی بحالی یا مرمت کے لیے فلاں سے فلاں وقت تک معطل رہے گی، آپ سے رابطہ کر سکتے ہیں۔ ہم آپ سے تشہیری مقاصد کے لیے رابطہ نہیں کریں گے جیسے کہ آپ کو سروس میں تبدیلیوں یا نئے حصے متعارف کروانے کے بارے میں آگاہ کرنا جب تک کہ آپ فارم بھرتے وقت یا بعد میں خود اس طرح کی تبدیلیوں کے بارے میں آگاہ رہنے اور تشہیری مواد کی درخواست نہ کریں۔5: آپ کی نجی معلومات تک رسائیآپ کو حق حاصل ہے کہ کسی وقت بھی بی بی سی کے پاس موجود اپنی تمام تر نجی معلومات کی ایک نقل حاصل کر سکتے ہیں۔ ( اس کے اخراجات کیلئے آپ کو دس پاؤنڈ ادا کرنے ہوں گے۔) اس قسم کی درخواستوں کے لیے پتہ درج ذیل ہے۔Data Protection OfficerRoom 315Brock House19Langham StreetLondon W1A 1AA6: سولہ سال اور اس سے کم عمراگر آپ کی عمر سولہ سال یا اس سے کم ہے تو آپ کے لیے بی بی سی کو نجی معلومات فراہم کرنے سے پہلے اپنے والدین یا سرپرست کی اجازت حاصل کرنا لازمی ہے۔ اس اجازت کے بغیر آپ ہمیں اپنے بارے میں نجی معلومات نہیں بھیج سکتے۔7: اپنا کوکی کوڈ کیسے دیکھیں۔کسی بھی کوکی پر کلک کرکے اسے کھول لیں۔ آپ کو اس میں بہت سارا متن حروف اور اعداد کی شکل میں نظر آئے گا۔ یہ نمبر آپ کا شناختی کارڈ ہیں جسے صرف وہ سرور دیکھ سکتا ہے جس نے یہ کوکی آپ کے کمپیوٹر کو جاری کی ہے۔مکمل اور اپ ٹو ڈیٹ پرائیویسی پالیسی کے لیے برائے مہربانی انگلش کی سائٹ چیک کریں: http://www.bbc.co.uk/privacy"},{"question":"Mene Sarewa?","answer":"Samari kan busa wa ‘yan matansu sarewa domin sanar da su cewa su fito zance."},{"question":"మానవ హక్కులు ఎన్ని రకాలు ? వాటిని తెలపండి.","answer":"మానవ హక్కులను స్థూలంగా రెండు రకములుగా వర్గీకరించవచ్చు. అవి 1) పౌర, రాజకీయ హక్కులు 2) సాంఘిక, ఆర్థిక సాంస్కృతిక హక్కులు."},{"question":"أريد أن أتعلم الشعر. قم بإنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر الكامل.","answer":"حسناً بالتأكيد: إِلّا يَكُن نَصلاً فَغِمدُ نُصولِغالَتهُ أَحداثُ الزَمانِ بِغولِأَو لا يَكُن بِأَبي شُبولٍ ضَيغَمٍتَدمى أَظافِرُهُ فَأُمُّ شُبولِتِلكَ الغَمامَةُ كانَ بارِقُ خالِهالَو أَنسَتِ الأَيّامُ غَيرَ مُخيلِكُنّا نُؤَمِّلُ أَن نُجَلّي صَوبَهاعَن أَخضَرٍ غَضِّ الجَنى مَطلولِلَولا طِلابُ النَصلِ يورِقُ عودُهُباتَ النِساءُ سُدىً بِغَيرِ بُعولِوَلَرُبَّما بُكِيَ الفَقيدُ لِنَفسِهِأَو لِلمَطامِعِ فيهِ وَالتَأميلِأَتُرى بِما نَغتَرُّ مِن أَيّامِناوَنُطيلُ مِن أَمَلٍ لَهُنَّ طَويلِأَبِوِردِها المَطروقِ أَو بِنَعيمِها المَمذوقِ أَم ميعادِها المَمطولِنَرجو البَقاءَ كَأَنَّنا لَم نَختَبِرعاداتِ هَذا العالَمِ المَجبولِلَو أَنَّ غَيرَ يَدِ الزَمانِ تُريعُنيوَتَفُلُّ حَدَّ مَعاشِري وَقَبيليلَلَوَيتُ مِن دونِ المَذَلَّةِ جانِبيوَجَرَرتُ عَن دارِ الهَوانِ ذُيوليلَكِنَّ سُلطانَ اللَيالي غالِبٌعَزمي وَقَطّاعٌ عَلَيَّ سَبيليقَدَرَت فَذَلَّ لَها العَزيزُ مَهابَةًلَيسَ الذَليلُ لِقادِرٍ بِذَليلِوَهوَ الزَمانُ يُبيحُ كُلَّ مُمَنَّعٍوَيَغُضُّ مِن طَمَحاتِ كُلِّ جَليلِمِن بَينِ مَجروحٍ بِحَدِّ نُيوبِهِيَدمى وَبَينَ مُبَضَّعٍ مَأكولِأَعدى جَذيمَةَ بِالرَدى وَعَدا عَلىرِدفَي جَذيمَةَ مالِكٍ وَعَقيلِوَاِستَنزَلَ الأَذواءَ عَن نَجَواتِهِمفَغَدَوا ذَوي ضَرَعٍ وَطَولِ خُمولِوَحَدا بِآلِ المُنذِرَينِ فَوَدَّعوابِالحيرَةِ البَيضاءِ كُلَّ مَقيلِوَسَطا عَلى أَبناءِ قَيصَرَ سَطوَةًأَمَماً فَأَجلَت عَن دَمٍ مَطلولِوَأَعادَ إيوانَ المَدائِنِ مَحرَماًعُريانَ مِن بُردِ العُلى المَسدولِوَاِستَلَّ مِنهُ مالِكيهِ وَدونَهُمعَدَدُ الدَراري مِن قَناً وَخُيولِوَهَوى بِتيجانِ الجَبابِرَةِ الأُلىعَن كُلِّ مَطرورِ الغِرارِ صَقيلِبَلَّت مَفارِقَهُم دَماً وَلَطالَماعَرَفوا بِمِسكٍ فَوقَهُنَّ بَليلِأَو بَعدَما رَفَعوا القِبابَ وَخَوَّلوافي ظِلِّ مُمتَنِعِ المَقامِ ظَليلِمِن كُلِّ أَغلَبَ كانَ يَحسَبُ عَهدَهُفي العِزِّ وَالعَلياءِ غَيرَ مُحيلِوَيَظُنُّ أَن لَو طاوَلَتهُ مَنيَّةٌلَأَبى إِباءَ المُصعَبِ المَعقولِأَو لَو طَغى غَربُ الفُراتِ لَرَدَّهُمُتَقَطِّعاً وَأَقامَ مَدَّ النيلِنَزَلَ القَضاءُ بِهِ فَعادَ كَأَنَّهُلَم يَغنَ أَمسِ بِطارِقٍ وَنَزيلِصَبراً جَميلاً يا عَلَيُّ فَرُبَّماصَبَرَ الفَتى وَالصَبرُ غَيرُ جَميلِلَو كُنتُ أَعلَمُ أَنَّ وَجداً نافِعٌلَقَدَحتُ فيكَ بِزَفرَةٍ وَغَليلِوَجَعَلتَ تَصعيبَ المُصابِ مُعَظَّماًمِن شَأنِهِ بَدَلاً مِنَ التَسهيلِلَكِنَّها الأَقدارُ يَمضي حُكمُهاأَبَداً عَلى الأُصعوبِ وَالأُذلولِوَلَرُبَّما اِبتَسَمَ الفَتى وَفُؤادُهُشَرِقُ الجَنانِ بِرَنَّةٍ وَعَويلِوَلَرُبَّما اِحتَمَلَ اللَبيبُ مُمَوِّهاًعَضَّ الزَمانِ بِبِشرِهِ المَبذولِوَغَطى عَلى تِلكَ الجِراحِ كَأَنَّهُما آبَ مِنهُ بِغارِبٍ مَخزولِ."},{"question":"દુનિયાનું સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેર કયું છે ? ","answer":"લાહોર, પાકિસ્તાન: આઈક્યૂ એરના 2023 વર્લ્ડ એર ક્વાલિટી રિપોર્ટ અનુસાર, લાહોર હાલમાં વિશ્વનું સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેર છે. શહેરમાં PM2.5નું સ્તર ખૂબ જ વધારે છે, જે ફેફસાની સમસ્યાઓનું કારણ બની શકે છેદિલ્હી, ભારત: દિલ્હી લાંબા સમયથી વિશ્વના સૌથી પ્રદૂષિત શહેરોમાંનું એક છે. વાહનો, ઉદ્યોગો અને ખેતરોમાંથી નીકળતા ધુમાડાને કારણે શહેરમાં હવાની ગુણવત્તા ખૂબ જ ખરાબ છે.બીજિંગ, ચીન: ચીનના ઘણા શહેરોમાં પ્રદૂષણની સમસ્યા છે, જેમાં બીજિંગ પણ સામેલ છે. શહેરમાં PM2.5નું સ્તર ખૂબ જ વધારે છે, જે ફેફસાની સમસ્યાઓનું કારણ બની શકે છે.ગુરુગ્રામ, ભારત: દિલ્હીની બાજુમાં આવેલું ગુરુગ્રામ શહેર પણ ખૂબ જ પ્રદૂષિત છે. શહેરમાં વાહનો અને ઉદ્યોગોને કારણે હવાની ગુણવत्ता ખરાબ છે.ગાઝિયાબાદ, ભારત: ગાઝિયાબાદ પણ ભારતનું એક ખૂબ જ પ્રદૂષિત શહેર છે. શહેરમાં વાહનો અને ઉદ્યોગોને કારણે હવાની ગુણવત્તા ખરાબ છે.આ યાદી દર વર્ષે બદલાય છે, અને ઘણા શહેરો પ્રદૂષણને ઘટાડવા માટે પગલાં લઈ રહ્યા છે. જો કે, પ્રદૂષણ હજી પણ વિશ્વના ઘણા શહેરોમાં ગંભીર સમસ્યા છે, અને તેની આરોગ્ય અને પર્યાવરણ પર નકારાત્મક અસર પડે છે.તમારે ધ્યાનમાં રાખવું જોઈએ કે આ યાદી માત્ર એક અંદાજ છે અને વિવિધ સ્રોતોના આંકડાઓના આધારે બનાવવામાં આવી છે. ચોક્કસ પ્રદૂષણ સ્તર વિવિધ પરિબળોના આધારે બદલાઈ શકે છે, જેમ કે હવામાન, સમય અને માપન પદ્ધતિઓ.આશા છે કે આ માહિતી ઉપયોગી છે."},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Lambang Paus Benediktus XVI didesain oleh Uskup Agung Andrea Cordero Lanza di Montezemolo (yang kemudian diangkat sebagai Kardinal) segera setelah pemilihan Paus pada tahun 2005.","answer":"Lambang Paus Benediktus XVI didesain oleh Uskup Agung Andrea Cordero Lanza di Montezemolo"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Jamal Khashoggi. ","answer":"Iriseoir ón Araib Shádach ab ea Jamal Ahmad Khashoggi (a rugadh ar an 13 Deireadh Fómhair 1958 agus a fuair bás ar an 2 Deireadh Fómhair 2018)."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Zâmbia?","answer":"Lusaca é a capital e maior cidade da Zâmbia. É também a sede da província de Lusaca e do distrito de Lusaca. Lusaca está situada ao sul do país e é a maior cidade do Zâmbia. Foi fundada em 1905 pelos britânicos e tornou-se capital da então Rodésia do Norte em 1935."},{"question":"Aṣiri Ṣẹgun ti wọn lo pa ọrẹbinrin ẹ, to tun sin in sinu igbo ti tu o","answer":"L’Ekoo, ọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ ọkunrin ọmọ ọdun méjìdínlógún kan, Ṣẹgun Titilayọ, lori ẹsun pe o pa ololufẹ ẹ, o si sin in lai sọ fẹnikẹni.Ọmọ ilu kan ti wọn n pe ni Otolu, nijọba ibilẹ Lẹkki, ni wọn pe ọkunrin yii, bẹẹ ni, ololufẹ ẹ ti wọn lọ pa yii n jẹ Oritokẹ Mannix.Ileetura K.C Hotel, niluu Apakin, ni Lẹkki, l’Ekoo, ni wọn sọ pe Oritokẹ, ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgbọn yii, ti n ṣiṣẹ ko too pade iku ojiji.Lọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, ni wọn sọ pe wọn ti ri ọmọbinrin naa gbẹyin.Awọn to sun mọ ọn sọ pe Ṣẹgun gan-an lo pe e lọjọ naa ni nnkan bii aago mọkanla aarọ.Wọn ni latigba naa ni wọn ti ri alọ ẹ, ti wọn ko gburoo ibi to ra si, ki wọn too fọrọ ọhun to awọn ọlọpaa leti.Bọ ṣe ku dẹdẹ ki oṣu kan pe ti wọn ti n wa a ni aṣiri ohun to ṣẹlẹ si i tu.Ileeṣẹ Adroan Homes, to n ṣiṣẹ lori ilẹ to ṣẹṣẹ ra si agbegbe Lẹkki, lo hu oku kan jade nibi ti katapila wọn ti n hulẹ kiri.Wọn ni loju ẹsẹ lawọn alaṣẹ ileeṣẹ naa fọrọ ọhun to ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa leti, ninu iwadii wọn ni wọn si ti ri i pe oku Oritokẹ ti wọn n wa kiri ni.Loju ẹsẹ ni wọn sọ pe awọn ọlọpaa bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn, ti wọn si ti mu Ṣẹgun sọdọ bayii, nibi to ti n sọ tẹnu ẹ lori bi Oritokẹ ṣe dẹni agbegbin bẹẹ yẹn.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, Muyiwa Adéjọbí, ti sọ pe wọn ti gbe oku arabinrin naa lọ fun ayẹwo, ati pe Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa l’Ekoo, Hakeem Odumosu, paapaa ti kilọ fawọn obi lati mọ iru ẹni ti ọmọ wọn yoo maa tẹle kiri.Bakan naa ni wọn lo ti sọ pe, ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa gbọdọ tu iṣu desalẹ ikoko lati mọ bọrọ ọmọ naa ṣe jẹ gan-an."},{"question":"வினா : இந்தியாவில் 'சுற்றுச் சூழலியலின் தந்தை ' என அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார் ?","answer":"விடை : டாக்டர் ராம்தேவ் மிஸ்ரா இந்தியாவில் சுற்றுச்சூழலின் தந்தை என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். இவர் வெப்பமண்டல சூழலியல் சர்வதேச சங்கத்தை 1956-ஆம் ஆண்டில் நிறுவினார்."},{"question":"Inona no fihetseham-po hita ao anatin'ity fanambarana ity?« Faly be aho fa efa bebe amin’izay », hoy Addiah.","answer":"Hafaliana no fihetseham-po aseho ao anatin'io fanambarana io."},{"question":"Iza no oniveriste lehibe indrinda ao Madagasikara?","answer":"oniversite Akantso no lehibe indrindra ao Madagasikara"},{"question":"દીપિકા પાદુકોણ વિશે જણાવો.","answer":"બેડમિન્ટન ખેલાડી પ્રકાશ પાદુકોણની પુત્રી પાદુકોણનો જન્મ કોપનહેગનમાં થયો હતો અને તેનો ઉછેર બેંગ્લોરમાં થયો હતો. કિશોરાવસ્થામાં, તેણીએ રાષ્ટ્રીય સ્તરની ચેમ્પિયનશીપમાં બેડમિન્ટન રમી હતી પરંતુ ફેશન મોડલ બનવા માટે તેણીએ રમતગમતમાં તેની કારકિર્દી છોડી દીધી હતી. તેણીને ટૂંક સમયમાં જ ફિલ્મની ભૂમિકાઓ માટે ઓફરો મળી અને તેણે 2006માં કન્નડ ફિલ્મ ઐશ્વર્યાના શીર્ષક પાત્ર તરીકે અભિનયની શરૂઆત કરી. ત્યારબાદ પાદુકોણે તેની પ્રથમ બોલિવૂડ રીલીઝ, રોમાંસ ઓમ શાંતિ ઓમ (2007) માં શાહરૂખ ખાન સાથે બેવડી ભૂમિકા ભજવી હતી, જેણે તેણીને શ્રેષ્ઠ મહિલા પદાર્પણ માટેનો ફિલ્મફેર એવોર્ડ જીત્યો હતો. રોમાંસ લવ આજ કલ (2009) માં તેણીની અભિનયની ભૂમિકા માટે પાદુકોણને પ્રશંસા મળી હતી, પરંતુ આને ટૂંકો આંચકો લાગ્યો હતો.રોમેન્ટિક કોમેડી કોકટેલ (2012)એ તેની કારકિર્દીમાં એક વળાંક આપ્યો, અને તેણીએ રોમેન્ટિક કોમેડી યે જવાની હૈ દીવાની અને ચેન્નાઈ એક્સપ્રેસ (બંને 2013), હેપી કોમેડી હેપ્પી ન્યુ યર (2014), સંજયમાં અભિનયની ભૂમિકાઓ સાથે વધુ સફળતા મેળવી. લીલા ભણસાલીની પીરિયડ ડ્રામા બાજીરાવ મસ્તાની (2015) અને પદ્માવત (2018), અને હોલીવુડની એક્શન ફિલ્મ XXX: રિટર્ન ઓફ ઝેન્ડર કેજ (2017). તેણીએ ભણસાલીની ગોલિયોં કી રાસલીલા રામ-લીલા (2013) માં જુલિયટ પર આધારિત પાત્ર ભજવવા માટે અને પીકુ (2015) માં હેડસ્ટ્રોંગ પુત્રીની ભૂમિકા ભજવવા બદલ ટીકાકારોની પ્રશંસા પણ મેળવી હતી, બે શ્રેષ્ઠ અભિનેત્રી માટેના ફિલ્મફેર એવોર્ડ જીત્યા હતા. ટૂંકા વિરામ બાદ અને તેની પોતાની કંપની કા પ્રોડક્શન્સ હેઠળની બે વ્યવસાયિક રીતે અસફળ ફિલ્મો પછી, પાદુકોણે પઠાણમાં અભિનયની ભૂમિકા ભજવી હતી અને 2023ની બંને ટોચની કમાણી કરનાર એક્શન ફિલ્મો, જવાનમાં ટૂંકી ભૂમિકા હતી."},{"question":"スポーツで、水の球と書けばもちろん水球のことですが、氷の球・氷球（ひょうきゅう）と書いたらどんなスポーツのことでしょう？","answer":"アイスホッケーです。"},{"question":"Ngancamelaukungafiki emsebenzini ngesikhathi, ngaya koyigqiba lapha. Abantu labobadutshulwa bafa, enye ingxenye yemali yatholakala kubona. Sengibuyaemsebenzini nami ngagwazwa ngabanye ekhumbini engabe ngikuyongashona. Ngenxa yokuthi inhliziyo yami yayilokhu ikule mali umoya wamiawukwazanga ukwedlulela endaweni yokuphumula.'Engikucela kuwe-ke Roy ukuba le mali uyithathe, uyisebenzise ngendlelaenenzuzo ungakhele umuzi oyisitezi lapho uyongikhumbula khona njalokanye ngonyaka njengomakoti wakho. Nami ngiyolokhu ngikuvakashelanjalo.'1. Umbhali ukwazile yini ukulandela umgomo wokuqoqeka kwendawokule ndaba emfishane?","answer":"Umgomo wokuqoqeka kwendawo okwenzeka kuyo indabaemfushane ufezekile kule ndaba. Konke kwenzeka eMlazikuphelele khona lapho."},{"question":"Mejuo ilu a:A tufuo azịza ụlọ.... ","answer":"Azịza:Ụtụtụ a chọwa ya.Nke a pụtara na eleghara ihe anya mma n'ọdịghị mkpa, mgbe mkpa bịara, a chọwa ebe ọ nọ. "},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: Outro objeto de controvérsia é a regra \\"um país, um filme\\" da Academia, que foi criticada por alguns cineastas. Guy Lodge, do \\"The Guardian\\", escreveu em 2015 que a ideia de uma categoria de Melhor Filme Estrangeiro é uma \\"premissa fundamentalmente falha\\" e esta é a \\"mais criticada de todas as categorias do Oscar\\". Ele também afirmava \\"Em um mundo perfeito — ou, pelo menos, um mundo tão perfeito quanto permitiria a ostentação de prêmios de filmes — não haveria necessidade de um Oscar separado para melhor filme em língua estrangeira. O fato de que, após 87 anos, a Academia nunca homenageou um filme não predominantemente em inglês, pois o melhor do ano diz tudo sobre suas próprias limitações, e nada sobre as do cinema mundial”. No","answer":"Oscar 2020, o filme sul-coreano \\"Gisaengchung\\" foi o primeiro a ganhar o recém-nomeado Melhor Filme Internacional e Melhor Filme no mesmo ano."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Maah -Maah yada soomaalidda mid ka mid ah?","answer":"Nin Dan Leh Ma Daalo."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxaa la aasaasay 1dii July 1976kii.Sheeg sanadkii lagu qabtay Magaalada Muqdisho Shirweynihii Ururka Midowga         Afrika isla mar ahaantaana Soomaaliya la wareegtay hoggaanka Ururkaas.Waxaa lagu qabtay sanadkii 1974kii.Sheeg magaca Safiirkii ugu dambeeyey ee Xukuumaddii Kacaanka u fadhiyey dalka          Jarmalka Galbeed? "},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ වනාන්තර ප්‍රතිශතය එහි මුළු භූමි ප්‍රමාණය හා  සැසඳෙන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"2023 වන විට, ඉන්දියාවේ මුළු වනාන්තර ආවරණය දළ වශයෙන් වර්ග කිලෝමීටර් 713,789 ක් වන අතර එය රටේ මුළු භූගෝලීය ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 21.71% ක් පමණ වේ. එය අනෙකුත් බොහෝ  ආසියානු රටවලට වඩා  වැඩිය."},{"question":"A complex project can be broken down into different related smaller projects.a. operational workb. subprojectc. programd. portfolio","answer":"b. subprojectsubproject is a project that is part of a larger project."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaoatrovaOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"avotra\\""},{"question":"কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ বিষয় সম্পর্কে অনুচ্ছেদ ?ইসলামের নবী হযরত মুহাম্মদের সামরিক পেশাজীবন ৬২২ থেকে ৬৩২ অবধি তার জীবনের শেষ দশ বছর স্থায়ী হয়েছিল। শক্তিশালী কুরাইশ গোত্র দ্বারা নিয়ন্ত্রিত পবিত্র মক্কা নগরী থেকে তাকে এবং তার অনুসারীদের বিতাড়িত করা হয়। তিনি মক্কার কাফেলাগুলিকে বাধা দিতে শুরু করেছিলেন। ৬২৪-এ বদর যুদ্ধের প্রথম লড়াইয়ের পরে তাঁর শক্তি ক্রমশ বৃদ্ধি পায় এবং কূটনীতি বা বিজয়ের মাধ্যমে তিনি অন্যান্য গোত্রগুলিকে প্রভাবিত করতে শুরু করেন। ৬৩০ সালে তিনি অবশেষে মক্কা এবং কাবা জয়ের দীর্ঘমেয়াদী লক্ষ্য অর্জন করেছিলেন। ৬৩২ সালে তাঁর মৃত্যুর সময়ে মুহাম্মদ আরব উপদ্বীপের বেশিরভাগ অঞ্চলকে একত্রিত করতে পেরেছিলেন এবং পরবর্তীকালে ইসলামিক বিস্তারের ভিত্তি স্থাপন করেছিলেন।","answer":"ইসলামের নবী হযরত মুহাম্মদ |"},{"question":"ஐந்தாம் வேதம் எனப்படுவது எது?","answer":"ஐந்தாம் வேதம் எனப்படுவது மகாபாரதம்.இந்து சமயத்தில் முதல் நான்கு ருக், யஜுர், சாம, அதர்வண வேதங்களுக்கு அடுத்தபடியாக ஐந்தாவது வேதமாக மதிக்கப்படும் பகவத்கீதை மகாபாரதத்தில் போரின்போது இறைவன் கண்ணன் அர்ச்சுனனுக்குச் செய்த உபதேசங்களாகும்...பிறப்பு, இறப்பு, மறுபிறவி, இறைவனின் அவதாரம், ஒருவர் செய்யவேண்டிய கடமைகள், அவற்றின் முக்கியத்துவம், யோகங்கள், இறைவனை அடையும் முறை போன்ற இன்னும் அநேக இந்துமதக் கோட்பாடுகளைத் தெள்ளந்தெளிவாகக் கூறும் புனித நூல்."},{"question":"Tichifunga chirevo chinotevera:\\"John anoda Jesica\\", shandura iyo kuArabic:","answer":"Kuturikirwa kwemutsara wekuti \\"John loves Jesica\\" kuArabic ndiko جون يحب جيسيكا"},{"question":"Miyom ne kadar olunca ameliyat gerektirir?","answer":"Boyutu ne olursa olsun Tip 0, 1 ve 2 (submüköz) miyomlar mutlak kanama nedeni olduklarından tanı konduğunda çıkarılmalıdırlar. Diğer tiplerdeki miyomlarda (Tip 3-7) miyom çapının genel olarak 5 cm ve üzeri boyutlarda olması durumunda ameliyat yöntemine başvurmak söz konusu olmaktadır."},{"question":"이 숙어를 사용하여 문장을 만들어보세요. '그림의 떡'","answer":"세계 여행을 가고 싶지만 그림의 떡이에요 "},{"question":"Miyaan u baahan ahay in aan qaato kiniinnada macdanta xadiidka?","answer":"Dadka intooda ugu badan macdanta xadiidka ee ay u baahan yihiin dhammaanteed waxay ka heli karaan cuntada kaladuwan iskuna dheellitiran ee ay qaataan umana baahna in ay qaataan daawooyinka kordhiya macdanta xadiidka ama kiniinnada macdanta xadiidka.Haddii macdanta xadiidku ay aad ugu yar tahay jirkaaga waxuu takhtarkaagu kuugula talin karaa in aad qaadato kiniin ka kooban macdanta xadiidka.Waa in kiniinnada macdanta xadiidka la qaata uun haddii uu takhtarkaagu kugula taliyo in aad sidaas samayso.Kiniinnada macdanta xadiidku waxay dadka qaar u geysan karaan calool-fadhi ama yaqyaqsi (matag qabasho). La tasho dhakhtarkaaga haddii aad dareento waxyeellooyin soo raaca. Wixii intaa kuu dheer ee ay kuu keeni karo iron la aantu waxaa ka mid ah:– Hurdo la´aan– Apitet la´aan– Daal faro badan– Hiin raag– Olal jidhka– Indhaha hoostooda oo kumadoobaada– Madax xanuun."},{"question":"ከዚህ በታች የተገለጸው ትዊት አዎንታዊ፣ አሉታዊ ወይም ገለልተኛ የሆነ ስሜትን ይገልፃል?በኤርትራ የኢትዮጵያ አምባሳደር ሆነው እያገለገሉ የሚገኙት እና ከጥቂት ሳምንታት በፊት የሹመት ደብዳቤያቸውን ለኤርትራው ፕሬዝደንት ያቀረቡት አምባሳደር ሬድዋን ሁሴን የውጭ ጉዳይ ሚኒ…","answer":"ትዊቱ ገለልተኛ ስሜትን እየገለጸ ነው።"},{"question":"උතුරු ඉන්දියානු ද්‍රෝණියේ කුණාටු බහුලව ඇති වන්නේ කවදාද?","answer":"උතුරු ඉන්දියානු ද්‍රෝණියේ, කුණාටු බහුලව දක්නට ලැබෙන්නේ අප්‍රේල් සිට දෙසැම්බර් දක්වා වන අතර, මැයි සහ නොවැම්බර් මාසවල උච්චතම අවස්ථාවන් වේ."},{"question":"Эки тизгин бир чылбыр, эптүү киши колунда.","answer":"Эл башкаруу же кандайдыр бир жерде лидерлик кылган учурда эки тизгин, бир чылбыр колго алынды делинет эмеспи."},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Con sông nào dài nhất trong số này?A. Trường GiangB. AmazonC. Yenisei","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: B. AmazonAmazon là một trong hai con sông dài nhất trên thế giới, chảy qua Peru, Brazil, Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador. Đây là một trong những tuyến đường thủy quan trọng nhất hành tinh.Các tài liệu trước đây cho biết con sông này dài 6.400 km. Năm 2007, theo National Geographic, một nhóm các nhà khoa học Brazil và Peru từng công bố sông Amazon có chiều dài 6.800 km, dài hơn sông Nile (6.695 km) tới 105 km. Tuy nhiên đến nay ngôi vị quán quân của nó vẫn chưa được công nhận."},{"question":"Bernardas Lownas, Aaronas Klugas – šie tarpukario Lietuvoje gimę žydai, kurių šeimos dar jų vaikystėje emigravo atitinkamai į JAV ir Pietų Afrikos Respubliką, yra susilaukę prestižinio tarptautinio įvertinimo. Koks tas įvertinimas? Atsakykite vienu arba dviem žodžiais.","answer":"Nobelio premija."},{"question":"Кыргыздардын улуттук суусундуктары кайсы?","answer":"Максым — бул ачытылган жарма суусундугу. Максым талкандан жасалат. Болгону, анын кайсы дандан жасалышына жараша арпа, буудай, жүгөрү максымы деген түрлөргө бөлүнөт. Максымды эки жол менен да жасоого болот.Максым ачытуунун 1-жолу: Тоң май кошулуп кайнап жаткан сууга үзгүлтүксүз чубуртуп бөлтөк болбогондой кылып талканды салат. 25-30 мүнөт жай отто бир калыпта кайнатып, андан соң отту өчүрүп, табы кайткыча коюп коюлат. Жылуураак кезинде көрөңгө куюп, унду чалып. Максым бөлмө температурасында 8-10 саатта ачып калат. Мезгил-мезгили менен чалып турса да болот. Ачыганга чейин максымга ак (сүт, айран, сүзмө) кошуп койсо, көбүрүп жакшы ачыйт.Максым ачытуунун 2-жолу: Казанга тоң майды эритип, ысыган мезгилде ага талканды кууруп, чуурута муздак сууну куюп 20-25 мүнөт кайнатат. Калган иш-аракеттин жүрүшү жогоруда айтылгандай эле уланат. Куурулган талкандан жасалган максым даамдуу, ичкиликтүү келет. Максым даамдуу болуусу үчүн, алгач унду тоң майга кызарта кууруп алууну шарт."},{"question":"ለመጀመሪያ ጊዜ ምድር ጸሓይን ትዞራለች እንጂ ፀሓይ መሬትን አትዞርም ብሎ ያስተማረው ማን ነበር?","answer":"ኒቆላዎስ ቆጰርኒቆስ"},{"question":"Жусуп Баласагындын \\"Куттуу билим\\" эмгегинен 1-2 сап жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Билимдин маанисин бил, айтканын ук,Акыл ал, ар балээден кутулуп чык."},{"question":"ஏனைய கல்வி முறைகள் என்னென்ன?","answer":"மாற்றுக் கல்வி முறை:மாற்றுக் கல்வி முறையில் கல்வி வேறு முறையில் கற்பிக்கப் படுகின்றது. எடுத்துக் காட்டாக, மாற்றுப் பள்ளிகள், தானே கற்றல், இல்லப் பள்ளி, பட்டறிவுக் கல்வி ஆகியன மாற்றுக் கல்வி முறையில் அறிவைக் கற்பிக்கின்றன. மாற்றுக் கல்வி முறையில் தோன்றும் பயனுள்ள கருத்துக்கள் பொதுக் கல்வியிலும் ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளப்பட்டுப் பின், நடை முறைப் படுத்தப்படுகின்றது.தொல்குடி சார்ந்த கல்வி:தொல்குடி சார்ந்த கல்வி என்பது அந்தந்த நாட்டில் பரம்பரையாக வந்த அறிவு, பண்பாடு ஆகியவற்றையும் கல்வி முறையில் சேர்த்து வழங்குவதாகும். பலவகைப் படை எடுப்புக்களினால் அழிந்து வரும் ஓர் இனத்தின் அடையாளம் இவ்வகைக் கல்வி முறையினால் காக்க வாய்ப்பு உண்டாகும்."},{"question":"เพราะเหตุใด นักท่องเที่ยวนิยมไปเที่ยวชมธรรมชาติที่จังหวัดเชียงใหม่โดยเฉพาะในช่วงฤดูหนาว","answer":"เนื่องจากมีแหล่งท่องเที่ยวธรรมชาติและดอยต่างๆ ให้เลือกไปชมมากมาย บนดอยจะมีทิวทัศน์ที่งดงามและอากาศเย็นสบายหากมาในช่วงฤดูหนาว เช่น ดอยสุเทพ ดอยเชียงดาว หรือจะไปดูนาขั้นบันไดที่อำเภอแม่แจ่มก็ได้"},{"question":"為什麼把孔子尊稱為聖人？","answer":"　孔子對後世影響深遠，雖說他“述而不作”，但他在世時已被譽為“天縱之聖”、“天之木鐸”、“千古聖人”，是當時社會上最博學者之一。　　後世並尊稱他為“至聖”（聖人之中的聖人）、“萬世師表”，認為他曾修《詩》《書》，定《禮》 《樂》，序《周易》(稱《易經》十翼，或稱易傳)，作《春秋》。《論語》是儒家學派的經典著作之一，由孔子的弟子及其再傳弟子編撰而成。它以語錄體和對話文體為主，記錄了孔子及其弟子言行，集中體現了孔子的政治主張、倫理思想、道德觀念及教育原則等。與《大學》《中庸》《孟子》並稱“四書”。通行本《論語》共二十篇。《論語》的語言簡潔精煉，含義深刻，其中有許多言論至今仍被世人視為至理。"},{"question":"Qual é o período orbital da Terra ao redor do Sol?","answer":"O período orbital da Terra ao redor do Sol é de aproximadamente 365,25 dias. Esse período é a base para o nosso calendário comum de 365 dias, com um dia adicional a cada quatro anos no ano bissexto, para compensar o quarto de dia extra. Essa órbita elíptica da Terra é fundamental para o clima e as estações do ano."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 法律が変わって、今年4月から18歳以上が成人になりました。成人になると、親の許可がなくても1人で契約ができます。国民生活センターは、新しく成人になった18歳と19歳からのトラブルの相談について調べました。4月から9月にいちばん多かったのは、腕や足などの毛を少なくする「脱毛エステ」の相談で、541ありました。去年の同じときの7倍に増えました。相談した人は「広告と違う高いプランのほうがいいと言われて、契約してしまった」とか「1回だけのつもりだったが、契約するように強く言われた」などと言っています。国民生活センターは「成人になると、契約は自分の責任です。契約についてしっかり聞いて、よく考えることが必要です」と言っています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"いくらはシャケの卵、たらこはスケトウダラの卵、ではぶりこは何の卵でしょう？","answer":"ハタハタです。"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Rickard Rakell var med i juniorlandslaget som vann Junior-VM 2012 genom att besegra Ryssland i förlängningen med 1-0. Han","answer":"var även med och vann guld för Tre Kronor i VM 2018."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:మగధ అనే దేశంలో మందారవతి అనే అడవిలో ఒక జింక, కాకి చాలా స్నేహంగా ఉన్నాయి. బాగా తిని బలిసిన జింక అడవిలో అటూఇటూ తిరుగుతుండగా ఒక నక్క చూసింది. దానిని ఎలా అయినా తినాలని, అందుకోసం స్నేహం నటించాలని అనుకున్నది. నేను నీతో స్నేహం చేయాలని చాలా కోరికతో ఉన్నాను. దయచేసి నన్ను నీ స్నేహితునిగా అంగీకరించు అనగానే జింక ఒప్పుకున్నది. జింక నక్కను తీసుకొని తాను నివసించే స్థలానికి వెళ్ళింది. అక్కడ మందారపు చెట్టుమీద ఉన్న కాకి ఇతనెవరు అని అడిగింది. ఈతఁడు సుబుద్ధి అనే మంచి నక్క నాతో స్నేహం చేయడానికి ఇక్కడికి వచ్చాడని జింక చెప్పింది.చివరి పేరా:సాయంకాలం అవుతున్నా తన మిత్రుడు ఇంకా ఇంటికి రాకపోయే సరికి కాకి వెతుకుతూ ఆ పొలం దగ్గరికి వచ్చింది. అక్కడ వలలో చిక్కుకున్న జింకను చూసి అయ్యో! మిత్రుడా ఇది ఎలా జరిగిందని అడిగింది. మిత్రుని మాట వినని దానికి ఇది ప్రతిఫలము అని, చెడు కాలం వచ్చిన వారికి మంచివారి మాటలు చెవికెక్కవని జింక చెప్పింది. దానికి కాకి మరి నక్క ఎక్కడికి పోయిందని అడగగా నామాంసము తినవలెనని ఇక్కడనే ఎక్కడో కాచుకొని ఉండవచ్చునని జింక తెలిపింది. నేను ముందే హెచ్చరించాను.","answer":"ఆ మాటలు విని కొత్తగా వచ్చినవారిని నమ్మవచ్చా ? ఇప్పుడు నీవు చేసినపని మంచిది కాదు. గతంలో ఒక ముసలి గుడ్డి నక్క ఇలానే పిల్లిని నమ్మి చనిపోయినదని ఆ కథ చెప్పినా జింక నక్కతో స్నేహం చేసింది. కొన్ని రోజుల తరువాత నక్క ఒక పొలాన్ని చూపించింది. జింక రోజూ అక్కడికి మేతకు వెళ్ళేది. అది గమనించిన పొలం యజమాని వలపన్ని ఇంటికి వెళ్ళాడు. అలవాటు ప్రకారం మేయడానికి వెళ్లి జింక వలలో చిక్కుకుంది. దాన్ని గమనించి లోపల సంతోషించిన నక్క ఆదివారం కాబట్టి పేగులు, నరాలతో చేసిన వల తాళ్ళను కొరకను అని చెప్పింది."},{"question":"ஒகேனக்கல் பகுதியில் நாம் பார்க்க வேண்டிய இடங்களைக் கூறுக.","answer":"ஒகேனக்கல் இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாடு மாநிலத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள தர்மபுரி மாவட்டம், பென்னாகரம் வட்டம், பென்னாகரம் ஊராட்சி ஒன்றியத்தின் கூத்தப்பாடி ஊராட்சிக்கு உட்பட்ட ஒரு கிராமம் ஆகும். இவ்வூர் கர்நாடக எல்லைப்புறத்தில் தர்மபுரி மாவட்டத்தின் மேற்கு பகுதியில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இங்குதான் சுற்றுலா தலமான காவிரி ஆறு அகன்று விரிந்த ஒகேனக்கல் அருவி உள்ளது. அழகான நீர்வீழ்ச்சியைப் பார்த்த பிறகு, மேலகிரி மலைகள் ஒகேனக்கல்லின் இரண்டாவது மிகவும் கவர்ச்சியான இடமாகும் . மலைகளுக்கு அருகாமையில் உள்ள மலைத்தொடர்கள் மற்றும் பல்வேறு மலையேற்றப் பாதைகள் மூலம் மலைத்தொடரை இறுதியாகப் பார்க்கும் உற்சாகம் அதிகரிக்கிறது. ஹோகேனக்கல்லில் இருந்து சுமார் இருபது தொலை அளவு அலகு உள்ள இந்த பென்னாகரம் கிராமம், சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை ஈர்க்கும் வகையில் மாதந்தோறும் நடைபெறும் கண்காட்சிக்காக நன்கு அறியப்பட்டதாகும் . இந்த நகரம் குறிப்பாக அதன் ஐயனார்களுக்காக பிரபலமானது , அவை பிரகாசமான நிறத்தில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க களிமண் உருவங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளன.ஹோகேனக்கல்லுக்கு அருகில் உள்ள தீர்த்தமலை என்பது நன்கு அறியப்பட்ட சமயத் தலமாகும். தீர்த்தமலை கோயில் அதன் மிகவும் விரும்பப்படும் ஈர்ப்புகளில் ஒன்றாகும். சிவபெருமானின் வெளிப்பாடான தீர்த்தகிரீஸ்வரர் கடவுளாக வணங்கப்படுகிறார்.ராவணனை வென்ற பிறகு, பல அரக்கர்களைக் கொன்ற குற்றத்திற்காக மன்னிப்பு கேட்க ராமர் இந்த கோவிலில் சிவனை வழிபட்டதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. எனவே, இந்த புனித நீரில் குளிப்பது மனிதன் தனது பாவங்களுக்கு மன்னிப்பு கேட்பதற்கும் அவற்றைக் குறைப்பதற்கும் துணைபுரியும் என்று கூறப்படுகிறது.ஒகேனக்கல்லில் கிருஷ்ணகிரி என்ற பெயரில் அணை உள்ளது. கிருஷ்ணகிரி அணை ஒரு அழகான சுற்றுலா இடமாக உள்ளது . சுற்றியுள்ள பகுதி அழகாக பராமரிக்கப்பட்டு பூங்காக்கள் மற்றும் தோட்டங்களாக உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இந்த பூங்கா பசுமையான பசுமை மற்றும் பல்வேறு வகையான மலர் வகைகளை வழங்குகிறது. இங்கு சிறிது நேரம் செலவிடுவது உற்சாகமாக இருக்கிறது.ஹொகெனெக்கல், அதன் நீர்வீழ்ச்சிகளுக்கு பிரபலமானது, ஆனால் இது 1975 ஆம் ஆண்டில் நிறுவப்பட்ட முதலை மீட்பு மையத்தையும் கொண்டுள்ளது . தமிழக அரசால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படும் இந்த வசதி, நூற்றுக்கணக்கான முதலைகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. அங்கு பல்வேறு அளவுகளில் முதலைகள் உள்ளன, பார்வையாளர்கள் எப்போதாவது இந்த அதிர்ச்சியூட்டும் மற்றும் அற்புதமான உயிரினங்களைப் பற்றி மேலும் அறிய விரும்பினால், சுவர்களில் நிறைய தகவல்கள் உள்ளன."},{"question":"Wat is een Exopropacris sudanica?","answer":"Exopropacris sudanica is een rechtvleugelig insect uit de familie veldsprinkhanen (Acrididae). De wetenschappelijke naam van deze soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1951 door Dirsh. "},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : డా|| మార్టిన్ లూథర్ కింగ్ జూనియర్ దా! కింగ్ ఇచ్చిన ఈ ప్రఖ్యాత ఉపన్యాసాన్ని చదివి, అమెరికా సమాజానికి అతడు.. ఉంచిన ఆదర్శాల గురించి, వాటిని సాధించటానికి అతడు రూపొందించుకున్న ప్రణాళిక గురించి ఒక వ్యాసం రాయంది.","answer":"ఉద్యమాలలో అమెరికాలోని పౌరహక్కుల ఉద్యమం చాలా ముఖ్యమైనది. ఈ ఉద్యమాన్ని డా|| మార్టిన్ లూథర్ కింగ్ జూనియర్ డా॥ కింగ్ ముందుకు నడిపించారు. అయితే ఈ ఉద్యమమనేది “పౌర నిరాకరణ” ధ్యేయంగా నడిచింది. (వివక్షతతో కూడిన చట్టాలను శాంతియుతంగా ఉల్లంఘించటం). డా॥ కింగ్ అమెరికా సమాజంపై ఉంచిన ఆదర్శాలు. పాఠశాలల్లో, బస్సుల్లో, బహిరంగ ప్రదేశాలలో నల్లజాతి వారిని వేరుగా ఉంచడానికి, ఉద్యోగాలలో, గృహవసతిలో, ఓటు హక్కులలో నల్లవారిని వివక్షతతో చూడకుండా వీరికి కూడా తెల్లవారితో సమానంగా హక్కులు కల్పించాలి.ఒక సంవత్సరం పాటు డా॥ కింగ్ అధ్యక్షతన మాంటగోయెరిలో నల్లజాతీయులు బస్సులను బహిష్కరించారు. ఈయన పౌరహక్కుల చట్టాన్ని చేయాల్సిందిగా కోరారు. ఉపాధి కల్పనకు కార్యక్రమాలు పూర్తి న్యాయమైన ఉపాధి, మంచి గృహవసతి, ఓటు హక్కు శ్వేతజాతి, నల్లజాతి పిల్లలు కలిసి చదువుకునే సమ్మిళిత విద్యా సదుపాయాలు కావాలని కోరాడు. మనుషులను శరీర రంగును బట్టి కాకుండా వాళ్ల వ్యక్తిత్వ లక్షణాలను బట్టి అంచనావేసే దేశంగా అమెరికా మారాలని డా॥ కింగ్ తన ఉపన్యాసంలో తెలియచేశాడు."},{"question":"Inona ary izany:  antsaha tsy misaraka, antanety tsy mifanary?","answer":"rano sy vary"},{"question":"Demal!","answer":"Go away!"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa calaamadaha Sonkorowga nooca koobaad iyo dadka halista ugu jira ?","answer":"Sonkorowga nooca koobaad waa cudur  haleela ganaca sababana in aan insulin la sameyn , taas oo aan la garanayn sababta keenta, waxaa la fahansan yahay in ay ka dhalatay jawaab celis ka socota difaaaca jirka uu kala garanwaayo unugyadiisa  iyo fayrus soo weeraray jirka. Insulin waa hormoon jirka ka caawinaya in cunadda aad ka hesho tamar sida glucose, sokorta dheeraadka ah waxaa lagu keydiyaa unugyada beerka iyo kuwa murqaha, iyagoo la soo daaya markii loo baahdo.Maxaa sababa sonkorowga nooca koobaadSonkorowga nooca koobaad waa cudur ku dhaca habka difaaaca jirka oo weerara unugyada ganaca kuwaas oo ah unugyada sameeya hormoonka insulin. Qofka qaba sonkorowga nooca koobaad jirkiisa masoo daayo insulin ku filan si loo xakameeyo sonkorta dhiiga.Sababta keenta in habka difaaca jirka in uu weeraro ma ahan mid la garanaayo ilaa iyo hada .Astaanta sonkorowga nooca koobaadSonkorowga nooca koowaad in qofka laga helo wey ka sahlan tahay tan qofka qaba sonkoroowga nooca labaad.  Calaamadaha soo socda waxay noqon karaan calaamadaha sonkorowga nooca koobaadGaajo,Harraad,Daal,Aragga oo tashwiish gala, Kaadi badan Kabuubyo amaba dareenka oo lugaha ka taga ,Miisaanka oo waqti gaaban ku lumaHaddii aad qabto mid ama ka badan calaamadahan, waa in aad u tagto dhakhtarkaaga.Sidee loo daryeeli karaa?Qorsheynta nooca cunadaIn la joogteeyo ka warqabka iyo baarista heerka sonkorta ee jirkaJirka oo la dhiso, sida socodka oo la joogteeyoDawada in waqti lagu qaato In aad ilaaliso oo aad ka warqabtid balamada aad la ledahay dhaqtarkaaga.Ha ilaawin in sokorowga nooca 1aad la maarayn karo hadii la joogteeyo daaweynta saxda ah."},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"புதுமைப்பித்தன் என்ற புனைபெயர் கொண்ட சொ. விருத்தாசலம் (ஏப்ரல் 25, 1906 - சூன் 30, 1948), மிகச்சிறந்த தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவர். நவீன தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் ஒரு முன்னோடியாக இவர் கருதப்படுகிறார். கூரிய சமூக விமர்சனமும் நையாண்டியும், முற்போக்குச் சிந்தனையும், இலக்கியச் சுவையும் கொண்ட இவருடைய படைப்புகள், இவரின் தனித்தன்மையினை நிறுவுகின்றன.மேற்கோள்:வேதாந்திகள் கைக்குள் சிக்காத கடவுள் மாதிரிதான் நான் பிறப்பித்துவிட்டவைகளும். அவை உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களுக்குள் அடைபடாதிருந்தால் நானும் பொறுப்பாளியல்ல, நான் பிறப்பித்து விளையாடவிட்ட ஜீவராசிகளும் பொறுப்பாளிகளல்ல; உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களைத்தான் என் கதைகளின் அருகில் வைத்து அளந்து பார்த்துக்கொள்கிறீர்கள் என்று உங்களுக்குச் சொல்லிவிட விரும்புகிறேன்."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపుగా ఒక పేరా రాయండి:ఒక భాషా పదాన్ని మరొక భాష స్వీకరించడం సర్వసాధారణం. పలు భాషలు మట్లాడే ప్రజలు ఒకచోట ఉండటంతో భాషలలో ఆధాన ప్రదానాలు సహజమే. భారతదేశ భాషలపై సంస్కృతం ఎంతటి ప్రభావాన్ని చూపించిందో ఉర్దూ బోధనా మాధ్యం గల ప్రాంతాలలో ఆంగ్ల భాష అంతగా ప్రభావాన్ని చూపించింది. అలా ఆంగ్ల పదాలను ఉర్దూ భాషలోకి అనువదించుకుని దానిని ఉర్దూ వానా అని పిలుచుకున్నారు.","answer":"ఒక భాష నుండి. మరొక భాషకు పదాలు వర్ణగమ, వర్ణలోప, వర్ణ వ్యత్యయ పద్ధతుల ద్వారా వెళ్తుంటాయి. ఒక్కోసారి యధాతదంగా కూడా వస్తుంటాయి. ఉదాహరణకు. లార్డ్ అనే ఆంగ్లపదం ఉ ర్దూలో లాట్సాహెబాను, ఫిలాసఫీ అనే పదం ఫల్సఫా గాను మార్పు చెందింది. కొన్ని పదాలు అర్థాన్ని మార్చుకుని కూడా ప్రవేశిస్తుంటాయి. ఉదాహరణకు ఉపన్యాసమంటే తెలుగులో ప్రసంగం హిందీలో నవల అన్న అర్థాన్ని స్తుంది."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa faa’idooyinka waa wayn ee Canabka Iyo Xanuunnada uu Ka hortagga u yahay?","answer":"Canabka waa miro macaan oo nafaqo badan oo caruurta iyo waa waynba ay jecel yihiin, maadooyinka ku jira waxaa ka mid ah fatty acids, barootinnada amino acids iyo FLAVONOIDS oo dhammaantood faa’ido u leh caafimaadka qofka, canabku wuxuu leeyahay midabo kala duwan sida, guduud, cagaar, madow, jaalle, iyo midabka casuuska (purple).Nafaqooyinka canabka laga helo waxaa ka mid ah barootiin, carbohydrate, fibre kaalsiyam, birta (iron) fiitamiinnada C iyo iyo A.Canabka waxaa ka buuxo maadooyinka sunsaarista jirka u qaabilsan ee loo yaqaanno “Antioxidants”, maadooyinkani waxay unuyada jirka ka ilaaliyaan dhaawaca ka dhasha sunta ka dhalata waxyaabaha jirka galo. Aan eegno faa’idooyinka caafimaad ee canabka: 1. Ka hortagga macaanka:Canabka waxaa ku yar waxa loo yaqaanno “glycemic index (GI)” oo ah cabbirka dhaqsiyaha ay cunnadu kor ugu qaado heerka sonkorta dhiigga. Canabka waxaa ku jirta maado la yiraahdo “Resveratrol” oo caawisa in sonkorta dhiigga heerkeeda dabiiciga ah aysan iska beddelin.2. Caafimaadka maqaarka iyo timaha:Canabka waxaa ka buuxo fitamiin C oo muhiim u ah difaaca jirka, wuxuuna ka caawiyaa ka hortagga xanuunada jeermisyaha ka dhasho, sidoo kale fitamiin C-ga wuxuu muhiim u yahay caafimaadka maqaarka, dadka joogteeyo canabka jirkooda dhakhso ma yeesho calaamadaha duqnimada sida laalaab ama duuduub. Canabku maqaarka wuxuu u sameeyaa dhalaal dabiici ah, wuxuu daaweeyaa finanka. Wuxuu timaha ka ilaaliyaa daadashada iyo cirrada.3. Caafimaadka indhaha:Canabku wuxuu kaloo ka hortagaa daawana u yahay xanuun ku dhaco indhaha loona yaqaanno “Macular Degeneration”, cilladaani waxay timaadaa qofka markuu duqoobo, wuxuu kaloo ka hortagaa caadka indhaha fuulo.4. Caafimaadka lafaha:Canabka waxaa ku jira maadooyinka resveratrol, calcium, fitamiin K, manganese, magnesium iyo potassium oo dhammaantood ka qeyb qaata kobcinta cufnaanta lafaha. Canabku wuxuu ka hortagaa xaalada lafo burburka oo ku badan dumarka.5. Caafimaadka maskaxda:Canabku waxa uu hoos u dhigaa madax xanuunka, waxa uu xoojiyaa caafimaadka maskaxda, waxa uu ka hortagaa cudurka maskaxda burburiya ee Alzhiemer ka, qofka uu ku dhacana waxa uu u noqdaa dawo wax badan ka caawisa. Miraha canabku waxay xoojiyaan xusuusta, waxayna wanaajiyaan dareenka qofka.6. Yaraynta heerka kolestaroolka:Maadada “Flavonoids” ee ku jirta Canabka waxa ay hoos u dhigtaa heerka kolestaroolka waxayna caawisa isku-dheelitirka dufanka marka horeba khafiifka ah ee LDL loo yaqaanno ama kalastaroolka xun iyo cufanka cufkiisu sarreeyo (High Density Lipoproteins HDL). Taas oo hoos u dhigaysa khatarta wadne istaagga, cudurka faaligga, iyo xanuunka xididka wadnaha (coronary artery disease)"},{"question":"相撲の階級のひとつ「前頭」はさらに細かく「何枚目」といって表しますが、前頭の一番上のことは特に何というでしょう？","answer":"前頭筆頭です。"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Aza atao toy ny _ hazo ny fitiavana, very tsy mampamoifo, hita tsy mahafaly\\"","answer":"Aza atao toy ny fanjaibe hazo ny fitiavana, very tsy mampamoifo, hita tsy mahafaly"},{"question":"كمل الحكي:\\"الشغله الثانيه هي اهميه الناس اللي بيشتغلوا حواليك. في ناس بيشتغلوا معك مش بس عشان العمل, يعني لما تغلط ما راح يقول لك انك انت ممتاز.","answer":"الحمد لله، الله رزقني بناس حوالي سواء مدير اعمالي. بس كمان مهم شركه االنتاج اللي بتخليك تثبت وجودك.\\""},{"question":" Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Qofkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Qora Bismillaahi Raxmaanil Raxiim","answer":" Wuxu Ahaa Nabi Suleymaan Cs."},{"question":"Unsa ang mga ngalan sa bulan sa tuig sa Bisaya? ","answer":"Enero - JanuaryFebrero - FebruaryMarso - MarchAbril - AprilMayo - MayHunyo - JuneHulyo - JulyAgosto - AugustSeptembre - SeptemberOktobre - OctoberNobyembre - NovemberDisyimbre - December"},{"question":"David David Godwin è rappresentato da Emma Townshend della DGA Associates. Emma Townshend e'rappresentata alla DGA Associates da David Godwin. Domanda: La frase 1 e la frase 2 esprimono lo stesso significato? - Sì o no?","answer":"No."},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan cara-cara mengelakkan kemalangan jalan raya.","answer":"Pada tahun 2022, satu fakta yang menarik telah menjadi bualan masyarakat di Malaysia iaitu jumlah kenderaan berdaftar adalah sama banyak dengan jumlah penduduk di dalam negara. Statistik ini menunjukkan negara kita bergantung kepada penggunaan kenderaan sebagai mod pengangkutan utama. Sebagai negara membangun dan antara pengeluar minyak mentah dunia, perkembangan ini adalah satu perkara yang baik untuk ekonomi tempatan khususnya bagi sektor automotif negara. Namun begitu, kita acapkali terpalit dengan peristiwa kemalangan jalan raya yang meragut nyawa hampir setiap masa. Tragedi yang menyayat hati apabila terdapat rakaman kemalangan dikongsikan di media sosial akan menjadikan ramai di antara kita trauma untuk memandu dan menggunakan jalan raya. Walaubagaimanapun, kita tidak mempunyai banyak pilihan dalam meneruskan kehidupan untuk bekerja dan melaksanakan tugasan harian dengan memandu kenderaan di jalan raya. Ikhtiar yang kita boleh lakukan adalah dengan mengenali cara-cara mengelakkan kemalangan jalan raya demi kemaslahatan bersama.Langkah pertama dalam memastikan kemalangan jalan raya dielakkan adalah dengan memandu secara berhemah. Antara punca kemalangan jalan raya berlaku kerana terdapat pemanduan secara melulu, melebihi had kelajuan yang telah ditetapkan dan melanggar peraturan jalan raya. Cara pemanduan yang berbahaya seperti di atas akan menyebabkan kecuaian dan seterusnya kemalangan berlaku. Tambahan pula terdapat pemandu yang cuai kerana menumpukan perhatian kepada telefon pintar sehingga menyebabkan kemalangan. Oleh sebab yang demikian, setiap pemilik lesen kenderaan diwajibkan untuk memandu secara berhemah. Sebagai contoh, memandu di bawah had laju yang ditetapkan, memakai tali pinggang dan topi keledar, serta memberikan signal sebelum membelok masuk ke simpang atau lorong. Langkah yang mungkin dianggap remeh ini sebenarnya yang akan menyelamatkan nyawa kita di atas jalan raya. Sikap berani dan kononnya lebih tahu dan membuli pemandu lain wajar dielakkan kerana turutkan rasa binasa, turutkan hati mati. Pemanduan yang berhemah dapat menyumbang kepada pengurangan kemalangan jalan raya.Inisiatif lain untuk mengatasi masalah kemalangan jalan raya adalah dengan menggunakan pengangkutan awam. Bagi penduduk di kawasan bandar, pengangkutan awam seperti bas dan tren dapat menjadi pengangkutan alternatif untuk bergerak dari satu destinasi ke satu destinasi yang lain. Manakala di kawasan luar bandar, pihak berkuasa tempatan seharusnya menyediakan jaringan pengangkutan awam untuk manfaat masyarakat setempat. Sekiranya kita menggunakan pengangkutan awam risiko kemalangan daripada kecuaian diri dapat dielakkan. Pemandu yang memandu pengangkutan awam lazimnya akan menjadi berhemah kerana dia ditugaskan untuk membawa banyak nyawa dengan selamat ke destinasi yang diinginkan. Bak kata pepatah, biar lambat asalkan selamat. Intihannya, pembangunan yang berorientasikan pengangkutan awam dapat mengurangkan kemalangan jalan raya berlaku dalam kalangan orang awam.Pada masa yang sama, kemalangan jalan raya boleh diatasi jika kita kerap membuat pemeriksaan ke atas kenderaan persendirian. Antara punca kemalangan berlaku selain daripada kecuaian pemandu adalah kerosakan teknikal yang berlaku pada kenderaan. Misalnya, tayar bocor, suhu enjin terlalu panas dan lampu kenderan yang tidak berfungsi. Setiap aspek pada kenderaan ini penting untuk diselenggara kerana ia memberikan fungsi bukan sahaja kepada kita sebagai pemandu tetapi juga kepada pemandu lain. Bayangkan jika anda memandu pada waktu malam tetapi lampu brek kenderaan anda tidak berfungsi. Situasi ini akan mengelirukan dan membahayakan pemandu lain sehingga boleh menyebabkan kemalangan berlaku. Maka, pemeriksaan kenderaan secara berkala di bengkel dapat mengurangkan risiko kemalangan daripada berlaku. Persis kata mutiara, sediakan payung sebelum hujan.Akhir sekali, tragedi kemalangan jalan raya yang meragut banyak nyawa yang tidak berdosa dapat dielakkan dengan memastikan jalan raya berada dalam keadaan yang baik untuk penggunanya. Kita boleh lihat melalui perkongsian di media sosial di mana keadaan jalan raya yang berlubang dan tidak rata telah membahayakan pengguna dan menyebabkan kemalangan. Lebih-lebih lagi pada waktu malam dan cuaca hujan lebat yang mengehadkan pemandangan seorang pemandu untuk melihat sama ada jalan yang dilalui baik atau sebaliknya. Masalah ini boleh dicegah sekiranya pihak berkuasa sentiasa menyelenggara keadaan jalan raya di seluruh kawasan. Selain itu, had penggunaan lori di jalan raya tertentu juga dapat mengurangkan kerosakan jalan raya kerana muatan yang berat akan menyumbang kepada kerosakan jalan raya. Pihak berkuasa juga boleh menambah baik ciri keselamatan jalan raya dengan memasang lampu amaran di selekoh atau persimpangan yang berbahaya. Jelasnya, jalan raya yang selamat dapat menjamin keselamatan pengguna jalan raya.Konklusinya, terdapat banyak cara untuk kita mengelakkan kemalangan jalan raya daripada berlaku. Ibarat kata mutiara, mencegah lebih baik daripada merawat. Setiap pihak bermula daripada kita sebagai pemandu atau penumpang perlu memainkan peranan untuk sentiasa memandu dengan berhemah dan mengingatkan orang sekeliling kita untuk melakukan perkara yang sama. Peristiwa kemalangan jalan raya yang mengorbankan nyawa perlu dibendung kerana kita tidak mahu kehilangan orang yang kita sayangi. Kerajaan sewajarnya memanifestasikan mekanisme terbaik bagi menjamin keselamatan jalan raya di negara ini ditambah baik dari tahun ke tahun. Semoga inisiatif ini diberi perhatian seluruh ahli masyarakat dan menyemat kata hikmah pandu cermat jiwa selamat sepanjang memandu bersama orang tersayang."},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் மிக உயர்ந்த இலக்கிய விருது எது?","answer":"விடை: ஞானபீட விருது"},{"question":"Алаң-алаң, алаң аяк,Жете албаймын жалаң аяк\\"- табышмактын жандырмагы кандай? ","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -\\"көлөкө\\"."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jung pecah, yu yang kenyang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika ada kerusuhan tentu ada orang yang mendapat keuntungan daripada kerusuhan itu; kerugian bagi seseorang, keuntungan bagi orang yang lain"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిరాబడి వ్యయము అనగానేమి ? ఉదాహరణలతో వివరింపుము.","answer":"ఏదైనా వ్యయము సంస్థ యొక్క రాబడిని లేదా లాభాన్ని ఆర్జించుటకు చేస్తే దానిని రాబడి వ్యయము అంటారు. ఆ వ్యయాలు పునరావృతస్వభావము కలవి. సంస్థలకు ఈ వ్యయాల వలన కలిగే ప్రయోజనము ఒక సంవత్సర కాలము కంటే తక్కువగా ఉంటాయి. ఉదా : జీతాలు, అద్దె, వేతనాలు, విద్యుచ్ఛక్తి, భీమా, మరమ్మత్తులు మొదలైనవి."},{"question":"Nitori owo Tinubu, ẹgbẹ APC ati PDP Ọṣun sọko ọrọ sira wọn ","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ti sọ pe ti Gomina Ademọla Adeleke ko ba le kede eto to ni gẹgẹ bii palietiifu fawọn araalu, ko bojumu kijọba rẹ tun pa ika mọ bìliọnu meji Naira tijọba apapọ fi ranṣẹ.Alaga ẹgbẹ naa, Sooko Tajudeen Lawal, sọ nipasẹ alakooso iroyin wọn, Oloye Kọla Ọlabisi, pe o jẹ ohun to buru ki ijọba ipinlẹ kankan lorileede yii maa huwa to le mu ki awọn araalu korira ijọba apapọ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, ohun ti ko ṣee gbọ ni pe ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ko biliọnu meji Naira tijọba apapọ fi ranṣẹ gẹgẹ bii palietiifu fawọn araalu pamọ lati oṣu meji sẹyin ti wọn ti gba a.O ni ko si awijare kankan tijọba Adeleke ni lori ohun ti wọn ṣe yii nitori ṣe ni wọn mọ-ọn-mọ n fara ni awọn araalu, ko si sẹni to mọ boya wọn n reti ki awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si i ku ki wọn too pin owo naa.Ṣugbọn nigba to n fesi, alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ọnarebu Sunday Bisi, sọ pe alainitiju lẹgbẹ APC, nitori ko yẹ ki wọn lẹnu ọrọ mọ pẹlu ọgbun gbese ti wọn ti ipinlẹ Ọṣun si ki wọn too kogba wọle.Sunday Bisi ṣalaye pe ẹgbẹ PDP ki i ṣe ẹgbẹ alajẹbanu bii tiwọn. O ni adari to bọwọ fun akoyawọ ni Gomina Adeleke, o si ti ranṣẹ ọpọlọpọ nnkan to wa fun iranwọ fun awọn araalu, laipẹ ni gbogbo aye yoo si ri i.O ni awọn nnkan palietiifu naa pọ debii pe yoo lọ kaakiri tibu-tooro ipinlẹ Ọṣun, awọn ti awọn araalu si fi ibo wọn le danu nitori iwa ole wọn nikan ni wọn le maa ro pe gomina to wa lati idile olowo yoo dẹbiti aya de owo palietiifu.O kilọ fun ẹgbẹ APC Ọṣun lati dẹkun sisọ ọrọ alufansa kaakiri nipa iṣẹjọba to wa lode, nitori awọn ko ni i kuna lati gbe igbesẹ to tọ lori wọn ni ibamu pẹlu ofin lọjọ ti wọn ba tun hu iru iwa bẹẹ."},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Στην πόλη του Καρς στο παρελθόν υπήρχε μεγάλη Αρμένικη κοινότητα η οποία εξοντώθηκε το 1915 (Γενοκτονία των Αρμενίων). Το 2009 η Τουρκία με την Αρμενία ξεκίνησαν διαβουλεύσεις για αποκατάσταση των διπλωματικών σχέσεων (και να ανοίξουν τα σύνορα των δύο χωρών τα οποία παραμένουν μέχρι και σήμερα κλειστά). Τότε ο πρώην δήμαρχος του Καρς Ναίφ Αλιβεϊογλου (Naif Alibeyoglu) αποφάσισε την ανέγερση αυτού του μνημείου ως ένδειξη φιλίας. Η διαδικασία συμφιλίωσης των δύο χωρών σταμάτησε το επόμενο έτος. Η Τουρκία με την Αρμενία βρίσκεται σε έντονη διένεξη για το χαρακτηρισμό ως γενοκτονίας της εξόντωσης των Αρμενίων το 1915.","answer":"Γενοκτονία των Αρμενίων"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?අමාරු ","answer":"පහසු"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa magaca loo yaqaano Neefka Caanaha yar?","answer":"Waxaa loo yaqaanaa Badho."},{"question":"ශාක ඔක්සිජන් අවශෝෂණය කරයි?","answer":"False (ශාක කාබන් ඩයොක්සයිඩ් අවශෝෂණය කරයි)."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko ingurumenarekin zerikusia duen politika publiko bat aipatu.","answer":"Politika publiko bat \\"Agenda 21 Lokala\\" da, tokiko garapen jasangarria sustatzeko."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கர்மாவை நம்பியவன் கடைத்தேற மாட்டான். விதியை நம்பினவன் மதியை இழப்பான்."},{"question":"అజీర్తికి ఎంటాసిడ్ మందును ఉపయోగిస్తాం. ఎందుకంటేA) ఎక్కువగా ఉత్పన్నమయిన ఆమ్లాన్ని తటస్థీకరిస్తుంది.B) జీర్ణమైన ఆహారాన్ని తటస్థీకరిస్తుంది.C) ఆహారాన్ని ఆక్సీకరణం చేస్తుంది.D) జీర్ణరసాల ఉత్పత్తిలో సహకరిస్తుంది.","answer":"A) ఎక్కువగా ఉత్పన్నమయిన ఆమ్లాన్ని తటస్థీకరిస్తుంది."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Savard draftades i fjärde rundan i 2009 års","answer":"draft av Columbus Blue Jackets som 94:e spelare totalt."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe osy?","answer":"Ny osy dia karazam-biby misy nono mihinana ahitra sady mamadi-kota, iray fianakaviana amin' ny omby izy ary maro koa ny biby mitovy karazana amin' ny osy. Raha ompiana ny osy amin' ny ankapobeny, dia tsy vitsy ny osidia toy ny hita any Kaokazy, Iràna, Iràka ary Afganistàna. Efa tany alohan' ny taonarivo faha-8 tal. J.K. no nanombohan' ny olona niompy osy. Ompiana ny osy mba hahazoana ny rononony, ny hodiny, ny volony ary ny henany. Mirefy eo amin' ny 60 sm hatramin' ny 1 m ny osy, arakaraka ny karazany. Misy somotra na ny osilahy na ny osivavy. Afaka miaina amin' ny faritra misy toetany maina sy be tendrombohitra ny osy."},{"question":"ఒక వ్యక్తి యొక్క నీడ, అతని పొడవులు. సమానము అయిన సూర్యుని కిరణాలు భూమితో చేయు కోణము ఎంత ?","answer":"tan θ = X/X = 1θ = 45°∴ సూర్యకిరణాలు భూమితో చేయు కోణము = 45°"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:“Ny tsiny toy ny rivotra tsy hita tarehy, ___ ka vao talanjona.”","answer":"\\"Ny tsiny toy ny rivotra tsy hita tarehy, potrany ka vao talanjona.\\""},{"question":"Mene ma’anar TURMI?","answer":"TURMI yana nufin abinda ake daka dashi acikin gida."},{"question":"Nan la gëbla gu Mongolie tudd ?","answer":"Gëbla gu Mongolie mongi tuddu Oulan-Bato."},{"question":"¿Dónde queda Capurgana Colombia y como ir allá?","answer":"El corregimiento de Capurganá pertenece al municipio Acandí, departamento del Chocó. Capurganá, que significa “tierra del ají”, se ubica en el extremo norte de Colombia, muy cerquita de la frontera con Panamá. Se puede viajar a Capurganá en avión desde Medellín, Aeropuerto Olaya Herrera, directo en un vuelo charter. Estos vuelos directos tienen una duración de una hora, aproximadamente y cambian de frecuencia según la temporada. En temporada baja solo operan dos días a la semana así que, asegúrate de comprar el boleto con anticipación."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'intan dikalungkan di leher anjing'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud memberikan sesuatu kepada orang yang tidak menghargainya atau bukan pada tempatnya"},{"question":" Sheeg Yaa Lagu Soo Dejiyey Kutubka Saxuuf","answer":" Waxaa Lagu Soo Dejiyey Nebi Ibraahim CS"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:\\"Ny harena mila vintana, ka raha tsy anjara tsy azo.”","answer":"\\"Ny _ mila vintana, ka raha tsy _ tsy azo.”"},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Müziği Matti Jurva tarafından bestelendi ve sözü Tatu Pekkarinen tarafından yazıldı. 1942'de ilk defa yorumlandıysa da sözü","answer":"Kış Savaşı (30 Kasım 1939 - 13 Mart 1940) döneminde yazıldı."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau:\\"Quảng Nghĩa là một nhà cung ứng phục trang ở Trịnh Châu (Hà Nam, Trung Quốc). Anh đã có hơn 10 năm kinh doanh trong ngành. Vài năm trở lại đây, việc kinh doanh phân phối phục trang của Quảng Nghĩa ngày càng suôn sẻ, số lượng khách hàng rất đông. Hàng tồn kho qua tay anh đều được tiêu thụ rất nhanh, anh chưa từng bị thua lỗ. Mùa xuân năm 2005, một xưởng may đã đến gặp Quảng Nghĩa và nhờ anh tiêu thụ giúp một số áo len còn tồn đọng trong kho. Người từ xưởng may khen ngợi anh hết lời, khiến Quảng Nghĩa lâng lâng phổng mũi. Anh xem qua áo len của xưởng may. Về phần chất lượng hoàn toàn không có vấn đề gì, nhưng kiểu dáng thì có hơi lỗi thời. Anh nhanh chóng đồng ý mua hết hàng của nhà máy với giá mua 60 tệ một chiếc. Mức giá này khá thấp so với thị trường. Quảng Nghĩa cảm thấy dù bán bằng cách nào đi chăng nữa thì anh ấy vẫn có thể kiếm được tiền. Nhưng anh đã bỏ qua một yếu tố quan trọng: Thời tiết. Quảng Nghĩa ban đầu dự định bán lô áo len này sau mùa xuân, không ngờ nhiệt độ tăng rất nhanh sau kỳ nghỉ lễ. Quảng Nghĩa còn chưa có thời gian để thu xếp việc bán hết lô hàng tồn đọng này thì áo len đã hết mùa. Bỗng chốc, món hàng trị giá mấy trăm vạn tệ trong tay trở thành \\"hàng chết\\" khiến anh hơn nửa năm không thu hồi được vốn. Quảng Nghĩa tính toán, cần phải bán được số hàng trong tay càng sớm càng tốt. Thường thì khi gặp phải trường hợp như Quảng Nghĩa, mọi người sẽ chọn phương pháp phổ biến nhất là xả lỗ. Mua vào 60 thì bán ra 50, chỉ mong lấy lại tiền nhanh chóng, được bao nhiêu hay bấy nhiêu. Nhưng Quảng Nghĩa đã không làm điều đó, vì anh ấy phải cân nhắc việc phát triển kinh doanh trong tương lai của mình. Khi bán hàng phá giá, một là sẽ khiến khách hàng cảm thấy sản phẩm của mình có vấn đề, hai là khiến khách hàng cảm thấy sản phẩm của mình không giữ được giá, điều này sẽ ảnh hưởng đến sự phát triển lâu dài. Quảng Nghĩa quyết đánh một trận thật tốt, không chỉ dẹp được đống đồ trong tay càng sớm càng tốt, mà còn không bị lỗ. Anh suy nghĩ cẩn thận từng bước và đặt nền móng cho kế hoạch tiếp theo. Đầu tiên Quảng Nghĩa thăm dò một số trung tâm mua sắm lớn trong thành phố và liên hệ với một số khách hàng nhập sỉ của mình để chuẩn bị cho việc tiêu thụ tháng sau được thuận lợi. Một bên liên lạc với khách hàng, một bên anh cũng bắt đầu nhập sản phẩm mới. Lần này, Quảng Nghĩa yêu cầu rất cao về kiểu dáng, màu sắc, đường may và chất liệu vải,…Hành động này của Quảng Nghĩa khiến cấp dưới của anh không khỏi ngạc nhiên: Hàng tồn đọng chưa kịp bán đi, sao anh đã bắt đầu nhập tiếp số lượng lớn quần áo cao cấp rồi? Quảng Nghĩa vẫn đang từng bước thực hiện kế hoạch của mình. Ngay khi sản phẩm mới về hàng, Quảng Nghĩa đã mang hàng mẫu đi tìm một số thương nhân mà anh thường hợp tác.\\"","answer":"Những tiểu thương này cũng có nỗi khổ của mình. Thị trường cạnh tranh ngày càng gay gắt, ai cũng sợ hàng về tay không bán được. Quảng Nghĩa hiểu điều này, cho nên anh đưa ra những điều kiện rất thuận lợi cho các thương nhân. Hàng mới có thể được bán ở đó trên cơ sở ký gửi. Bán hàng ký gửi là cách phân phối hàng hóa mà các thương nhân mong muốn nhất, vì về cơ bản phương pháp này không có rủi ro. Tuy nhiên, Quảng Nghĩa đưa ra hai điều kiện bổ sung: Thứ nhất, hàng hóa phải được treo ở vị trí dễ thấy nhất của cửa hàng. Thứ hai, các mặt hàng đều đồng giá 498 tệ, tuyệt đối không được có các hành vi chiết khấu hoặc giảm giá. Những thương nhân này không muốn đắc tội với chủ buôn như Quảng Nghĩa, bởi dù gì sau này họ vẫn phải nhập hàng từ anh, hơn nữa lần đầu tư này họ cũng không có rủi ro gì. Ngay sau đó, tại một số trung tâm mua sắm lớn, các sản phẩm mới của Quảng Nghĩa đều được lần lượt bày lên kệ. Tiếp theo, Quảng Nghĩa bắt đầu kế hoạch thứ hai của mình. Trước gian hàng bán buôn của mình treo bảng thông báo \\"Mừng sinh nhật 5 năm, triển lãm áo len ưu đãi mới nhất\\" là để tạo không khí tiêu thụ. Quảng Nghĩa biết rất rõ không khí như thế này sẽ rất thu hút người tiêu dùng. Sau khi tấm biển được dựng lên, anh yêu cầu nhân viên bán hàng đem hàng tồn đọng trong kho ra bày chất đầy gian hàng của mình, tạo cho mọi người cảm giác hàng hóa đa dạng phong phú. Bầu không khí đã đủ, cuối cùng Quảng Nghĩa đã xuất chiêu thứ 3. Tất cả các sản phẩm đều có giá đồng nhất là 180 nhân dân tệ mỗi chiếc. So với mức giá 498 nhân dân tệ trước đó cho một chiếc áo len cùng kiểu dáng và chất lượng, giá của Quảng Nghĩa quá thấp, mọi người đều nhận ra rằng mức giá đặc biệt này quá hời. Sẽ chẳng mua được áo len ở đâu với giá này nữa, bởi vì áo len này nhập vào cũng đã 180 tệ rồi. Do đó, gian hàng bán buôn của Quảng Nghĩa nhanh chóng thu hút một lượng khách chen chúc nhau mua hàng. Nhân viên đều không hiểu, chính xác thì Quảng Nghĩa định làm gì? Bán lỗ vốn thế mà anh cũng bán sao? Thực ra, Quảng Nghĩa sớm đã tính toán kĩ càng rồi. Trong tiệm ngoài hàng mới thì còn có hàng chết nhập vào với giá 60 tệ đọng từ kì trước. Khi bán đồng giá những chiếc áo len này cũng sẽ được mọi người chen chúc nhau mua. Sau khi kết thúc sự kiện, số \\"hàng chết\\" ban đầu về cơ bản đã được dọn sạch. Nhờ khéo léo sử dụng chiến thuật kéo cao hạ thấp, dùng lợi nhuận của \\"hàng chết\\" ban đầu để bù lỗ cho hàng mới, sau cùng Quảng Nghĩa vẫn kiếm được bộn tiền. Điều quan trọng nhất là cuộc triển lãm này đã khiến nhiều đại lý nghĩ rằng Quảng Nghĩa là một nhà bán buôn rất mạnh và sẽ mở rộng hoạt động kinh doanh bán buôn của anh trong tương lai. Bên cạnh đó, cũng có một chút rắc rối nhỏ là các cửa hàng trong trung tâm mua sắm có rất nhiều ý kiến. Vì vậy Quảng Nghĩa đã lấy lại 10 sản phẩm cao cấp đặt nhờ ở đó lúc trước và bồi thường cho họ một ít \\"tổn thất \\". Sự không hài lòng của các cửa hàng cũng nhanh chóng được lắng xuống. Trong quá trình kinh doanh hàng chục năm, Quảng Nghĩa đã gây dựng cho mình được nền tảng tài nguyên vững chắc và tạo dựng những mối quan hệ mật thiết với một nhóm khách hàng. Vì vậy, khi có vấn đề xảy ra, điều đầu tiên chúng ta phải xem xét là hiện mình đang có những tài nguyên nào? Liệu mình có thể sử dụng tài nguyên hiện có không? Có thể mượn sức của người khác để phục vụ cho mình không? Sau một hồi suy xét và lược bỏ, Quảng Nghĩa ngay lập tức phác thảo ra biện pháp khắc phục vấn đề. Để đạt được sự tinh tế và điềm tĩnh của Quảng Nghĩa, trước tiên chúng ta phải học được cách sắp xếp sàng lọc và phân loại tài nguyên. Tức là liệt kê những tài nguyên hiện có, tìm ra tài nguyên phù hợp với điều kiện hiện tại, rồi tổng hợp chúng lại. Tiếp đến chúng ta phải học cách phân tích tâm lý của người tiêu dùng. Hãy chủ động đánh vào tâm lý hàng tốt giá rẻ để kích thích nguyện vọng mua sắm của người tiêu dùng."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਬਾਵਰ ਸੋਇ ਰਹੇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮੋਹ ਕੁਟੰਬ ਬਿਖੈ ਰਸ ਮਾਤੇ ਮਿਥਿਆ ਗਹਨ ਗਹੇ ॥੧॥ਮਿਥਨ ਮਨੋਰਥ ਸੁਪਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਉਲਾਸ ਮਨਿ ਮੁਖਿ ਸਤਿ ਕਹੇ ॥੨॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਸੰਗੇ ਤਿਲੁ ਮਰਮੁ ਨ ਲਹੇ ॥੩॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਰਾਖੇ ਸਤਸੰਗੇ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਰਣਿ ਆਹੇ ॥੪॥੨॥੧੪੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 406 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਝੱਲੇ ਹੋਏ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗ਼ਫ਼ਲਤ ਦੀ ਨੀਂਦ ਵਿਚ) ਸੁੱਤੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਅਜੇਹੇ ਬੰਦੇ) ਪਰਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਸੁਆਦਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਕੂੜੀਆਂ ਮੱਲਾਂ ਮੱਲਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਗਲ ਹੋਏ ਮਨ) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਥ ਨਹੀਂ ਨਿਭਣਾ ਜੋ ਸੁਪਨਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਤ ਹੋ ਰਹੇ ਮੌਜ-ਮੇਲਿਆਂ ਵਾਂਗ ਹਨ, (ਅਜੇਹੇ ਬੰਦੇ) ਇਹਨਾਂ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਹਨ, ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਭੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਪੱਕੇ ਸਾਥੀ ਆਖਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਸਾਥ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਝੱਲੇ ਹੋਏ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਸ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਭੇਤ ਰਤਾ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦੇ ।੩।(ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ?) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੨।੧੪੨।\\""},{"question":"ما هي أكبر دول الشرق الأوسط من حيث مساحة؟","answer":"المملكة العربية السعودية هي أكبر دول الشرق الأوسط من حيث المساحة."},{"question":"අසතුට යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අසතුට යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය සතුට වේ. "},{"question":"Fẹlá Kútì","answer":"Fẹlá Aníkúlápó Kútì (orúkọ ìbí Olúfẹlá Olúṣégun Olúdọ̀tun Ransome-Kútì, October 15, 1938 - August 2, 1997) tàbí Fẹlá jẹ́ olórin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà, ó tún jẹ́ adìjà-gbara fún àwọn ọmọ orílè- èdè Nàìjíríà; ó sì tún ma ń kọ orin. Wón mọ̀ó ṣí ẹni tí ó ò síwájú orin àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú. Orúkọ mìíràn tí won a máa pe Felá ni \\"Abàmì Èdá.\\"Fẹlá Kútì jẹ́ ọmọ adìjà-gbara fún ètó àwọn obìnrin, Ìyá ààfin Fúnmiláyò Ransome Kútì. Ní ìgbà tí ó dé láti ìlú òyìnbó, orin rè kan tí ó ń jẹ́ \\"Africa '70\\" jáde ní ọdún 1970. Ní ọdún yì í ni ó fi orin rè bá àwọn ìjọba alágbádá tó wà ní'pò wì i. Ní ọdún yìí náà ni ó dá \\"Kàlàkútà Republic Commune\\" sí'lè, tí ó sì yo ara álà rè kúrò láàrín ín àwon tó ní'fèé sí ìjọba alágbádá. Ìjọ \\"Commune\\" yìí padà dárú ní ọdún un 1977 ní'gbà tí wón dá'ná sun-ún. Láti ìgbà tí Felá Kútì ti di olóògbé ni omo rè, Fémi Kútì, ti kó gbogbo orin rè jo s'ójú kan.Olúfelá Olúségun Olúdòtun Ransome-Kútì ni wón bí ní ọdún un 1938, ní ojó karùndínlógún Oşù Òwàrà (October 15) sí ìlú u Abẹ́òkúta, ní ìpínlè Ògùn, ní orílè-èdè Nàìjíríà. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a ṣe mọ̀ pé adìjà-gbara fún ètọ̀ àwọn obìnrin ni ìyá a rè, Olóyè Fúnmiláyò Ransome-Kútì, tí bàbá rè ṣì jẹ́ Olùşó Àgùntàn ti ìjọ Ańglícàń, olùkó-àgbà àti ààrẹ fún gbogbo Olùkó. Àwọn ọmọ ìyá rè ni Béèkó Ransome-Kùi àti Olíkóyè Ransome-Kútì, Dókítà ìlúmòóká Dókítà. Fẹlá tún tan mó Ọ̀jọ̀gbón Wolé Sóyínká, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ eni àkókó ní ilè aláwọ̀ dúdú tí ó gba Èbùn Iyì Lítírésò (Nobel Prize in Literature).Kútì lọ sí ilé ìwé girama ti ìlú u Abẹ́òkúta. Ní ọdún 1958, ó lọ sí òkè òkun lọ ka èkó ìmò ìşègùn. Şùgbón, ó padà lọ sí ilé ìwé èkó orin kan tí wón ń pè ní Trinity College of Music. Kàkàkí ni ó fẹ́ràn láti máa fi kọ orin. Ní'gbà tí ó wà l'óhùn ún, ó dá egbé orin ti tirè sí'lè, tí ó ń jé \\"Koola Lobitos\\", tí wón ń ko \\"jazz\\" àti \\"highlife\\". Ní ọdún 1960, Felá fẹ́ ìyàwó o rè tí orúko rè ń jé Rèmílékún Kútì, eni tí ó sì bí ọmọ méta fun; orúko won a sì má a jé Fémi, Yemí àti Solá. Ní odún 1963, Kútì padà sí Nàìjíríà l'ẹ́yìn ìgbà tí ó ti gba òmìnira; ó sì ń kó egbé orin rè káàkiri.Ní ọdún 1967, Kútì lọ sí Orílè Èdè Ghánà láti lọ wá ònà mìíràn bí yó ò ti mà a pe orin re. Ònà ìpè orin mììràn ti è yì í wá ni \\"Afrobeat\\", ìyẹn tí ń ṣe àpapọ̀ \\"highlife\\", \\"fun\\", \\"jazz\\", \\"salsa\\", \\"calypso\\" àti orin ìjìnlè ilẹ̀ Yorùbá.Bí Felá ti ṣe ń ṣe ìjà-n-gbara, bẹ́èni wón ń fì pamó sí àgó ọlópàá. Ní gbogbo ìgbà tí ó bá fi èhónú hàn ni wón maá mu lọ sí àtìmólé, béè náa ni wón a má a fi ìyà je àwọn ìyàwó àti àwọn ọmọ rè. Felá Kútì jé adìjà-gbara fún ètó ọ ará ìlú tí tí ó fi di olóògbé. Kútì a máa dojú kọ ìjọba Nàìjíríà fún gbogbo ìwà ìbàjé tí wọn wù sí àwọn ará ìlú tí wón fi wón sí ipò. Felá jé kí wón mọ̀ pé àwọn òyìnbó ni wón dá rògbòdìyàn sí ìlú Nàìjíríà. Felá tún jé kí wón mọ àwọn ìwà ìbàjé kan tí ó wà láàárín in àwọn aláwọ̀ dúdú: bí i kí a máa gba àbètẹ́lẹ̀, kí a má ṣe òótó, kí a máa se ojúkòkòrò , kí a máa da ìbò rú, kí a máa gbé'ni pa, kí a máa se jàgídí-jàgan àti bẹ́èbéẹ̀ lọ.Gbogbo ènìyàn ló mọ̀ pé Felá Kútì jẹ́ akínkanjú, tí o fi orin rè tún ìlú ṣe. Ayẹyẹ ọdọọdún kan sì wà, tí wón ń pè ní \\"Felabration\\" láti fi máa ṣe ìrántí olóògbé Felá Kútì gégé bí i eni orin rè wuyì l'áwùjọ.Ní ọdún 1999, Universal Music France, ní abé e ìdarí i Francis Kertekian, gbé áábóòmù ọgóójì ó lé márùn ún (àrùn-dín-láàdóta) ti Felá jáde. Bẹ́è sì tún ni Felá tún gba oríyìn àti àmì ìpegedé l'ókè òkun.Ní ọdún 2007 ni eré orí ìtàgé kan tí àkọólé rè ń jé \\"The Visitor\\" (Àlejò) tí arákùnrin kan tó ń jé Thomas McCarthy darí jáde. Eré yì í ṣe àfihan an òjògbón kan tí orúko rè ń jé Richard Jekins, eni tí ó fé gbó orin kan tí àkólé rè ń jẹ́ \\"djembe\\" tí ó kó láti ọ̀dọ̀ arákùnrin kan tí a ń pè ní Haaz Sleiman eni tí ó wá láti orílè-èdè Syria. Haaz Sleiman sì sọ fún ọ̀jọ̀gbón yìí pe kò sí bí òun şe lè gbó àgbóyé orin àwon aláwò dúdú àyàfi tí òun bá kókó gbó orin Fẹlá. Nínú eré yìí náà ni wón ti ṣe àfihàn orin Felá méjì kan tí àkólé e won ń jẹ́ \\"Open and Close\\" àti \\"Jẹ́ n wí tèmi\\".Nígbà ayé e rẹ̀, oríşiríşi nnkan ló fi lé'lẹ̀. Bẹ́è náà ni wón fun ní oríṣiríṣi èbùn tó pọ̀ já-ǹ-tíì-rẹrẹ. Wón sì tún fà á ka'lè ni èèmọkànlá gégé bí i ẹni tó yẹ látì gba èbùn ìpegede títayọ nínú işé orin kíkọ.Felá jé olórin tó dáńgájíá, nítorí náà àwon olórin jàǹkàn-jàǹkàn bí i Shawn “Jay-Z” Carter dara pò pèlú u Will Smith àti ìyàwó o rè, Jada Pinkett Smith láti şe işé àkànşe orin àti eré orí ìtàgé láti owó Eugene O'Neill tí wón pe àkólé e rè ní Felá, láti bu olá fún un."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH do Egito?","answer":"O Índice de Desenvolvimento Humano (IDH) compara indicadores de países nos itens riqueza, alfabetização, educação, esperança de vida, natalidade e outros, com o intuito de avaliar o bem-estar de uma população. Esse índice varia de zero a um e é divulgado pelo Programa das Nações Unidas para o Desenvolvimento (Pnud) em seu relatório anual.  Em 2021, o IDH do Egito foi 0,731."},{"question":"Taye ati Kẹhinde to n ṣe ‘yahoo’ rẹwọn he ni Kwara","answer":"Olukọ ileewe giga kan to wa niluu Ọffa, Kwara State College of Health Technology, Abdullahi Ọpaṣhọla, ati ọmọ iya meji ti wọn jẹ ibeji, Taiye-Kẹhinde Adebayọ, ni wọn ti dero ẹwọn bayii fẹsun jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara tawọn eeyan mọ si ‘Yahoo-Yahoo’.Adajọ Adenikẹ Akinpẹlu tile-ẹjọ giga kan nipinlẹ Kwara lo paṣẹ pe ki Ọpaṣhọla lọọ ṣẹwọn oṣu mẹrin, o si sọ awọn ibeji naa sẹwọn oṣu mẹfa.Ajọ EFCC lo wọ awọn afurasi mẹtẹẹta lọ sile-ẹjọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi tile-ẹjọ ti gbe idajọ rẹ kalẹ.Awọn olujẹjọ mẹtẹẹta gba pe loootọ lawọn jẹbi ẹsun ti EFCC fi kan wọn.Ọpaṣhọla ni wọn lo n lo ayederu orukọ; Devin Snow, pẹlu foto obinrin alawọ funfun, lati fi lu oyinbo kan, Eugene Myvett, ni jibiti igba dọla, 200 USD.Ni ti Taiye Adebayọ, ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an ni pe, laarin oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2020, o lu oyinbo kan, Gary Brenton, to pade lori ikanni ibanidọrẹẹ TWOO, ni jibiti ẹẹdẹgbẹta din mẹwaa dọla, 490.Bẹẹ naa lẹsun ti wọn fi kan Kẹhinde Adebayọ, ori ikanni TWOO kan naa lo ti pade Gary Brenton, to si lu u ni jibiti irinwo dọla, 400 USD, lẹyin to fi ifẹ ẹtan tan an, to si pe ara rẹ ni obinrin fun iyẹn.Agbẹjọro EFCC, Andrew Akoja, ko awọn ẹri to daju silẹ, o si pe awọn ẹlẹri meji; Paul Kera ati Emezie Dominic, lati jẹrii lori ẹsun naa.Adajọ Akinpẹlu ni ki olukọ ileewe giga naa, Ọpaṣhọla, ṣẹwọn tabi ko san owo itanran ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un le aadọta naira, #150,000.Bakan naa, Adajọ fun Taiye ati Kẹhinde lanfaani lati sanwo itanran ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta naira lori ẹsun kọọkan ta a fi kan wọn tabi ki wọn lọọ ṣẹwọn. Ẹsun mẹfa ọtọọtọ to da lori jibiti ni EFCC fi kan awọn mejeeji."},{"question":"జనం బిలాబిలా లోపలకు వెళ్లి, క్యూ కడుతున్నారు.  కొంత తోపులాట కూడా కనిపిస్తోంది.  క్యూ వేగంగా కదులుతోంది. మగవారు, ఆడవారు ఒక చిన్న కిటికీ దగ్గరకు వెళ్తున్నారు. అక్కడ డబ్బులు ఇచ్చి తలా ఒకటి, లేదా రెండు ఆకుపచ్చ రంగు టోకెన్లు తీసుకొంటున్నారు. అక్కడి నుంచి ఒక కౌంటరు దగ్గరకు వెళ్తున్నారు. టోకెన్లు కౌంటరులో ఇచ్చి ఆహారం తీసుకొంటున్నారు. తీసుకున్న ఆహారం తినేందుకు క్యాంటీన్ లోపల ఉన్న బల్లల వద్దకు లేదా వెలుపలకు వెళ్తున్నారు.  నేను (బీబీసీ ప్రతినిధి గీతా పాండే) అల్పాహారం (బ్రేక్ ఫాస్ట్) టోకెన్లు తీసుకొన్నా. మెనూలో ఇడ్లీలు, పొంగలి, కొబ్బరి చట్నీ ఉన్నాయి. వంటకాలు బాగున్నాయి...  వేడి వేడిగా... రుచికరంగా..! అన్నింటికన్నా ముఖ్యమైన విషయమేంటంటే- ఇక్కడ ఏ వంటకమైనా కేవలం ఐదు రూపాయలే! 'ఇందిర క్యాంటీన్లు' పేరుతో సిద్ధరామయ్య నేతృత్వంలోని కాంగ్రెస్ ప్రభుత్వం ఈ క్యాంటీన్లు ఏర్పాటు చేసింది. ఆగస్టు 16న బెంగళూరులో కాంగ్రెస్ ఉపాధ్యక్షుడు రాహుల్ గాంధీ చేతుల మీదుగా వీటిని ప్రారంభించారు. ఒక కేంద్రీకృత వంటశాలలో ఆహారం వండి, సమీపంలోని క్యాంటీన్లకు తరలిస్తారు. తమిళనాడులో బాగా ప్రాచుర్యం పొందిన 'అమ్మ క్యాంటీన్ల'ను ప్రేరణగా తీసుకొని వీటిని ఏర్పాటు చేసినట్లు కనిపిస్తోంది.  తమిళనాడులో జయలలిత హయాంలో అమ్మ క్యాంటీన్లను ప్రారంభించారు. ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్‌లో, తెలంగాణలో కూడా ఇలాంటి క్యాంటీన్లను ఆయా రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాలు ప్రారంభించాయి.నేను నిరుడు అమ్మ క్యాంటీన్‌లో తిన్నాను. అక్కడ ఆహారం బాగుంది. ఇందిర క్యాంటీన్‌లో ఇంకా బాగుంది. 'రూ.25 మిగులుతోంది'ఈ క్యాంటీన్లకు ఎక్కువగా పేదలు, దినసరి కూలీలు, డ్రైవర్లు, సెక్యూరిటీ గార్డులు, యాచకులు వస్తుంటారు. బెంగళూరులో ఒక షాపింగ్ కేంద్రంలో సెక్యూరిటీ గార్డుగా పనిచేసే మొహమ్మద్ ఇర్షద్ అహ్మద్ నాతో మాట్లాడుతూ- ఇందిర క్యాంటీన్‌కు రోజూ వస్తానని చెప్పారు.  ''ఇక్కడ వంటకాలు చాలా బాగుంటాయి. ఇంతకుముందు దగ్గర్లోని ఒక రెస్టారెంట్లో తినేవాణ్ని. అల్పాహారానికి రూ.30 అయ్యేది. ఇక్కడైతే 5 రూపాయలే. రూ.25 మిగులుతోంది. ప్రభుత్వం కర్ణాటక అంతటా ఇలాంటి క్యాంటీన్లు ఏర్పాటు చేస్తే బాగుంటుంది'' అని ఆయన సూచించారు. ‘‘క్యాంటీన్ వల్ల నా పని తేలికయ్యింది. క్యాంటీన్‌లో ధరలు చాలా తక్కువ’’ అని లక్ష్మి సంతోషం వ్యక్తంచేశారు.పొద్దున పూట వండే పని తప్పింది!ఇందిర క్యాంటీన్‌కు వచ్చే లక్ష్మి అనే మహిళను నేను పలకరించాను. . nnGive me a good title for the article above.","answer":"బెంగళూరు ఇందిర క్యాంటీన్లు: కడుపు నింపుతాయి సరే.. మరి ఓట్లు రాలుస్తాయా!"},{"question":"Ao anatin'ny fanangonana mofomamy dia misy mofomamy sôkôla, mofomamy voasarimakirana ary mofomamy lavanila. Ny mofomamy sôkôla rehetra dia malefaka, ny mofomamy voasarimakirana rehetra dia marikivy, ary ny mofomamy lavanila dia matsatso.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny mofomamy malefaka rehetra dia sôkôla.B. Tsy matsatso mihitsy ny mofomamy voasarimakirana.C. Ny mofomamy lavanila dia tsy matsatso mihitsy.D. Ny mofomamy malefaka sasany dia lavanila.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia A. Ny mofomamy malefaka rehetra dia sôkôla."},{"question":"Tohizo ity : “ Aoka ianao tsy ho sodokan’ny fidoroboky ny akoholahy fahavaratra, fa lasan-kovolony fotsiny ireny. Borahy ny farihy ahitana ny trondro . _____________ “ .","answer":"“ Aoka ianao tsy ho sodokan’ny fidoroboky ny akoholahy fahavaratra, fa lasan-kovolony fotsiny ireny. Borahy ny farihy ahitana ny trondro . Savasavao ny fotony ahitana ny fakany “ ."},{"question":"هل يمكنك مساعدتي في إنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر البسيط؟","answer":"بالطبع، تفضل هذه القصيدة: اللَهُ يَعلَمُ مَيلي عَن جَنابِكُمُوَلَو تَناهَيتَ لي في البِرِّ وَاللَطَفِفَكَيفَ بي وَعَلى عَينَيكَ تَرجَمَةٌمِنَ الحُقودِ وَعِنوانٌ مِنَ الشَنَفِأُطيفُ مِنكَ بِوَجهٍ غَيرِ مُلتَفِتٍإِلى المُناجي وَعِطفٍ غَيرِ مُنعَطِفِفَما أَغُبُّكَ مِن عُذرٍ وَلا شَغَلٍوَلا أَزورُكَ مِن وَجدٍ وَلا شَغَفِقَد كانَ قَبلَكَ مَرجُوٌّ فَواضِلُهُراقٍ إِلى المَجدِ طَلّاعٍ إِلى الشَرَفِتَمُرُّ نَفحَةُ نُعماهُ إِذا خَطَرَتمِنَ القَبولِ بِجَنبي رَوضَةٍ أُنُفِإِن تَستَعِضكَ المَعالي بَعدَ ذاكَ فَقَدأَفحَشنَ في بَدَلٍ مِنهُ وَفي خَلَفِيَهَشُّ لِلمَرءِ تَفريهِ أَظافِرُهُكَما تَهَشُّ سِباعُ الطَيرِ لِلجِيَفِإِذا نَجا مِن يَدَيهِ غَيرَ مُنعَقِرٍأَفنى أَنامِلَهُ عَضّاً مِنَ الأَسَفِيَظُنُّ أَنِّيَ وَصّالٌ بِهِ سَبَبيإِنّي إِذاً مِن أَميرِ المُؤمِنينَ نَفيإِذا لَبِستُ جَمالاً أَنتَ مُلبِسُهُفَإِنَّني قَد طَرَحتُ المَجدَ عَن كَتِفيلا قَدَّسَ اللَهُ نَفساً مِنكَ جامِعَةًكَيدَ البِغالِ إِلى ذي الجُلَّةِ الشَرَفِوَلا سَقى الغَيثُ داراً أَنتَ ساكِنُهاإِلّا بِأَغبَرَ نارِيِّ الذُرى قَصِفِ."},{"question":"கேள்வி : முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்றால் என்ன? விளக்குக.","answer":"முத்தொள்ளாயிரம்:இந்திய அரசின் செம்மொழித் தமிழ் உயராய்வு நிறுவனம் பட்டியலிட்டுள்ள நாற்பத்தொரு செம்மொழி இலக்கண இலக்கியங்களில் முத்தொள்ளாயிரமும் ஒன்று. சங்க இலக்கியங்களோடு ஒருங்குவைத்து எண்ணப்படும் தகுதிவாய்ந்தது இந்நூல். வெண்பா யாப்பில் இயற்றப்பட்ட இந்நூல் சேர, சோழ, பாண்டியர்களாகிய மூவேந்தர்களின் புகழ்பாடும் ஓர் அரிய புதையலாகும். மூவேந்தர்களைப் பாடினாலும் குறிப்பிட்ட எந்த மன்னனையும் பெயர்சுட்டிப் பாடாமல் வேந்தர்களின் பொதுப் பெயர்களாலேயே அவர்களைச் சிறப்பித்துப் பாடும் வகையில் இந்நூலை யாத்துள்ளார் இந்நூலாசிரியர். அகம், புறம் என்ற இருவகைப் பாடுபொருளாலும் வேந்தர்களைச் சிறப்பிக்கும் இந்நூலின் ஆசிரியர் யாரென்று அறிய இயலவில்லை. நூலும் காலவெள்ளத்தில் காணாமல் போய்விட்டது. ஆயினும் புறத்திரட்டு என்னும் நூலின்வழியாக 108 பாடல்கள் முத்தொள்ளாயிரச் செய்யுள்களாக இன்றைக்குக் கிடைக்கின்றன. முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற முழுநூல் மூவேந்தர்கள் ஒவ்வொருவர் மீதும் முந்நூறு முந்நூறு பாடல்களாக மொத்தம் தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட பேரிலக்கியமாகத் திகழ்ந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்பது அறிஞர்களின் துணிபு.எண் செய்யுள் சிற்றிலக்கியம்:முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற நூற்பெயரில் உள்ள தொள்ளாயிரம் என்பது ஒருவகை சிற்றிலக்கியமாகும். தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற தொகையுடைய நூல்கள் தமிழில் பல இருந்தன என்று அறிகிறோம். ‘வச்சத் தொள்ளாயிரம்’, ‘அரும்பைத் தொள்ளாயிரம்’ முதலான நூல்கள் பற்றிய குறிப்பினை இலக்கண உரையாசிரியர்களின் உரைவழி அறிய முடிகின்றது. தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற சிற்றிலக்கிய வகை எண் செய்யுள் என்று பாட்டியல் நூல்கள் குறிப்பிடும் இலக்கிய வகையின் ஓர் உட்பிரிவாயிருக்கக் கூடும் என ஊகிக்க முடிகின்றது.ஊரையும் பேரையும் உவந்தெண் ணாலேசீரிதிற் பாடல்எண் செய்யு ளாகும். (இ.வி.பாட்டியல், நூ.88)ஏற்றிடும் பாட்டுடைத் தலைவனூர்ப் பெயரினையிசைத்து மெண்ணாற் பெயர் பெறஈரைந்து கவிமுதல் ஆயிரம் வரைசொலல்எண்செய்யு ளாகு மன்றே (பிரபந்த தீபிகை, நூ.14)இலக்கண விளக்கப் பாட்டியல் எண் செய்யுள் நூற்பாவிற்கு எழுதியுள்ள உரையில், “பாட்டுடைத் தலைவன் ஊரினையும் பெயரினையும் உவந்து எண்ணாலே பத்து முதல் ஆயிரமளவும் பொருட்சிறப்பினாலே பாடுதல் அவ்வவ் எண்ணாற் பெயர்பெற்று நடக்கும் எண் செய்யுளாம். அவை முத்தொள்ளாயிரம், அரும்பைத் தொள்ளாயிரம் முதலியன” என்று விளக்கம் தரப்பட்டுள்ளது. இவ்விளக்கங்களை மேற்கோள் காட்டிப் பாட்டியல் நூல்கள் குறிப்பிடும் எண் செய்யுள் எனும் இலக்கிய வகையே முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என விளக்கமளிக்கிறார் பேராசிரியர் வையாபுரிப் பிள்ளை. (இலக்கிய தீபம், பக். 178-79)ஆக, பாட்டியல் நூல்கள் குறிப்பிடும் எண் செய்யுள் என்ற இலக்கிய வகையில் பல பிரிவுகள் உண்டென்பதும் பத்து பாடல்கள் முதல் ஆயிரம் பாடல்கள் வரை பாடப்படும் எண் செய்யுள்கள் பாடப்படும் பாடல்களின் எண்ணிக்கைக்கேற்பப் பெயர்பெறும் என்பதும் பெறப்படுகின்றது. அப்படிப் பாடப்படும் எண் செய்யுள்களில் தொள்ளாயிரம் எண்ணிக்கை அமைய, பாட்டுடைத் தலைவனைப் புகழ்ந்து பாடும் ஒரு மரபு உண்டென்பதும் அத்தகு மரபின் அடிப்படையின் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடப்பட்டது என்பதும் நாம் கவனத்தில் கொள்ளத்தக்க செய்தியாகும்.மரபாகப் பாடப்படும் இலக்கியவகை அல்லாது புதிதாகப் புனைந்து பாடப்படும் இலக்கியவகையைத் தொல்காப்பியர் விருந்து என்று குறிப்பிடுவார்.விருந்தே தானும்புதுவது கிளந்த யாப்பின் மேற்றே (தொல். செய்யுளியல் நூ. 551)பேராசிரியர் இந்நூற்பா உரையில் விருந்து இலக்கியவகை குறித்து விளக்கமளிக்கையில், “புதிதாகத் தாம் வேண்டியவாற்றாற் பல செய்யுளுந் தொடர்ந்துவரச் செய்வது, அது முத்தொள்ளாயிரமும், பொய்கையார் முதலாயினோர் செய்த அந்தாதிச் செய்யுளுமென உணர்க” என்று எழுதியுள்ளதனால் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் விருந்து என்ற வனப்பினால் அமைந்த இலக்கியவகை என்பது பெறப்படும்.கிடைத்துள்ள முத்தொள்ளாயிரப் பாடல்களின் எண்ணிக்கை:முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் கால வெள்ளத்தில் மறைந்து போன தமிழ் நூல்களில் ஒன்று என்றாலும், புறத்திரட்டு என்ற நூலின் வழியாகவும் (108 பாடல்கள்) உரையாசிரியர்களின் இலக்கண உரைகளின் வழியாகவும் நூலின் ஒரு சிறு பகுதியேனும் நமக்குக் கிடைத்திருப்பது உண்மையில் ஓர் அருமைப்பாடுடைய நிகழ்வே. இப்பொழுது முத்தொள்ளாயிரப் பாடல்கள் என்று நமக்குக் கிடைப்பன நூற்று முப்பது பாடல்களேயாகும். இதில் இருபதுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட பாடல்கள் பழைய உரைகளினிடையே கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்டு முத்தொள்ளாயிரச் செய்யுளாக இருக்கக்கூடும் என்ற யூகத்தில் சேர்க்கப்பட்டவைகளாகும்.முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தை முதன்முதலில் தனி நூலாகப் பதிப்பித்தவர் இரா.இராகவய்யங்கார். 1905 இல் இப்பதிப்பு வெளிவந்துள்ளது. இப்பதிப்பில் 110 பாடல்கள் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளன. பின்வந்த பதிப்பாசிரியர்கள் பலரும் இதனையே பின்பற்றி 110 பாடல்களைப் பதிப்பித்தனர். ரசிகமணி டி.கே.சி. அவர்கள் தம் பதிப்பில் 99 பாடல்களை மட்டுமே பதிப்பித்தார். 1946 இல் சைவ சித்தாந்த நூற்பதிப்புக் கழகத்தின் வாயிலாக முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தைப் பதிப்பித்த ந.சேதுரகுநாதன் அவர்கள் 130 பாடல்களைப் பதிப்பித்துள்ளார். கூடுதலாக அவர் பதிப்பித்தப் பாடல்கள் குறித்து முன்னுரையில் பின்வருமாறு குறிப்பிடுகின்றார்.இற்றைக்கு ஐந்நூறியாண்டுகட்கு முன்னர்ப் புறத்திரட்டு என்னுந் தொகைநூல் தொகுத்த சான்றோர், அந்நூலின்கண் இடையிடையே மிளிரவைத்துப் போந்த நூற்றெட்டு முத்தொள்ளாயிரச் செய்யுட்களைப் பெற்று, அவற்றைப் பயின்று இன்பந் துய்த்துத் தன்னை மறந்து உவகை எய்தும் பேறும் கிடைத்துள்ளது.கிடைக்கப்பெற்ற விழுமிய பாடல்களின் விழுமிய சுவையானது தூண்ட இனிமேலும் இத்தகைய பாடல்கள் கிடைக்கும் கொல்லோ என ஆராய்ந்து செல்வுழிப் பழைய உரைகளினிடையே பயின்று கிடந்தனவாய இருபத்திரண்டு பாடல்கள் இவற்றோடு ஒத்த இயல்பினவாய்க் காணப்பட்டமையின் அவையும் இவற்றோடு சேர்த்து உரையெழுதி வெளியிடப் பெறுவனவாயின. (சேதுரகுநாதன், முன்னுரை, ப.6)என்கிறார் முத்தொள்ளாயிர உரையாசிரியர் சேதுரகுநாதன் அவர்கள். அவர் பதிப்பின்படி கடவுள் வாழ்த்துப் பாடல்- 1, பாண்டியன் பற்றிய பாடல்கள்- 60, சோழன் பற்றிய பாடல்கள்- 46, சேரன் பற்றிய பாடல்கள்- 23 என 130 பாடல்கள் நூலில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளன.தொள்ளாயிரமா? மூன்று தொள்ளாயிரமா?இன்றைக்கு முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் நூல் என்றவகையில் நமக்குக் கிடைப்பன 130 பாடல்கள் என்றாலும் முழுநூல் பாடல்களின் எண்ணிக்கை குறித்து இருவேறு கருத்துக்கள் நிலவுகின்றன. முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற நூற்பெயர் மூன்று தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட நூல் என்று பொருள்படும் என்பார் சிலர். அதாவது, சேர, சோழ, பாண்டியர்களாகிய மூவேந்தர்கள் ஒவ்வொருவர் மீதும் பாடப்பட்ட மூன்று தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடல்கள் என இரண்டாயிரத்து எழுநூறு பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட நூல் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்பது அவர்கள் கருத்து. பேராசிரியர் வையாபுரிப் பிள்ளை அவர்களும் தொடக்கத்தில் இக்கருத்தினராயிருந்து பின்னர் இக்கருத்தினை மறுத்துரைக்கின்றார்.எண் செய்யுள் என்ற இலக்கியவகையை விளக்கும் பாட்டியல் உரையாசிரியரும் பிரபந்த தீபிகையும் ‘ஈரைந்து கவிமுதல் ஆயிரம் வரைசொலல் எண்செய்யுளாகும்’ என்று பேரெல்லையை வரையறுத்துச் சொல்லியிருப்பதனால் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற எண் செய்யுள் ஆயிரம் என்ற பேரெல்லையைக் கடந்து 2,700 பாடல்களால் பாடப்பட்டது என்பது பொருந்தாது என்றும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரச் செய்யுட்கள் மொத்தம் தொள்ளாயிரமே என்றும் மூன்று வகைப்பட்ட தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட நூல் என்று பொருள்கொள்ளலே பொருந்துமென்றும் சேர, சோழ, பாண்டிய வேந்தர்கள் ஒவ்வொருவர் மீதும் முந்நூறு முந்நூறு செய்யுட்களாக முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் இயற்றப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டுமென்றும் வையாபுரிப்பிள்ளை கருதுகின்றார். (இலக்கிய தீபம், ப.179)இக்கருத்தே வலிமையுடையது. ஏனெனில் 2,700 பாடல்களால் ஒரு சிற்றிலக்கியம் பாடப்பட்டிருக்க வாய்ப்பில்லை என்பதோடு வச்சத் தொள்ளாயிரம், அரும்பைத் தொள்ளாயிரம் முதலான நூல்களும் தொள்ளாயிரம் என்ற எண்ணால் பெயர் பெற்றிருத்தலை நோக்க முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் மொத்தம் தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடல்களைக் கொண்ட இலக்கியமே என்பது வெளிப்படை.முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் காலம்:முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தை முதல் முதலில் பதிப்பித்து வெளியிட்ட இரா. இராகவய்யங்கார் இந்நூலினை ‘ஓர் அரிய பெரிய பண்டைத் தமிழ் நூல்’ என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார். பின்னர்வந்த பதிப்பாசிரியர்கள் பலரும் சங்க காலத்திற்குப் பிற்பட்ட பழந்தமிழ் நூல் என்ற கருத்தினைப் பதிவு செய்கின்றார்கள். தொல்காப்பிய இலக்கண உரையாசிரியர்கள் பலரும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தைப் பல இடங்களில் சான்று காட்டி உரை வரைந்துள்ளமையை நோக்க இடைக்காலத்தில் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் தமிழறிஞர் களிடையே பெருவழக்காகப் பயின்று வந்துள்ளமையை உணர முடிகின்றது.முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூல் முழுமையும் வெண்பா யாப்பில் பாடப்பட்டிருப்பதனைக் கொண்டு இந்நூல் பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்குக் காலத்தை ஒட்டியோ அல்லது அதன்பிறகோ பாடப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டும் என்று கருத வாய்ப்புள்ளது. தொல்காப்பிய உரையாசிரியர் இளம்ப+ரணர் தம் பொருளதிகாரப் புறத்திணையியல் உரையில் முத்தொள்ளாயிரச் செய்யுள் ஒன்றினை மேற்கோள் காட்டுகிறார். அவரது காலம் கி.பி. 12 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு என்பர். எனவே அவர் காலத்திற்கு முந்தைய நூல் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் என்பது தெளிவாகின்றது.‘முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் காலம்’ என்ற கட்டுரையில் இந்நூலின் காலம் குறித்துத் தனிப்பட ஆய்வுசெய்யும் வையாபுரிப்பிள்ளை அவர்கள் பல்வேறு அகப்புறச் சான்றுகளின் வழியாகக் கி.பி. ஒன்பதாம் நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் இயற்றப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டுமென நிறுவுகிறார். (இலக்கிய தீபம், பக். 183-88) இக்கருத்தே வலிமையுடையதென்றால், மூவேந்தர்களைப் புகழ்ந்து பாடும் இந்நூல் கி.பி. 6 முதல் 8 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு வரை தமிழகத்தில் கோலோச்சிய பல்லவப் பேரரசு குறித்து ஏதும் குறிப்பிடாமல் மௌனம் சாதித்திருப்பதற்கான காரணங்கள் குறித்து ஆராயப்பட வேண்டியதாகிறது.முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் ஆசிரியர்:முழுநூல் நமக்குக் கிடைக்காத காரணத்தால் முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூலின் ஆசிரியர் பற்றி ஏதும் அறியமுடியவில்லை. உரையாசிரியர்கள் பலரும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தை மேற்கோள் காட்டும் சமயங்களில் கூட நூலாசிரியரின் பெயரைக் குறிப்பிடாமல், நூற்பெயரை மட்டுமே மீண்டும் மீண்டும் குறிப்பிடுவதை நோக்கும் பொழுது நூல் கிடைத்த காலத்திலேயே கூட நூலாசிரியர் பெயர் பற்றிய குறிப்பு கிடைக்காமல் போயிருக்குமோ என்று எண்ணத் தோன்றுகிறது. சைவ சித்தாந்த நூற்பதிப்புக் கழகத்தின் வாயிலாக முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தைப் பதிப்பித்த சேதுரகுநாதன் அவர்கள் தம் உரைநூலின் முன்னுரையில் முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் நூலாசிரியர் யாராயிருக்கக் கூடும் என்று ஓர் ஒப்பியல் ஆய்வினை நிகழ்த்தி, முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூலுக்கும் கயிலைபாதி காளத்திபாதி அந்தாதி, திருஈங்கோய் மலை எழுபது ஆகிய இருநூல்களுக்கும் இடையே உள்ள ஒற்றுமைக் கூறுகள் பலவற்றையும் எடுத்துக்காட்டி, மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட இருநூல்களின் ஆசிரியராகிய நக்கீரதேவ நாயனாரே முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் ஆசிரியராயிருத்தல் கூடும் என்று எழுதுகின்றார். சேதுரகுநாதன் காட்டிய ஒப்புமைப் பகுதிகள் உண்மையில் மிகுந்த வியப்பளிக்கக் கூடிய விதத்தில் ஒத்து அமைகின்றன என்றாலும் இக்கருத்தினை முடிந்த முடிபாக ஏற்றுக்கொள்ளுதல் எளிதன்று.தமிழகத்தில் மூவேந்தர்களும் எந்தக் காலத்திலும் இணைந்து செயல்படாத ஒரு வரலாற்றுச் சூழலில் மூவேந்தர்களையும் ஒத்த நிலையில் இணைத்துப் பாட்டுடைத் தலைவர்களாக்கி ஓர் இலக்கியம் படைக்கவேண்டுமென்ற முத்தொள்ளாயிர ஆசிரியரின் பெருவிருப்பம் வரலாற்று முக்கியத்துவம் வாய்ந்ததாகும். சிலப்பதிகார ஆசிரியர் இளங்கோவடிகள் உருவாக்கிக் காட்டிய ஒன்றுபட்ட தமிழகம் என்ற பாதையில் புதுநடை போட்ட பெருமை இந்நூலாசிரியருக்கு உண்டு. மூவேந்தர்களைக் குறிப்பிடும் போதும் அவர்களின் வெற்றியைக் குறிப்பிடும் போதும் பகைவர்கள் மற்றும் சிற்றரசர்களைக் குறிப்பிடும் போதும் வரலாற்று அடையாளங்கள் தோன்றாமல் பொதுப் பெயர்களையே கையாண்டு நூலை அமைத்துள்ள நூலாசிரியரின் திறம் அவரின் தமிழ்நிலப் பொதுநோக்கைப் புலப்படுத்துகின்றது.மூவேந்தர்களும் வலிமையிழந்து அந்நியர் ஆட்சியில் கீழ்நிலை உற்ற காலத்தில் தமிழ் வேந்தர்களின் ஒற்றுமையை வலியுறுத்தும் நோக்கோடும் தமிழின எழுச்சியின் அடையாளமாகவும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் பாடப்பட்டிருக்க வேண்டும் என ஊகிக்க முடிகின்றது. முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள, “மாறனை இன்தமிழால் யாம்பாடும் பாட்டு” (முத். பா.2), “பார்படுப செம்பொன் பதிபடுப முத்தமிழ் நூல்” (முத். பா.5), “தண்படா யானை தமிழ்நர் பெருமாற்கென்” (முத். பா.32) முதலான பகுதிகள் இக்கருத்திற்கு அரண் சேர்ப்பனவாக அமைந்துமை கண்கூடு.நூலாசிரியர் சமயம்:முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூலாசிரியர் யார்? என்பது தெரியவில்லை என்றாலும் அவரின் சமயம் இன்னது என்று அறிவதற்கான சான்று நூலில் வெளிப்படையாகவே அமைந்துள்ளது.மன்னிய நாண்மீன் மதிகனலி யென்றிவற்றைமுன்னம் படைத்த முதல்வனைப் -பின்னரும்ஆதிரையா னாதிரையான் என்றென் றயருமால்ஊர்திரைநீர் வேலி யுலகு (முத். பா.1)என்ற பாடல் கடவுள் வாழ்த்துச் செய்யுளாக முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இப்பாடல் ஆதிரையான் என்று சிறப்பிக்கப்படும் சிவபெருமானை வாழ்த்தும் வகையில் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளதால் இக்கடவுள் வாழ்த்துப்பாடலை நூலின் காப்புச் செய்யுளாகப் பாடிய முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூலாசிரியர் சைவ சமயத்தினர் என்பது வெளிப்படையாகிறது.முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் பாடுபொருள்:பழந்தமிழ் மரபு, பாடுபொருளை அகம், புறம் என இரண்டாகப் பகுக்கின்றது. முத்தொள்ளாயிரமும் பழந்தமிழ் மரபைப் பின்பற்றி அகம், புறம் என்ற இரண்டு பொருண்மையிலேயே அமைந்து சிறக்கின்றது. இதில் புகழ், நாடு, நகர், திறை, எயில் கோடல், குதிரை மறம், யானை மறம், களம், பகைப்புலம் பழித்தல், வெற்றி என்ற பகுதியில் அமையும் பாடல்கள் அனைத்தும் புறம் சார்ந்த நிலையிலும், கைக்கிளை சார்ந்த பாடல்கள் அனைத்தும் அகம் சார்ந்த நிலையிலும் அமைந்துள்ளன.புறம் சார்ந்த உள்ளடக்கங்களைக் கொண்டு எழுதப்பட்ட முத்தொள்ளாயிரப் பாடல்கள் பெரிதும் பழைய புறப்பொருள் மரபினைச் சார்ந்தே அமைகின்றன. பாடல்களின் வெளிப்பாட்டுப் பாங்கு முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்திற்கே உரிய தனிச்சிறப்போடு வெளிப்படுகின்றது. திணை, துறை முதலான பகுப்புகளின்றி உரிப்பொருளையே முதன்மைப்படுத்தித் திருவள்ளுவர் அகப்பாடல்களை அமைத்த நெறி போன்று முத்தொள்ளாயிர ஆசிரியர் திணை, துறைப் பகுப்புகளின்றி உரிப்பொருளையே முதன்மைப்படுத்திப் புறப்பாடல்களை அமைத்துக் காட்டுகின்றார். இப்புதிய மரபு முத்தொள்ளாயிரப் புறப்பாடல்களுக்குப் புதிய பரிமாணத்தைத் தருகின்றது.முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள்:தற்போது கிடைத்துள்ள 130 முத்தொள்ளாயிரப் பாடல்களில் 85 பாடல்கள் கைக்கிளைப் பொருண்மையில் அமைந்துள்ளன. இக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள் புறத்திணையில் இடம்பெறும் பெண்பாற் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்களாகும். ‘அங்கதப் பாட்டவற் றளவோ டொக்கும்’ என்ற தொல்காப்பியச் செய்யுளியல் 159 ஆம் நூற்பாவிற்கான உரையில் பேராசிரியர், ‘கைக்கிளைச் செய்யுள் முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்துட் போலப் பலவாயினும்’ என்று உரை எழுதியுள்ளமையை நோக்க இரண்டு உண்மைகள் புலனாகின்றன. அவை, கிடைக்காமல் போன முழு முத்தொள்ளாயிர நூலிலும் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள் மிகுதி என்பதும் இவ்வகைப் பாடல்களைக் கைக்கிளை எனப்பாகுபாடு செய்வதே மரபு என்பதுமாகும்.முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள்,காமப் பகுதி கடவுளும் வரையார்ஏனோர் பாங்கினும் என்மனார் புலவர் (தொல். புறத். 28)என்ற தொல்காப்பியப் புறத்திணையியல் பாடாண் திணை கூறும் கைக்களைப் பொருண்மை உடையது. இந்நூற்பா உரையில் நச்சினார்க்கினியர், “இக்காமப் பகுதி எழுதிணைக்குரிய காமமும், ‘காமஞ் சாலா இளமையோள் வயின்’ காமமுமன்றி இது வேறொரு காமமென்று கொள்க” என்கிறார். இவ்வுரையின் வழிப் பாடாண் திணைக் கைக்கிளை என்பது அகம் எழுதிணையின் முதலில் இடம்பெறும் கைக்கிளையோ, கைக்கிளைக் குறிப்போ அன்று என்பதும் இது வேறு ஒரு கைக்கிளை, அதாவது புறப்பொருள் கைக்கிளை என்பதும் பெறப்படும். எனவே, பெண்களின் காமப்பகுதியைக் கூறும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள் புறப்பொருள் பெண்பாற் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்களே என்பது பெறப்படும். நூற்பாவில் இடம்பெறும் ‘ஏனோர் பாங்கினும்’ என்பதற்கு விளக்கமளிக்கும் நச்சினார்க்கினியர், “கிளவித் தலைவனல்லாத பாட்டுடைத் தலைவனைக் கிளவித் தலைவனாகக் கூறுவனவும் கொள்க” என்பார். முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்களில் சேர, சோழ, பாண்டிய மூவேந்தர்கள் பாட்டுடைத் தலைவர்களாக மட்டுமன்றிக் கிளவித் தலைவர்களாவும் வந்துள்ளமையைக் காணமுடியும்.உலா போந்த மூவேந்தர்களைக் கண்டு, பருவப் பெண்கள் காமுற்றதாகப் புனையப்பட்டுள்ள முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்கள் இடைக்காலத்தில் எழுந்த பல அகப்பொருள் சிற்றிலக்கியங்களுக்கு வித்தாக அமைந்தமை இப்பாடல்களின் தனிச் சிறப்பாகும். பக்தி இலக்கியங்கள் புனைந்து காட்டும் நாயக நாயகி பாவத்திலமைந்த கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்களுக்கும் முத்தொள்ளாயிரக் கைக்கிளைப் பாடல்களும் உள்ள தொடர்பு சிறப்பாகக் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. முத்தொள்ளாயிரத்தின் காலத்தைச் சரியாக வரையறுத்தால் மட்டுமே இக் கைக்கிளை மரபைப் பக்தி இலக்கியங்களிடமிருந்து முத்தொள்ளாயிரம் பெற்றதா? அல்லது முத்தொள்ளாயிர இலக்கியத்திலிருந்து பக்தி இலக்கியங்கள் பெற்றனவா? என்பதை உறுதிப்படுத்த முடியும். எப்படியாயினும் இரண்டிலும் செயல்படும் அகப்பொருள் படைப்பாக்க உத்தி என்பது ஒன்றே."},{"question":"బహుకణయుత జీవులలో శ్రమవిభజన ఉంటుంది. వివరించండి.","answer":"బహుకణజీవులు మిలియన్, ట్రిలియన్ కణాలతో నిర్మితమై ఉంటాయి. ఈ కణాలు అన్ని వేరు వేరు పనులు నిర్వర్తిస్తాయి. ఒకేరకమైన విధులు నిర్వర్తించే కణాల సముదాయమును కణజాలము అంటారు. కావున జీవి దేహంలో, ప్రత్యేక విధిని ప్రత్యేకకణజాలం ఒక ప్రదేశంలో నిర్వహిస్తుంది.అదేవిధంగా వివిధ రకాల కణాలు వివిధ రకాల విధులను నిర్వహిస్తాయి. ఈ విధమైన శ్రమ విభజన వల్ల బహుకణయుత జీవులు, సంక్లిష్ట పరిస్థితులను కూడా ఎదుర్కొనగలుగుతాయి."},{"question":"De qual categoria é esta pergunta: Qual foi o último álbum do Nirvana?","answer":"A categoria da qual a pergunta provém é música."},{"question":"Apakah faktor yang mempengaruhi penghasilan ideofak oleh masyarakat silam?","answer":"Kepercayaan"},{"question":"Cé hé Mike \\"Twin\\" Sullivan? ","answer":"Dornálaí Gael-Mheiriceánach, a bhí ina churadh marcmheáchain, ab ea Mike \\"Twin\\" Sullivan, a rugadh ar 23 Meán Fómhair, 1878 i gCambridge, Massachusetts agus a fuair bás ar an 31 Deireadh Fómhair, 1937. "},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Belize.","answer":"A bandeira de Belize é composta por um fundo azul marinho com a silhueta de um templo asteca (um templo maia) em branco no centro, cercado por duas listras diagonais de cor vermelha."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 日本肝臓学会は、2018年から2021年に肝硬変という肝臓の病気になった2万3847人を調べました。病気の原因を調べると、アルコールがいちばん多くて、28.8%でした。C型肝炎ウイルスが、27.1%でした。太ったことや運動不足で肝臓に脂肪がたまったことが、12.7％でした。2017年までの４年と比べると、ウイルスの割合が少なくなって、アルコールや肝臓に脂肪がたまったことの割合が増えました。専門家は、新型コロナウイルスが広がってから、家で酒をたくさん飲んだり運動不足になったりする人が増えて、肝臓を悪くする人が増える心配があると言っています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- 肝臓: 1）胃の右上にある器官。胆汁を出して消化を助けたり、血液の中の毒物をこわしたり、余分な栄養をたくわえたりする。- 不足: 1）十分でないこと。足りないこと。2）満足しないこと。不満。- 脂肪: 1）動物や植物の中に含まれているあぶら。栄養素の一つ。- たまっ: 1）集まって増える。2）お金や財産がふえる。3）後まで残る。- ウイルス: 1）日本脳炎やインフルエンザなどの病気を起こす、ふつうの顕微鏡では見えないような、非常に小さな生物。ビールス。- 割合: 1）物と物との関係を、数で表したもの。割。率。歩合。2）思いのほか。比較的。- 広がっ: 1）広くなる。2）広々と見わたせる。3）行きわたる。4）大きくなる。"},{"question":"السؤال: من صاحب مقترح جمع القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الإجابة: عمر بن الخطاب رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pucuk dicita ulam mendatang'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud memperoleh sesuatu yang dihajati. Contoh ayat: Penyertaan Erra dalam pertandingan mencari harta karun itu seperti pucuk dicita ulam mendatang apa bila dia telah berjaya memenangi sebuah rumah banglo baharu yang sudah lama diidamkannya."},{"question":"Бир гана сабак боюнча окуучунун даярдык денгээлин текшерүү үчүн түзүлгөн тест:а)Гомогендүүб)Гетерогендүүв)Адаптивдүү","answer":" Тураа жообу:б)Гетерогендүү"},{"question":"La domanda: Quali libri di Maze Runner non hanno più di 70 capitoli?","answer":"La risposta. Ci sono The Maze Runner, The Scorch Trials, The Kill Order, The Fever Code."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane,  sidoo kale goorta uu dhashay iyo meesha uu ku dhashay?","answer":"Maxamed Cabdulle Xalane waxa uu dhashay sanadkii  1943, wuxuuna ku dhashay Ceelbuur."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: മലയാളത്തിലെ ഇന്ദുലേഖ എന്ന പുസ്തകം എഴുതിയത് ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ചന്തുമേനോൻ എന്ന മലയാള സാഹിത്യകാരനാണ് \\"ഒ. ഇന്ദുലേഖ\\" എഴുതിയത്."},{"question":"Ta yaya Dr. Grey da Dr. Pierce suke da alaƙa?","answer":"Ƴar'uwar kakarta ce."},{"question":"Ahoana ny famatsiam-bolan'ny kandidà ny fampielezan-keviny?","answer":"Amin’ny alalan’ny fanomezana manokana, famatsiam-bolam-panjakana na volan’ny fampielezan-kevitra."},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny CSB ?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny CSB dia Centre de Santé de Base"},{"question":"Адамдар менен унаалар басып өтүүчү жаныбар кандай аталат?","answer":"Зебра"},{"question":"A quale categoria appartiene questa domanda: \\"Quando fu completato il monumento a Washington?\\".","answer":"La categoria è: geografia."},{"question":"வினா: உலகில் அதிகூடிய விஷத்தன்மை வாய்ந்த மீன் இனம் எது?","answer":"விடை: ஸ்டான் பிஷ் "},{"question":"艾曼努埃尔·里瓦最出名的是她在1959年由法国电影导演阿伦·雷斯内斯执导的哪部电影","answer":"广岛我的爱"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是心理學中的「情緒智商」？","answer":"答案：情緒智商是指個體對於自己和他人情緒的認識、理解和應對的能力。它包括情緒辨識、情緒管理、情緒應對和情緒表達等方面，對於個體的情緒健康和人際關係具有重要影響。"},{"question":"وجدت هذا السؤال في موقع ثقافي: متى عقدت الجمعية البرلمانية لمجلس أوروبا دورتها الأولى؟","answer":"عقدت الدورة الأولى للجمعية البرلمانية لمجلس أوروبا في عام 1949."},{"question":"ලොව විශාලතම ඩෙල්ටාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොව විශාලතම ඩෙල්ටාව ගැන්ගස් ඩෙල්ටාවය."},{"question":"ब्रिटीश कॅप्टन हॉकिन्स भारतात केव्हा आला होता ?","answer":"ब्रिटीश कॅप्टन हॉकिन्स भारतात इ.स. 1609 मध्ये आला होता."},{"question":"கீழ்க்காணும்  பொதுஅறிவு அறிவு வினாவுக்கு விடையளிக்கவும்.இந்தியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய நதி எது?","answer":"விடை: கங்கை"},{"question":"வினா : மனிதனைப்போல் தலையில் வழுக்கை விழும் குரங்கு எது ?","answer":"விடை : ஆண் குரங்கு,"},{"question":" Đọc số sau:  21 515A. Hai một năm một năm B. Hai mươi một nghìn năm trăm mười nămC. Hai mươi mốt nghìn năm trăm mười lămD. Hai mốt nghìn năm trăm mười lăm","answer":"Lời giảiSố 21 515 được đọc là “hai mươi mốt nghìn năm trăm mười lăm”. Chọn đáp án C. "},{"question":"Kíni à ń ki èṣù ní ilẹ̀ Yorùbá?","answer":"Èṣù láàálú ògiri òkò ni."},{"question":"ما هو الدعاء الذي أوصانا الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم بتكراره في العشرة الأخيرة من رمضان؟","answer":"اللهم إنك عفواَ كريماً تحب العفو فأعفو عنا."},{"question":"「さえ」と「すら」は同じ、と言ってもいいですか。","answer":"「疲れて、立つことすらできない」「疲れて、立つことさえできない」確かにこのようなケースではいずれも使うことができますね。「お金さえ払えば、誰でも入会できるよ」このパターンでは、「すら」は使えません。「すら」は主に後ろの節に、ネガティブな要素が来る時に使い、対象をすこし低く見るようなニュアンスが含まれます。「さえ」はネガティブな場合、だけでなく、「〜さえ、〜ば」のように「ば」と一緒に使ってポジティブな文脈にも使うことができます。○彼はまだひらがなさえよめない。○彼はまだひらがなすらよめない○ひらがなさえ読めれば、簡単な作業を手伝ってもらえる×  ひらがなすら読めれば、簡単な作業を手伝ってもらえる"},{"question":"Makungenziwa iphutha lokucabanga ukuthi ukuzimela kusho ukukhohlwaabazali. Akekho umuntu obaluleke ukwedlula umzali empilweni. Umzali usukeesakhombisa uthando oluyisimangaliso uma ekutshela ukuthi zifunele indawoyakho. Lena enye yezindlela zokubona ukuthi uphumelele yini ekukukhuliseningendlela efanele. Yimuphi umzali ongejabule ukuvakashela ingane yakhekwayo?Asikho isikhathi esiqoshiwe sokuphuma ekhaya. Ngokwama-Afrika umfanauma esekhulile wakhelwa ilawu ekhaya. Lokho kusuke kuyisiqalosokuphemba umuzi. Amantombazane wona ahamba uma eseyogana. Lokhukwakwenzeka ngezikhathi esezadlula. Ucabanga ukuthi kusengenzekanamanje? Kuhle ukuphuma ekhaya usulungisele abazali umuzi. Ikhaya lakiniselibukeka. Lokhu kwenza kunikeza iqholo lokukhomba ikhaya lakiningaphandle kokuzenyeza kanye nokwesaba. Ukuvakasha ekhaya kubalula,kube mnandi futhi nakubazali ukuvakashelwa ingane yabo eyaphuma kahleekhaya. Ukujabula akugcini kubazali kuphela. Izinyanya zakini kanye noMdalibahlale bekubhekile futhi bekulethela izinhlanhla.Kwesinye isikhathi akubi lula ukulungisa ikhaya lakini uma nibaningi. Inganikuba khona ukubhekana emehlweni, niqhubane ngamadolo. Isizathu salokhuukuthi ningaba ngabandawonye impela kodwa indlela enicabanga ngayonenenza ngayo izinto ingafani. Ezinye izingane ukukhuliswa nokunakekelwangabazali zikuthatha njengento okwakufanele bayenze abazali. Ngaleyondlela zona njengezingane azibakweleti lutho abazali bazo. Ezinye zize zenzeimicimbi emikhulu uma seziphuma ekhaya. Lokhu kusuke kuwukubongaukukhuliswa, nokuzicelela izinhlanhla lapho ziya khona. Kuya ngenkoleloyakho-ke ekutheni uzicelela izibusiso kuMdali noma uzicelela kwabakiniukuba bahambe nawe.Kukhona ezinye izizathu zokungaphumi kwezinye izingane emakhaya.Kanjalo nabazali kuyenzeka babe nezizathu zabo zokungafuni ukubaizingane zabo ziphume. Izingane ezikhubazekile nganoma iyiphi indlelazidinga ukunakekelwa. Umzali kuphela osuke eyazi kahle ingane yakhe. 1. Ngokucabanga kwakho yiziphi ezinye izizathu ezingekhoesiqeshini ezenza ukuthi izingane eziningi zikubona kunzimaukuphuma emakhaya nakuba sezikhulile? Nikeza kube KUBILI. ","answer":"Azifuni ukusebenzisa imali yazo.Zibheke amafa asemakubo. "},{"question":"Title: ఉత్తమ్‌ కుమార్‌రెడ్డి: పైలట్ గెలిచారు.. పార్టీ ఓడిపోయిందిnSummary: నలమంద ఉత్తమ్‌కుమార్‌రెడ్డి.. అనే కన్నా కెప్టెన్ ఉత్తమ్‌కుమార్‌రెడ్డి అంటే చాలా మందికి తెలుస్తుంది. భారత వాయుసేనలో యుద్ధ విమాన పైలట్‌గా పనిచేసిన ఉత్తమ్‌కుమార్.. ఇప్పుడు ప్రదేశ్ కాంగ్రెస్ కమిటీ అధ్యక్షుడిగా తెలంగాణ శాసనసభ ఎన్నికల సమరంలో కాంగ్రెస్ పార్టీకి సారథిగా ఉన్నారు.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"జననం: 1962 జూన్ 20న తెలంగాణలోని సూర్యాపేట విద్య: బీఎస్‌సీ వృత్తి: భారత వాయుసేనలో పైలట్‌గా పనిచేశారు. మిగ్ 21, మిగ్ 23 యుద్ధ విమానాలకు పైలట్‌గా ఉన్నారు. 1990లో రాష్ట్రపతి భద్రతా వ్యవహారాల బాధ్యతలు నిర్వర్తించారు. వివాహం: ఉత్తమ్‌కుమార్ వాయుసేనలో ఉండగానే ఆర్కిటెక్ట్ పద్మావతితో 1990లో వివాహమైంది. రాజకీయ ప్రవేశం... 1994లో వాయుసేన ఉద్యోగానికి రాజీనామా చేసిన ఉత్తమ్‌కుమార్‌రెడ్డి కాంగ్రెస్‌ పార్టీలో చేరటం ద్వారా క్రియాశీల రాజకీయాల్లోకి వచ్చారు. "},{"question":"2x + y = 5 మరియు kx – y = 11 యొక్క సాధన z = 4, y = – 3 అయిన ఓ విలువను కనుగొనుము.","answer":"k(4) – (- 3) = 11 ⇒ 4k + 3 = 11= 4k = 8 ⇒ k = 2"},{"question":"Qual é a diferença entre carvão antracito e carvão betuminoso?","answer":"O carvão antracito é um tipo de carvão com classificação superior devido à sua maior percentagem de carbono (87%) e menores impurezas. O antracito processa uma quantidade maior de calor por unidade de massa do que os outros tipos de carvão. Ele não acende facilmente e queima de forma limpa. O antracito é mais duro do que outros tipos de carvão; portanto, é conhecido como carvão duro. O antracito é formado quando outros tipos de carvão de classificação inferior são submetidos a temperaturas mais altas por um longo período de tempo. Já o carvão betuminoso é um tipo de carvão mais abundante. É macio e contém uma substância chamada betume, que é semelhante ao alcatrão. A porcentagem de carbono no carvão betuminoso é normalmente menor que no antracito e também contém água, hidrogênio, enxofre e outras impurezas. Pode ser classificado em três categorias:,baixo volume, média volatilidade e de alta volatilidade, com base em seu conteúdo volátil. "},{"question":"Tóm tắt văn bản sau: Nguồn tin của Reuters ngày 18.9 cho hay động thái mới dự kiến diễn ra ngay trong tuần này. Đây được coi là một bước đi hứa hẹn lâu dài nhằm giảm bớt áp lực lên các doanh nhân mới nổi của Cuba trong bối cảnh quốc đảo này chịu sự cấm vận kinh tế nặng nề từ Mỹ.Nguồn tin cũng tiết lộ thêm rằng bước đi mới cũng giúp Washington dễ dàng hỗ trợ trực tiếp các chủ doanh nghiệp nhỏ ở Cuba bằng cách cung cấp các hướng dẫn cho vay thông qua hệ thống tài chính Mỹ.Các biện pháp mới có thể được triển khai trong thời gian Chủ tịch nước Cuba Miguel Diaz-Canel ở New York để tham dự cuộc họp của Đại hội đồng Liên Hiệp Quốc bắt đầu vào ngày 19.9, theo hãng tin Bloomberg.Tuy nhiên, không có dấu hiệu nào cho thấy động thái này có thể là một phần trong quá trình nới lỏng đáng kể các lệnh cấm vận của Mỹ và các hạn chế khác đối với Cuba, sau những bước đi khiêm tốn mà ông Biden đã thực hiện kể từ khi nhậm chức vào tháng 1.2021.Một quan chức Bộ Ngoại giao Mỹ nói với Reuters: \\"Chúng tôi tin rằng doanh nghiệp tư nhân là hy vọng tốt nhất của Cuba trong việc tạo ra sự phát triển kinh tế và việc làm nhằm cải thiện mức sống cho người dân và giảm mức độ di cư cao hiện nay\\".Quan chức này nhấn mạnh rằng bất kỳ bước đi nào của Mỹ nhằm hỗ trợ người dân Cuba sẽ được thực hiện nhưng sẽ hạn chế tối đa việc quân đội Cuba hưởng lợi từ đây.Đại sứ quán Cuba ở Washington chưa bình luận.Doanh nghiệp tư nhân tái xuất hiện ở Cuba chỉ 2 năm trước sau khi bị cấm trong nhiều thập niên. Tuy nhiên nguồn tài chính nước ngoài phần lớn đã bị chặn bởi lệnh cấm vận kinh tế thời Chiến tranh Lạnh của Washington đối với hòn đảo này.Các biện pháp mới có thể giúp tạo điều kiện thuận lợi cho dòng vốn vay của Mỹ.Ông Biden năm ngoái đã dỡ bỏ một phần một số hạn chế từ thời người tiền nhiệm Donald Trump đối với Cuba nhưng vẫn duy trì các hạn chế khác.Ngoài ra, theo Reuters, trong thời gian ở New York, ông Diaz-Canel dự kiến thúc đẩy vụ kiện của Havana để Mỹ loại Cuba khỏi danh sách các quốc gia tài trợ khủng bố. Chính quyền ông Biden cũng đang xem xét lại việc liệt Cuba vào danh sách các quốc gia tài trợ khủng bố mà ông Trump áp đặt vào cuối nhiệm kỳ.","answer":"Chính quyền Tổng thống Joe Biden đang chuẩn bị công bố các biện pháp quản lý mới nhằm cho phép Mỹ hỗ trợ tài chính nhiều hơn cho các doanh nghiệp tư nhân nhỏ ở Cuba."},{"question":"Apakah ibu negara Kemboja?","answer":"Ibu negara ialah Phom Penh."},{"question":"Ответьте на этот сложный вопрос: Какой род содержит наибольшее количество видов?","answer":"Астрагал насчитывает самое большое количество видов. Согласно данным сайта \\"The Plant List\\", счет видов выше 2455. Астрагал — род растений семейства Бобовые. Основные жизненные формы — кустарники, полукустарники, травы."},{"question":"बुद्ध धर्मको बारेमा केही भन्नुहोस्।","answer":"बुद्ध धर्म, जसलाई धर्मविनय (अनुवाद - \\"सिद्धान्त र अनुशासनहरू\\") पनि भनिन्छ, एक भारतीय धर्म वा दार्शनिक परम्परा हो जुन बुद्धलाई दिइएको शिक्षामा आधारित छ। यो ५ औं शताब्दी ईसा पूर्वमा श्रमण-आन्दोलनको रूपमा पूर्वी गंगाको मैदानमा उत्पत्ति भएको थियो र बिस्तारै सिल्क रोड हुँदै एशियाको धेरै भागमा फैलियो। यो संसारको चौथो ठूलो धर्म हो, ५२० मिलियन भन्दा बढी अनुयायीहरू (बौद्ध), जसले विश्वव्यापी जनसंख्याको सात प्रतिशत समावेश गर्दछ।बुद्धको केन्द्रीय शिक्षाले दुखबाट मुक्ति प्राप्त गर्ने उद्देश्यलाई जोड दिन्छ (प्रायः \\"पीडा\\" वा \\"अस्वस्थ\\" को रूपमा अनुवाद गरिएको), जसको स्रोत संलग्न वा टाँसिएको भनिन्छ। उनले मध्य मार्गलाई समर्थन गरे, विकासको बाटो जसले चरम तपस्या र हेडोनिज्म दुवैलाई बेवास्ता गर्दछ। यस मार्गको सारांश नोबल एट्फोल्ड पथमा व्यक्त गरिएको छ, मनको खेती जसले बौद्ध नैतिकता र ध्यानको पालना गरेर जागृति र पूर्ण मुक्तितर्फ लैजान्छ। अन्य व्यापक रूपमा अवलोकन गरिएका अभ्यासहरूमा भिक्षुवाद, तीन रत्नहरूमा \\"शरण लिनु\\" समावेश छ: बुद्ध, धर्म, संघ, र पूर्णताको खेती (पारमिता)।बौद्ध विद्यालयहरू मुक्तिको मार्ग (मार्ग), विभिन्न बौद्ध ग्रन्थहरूमा तोकिएको सापेक्ष महत्त्व र 'प्रामाणिकता', र तिनीहरूका विशिष्ट शिक्षा र अभ्यासहरूको व्याख्यामा भिन्न हुन्छन्। बौद्ध धर्मका दुई प्रमुख विद्यमान शाखाहरू सामान्यतया विद्वानहरूले मान्यता पाएका छन्: थेरवाद (साहित्य 'एल्डरहरूको विद्यालय') र महायान (शाखा 'महान वाहन')। थेरवाद परम्पराले व्यक्तिगत आत्मलाई पार गर्ने र मृत्यु र पुनर्जन्मको चक्र (संसार) समाप्त गर्ने माध्यमको रूपमा निर्वाण (अर्थात 'निभाउने') को प्राप्तिलाई जोड दिन्छ। यसको विपरित, महायान परम्पराले बोधिसत्व-आदर्शलाई जोड दिन्छ, जसमा सबै प्राणीहरूलाई मुक्त गर्ने काम गर्दछ। विभिन्न भाषाहरू (जस्तै संस्कृत, पाली, तिब्बती र चिनियाँ) मा धेरै पाठ्य संग्रहहरू सहित, बौद्ध क्यानन विशाल छ।थेरावडा शाखाको श्रीलंका र दक्षिणपूर्व एशियामा व्यापक रूपमा पछ्याइएको छ: म्यानमार, थाइल्याण्ड, लाओस र कम्बोडिया। महायान शाखा - जसमा जेन, शुद्ध भूमि, निचिरेन, तियानताई, तेन्डाई र शिंगोनको परम्पराहरू समावेश छन् - मुख्य रूपमा नेपाल, भुटान, चीन, मलेसिया, भियतनाम, ताइवान, कोरिया र जापानमा अभ्यास गरिन्छ। थप रूपमा, वज्रयान, भारतीय निपुणहरूलाई श्रेय दिइएको शिक्षाको एक निकाय, महायान भित्र छुट्टै शाखा वा परम्पराको रूपमा हेर्न सकिन्छ। तिब्बती बौद्ध धर्म, जसले आठौं शताब्दीको भारतको वज्रयान शिक्षालाई संरक्षण गर्दछ, हिमालय राज्यहरू, मंगोलिया र रूसी कल्मिकियामा अभ्यास गरिन्छ। ऐतिहासिक रूपमा, प्रारम्भिक दोस्रो सहस्राब्दी सम्म, बौद्ध धर्म भारतीय उपमहाद्वीपमा व्यापक रूपमा अभ्यास गरिएको थियो; अफगानिस्तान, तुर्कमेनिस्तान, उज्बेकिस्तान र ताजिकिस्तान जस्ता एसियाका अन्य ठाउँमा पनि यसले आफ्नो पाइला राखेको थियो।"},{"question":"왜 날숨으로 촛불을 끌 수 있을까요?","answer":"호흡에 관한 간단한 설명을 보면 숨을 들이쉬는 것은 산소를 들이마시기 위함이고,내쉬는 것은 이산화탄소를 내보내기 위함이라고 합니다.그러면 이 때 나오는 이산화탄소 때문에 불을 끄는 거라고 생각할 수 있습니다.그러나 엄밀히 말해서 이산화탄소 자체가 불을 끄는 것이 아닙니다.산소를 차단하여 불이 유지되는 것을 막는 간접적인 역할을 하거나,CO2 소화기의 경우에는 분출할 때 압력변화에 따른 냉각효과를 이용하는 것이지요.게다가 사실, 날숨에는 이산화탄소보다 산소가 더 많습니다!대부분은 (공기 중에서도 가장 많은) 질소로 구성되어 있고,산소가 15% 내외, 이산화탄소는 4% 내외입니다. 산소가 훨씬 더 많지요.그러니 불을 끌 때 날숨의 이산화탄소는 관련이 없습니다.날숨으로 불을 끌 수 있는 것은 숨을 내쉬며 나오는 바람 때문입니다.불이 유지될 수 있는 조건은 발화점 이상의 온도, 탈 물질, 산소입니다.바람은 이 중에서 탈 물질을 날려보내서 불을 끄는 것입니다.촛불은 파라핀 성분이 기화하면서 계속 공급되기 때문에 불꽃이 지속되는 것이지요.이 때 바람을 불면 이 기화된 파라핀이 날아가버리므로 탈 물질을 잃은 촛불은 꺼지고 맙니다.따라서 우리가 촛불을 불어서 끄는 이유는 날숨의 이산화탄소 때문이 아님을 알 수 있습니다.날숨을 낼 때의 바람 때문이지요.굳이 날숨이 아니더라도 밖에서 바람이 불어오거나 부채질을 하면 촛불이 꺼지는 것을 봐도촛불을 끄는 것은 바람이라는 것을 알 수 있습니다."},{"question":"انا ذاهب الى الحديقة. يجب أن أحضر مظلة لأنها تمطر. نعم أم لا؟","answer":"نعم"},{"question":"cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿En qué consola el juego introdujo a Yoshi, el compañero de Mario?","answer":"El tema principal de la pregunta ¿En qué consola el juego introdujo a Yoshi, el compañero de Mario? es sobre video juegos"},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta alla seguente domanda?\\"Qual è stato il primo presidente degli Stati Uniti ad essere stato accusato formalmente dal Congresso?\\"","answer":"Il primo presidente degli Stati Uniti ad essere stato accusato formalmente dal Congresso fu Andrew Johnson."},{"question":"வினா :உலகின் மிக நீளமான மணற்கல் குகை எந்த இந்திய மாநிலத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது? ","answer":"விடை: கிரேம் பூரி, மேகாலயா ."},{"question":"Nhà bác học nào đã phát minh ra kính thiên văn: Newton, Tesla, Gallileo hay Einstein?","answer":"Nhà bác học Gallileo là \\"cha đẻ\\" của kính thiên văn."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Thịt nướng hay barbecue là một món ăn phổ biến trong các bữa tiệc cuối tuần, đặc biệt là các bữa tiệc ngoài trời vào mùa hè. Trong các bữa tiệc này, người ta thường dùng thịt gà, thịt bò, sườn heo, xúc xích,... để nướng. Một nghiên cứu đã chỉ ra rằng các loại thịt nướng ở nhiệt độ cao trên 300 độ F (tương đương 148,8 độ C trở lên) làm tăng nguy cơ ung thư. Theo một nghiên cứu được công bố trên Tạp chí Nutrients vào năm 2019, quá trình nướng thịt sản sinh ra các chất gây ung thư là amin dị vòng (HA) và hydrocacbon thơm đa vòng (PAH). Creatine - một axit hữu cơ trong thịt - khi nấu ở nhiệt độ cao sẽ sản sinh ra HA. Chất béo trong thịt rơi xuống lửa khi nướng sẽ cháy bốc lên dưới dạng hydrocacbon thơm đa vòng (PAH) và dính vào thịt. HA và PAH là những chất gây đột biến, có thể gây ra những thay đổi trong DNA của các tế bào, từ đó có thể dẫn tới ung thư. Tuy nhiên, đây mới chỉ là kết quả của nghiên cứu trong phòng thí nghiệm và trên động vật với liều lượng HA và PAH cao hơn mức mà con người có thể tiêu thụ. Cho tới nay vẫn chưa có bất kỳ nghiên cứu nào trên người để làm rõ vấn đề này. Cho dù thịt nướng có làm tăng nguy cơ ung thư hay không, bạn nên nhận thức được mối nguy hiểm và có biện pháp phòng ngừa. Theo các chuyên gia dinh dưỡng, chúng ta có thể thưởng thức các món nướng yêu thích của mình một cách an toàn hơn bằng các cách sau đây: Có rất nhiều cách để tăng cường chất chống oxy hóa trong bữa ăn. Những hợp chất chống oxy hóa bảo vệ các tế bào trong cơ thể trước các chất gây ung thư và thậm chí có thể làm giảm sự sản xuất các hợp chất gây ung thư khi nướng thịt. Một cách để đưa chất chống oxy hóa vào món nướng là ướp thịt ít nhất 20 phút trước khi nướng. Một nghiên cứu đã phát hiện ra rằng ướp thịt ít nhất 20 phút trước khi nướng làm giảm 72% nồng độ các hợp chất gây ung thư . Bạn có thể dùng các loại nước xốt tự chế như nước cam quýt, gia vị hoặc thêm dầu ô liu. Nếu dùng nước xốt đóng gói sẵn, hãy chọn loại ít đường và ít muối. Bạn cũng có thể bổ sung chất chống oxy hóa vào bữa ăn bằng cách ăn nhiều trái cây, rau và chất béo lành mạnh có trong bơ, quả hạch và các loại hạt. Thịt nướng ở nhiệt độ cao càng lâu thì hàm lượng hợp chất gây ung thư càng cao. Bạn có thể giảm thời gian nướng thịt bằng cách cắt thịt thành các miếng nhỏ hơn hoặc nướng một phần thịt trong lò nướng, lò vi sóng trước khi nướng trên lửa để giảm bớt phần chất béo. Đồng thời, việc làm này sẽ giúp giảm bớt thời gian nướng thịt trên ngọn lửa. Bạn cũng có thể gói thịt trong giấy bạc và nướng để giảm lượng chất béo nhỏ vào ngọn lửa, đồng thời giúp thời gian nướng nhanh hơn. Hãy chọn thịt nạc hơn để nướng. Điều này sẽ giúp giảm lượng chất béo rơi xuống lửa trong khi nướng, từ đó giảm việc hình thành các chất gây ung thư. Ngoài ra, để giảm chất gây ung thư khi nướng thịt, bạn nên vệ sinh kỹ vỉ nướng mỗi lần sử dụng để giảm bớt các vụn thịt bị cháy dính vào thức ăn. Bạn có thể để sẵn một chai nước để dập lửa khi chất béo rơi xuống lửa và làm lửa bùng lên. Khi nướng thịt, bạn nên để vỉ nướng cách xa ngọn lửa để hạn chế bị PAH từ khói ám thêm vào thịt. Nhiều cơ quan y tế đã đưa ra lời khuyên về việc hạn chế ăn các loại thịt đỏ, cho dù bạn nấu chín bằng cách nướng hay bất kỳ cách nào khác. Bạn có thể kiểm soát lượng thịt mà mình tiêu thụ bằng cách chia đĩa ăn thành 3 phần, các sản phẩm từ thịt chiếm ⅓ đĩa ăn hoặc ít hơn. ⅔ còn lại là các loại thực phẩm giàu chất chống ung thư như các loại rau họ cải (chứa nhiều glucosinolate) và các loại rau có màu xanh đậm khác. Rau, củ không hình thành chất gây ung thư trong quá trình nướng. Vì vậy, hãy thêm khoai tây, ớt chuông, bí ngòi, hành tây (giàu quercetin), nấm và bất kỳ loại rau nào khác mà bạn thích để nướng. Bạn cũng đừng quên các loại gia vị - những thành phần đã được chứng minh có chứa các chất chống ung thư hiệu quả. Một số loại gia vị có thể kể đến là húng quế, hương thảo, tiêu,... Bạn cũng nên hạn chế các loại thịt đã qua chế biến như xúc xích, thịt hun khói… Hãy nhớ rằng cũng giống như mọi thứ trong cuộc sống, điều độ là chìa khóa quan trọng. Bạn vẫn có thể thưởng thức thịt nướng, nhưng chỉ nên ăn với mức độ vừa phải và đừng nấu ở nhiệt độ quá cao. Đối với những người có các tình trạng sức khỏe tiềm ẩn, những người bị ung thư vú, ung thư đại tràng càng nên hạn chế ăn thịt nướng.","answer":"Đừng vì sợ ung thư mà chia tay thịt nướng: 4 cách giảm chất gây ung thư khi nướng thịt"},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Austrália?","answer":"A capital da Austrália é Camberra. Ela foi escolhida como a capital do país em 1913, substituindo Melbourne e Sydney como alternativas, e foi projetada especificamente para ser a sede do governo federal australiano."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:మహైక దీర్ఘకవిత సమాజంలో ఆధునికతను కోరుకుంటూ ప్రయోగాత్మకంగా నడచిన కవిత. ఇది సామాన్య మానవుడు, కవి, కార్మికుడు, పతతి పాత్రల పరస్పర సంభాషణలతో కూడి ఉన్నది. నేటి నాగరిక సమాజంలో తాను అనుభవిస్తున్న కష్టాలను, వేదనలను, నిరాశతో నిట్టూర్పుతో కవి చెప్పటం ఈ కవిత లోని ప్రధానాంశం. సమాజానికి ప్రాతినిథ్యం వహిస్తున్నవారిని ఓదారుస్తూ మనిషిపై మనిషికి విశ్వాసం తగ్గకుండా ప్రోత్సహించే విప్లవ రచన ఇది.చివరి పేరా:తోటమాలి తనని తాను బలిదానంగా సమర్పించుకుంటేనే పువ్వులు పరిమళాలను వెదజల్లుతాయి. మనిషి మనిషి కలిస్తేనే దేశం వృద్ధి చెందుతుంది. యుగ యుగాల నైరాశ్యం మన బతుకులను నాశనం చేస్తున్నది. చేయి చేయి కలిపి సోమరితనాన్ని వదలిపెట్టి ఆనందంతో శ్రమ చేస్తే అందరికి సంతోషం భూగోళానికి నూతనత్వం వస్తాయి.","answer":"భవిష్యత్తుపై ఆశలను నిలుపుతూ మానవీయ లక్షణాలను పెంపొందిస్తూ అసమానతలు లేని సోషలిజానికి దారులు వేసిందీ కవిత. దీర్ఘకవితను చదివినపుడు ఏడో నూతన లోకాన్ని చూసినట్లుంది అంటారు. ఈ కావ్యానికి ముందుమాట రాసిన బెల్లకొండ రామదాసు, రెంటాల గోపాలకృష్ణులు. ‘మహైకా’ను చదువుతుంటే టి.ఎస్. ఇలియట్ వేస్టాండ్ జ్ఞాపకం వస్తుంది. చిలి దేశ మహాకవి ‘పోబ్లో నెరుడా’ ఎలాంటి కవో తెలుగులో మూర్తి అలాంటివాడు."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kari tulang rusuk? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Kari tulang rusuk ialah sejenis hidangan kari yang dibuat menggunakan tulang rusuk, biasanya tulang rusuk lembu, sebagai bahan utamanya. Hidangan ini popular di beberapa negara, termasuk Malaysia, dan dikenali dengan kekayaan rasanya serta tekstur daging yang lembut.Bahan untuk kari tulang rusuk: 1 kg tulang lembu (rusuk), 2 sudu besar atau 1 paket kecil rempah kari daging, 1 cawan santan pekat segar, 4 cawan air (tambah atau kurangkan ikut suka), ½ inci lengkuas, 2 biji ubi kentang - opsyenal, gula pasir / gula melaka dan garam secukup rasa, air asam jawaBahan tumis: 1 tangkai daun kari - dilurut, 5 biji bawang merah, 2 ulas bawang putih, ½ inci halia, 2 sudu besar cili kisar/boh, 2 sudu besar minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Cuci tulang, buang lemak yang berlebihan. Kemudian toskan.2. Kupas dan potong dadu ubi kentang.3. Ketuk lengkuas.4. Bancuh serbuk rempah kari dengan sedikit air supaya menjadi pes.5. Kisar bawang merah, bawang putih dan halia.Cara memasak:1. Masukkan tulang ke dalam periuk, tambah air dan lengkuas. Tutup periuk, kemudian rebus sehingga daging pada tulang empuk. Kalau menggunakan periuk tekanan (Noxxa, Philips), rebus dengan tekanan tinggi selama 15 minit *. Kemudian ketepikan.2. Panaskan minyak masak di dalam periuk lain dengan api sederhana. Tumis bahan kisar dan daun kari sehingga garing dan naik bau.3. Masukkan cili kisar dan tumis hingga pecah minyak. Tambah pes rempah kari, dan tumis hingga pecah minyak juga.4. Masukkan tulang, gaul sebati dan biarkan seketika (5-10 minit) supaya tulang mesra dengan rempah.5. Masukkan air rebusan yang telah ditapis (untuk membuang buih kotoran dan serpihan tulang), kentang, santan dan air asam jawa.6. Masak sambil mengacau sehingga kentang empuk dan kuah pecah minyak.7. Perasakan dengan gula dan garam, kemudian padamkan api, angkat dan dihidang.* 15 minit adalah masa memasak high pressure untuk tulang rusuk. Kalau guna tulang gearbox, set pada 25minit"},{"question":"Inona no hevitry ny teny hoe \\"vatombatony\\"?","answer":"ny hevitry ny teny hoe \\"vatombatony\\" dia hoe mbola kelikely, fa efa ho lehibe"},{"question":"නිදහස් ලංකාවේ බිහි වූ පළමු ආණ්ඩුවේ සභානායක ධුරයත්, සෞඛ්‍ය හා පළාත් පාලන අමාත්‍ය ධුරයත් දරන ලද්දේ","answer":"එස්.ඩබ්.ආර්.ඩී. බණ්ඩාරනායක"},{"question":"ध्यान अनुभव गर्न नेपालका विभिन्न ठाउँहरू के-के छन्?","answer":"अन्नपूर्ण, काठमाडौं, पशुपतिनाथ, लुम्बिनी, खप्तड, टेङ्बोचे, जोमसोम र मुक्तिनाथ, पाटन आदि नेपालका विभिन्न ठाउँमा ध्यानको अनुभव लिन सकिन्छ।"},{"question":"तिमी एउटा स्थितिमा छौ ।  \\"म मेरो साँचोहरु  फेला पार्न प्रयास गर्दैछु । मलाई सम्झना छ कि दुई घन्टाअघि मेरो कोठामा पस्द मसँगै थियो ।निम्न संकेत अनुसार प्रश्नको जवाफ दिनुहोस् । प्रश्न - \\"मेरो साँचोहरु  कहाँ छन् ?\\" संकेत - \\"मैले एक साथीलाई भेट्नको लागि फुत्त निस्केको थिएँ ।\\"","answer":"सायद मैले साँचोहरु मेरो साथीको घरमा बिर्सें ।"},{"question":"මුත්තැස් කුඹුරු යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගොයම් කපා පාගා ගත් කුඹුරු( මුත්සස්).මෙය විශේෂ කුඹුරු වර්ගයකට භාවිත කෙරුණක් නොව, ඕනෑම කුඹුරකට අස්වැන්න කපාගත් පසුව යෙදුණකි. "},{"question":" Sheg meeshay eheed meeshii ay aayada Quraanka ugu horeesay Ku Soo degtay?","answer":"Meeshii ugu horeesay ay aayada Quraanka Ku Soo degto waxay eheed qaaru- Xiraa."},{"question":"A Ki Yin Lati Ilé – Greetings From Home","answer":"Ni ai pẹ yi, Olùkọ̀wé yi bẹ ilé wò fún bi ọ̀sẹ̀ mẹta.  A ṣe àwọn akiyesi wọnyi.  Ilú Èkó n fẹ̀ si, ṣùgbọ́n ọ̀nà kò fẹ̀ tó bi èrò àti ọkọ̀ ti pọ̀ tó, nitori eyi, sún-kẹrẹ fà-kẹrẹ ọkọ̀ kò jẹ́ ki ará ilú gbádùn.  Àwọn ti ó nlọ si ibi iṣẹ́ agogo mẹjọ ni lati kúrò ni ilé ki agogo marun tó lù, wọn yio si wọlé ni agogo mẹwa lẹhin ti wọn bá pari iṣẹ́ ni agogo marun.  Ó kéré jù, òṣìṣẹ́ yio lo wákàtí mẹfa lati lọ àti bọ ni ibi iṣẹ́ nitori sún-kẹrẹ fà-kẹrẹ ọkọ̀.Ìjọba ko ti i ṣe ìpèsè omi ẹ̀rọ, ọ̀nà àdúgbò àti ohun amáyédẹrùn igbàlódé pàtàki ni àwọn agbègbè tuntun.  Iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná ti dára di ẹ̀ si, nitori iná kò lọ púpọ̀ mọ́ bi ti tẹ́lẹ̀.Ni àwọn olú ilú ilẹ̀ Yorùbá yókù bi Ìbàdàn, Òṣogbo, Abẹ́òkúta, Àkúrẹ́ àti Adó-Èkìtì, kò si sún-kẹrẹ fà-kẹrẹ ọkọ̀ bi ti Èkó ṣùgbọ́n iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná kò ṣe déédé bi ti ilú Èkó.  Ọ̀wọ́n epo-ọkọ̀ ti ó gbòde ni igbà ọdún Kérésìmesì ti ó kọjá àti ni ibẹ̀rẹ̀ ọdún tuntun ti lọ ṣùgbọ́n epo-ọkọ̀ wọn ni ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ilé epo ni àwọn olú ilú yókù ju ti Èkó.  Gbogbo ohun tita ló ti wọ́n si.Ó ṣòro lati lo ayélujára nitori ai ṣe déédé iná mọ̀nàmọ́ná àti ayélujára, pàtàki bi enia ba jade kúrò ni ilú Èkó, ṣùgbọ́n ó sàn ju ti àtẹ̀hin wá lọ.  Ni àpapọ̀, ọyẹ́ jẹ́ ki ẹni ti ó bá nti Òkè-Òkun bọ̀ gbádùn nitori ooru din kù."},{"question":"\\"Адамдын көркү баш болот....\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адамдын көркү баш болот, кабактын көркү каш болот.\\""},{"question":"කෘතඥතාව උණුසුම් ඩිල්මා තේ කෝප්පයකට සමාන කළ හැක්කේ කෙසේද?","answer":"කෘතවේදීත්වය උණුසුම් දිල්මා තේ කෝප්පයකට සමාන කර ඇත්තේ එය තේ කෝප්පයක් තොලගාන විට ඇතිවන සැනසිලිදායක සහ සාරවත් අත්දැකීමක් මෙන් එය සැනසීම සහ ආත්මය පොහොසත් කරන බැවිනි."},{"question":"Саякбай Каралаев жөнүндө кызыктуу  факты...","answer":"Экранда чагылдырылган өмүр. Режиссер Болот Шамшиев улуу манасчы Саякбай Каралаевге арнап \\"Манасчы\\" даректүү тасмасын тарткан. Ал кезегинде Германияда өткөн 80ге жакын өлкөнүн тасмаларынын ичинен баш байге — Алтын медаль алган. Дагы бир көрөңгөлүү режиссёр Мэлис Убукеев үч бөлүктөн турган \\"Саякбай Каралаев\\" (1962) аттуу атайын тасма жараткан. Бул линияны 1988-жылдагы тарткан \\"Улуу манасчы\\" аттуу жети бөлүктөн турган толук метраждуу тасмасында уланткан. Учурда дагы бир режиссер Эрнест Абдыжапаров \\"ХХ кылымдын Гомери\\" туурасында кино жаратууга белсенип турат. "},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny OTIV?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny OTIV dia: Ombona Tahiry Ifampisamborana Vola."},{"question":"Waxaan Nahay Afar Walaalo Ah, Hadana Waxaan Leenahay Hal Madax, Hadaba Yaan Nahay?","answer":"Waa Afarta Lug Ee Miiska Uu Leeyahay."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adu buku\\"?","answer":"'Adu buku' bermaksud berkelahi."},{"question":"*من هو النبى الذي طلب رؤية الله ولم يره؟","answer":"سيدنا موسى"},{"question":"*في أي سنة عرف مرض الأيدز؟","answer":"1984"},{"question":"Kedụ ihé bụ Ọrịa akpụ (Cancer)?","answer":"E wepụ ọrịa akpụ nke ara bụ 'breast cancer' na Bekee, nnyocha gosiri na ọ bụ ụmụnwoke ka ọrịa akpụ ndị ọzọ kacha emetụta.Ndị a gụnyere ọrịa akpụ nke ọnụ (oral cavity cancer), ọrịa akpụ nke mgbịrịafọ (colon cancer), ọrịa akpụ nke akịrị (kidney cancer), dgz.Ndị ọkammụta sayensị na-ekwu na nke a nwere ike ịbụ maka na ọ bụ ụmụnwoke na-emekarị ihe nwere ike ịkpata ụdị ọrịa ndị a, dịka ise anwụrụ nakwa ịṅụ mmanya na-aba n'anya.Otu ụzọ a na-ejikarị agwọ ọrịa ndị a bụ site n'iwa ahụ."},{"question":"Kedụ ihe bụ ọrịa Lupus, ihe kpatara na ọgwụgwọ?","answer":"Lupus\\" bụ otu n'ime ọrịa nke bekee kpọrọ \\"autoimmune diseases\\".E nwere ihe ndị dị n'ime ahụ mmadụ nke na-enye aka iji gbochie ọrịa, mana mgbe ụfọdụ, ihe ndị ahụ na-egbochi ọrịa nwekwara ike tụgharịa malite ibuso ahụ mmadụ agha.Ọ bụ mgbe ihe dị otu a mere ka a na-ekwu na mmadụ nwere 'autoimmune disease.Otu ọgwụ nke ndị ọkachamara kwuru na ọ na-enye aka maka ọrịa 'Lupus' bụ nke a kpọrọ 'hydroxychloroquine'."},{"question":"दिइएको टुक्काको अर्थ पहिल्याई तेस्लाई वाक्यमा प्रयोग गर्नुहोस् :कुरा खानु","answer":"कुरा खानु : भनेको मान्नुशिक्षकले भनेको कुरा खानु विद्यार्थीको हितमा हुन्छ । "},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ કહે છે: \\"આશ્રમવૃક્ષો પછી આ વનવૃક્ષો છે. મનુષ્યજીવન અને વનસ્પતિજીવન એકબીજાનાં કેવી રીતે સહાયક છે અને કુદરતનું ડહાપણ કેવું અદ્‌ભૂત છે એની ખબર કુદરતના અભ્યાસમાંથી પડે છે. વનવૃક્ષો માત્ર વૃક્ષોની યાદી નથી કે તેનાં વર્ણનો નથી. પક્ષીઓ પેઠે વૃક્ષો પણ અભ્યાસ કરવા યોગ્ય છે, અને એ રસિક અભ્યાસની દિશા ઉઘાડવા માટે આવાં પુસ્તકોની યોજના છે.\\"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાએ \\"બહેડાં\\" વિષે વર્ણન કરતા નીચે મુજબ ની વાતો કહી છે:\\"બોરડી કરતાં બાવળ ઊંચો ને બાવળ કરતાં આંબલી ઊંચી. પણ આંબલી કરતાં ને ઘણાં ઘણાં ઝાડ કરતાં બહેડાનું ઝાડ ઘણું જ ઊંચું.પણ ઝાડ ઊંચું એટલે ફળ ઊંચાં એવું કાંઈ નથી. લાંબો તો તાડે ય થાય છે પણ ઉપરથી તાડિયાં ખેરે છે; ભલે આંબો નીચો થાય છે, પણ ઉનાળે ઉનાળે મીઠી ને મધુરી કેરી જમાડે છે.તો ય ઊંચાં ઝાડનો મહિમા તો છે. આપણે પેલા રૂપાળાં શીંગડાંવાળા સાબર જેવા ન થવું જોઈએ. પગ કામના છે, પણ શીંગડાં ય કાંઈ નકામાં નહિ હોય. આંબો ફળ આપે છે; પણ પાંચ ઝાડ એવાં ય જોઈએ ને, કે જે ઘટાદાર હોય, જે જંગલની શોભારૂપ હોય, જે જંગલમાં ચંદરવારૂપ હોય, ને બીજા છોડ નાના હોય ત્યાં સુધી બહુ તડકામાંથી જે તેમને બચાવતાં હોય.ઊંચા ઝાડે ચડીને કહો જોઈએ કેટલે બધે દૂર સુધી દેખી શકાય ? મિનારો ચણવા બેસવું પડે એના કરતાં બહેડાં ઉપર ચડી આકાશ સાથે વાતો કરવી શી ખોટી ? સાત માળની હવેલીએ ચડીને મુંબઈ જોવા કરતાં બહેડાં ઉપર ચડીને આખી સીમ ને જંગલ જોવામાં મજા છે. કોઈ વાર જંગલના ગોવાળિયા મળે તો પૂછજો : “અલ્યા બહેડાંના ઝાડે ચડવું કેવું મજાનું ?”એમ સાવ કાંઈ બહેડાં કાઢી નાખવા જેવાં નથી. બહેડાંને ફળ આવે છે અને પાકીને નીચે પડે છે ત્યારે ઢગલેઢગલા થાય છે.વૈદોની ચોપડીમાં જુઓ તો ખબર પડે કે બહેડો કેટલો ઉપયોગી છે. ખૂબખૂબ ખાધાથી માંદા પડીએ એ ચીજો સારી, કે જુદા જુદા રોગોને મટાડે એ ચીજો સારી ?\\"તેમનું આગળ \\"બહેડાં\\" વિષે નું વર્ણન શું હશે?","answer":"તમે કહેશો કે રોગોને મટાડે એ ચીજો સારી. પણ હું કહીશ કે ખૂબ ખૂબ ખાઈએ ત્યારે રોગ થાય ને ? રોગ કરે ય નહિ ને મટાડે ય નહિ તે ચીજો શી ખોટી ?પણ આપણે તો બહેડો કેટલો બધો કામનો છે તેની વાત કરતા હતા. ઉપર તો જરા આડી વાત થઈ ગઈ. કોઈ વાર વાત કરતાં એમ પણ થઈ જાય. લખનાર પણ માણસ છે ને ! આડુંઅવળું ન લખે ?ત્યારે બહેડાંની દવાઓ સાંભળો. એક તો તમે જાણતા હશો કે આંબળા ને હરડાં સાથે બહેડાંને પલાળી તેનું પાણી આંખે છંટાય. બાકી બહેડું કફ ઉપર કામ આવે, ઉધરસ ઉપર કામ આવે, ઢોરોને વાગ્યું હોય તેના ઉપર આવે; એમ બહુ કામમાં આવે.એમ ન સમજતા કે આંબળાનો જ મુરબ્બો થાય છે. બહેડાંનો પણ મુરબ્બો થાય છે ને તે આંબળાના મુરબ્બાની પેઠે જ.માણસો કાંઈ મોળાં નથી. કુદરતની અનેક ચીજોનો તેમણે જાતજાતનો ઉપયોગ કર્યો છે. અને આ ઉપયોગ શોધતા કેટલી બધી વાર લાગી હશે ? ને કેટલા બધા પ્રયોગો કર્યા હશે ? ને કેટલો બધો ગોટાળો થયો હશે ? એ તો હવે ફરી આપણે આંબળાં ને બહેડાં લઈએ ને મુરબ્બા બનાવીએ ને ખાઈએ.જુના લોકોએ બહુ શોધી રાખ્યું લાગે છે. આપણે તેમનો ઉપકાર માનીએ તો ?"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk karipap kentang? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan pastri: 2 cawan tepung gandum, 1/4 cawan marjerin, 1/2 sudu kecil garam, 2/3 cawan air sejuk (dari peti ais), Gula secukup rasa, Minyak masak untuk menggorengBahan inti: 3 biji ubi kentang saiz sederhana, 100gm daging, 3 sudu besar (rata) serbuk kari daging, 1 biji bawang besar, 2 ulas bawang merah, 2 tangkai daun kari◦ 1/2 sudu kecil garam, 3 sudu besar minyak, 1/2 cawan airCara penyediaan:1. Bersihkan daging, kemudian cencang.2. Kupas dan basuh kentang dan bawang besar. Kemudian potong dadu kecil-kecil.3. Cencang bawang merah.3. Lurut daun kari dan bancuh serbuk kari supaya menjadi pes.Cara memasak inti:1. Panaskan minyak di dalam kuali dan tumis bawang merah, bawang besar dan daun kari sehingga naik bau.2. Masukkan pes kari dan kacau sehingga ia pecah minyak.3. Masukkan daging, kacau dan masak selama beberapa minit sehingga ia berubah warna.4. Masukkan kentang, garam, air dan kacau sebati. Kemudian tutup kuali dan dan masak hingga kentang empuk dan intinya agak kering.5. Angkat dan biarkan sejuk.Cara menyediakan pastri/doh rapuh dan karipap:1. Panaskan minyak masak bersama marjerin.2. Masukkan tepung gandum dan garam ke dalam mangkuk kaca, gaul rata, kemudian buat lubang di tengah-tengah.3. Tuang minyak+marjerin panas ke dalam lubang. Gaul sebati menggunakan sudip.4. Uli sambil memasukkan air sedikit demi sedikit sehingga doh tidak melekat di tangan dan mangkuk.5. Canai doh kepada ketebalan 3 mm. Terap doh dengan penerap bulat untuk membentuk kulit karipap.6. Ambil satu keping kulit karipap, isikan dengan satu sudu besar inti dan basahkan tepinya dengan sedikit air.7. Lipat kulit karipap untuk menutup inti, picit-picit tepi untuk mencantumkan kulit karipap, kemudian kelim.8. Ulangi sehingga habis doh / intiCara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali. Goreng dalam minyak banyak (deep fry). Balikkan sekali supaya masak sekata sehingga kuning keemasan.(Jika ingin dibakar, atur karipap dalam dulang pembakar, sadur bahagian atasnya dengan telur yang dipukul dan bakar dalam oven yang panas hingga kuning sama rata).2. Angkat, tuskan minyak dan letak atas pinggan yang dilapik dengan paper towel atau tisu.3. Hidangkan panas-panas atau sejuk."},{"question":"Peter Obi","answer":"Peter Gregory Obi (tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún, oṣù Agẹmọ, ọdún 1961) jẹ́ olóṣèlú ọmọ ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà, òun sì ni Gómínà Ìpínlẹ̀ Anambra láàárin ọdún 2006 sí ọdún 2014. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ olóṣèlú APGA àti People's Democratic Party(PDP) tẹ́lẹ̀rí. Ó fi ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú Alábùradà (PDP) ka'lẹ̀ ní oṣù Èbìbí, ọdún 2022 láti darapọ̀ mọ́ ẹgbẹ́ Labour Party(LP). Ní oṣù kan-náà ni ó di olùdíje ipò Ààrẹ Nàìjíríà lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú Labour Party ní ìdìbò Ààrẹ l'ọ́dún 2023. A bí Peter Obi sí Onitsha, ó lọ ilé-ìwé sekondiri rẹ̀ ní ilé-ìwé Christ The King College ní Onitsha. Ní ọdún 1980, a gbàá sílé ìwé Yunifásitì ti Nàìjíríà, Nsukka, ó sì gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ nínú ìmọ philosophy ní ọdún 1984. Ó padà lọ ilé-ìwé oníṣòwò ti ÈkóPeter Obi jẹ́ oníṣòwò ọkùnrin kó tó di pé ó wọ òṣèlú. Obi sọ pé a bí òun sínú ìdílé olùtajà, òun náà sì ń tajà kó tó di pé ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ń ṣiṣẹ́ ní àwọn ilé-iṣẹ́, ó di ipò adarí mú ní àwọn ilé-iṣẹ́ bíi: Next International Nigeria Ltd, Chairman and Director of Guardian Express Mortgage Bank Ltd, Guardian Express Bank Plc, Future View Securities Ltd, Paymaster Nigeria Ltd, Chams Nigeria Ltd, Data Corp Ltd and Card Centre Ltd., òun ni ẹni tó kéré jù nínú àwọn tó ti jẹ́ alága ilé ìfowópamọ́ Fidelity rí. Ní ọdún 2003, Obi díje fún ipò Gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Anambra ṣùgbọ́n ó fìdírẹmi fún alátakò rẹ̀, Chris Ngige, ẹni tí o jẹ́ olùdíje lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú People's Democratic Party(PDP), Obi gbé ọ̀rọ̀ náà lọ ilé-ẹjọ́ Kòtẹ́milọ́rùn (Court of appeal), níbi tí wọ́n ti rojọ́ ọ̀rọ̀ náà fún ọdún mẹ́ta kó tó di pé wọ́n yọ Chris Ngige nípò láti gbé Obi wọlé ní oṣù Ẹrẹ́nà, ọdún 2006. Ní oṣù Belú, ọdún 2006, àwọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin ti ìpínlẹ̀ Anambra yọ Obi nípò gómínà, wọ́n sì fi igbá kejì rẹ̀, Virginia Etiaba sípò Gómínà, èyí mú kí Virginia jẹ́ Gómínà obìnrin àkọ́kọ́ ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ilé-ẹjọ́ Kòtẹ́milọ́rùn (Court of Appeal) tún dá Peter Obi padà sípò Gómínà, Virginia dá agbára padà fún Peter Obi lẹ́yìn ìdájọ́ ilé ẹjọ́. Ní oṣù Èbìbí, ọdún 2007, Peter Obi tún fi ipò Gómínà s'ílẹ̀ lẹ́yìn tí Andy Uba wọlé gẹ́gẹ́bí Gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Anambra, ó torí ọ̀rọ̀ yìí lọ ilé-ẹjọ́ lẹ́ẹ̀kansi, ó ní sáà ìjọba rẹ̀ tó yẹ kó bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ọdún 2003 kí ó sì parí ní ọdún 2007 bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ọdún 2006, nítorí náà, kí ilé-ẹjọ́ jẹ́ kí sáà ìjọba rẹ̀ di ọdún 2010 (kí ó baà lè lo ọdún mẹ́rin ìjọba rẹ̀ pé). Ilé-ẹjọ́ gígajùlọ (Supreme Court) ti Nàìjíríà fi àṣẹ sí ọ̀rọ̀ yìí, èyí tí ó mú kí a yọ Andy Uba kúrò nípò Gómínà Anambra.Ní ọjọ́ keje, oṣù Èrèlé, ọdún 2010 (7 Feb 2010), àjọ elétò-ìdìbò (Independent National Electoral Commission) kéde Peter Obi gẹ́gẹ́bí olùjáwéolúborí fún ipò Gómínà nínú ìdìbò ọdún 2010. Èyí múu kí Obi lo ọdún mẹ́rin síi nípò Gómínà Anambra. Ní ọjọ́ kẹtàdínlógún, oṣù Ẹrẹ́nà, ọdún 2014, Obi fi ipò Gómínà ka'lẹ̀, Willie Obiano sì di Gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Anambra nígbà náà.Lẹ́yìn ìdìbò gbogbogbò ti ọdún 2015, Ààrẹ Goodluck Jonathan yan Peter Obi sípò alága Nigerian Security and Exchange Commission (SEC).Ní ọjọ́ kejìlá, oṣù Ọ̀wàwà, ọdún 2018, a yan Peter Obi gẹ́gẹ́bí ígbákejì olùdíje Atiku Abubakar, ẹni tí ó jẹ́ olùdíje fún ipò Ààrẹ lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú People Democratic Party. Ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP gbé ipò kejì nínú ìdìbò gbogboògbò ti ọdún 2019.Ní ọjọ́ kẹrìnlélógún, oṣù Ẹrẹ́nà, ọdún 2022, Peter Obi kéde ète rẹ̀ láti díje fún ipò Ààrẹ lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú PDP, ṣùgbọ́n ó padà yà sí ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú Labour Party (LP), lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú náà ni ó ti díje fún ipò Ààrẹ Nàìjíríà ní ọdún 2023.Obi fẹ́ Margaret Brownson Obi ní ọdún 1992, wọ́n bí ọmọ méjì, ọmọkùnrin kan àti ọmọbìnrin kan. Obi jẹ́ ọmọ ìjọ Kátólíìkì."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza atao fihavanam-bato fa  ..........................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aza atao fihavanam-bato fa raha tapaka tsy azo atohy intsony \\" "},{"question":"හෙව්ලට් පැකාඩ් සමාගම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"හෙව්ලට් පැකාඩ් සමාගම ඇමරිකානු බහුජාතික තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණ සමාගමකි. මෙම සමාගමේ ප්‍රධාන මුලස්ථානය ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ කැලිෆෝනියා ප්‍රාන්තයේ පාලෝ ඇල්ටෝ හි පිහිටා ඇත. හෙව්ලට් පැකාඩ් සමගම පාරිභෝගිකයන්, සුළු හා මධ්‍යම පරිමාණ ව්‍යාපාරිකයන් සහ විශාල පරිමාන ව්‍යාපාර, රාජ්‍ය අංශයේ ආයතන, සෞඛ්‍යය සහ අධ්‍යාපනික ක්ෂේත්‍ර වලට මෘදුකාංග, නිෂ්පාදන සහ සේවා සපයනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"Maa rabta inaad maaclumad badan ogaato?","answer":"Maa rabta inaad maaclumad badan ogaato?Youtuberrada Somalida kuwooda ugu waxtarka badan.Youtuberadas waxan uu kala qaybiin doona  dhawr qaybood inkaasto midwaliba mawduucyo badan o kala duuwan uga  hadlan.  Youtuberrada macluumadyada guud ka hadlo 1. Ogaansho  2. Sahanka xogaha  3. Galbeedka media3. Waaberi media4. Annaga production 5. Buulo xuubey  iwmDiinta 1. Salaf media2. Sheikh shiblii3. Sheikh Mustafe official Channel 4. Dacwaa TV iwm ......Waararka1. Horufadhi media 2. Maracede show3. Hussein kurdi4. HanoolaatoAriimaa Bulshada 1. Suhaybsajid2. Salman maadow3. Sheikh Mustafe official Channel4. Nasra abtidoon iyo kanaalo badan o la talinta bulshada aad ugu fiican.Somali🇸🇴 youtubers midkee ayaad ka heshaa ama inta badan daawataa?"},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：人类学如何研究不同文化的文化表达与符号？","answer":"答案：人类学通过研究不同文化的文化表达形式、符号系统、文化意义等方面来了解其文化表达与符号的文化多样性和社会功能。"},{"question":"W hich British action actor played Sylvester Stallone in the film The Expendables?","answer":"Statham"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Andriamanitra no nanome fa _\\"","answer":"\\"Andriamanitra no nanome fa i Balita no tsy nambibina\\""},{"question":"મેડિકલ ડ્રામા શૈલી પર ગ્રેના એનાટોમી શોની અસર શું છે?","answer":"ગ્રેની એનાટોમીને મેડિકલ ડ્રામા શૈલીને લોકપ્રિય બનાવવાનો શ્રેય આપવામાં આવે છે, જે ટેલિવિઝન પ્રોગ્રામિંગનો મુખ્ય ભાગ બની ગયો છે. આ શોની સફળતાને કારણે \\"હાઉસ M.D.,\\" \\"સ્ક્રબ્સ,\\" અને \\"ધ ગુડ ડોક્ટર\\" સહિત અસંખ્ય અન્ય તબીબી નાટકોની રચના થઈ છે."},{"question":"Mimu Sunday Igboho ko le mu ki ariwo ibeere fun idasilẹ Orileede Oodua rọlẹ, yoo fun wa lagbara si i ni– Alaga OPC","answer":"Ọkan lara awọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ Oodua Peoples Congress (OPC) ni agbegbe Ibarapa ati Abuja, Ọgbẹni Oluwọle Adedeji, ti sọ pe bi awọn agbofinro ṣe lọọ mu ajijagbara ilẹ Yoruba nni, Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ti wọn n pe ni Sunday Igboho ko tọna, ko si le mu ki ariwo ibeere fun idasilẹ Orileede Oodua, iyẹn Yoruba Nation, lọ silẹ, kaka bẹẹ, niṣe lo maa tubọ mu ko le si i.Nigba to n ba ALAROYE sọrọ lori aago laaarọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, nipa iṣẹlẹ ọhun, Adedeji ni ohun tijọba ko mọ ni pe ijangbara ti Sunday Igboho n ṣe ki i ṣe tara rẹ nikan rara, ọgọọrọ awọn alatilẹyin ati ajijangbara ni wọn wa labẹlẹ, ti wọn si n ṣatilẹyin to ju ti Sunday Igboho lọ.“Sunda Igboho nijọba n ri, iyẹn lo fi jẹ pe oun ni wọn fẹju mọ, wọn o mọ pe ki i ṣe Sunday Igboho nikan lo n sọrọ, aimọye awọn to lowo, ti wọn si lagbara ju Igboho lọ, ti wọn si ti pinnu lori Yoruba Nation yii.Mimu ti wọn mu un yii ko le bomi tutu sọkan wa, ipinnu yii ki i ṣe ọrọ Sunday Igboho, ọrọ Yoruba ni, ki wọn too le pana ariwo Yoruba Nation, gbogbo Yoruba ni ki wọn mu.Ati pe kin ni Sunday Igboho ṣe funjọba gan-an ti wọn fi n dọdẹ ẹmi ẹ kiri, ki ni wọn fẹẹ lo ṣe fawọn, ki wọn bọ sita sọ faraye? Ṣe ẹṣẹ ni keeyan sọ ohun to n fẹ, kawọn ololufẹ ẹ si sọpọọti ẹ ni?”Adeyemọ pari ọrọ rẹ pe “niṣe ni ki Sunday mọkan le, ko ma bẹru rara, ko si ohun ti wọn le fi i ṣe. Ọlọrun lo n lo o lasiko yii, awọn alalẹ Yoruba ko sun, wọn si wa lẹyin ẹ. Ohun to n ja fun ki i ṣe tara ẹ nikan. Orileede Yoruba maa ṣẹlẹ, boya wọn fẹ tabi wọn kọ.”"},{"question":"ஐம்பூதங்கள் ஒவ்வொன்றிற்கும் வழங்கப்படும் வேறு பெயர்களை எழுதுக.","answer":"(i) நிலம் – பூமி, தரை, புவி(ii) நீர் – புனல், தண்ணீர்(iii) தீ – அனல், நெருப்பு, கனல்(iv) காற்று – வளி, கால்(v) வானம் – ஆகாயம், விண்முதலில் ’ஆகாயம்’ (விண்வெளி) எனும் பூதம் ’ஒலி’ எனும் ஒரே குணத்துடன் தோன்றியது. ஆகாயத்திற்கு தன்னில் அனைத்து சடப்பொருள்களுக்கு இடமளிக்கும் தன்மை உள்ளது. ஆகாயம் மற்ற நான்கு பூதங்களான காற்று, தீ, நீர் மற்றும் மண் ஆகியவைகள் தோன்றக் காரணமாக உள்ளது.ஆகாயம்’ எனும் பூதத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியிலிருந்து ’காற்று’ (வாயு) எனும் பூதம், ’தொடு உணர்வு’ (ஸ்பர்சம்) எனும் குணத்துடனும், ஆகாயத்தின் சொந்த குணமாக ஒலி எனும் குணத்துடனும் தோன்றியது. எனவே காற்று தன் சொந்த குணமான தொடு உணர்வுடன், ஆகாயத்தின் ஒலி எனும் குணத்துடன் இரண்டு குணங்கள் கொண்டுள்ளது. காற்று எனும் பூதத்தின் இயல்பு ஒரு பொருளை உலர்த்தும் சக்தி படைத்தது. காற்றில் பிராணன் எனும் பிராணவாயு ஒரு சீவனை காப்பதால், அதையும் பிரம்ம த்த்துவமாக சில உபநிடதங்கள் காற்று எனும் பூதத்தின் சிறப்பை விளக்குகிறது.படம்காற்று எனும் பூதத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியிலிருந்து ’தீ’ எனும் பூதம் ’உருவம்’ (ரூபம்) எனும் குணத்துடன் தோன்றியது. அத்துடன் ஆகாயம் மற்றும் காற்றின் குணங்களான ஒலி மற்றும் தொடு உணர்வு குணங்களுடன் தன் சொந்த குணமான உருவம் எனும் குணத்துடன் ’தீ’ எனும் பூதம் மூன்று குணங்கள் கொண்டுள்ளது.தீ எனும் பூதத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியிலிருந்து திரவ நிலையில் உள்ள ‘நீர்’ எனும் பூதம் ’சுவை’ எனும் குணத்துடன் உண்டானது. அத்துடன் ஆகாயம், காற்று, தீ எனும் பூதங்களின் குணங்களான ஒலி, தொடு உணர்வு மற்றும் உருவம் (ரூபம்) எனும் மூன்று குணங்களுடன் தன் சொந்த குணமான சுவை எனும் குணத்துடன், நான்கு குணங்களுடன் நீர் எனும் பூதம் விளங்குகிறது.நீர் எனும் பூதத்திலிருந்து ’நிலம்’ எனும் பூதம் ’வாசனை’ எனும் குணத்துடன் தோன்றியது. அத்துடன் ஆகாயம், காற்று, தீ, நீர் எனும் நான்கு பூதங்களின் குணங்களான ஒலி, தொடு உணர்வு, உருவம் (ரூபம்), சுவை எனும் நான்கு குணங்களுடன், தன் சொந்த குணமான வாசனை எனும் குணத்துடன் ஐந்து குணங்களைக் கொண்டது மண் (பிருதிவி) எனும் பூதம்."},{"question":"Дүйнөдө сейрек кездешкен гүлдөрдүн кайсы бири, бир гана Баткен облусунда өсөт?","answer":"Бул сейрек кездешкен гүл - Айгүл гүлү болуп саналат."},{"question":"రైత్వారి విధానం గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఈ విధానంలో శిస్తును రైతులు నేరుగా ప్రభుత్వమునకు అనగా ప్రభుత్వ ఖజానాకు గాని, ప్రభుత్వోద్యోగులకు చెల్లించెదరు. ఇట్లు శిస్తు వసూలునందు ప్రభుత్వమునకు, రైతులకు మధ్య ఎట్టి మధ్యవర్తులు అనగా దళారులు లేకుండుట వలన ఈ విధానమును రైత్వారీ విధానముగా ప్రసిద్ధికెక్కెను. ఇంకనూ రైతులకు పట్టాలిచ్చి వారి వద్ద నుండి కబూలియత్లు (శిస్తు చెల్లింపు ఒడంబడికలు) తీసుకొనెడి సంప్రదాయము కూడా కలదు."},{"question":"أكمل ما يلي: معركة سندويتش كانت مناوشة بحرية وقعت في عام 1460 ","answer":". في هذه المعركة البحرية هُزم فيها أسطول اللانكاسترين وألقي القبض على عدد من سفنهم. هناك القليل من المعلومات والتفاصيل عن هذه المعركة البحرية."},{"question":"అయితే, అది కొత్త నోటిఫికేషన్ ఏం కాదని పాకిస్తాన్ విదేశాంగ శాఖ చెబుతోంది. ఆగస్టు 18న జారీ అయిన ఒక నోటిఫికేషన్ గురించి స్థానిక విలేకరులతో పాకిస్తాన్ విదేశాంగ శాఖ ప్రతినిధి జాహిద్ చౌధరి మాట్లాడారు.‘‘పాకిస్తాన్ 2020 ఆస్టు 18న జారీ చేసిన ఎస్ఆర్ఓ (చట్టబద్ధమైన నోటిఫికేషన్) చాలా పక్కా సమాచారంతో ఉంది. ఇంతకు ముందు జారీ చేసిన ఎస్ఆర్ఓను కూడా ఒక ప్రక్రియ ప్రకారమే ఇచ్చాం. అందుకే నిషేధిత జాబితా, నిషేధిత చర్యల్లో ఎలాంటి మార్పులూ ఉండవు” అన్నారు.“ఐక్యరాజ్యసమితి ఆంక్షల జాబితాలో తాలిబాన్, ఐఎస్, అల్‌ఖైదాల ప్రస్తుత స్థితిని చూపించడానికి 2020 ఆగస్టు 18న రెండు సంయుక్త ఎస్ఆర్ఓలు జారీ చేశాం. అప్పుడప్పుడూ ఈ ఎస్ఆర్ఓలు విడుదల అవుతుంటాయి. అలాగే, చట్టపరమైన అవసరాలు, అంతర్జాతీయ బాధ్యతల ప్రకారం విదేశాంగ శాఖ ఈ ఎస్ఆర్ఓలను ప్రచురిస్తుంది. చివరి ఎస్ఆర్ఓను 2019లో ప్రచురించాం” అని ప్రతినిధి తెలిపారు. “ఈ ఎస్ఆర్ఓలో ఐక్యరాజ్యసమితి నిషేధించిన వ్యక్తులు, సంస్థల సమాచారం ఉంది. మీడియాలో కొన్ని వర్గాలు ఈ రిపోర్ట్ ద్వారా పాకిస్తాన్ ఏవో కొత్త ఆంక్షలు విధించిందని కథనాలు నడిపిస్తున్నాయి. అది సరికాదు. ఈ ఎస్ఆర్ఓను చూపిస్తూ మా దేశంలో గరిష్ఠంగా మరో 4000 అక్షరాలతో కథనాన్ని కొనసాగించండి:","answer":"కొందరు ఉన్నట్లు పాకిస్తాన్‌ అంగీకరించిందని భారత మీడియాలోని కొన్ని వర్గాలు చెబుతున్నాయి. అవి నిరాధారం, కల్పితం” అన్నారు. పాకిస్తాన్ విదేశాంగ శాఖ ఇటీవల ఒక నోటిఫికేషన్‌ విడుదల చేసింది. అందులో ఐక్యరాజ్యసమితి భద్రతా మండలి ఏయే వ్యక్తులు, సంస్థల ఆర్థికకార్యకలాపాలు, పర్యటలపై నిషేధం విధించిందో, ఆ వ్యక్తులు, సంస్థల ఆస్తులు, బ్యాంక్ అకౌంట్లను ఎలాంటి నోటీసులూ ఇవ్వకుండా జప్తు చేస్తున్నామని చెప్పింది. 2018 జూన్‌లో పాకిస్తాన్‌ను గ్రే లిస్టులో పెట్టిన పారిస్‌లోని ‘ఫైనాన్షియల్ యాక్షన్ టాస్క్ ఫోర్స్’ (ఎఫ్ఏటీఎఫ్), పాకిస్తాన్ 2019 లోపు సదరు సంస్థలు, వ్యక్తులపై చర్యలు తీసుకోవాలని చెప్పింది. పాక్ విదేశాంగ శాఖ నోటిఫికేషన్దావూద్‌కు ఎన్ని అడ్రస్‌లు ఉన్నాయి?పాకిస్తాన్ విదేశాంగ శాఖ జారీ చేసిన జాబితాలో 1993 ముంబయి వరుస పేలుళ్ల ప్రధాన నిందితుడు దావూద్ ఇబ్రహీం చిరునామా క్లిఫ్టన్, వైట్‌ హౌస్ అని ఉంది. అది కాకుండా కరాచీలో దావూద్ పేరున మరో రెండు అడ్రస్‌లు కూడా ఉన్నట్టు అందులో చెప్పారు.  దీనితోపాటూ దావూద్‌కు చాలా పేర్లు ఉన్నాయని ఆ జాబితాలో చెప్పారు. ఆతడు మహారాష్ట్రలోని రత్నగిరిలో పుట్టాడని, అతడి భారత పాస్‌పోర్టును రద్దు చేశారని కూడా అందులో ప్రస్తావించారు.పాకిస్తాన్ ప్రభుత్వం ఆగస్టు 18న ఈ నోటిఫికేషన్ జారీ చేసింది. అందులో 88 తీవ్రవాద సంస్థలు, వ్యక్తులపై విధించిన ఆర్థిక ఆంక్షల సమాచారం ఉంది.వాటిలో జమాత్ ఉద్ దవా చీఫ్ హఫీజ్ సయీద్, జైష్-ఎ-మొహమ్మద్ చీఫ్ మసూద్ అజహర్ పేర్లు కూడా ఉన్నాయి.సోషల్ మీడియాలో జోరుగా చర్చదావూద్ ఇబ్రహీం చిరునామాకు సంబంధించిన వార్తలు వెలుగులోకి రాగానే, సోషల్ మీడియాలో దీనిపై జోరుగా చర్చ జరిగింది. చాలా మంది దీని గురించి ట్వీట్లు చేశారు. “భారత సైన్యం సర్జికల్ స్ట్రైక్స్ చేయాల్సిన సమయం వచ్చింద”ని మంజరీ యశ్వంత్ ట్వీట్ చేశారు. జర్నలిస్ట్ రవిందర్ సింగ్ రాబిన్ మాత్రం “పాకిస్తాన్ ఇందులో కొత్తగా ఏం చెప్పలేదు. పాకిస్తాన్ పీఆర్ ఎక్సర్‌సైజ్ చూసి మోసపోకండి. అసలు నిజం ఏంటంటే పాకిస్తాన్‌లో వీళ్లంతా జల్సా చేస్తున్నారు” అన్నారు.దావూద్ ఇబ్రహీం కరాచీలో ఉంటున్నాడని భారత్ చాలాకాలంగా చెబుతోంది. కానీ పాకిస్తాన్ భారత్ వాదనలు కొట్టిపారేస్తూ వస్తోంది.దావూద్ ఇబ్రహీంపై ముంబయి బాంబు  పేలుళ్లతోపాటూ హవాలా, కిడ్నాపింగ్ లాంటి కేసులు ఉన్నాయి. ముంబయి బాంబు పేలుళ్లలో 257  మంది చనిపోయారు, 700 మంది గాయపడ్డారు."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat bertentu, bilang beratur\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah segala pekerjaan harus dijalankan dengan menurut peraturan yang ditetapkan"},{"question":"జలియన్ వాలాబాగ్ మారణకాండ ప్రాముఖ్యతను వివరించండి.","answer":"1919లో ఆంగ్ల ప్రభుత్వం భారతదేశంలో మాంటేగు – ఛేమ్స్ఫర్డ్ సంస్కరణలు ప్రవేశపెట్టింది. ఈ సంస్కరణలు భారతీయులకు ఎట్టి ప్రత్యేక హక్కులు ఇవ్వకపోగా ముస్లింలతో పాటు సిక్కులకు కూడా ప్రత్యేక స్థానాలు కేటాయించాయి. అందుకు భారతీయులలో అసంతృప్తి ప్రబలింది. ఇదే సమయంలో 1915 1918 కాలంలో చోటు చేసుకున్న ఉగ్రవాద కార్యకలాపాలను సమీక్షించడానికి ఆంగ్ల ప్రభుత్వముచే నియమించబడిన రౌలట్ కమిటీ కొన్ని చర్యలను సూచించింది. ఈ చర్యలన్నీ చట్టరూపం దాల్చాయి. దీనినే రౌలట్ చట్టం అంటారు. ఈ చట్టం వలన ప్రభుత్వానికి అసాధారణ అధికారాలు సంక్రమించాయి. ఈ చట్టప్రకారం రాజకీయ ఆందోళనకారులను వారంట్ లేకుండా నిర్బంధించవచ్చు. నిర్బంధించిన వారిని విచారించవలసిన పనిలేదు. ప్రభుత్వానికి వ్యతిరేకమయిన ఏ చిన్న కాగితాన్ని కలిగివున్నా అది నేరంగా పరిగణింపబడుతుంది. ఇంగ్లాండ్లో పౌరుల హక్కులకు పునాది అయిన హెబియస్ కార్పస్ హక్కు భారతీయులకు లేకుండా పోయింది. ఈ బిల్లులను కాంగ్రెస్ వ్యతిరేకించింది. గాంధీజీ ఆ బిల్లును ఆమోదించవద్దని గవర్నర్ జనరల్ను కోరాడు. కానీ అది ఆమోదించబడింది. కనుక వాటి ఉపసంహరణకు గాంధీజీ ఉద్యమించాడు. 1919 ఏప్రియల్ 6న హర్తాళ్ పాటించవలసిందిగా ఆయన ప్రజలకు పిలుపునిచ్చాడు. ఆ పిలుపునందుకొని దేశమంతటా హర్తాళ్ జరిగింది. హిందూ, ముస్లిం భేదం లేకుండా అందరూ ఈ ఉద్యమంలో పాల్గొన్నారు. ఢిల్లీ, అహ్మదాబాద్, పంజాబ్లలో హింసాకాండ జరిగింది. ముఖ్యంగా పంజాబ్లో ప్రజల నాయకులైన సత్యపాల్, సైఫుద్దీన్ కిచ్లూలను ప్రభుత్వం నిర్బంధించింది.ఈ నిర్భంధానికి వ్యతిరేకంగా అమృత్సర్ ప్రజలు జలియన్ వాలాబాగ్ వద్ద సమావేశమైనారు. సమావేశం సాగుతుండగానే అమృత్సర్ మిలిటరీ కమాండర్ జనరల్ డయ్యర్ అక్కడకు వచ్చి ప్రజలపై ఎటువంటి హెచ్చరికలు లేకుండా కాల్పులు జరిపించాడు. ఈ కాల్పుల్లో 379 మంది మరణించగా, 1200 మంది గాయపడ్డారు. ఈ సంఘటనే చరిత్రలో జలియన్ వాలాబాగ్ దురంతంగా ప్రసిద్ధి చెందింది. జలియన్ వాలాబాగ్ సంఘటన భారత స్వాతంత్ర్య సమరంలో ఒక మైలురాయి. ఈ సంఘటన వలన భారత స్వాతంత్ర్యోద్యమం ఒక మహా సంగ్రామంగా మారింది."},{"question":"Yaa lagu soo dejiyey kutubka Towraad?","answer":"Waxaa lagu soo dejiyey kutubka Towraad nabi Muuse(CS)."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 22 ਫਰਵਰੀਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਵਸੀਲਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ (ਐਚਆਰਡੀ) ਨੇ ਜਾਮੀਆ ਮਿਲੀਆ ਇਸਲਾਮੀਆ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਬੌਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਸੁਪਰਸਟਾਰ ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਆਨਰੇਰੀ ਡਾਕਟਰੇਟ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਨਕਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ ਨੇ ਦਲੀਲ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਕੋਲ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਹੋਰ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਦੀ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਖ਼ੁਲਾਸਾ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਤਹਿਤ ਮੰਗੀ ਗਈ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ’ਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।ਬੌਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਸਟਾਰ ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਜਾਮੀਆ ਮਿਲੀਆ ਇਸਲਾਮੀਆ ਦਾ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਤਜਵੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਸਹਿਮਤੀ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਲੈਣ ਲਈ ਹੀ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਨੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਵਸੀਲਿਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ ਕੋਲ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਭੇਜੀ ਸੀ। ਇਕ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਜਦੋਂ ਜਾਮੀਆ ਮਿਲੀਆ ਇਸਲਾਮੀਆ ਤੋਂ ਇਸ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੰਗੀ ਗਈ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਜਵਾਬ ’ਚ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੌਲਾਣਾ ਆਜ਼ਾਦ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਉਰਦੂ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਤੋਂ 2016 ’ਚ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਮਿਲ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ।ਐਚਆਰਡੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਜਦੋਂ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਅਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਡਿਗਰੀਆਂ ਜਿੰਨੀ ਮਰਜ਼ੀ ਵਾਰ ਲਈਆਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਬਤ ਕੋਈ ਤੈਅ ਨੇਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ। ਉਂਜ ਅਕਸਰ ਵੱਧ ਡਿਗਰੀਆਂ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਰੋਕਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਜਾਮੀਆ ਮਿਲੀਆ ਇਸਲਾਮੀਆ ’ਚ ਮਾਸ ਕਮਿਊਨਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਖੋਜ ਸੈਂਟਰ ’ਚ ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਹਾਜ਼ਰੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਨਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਖਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਸਲਾਨਾ ਇਮਤਿਹਾਨ ਵਿਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਇਆ?","answer":"ਸ਼ਾਹਰੁਖ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਹਾਜ਼ਰੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਨਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਖਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਿਆ ਸੀ। "},{"question":"एक समाज कल्याण संस्था का काम।","answer":"संस्था ने समाज में सकारात्मक परिवर्तन लाने के लिए काम किया और जरूरतमंद लोगों की मदद की।"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo lafin-javatra mety mahatonga ny paralysie du sommeil ?","answer":" Misy ireo anton-javatra mety mahatonga ny fitrangan’ny paralysie du sommeil, anisan’izany ny :-rarin-tsaina ;-fitebitebena ;-havizanana be loatra nandritra ny tontolo andro ;-tsy fahampiana torimaso ;-fikorontanan’ny torimaso ;-fiovana eo amin’ny lafim-piainana toy ny fahafatesana olona akaiky, fiovana asa, fisaraham-panambadiana..."},{"question":"ما هو الفرق بين الشبكة والإنترنت؟. ","answer":"الشبكة هي بنية توفر وسيلة للأجهزة المختلفة للاتصال وتبادل البيانات. يمكن أن تكون الشبكات محلية (مثل شبكة منزلية) أو عالمية (مثل شبكة الإنترنت). الإنترنت، بالمقابل، هو نظام عالمي لربط الشبكات المحلية والعالمية، مما يتيح للأفراد والمؤسسات التفاعل وتبادل المعلومات عبر العالم باستخدام مجموعة من البروتوكولات والتقنيات. ببساطة، الإنترنت هو نوع من الشبكات، وهو يشمل جميع الشبكات المتصلة على مستوى العالم."},{"question":"อธิบายความหมายของคำต่อไปนี้: ศิลปะ","answer":"ศิลปะ หมายถึงสิ่งซึ่งเป็นหรือเป็นผลผลิตจากกิจกรรมของมนุษย์ ซึ่งประกอบด้วย ความคิด เพื่อแสดงออกซึ่งฝีมือ, สุนทรีย์, อำนาจทางอารมณ์, หรือแนวคิด"},{"question":"Ahoana no hijanonana mafana amin'ny ririnina? Manana vahaolana roa azo atao ianao:Vahaolana 1: Manaova akanjo mafana.Vahaolana 2: Mitsambikina ao anaty dobo filomanosana mangatsiaka.","answer":"Ny vahaolana 1 dia mitombina kokoa. Tafiditra ao anatin'izany ny fanao mahazatra ny mijanona mafana amin'ny ririnina, fa ny vahaolana 2 kosa dia mifanohitra amin'ny vokatra andrasana."},{"question":"Ọdun Iṣẹṣẹ: Gomina Oyetọla kede ọjọ Ẹti gẹgẹ bii isinmi lẹnu iṣẹ","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Adegboyega Oyetọla, ti kede ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to n bọ, iyẹn ogunjọ, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, gẹgẹ bii ọjọ isinmi lẹnu iṣẹ lati fun awọn ẹlẹsin abalaye laaye lati ṣe ayẹyẹ  ọdun Iṣẹṣẹ ọdun 2021.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ ibagbepọ idile (Commissioner for Home Affairs), Alhaji Tajudeen Ọlaniyi Lawal, fi sita lorukọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun, lo ti ni ayẹyẹ ti ọdun yii ko ni i ni gbagba-gbugbu ninu.Gẹgẹ bi Lawal ṣe sọ, idi ti ayẹyẹ Iṣẹṣe ti ọdun yii ko fi ni i lariwo ninu ni ti wahala ajakalẹ arun Koronafairọọsi to n lọ lọwọ lorileede yii.Lorukọ gomina, Lawal ki awọn ẹlẹsin abalaye kaakiri ipinlẹ Ọṣun ku oriire ayẹyẹ ọdun naa, o si rọ wọn lati ṣọdun pẹlu alaafia, ki wọn si bọwọ fun ofin lasiko ayẹyẹ naa.O tun bẹ wọn lati lo asiko naa lati gbadura fun idagbasoke ipinlẹ Ọṣun, ki wọn si fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu iṣejọba to wa lode yii.Bakan naa lo tun kilọ pe ki wọn tẹle gbogbo ilana to n dena itankalẹ arun korona, ṣaaju, lasiko ati lẹyin ọdun Iṣẹṣe."},{"question":"ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆ: ತಾಯಿ ಸಿಂಹವು ಊಟಕ್ಕೆ ಮುಂಚೆ ತನ್ನ ಮರಿಗಳಿಗೆ ಏನು ಹೇಳಿತು? ಉತ್ತರ: ಲೆಟ್ ಅಸ್ ಪ್ರೇ! ಮೇಲಿನ ಹಾಸ್ಯದ ಪಂಚ್ಲೈನ್ ಏನು ಎಂದು ನೀವು ಭಾವಿಸುತ್ತೀರಿ?","answer":"ವಿವರಣೆ: ಅನೇಕ ಜನರು ಭೋಜನಕ್ಕೆ ಮುಂಚೆ ಪ್ರಾರ್ಥಿಸುತ್ತಾರೆ; ಅವರು ತಮ್ಮ ದೇವರು, ಆತ್ಮ ಅಥವಾ ಉನ್ನತ ಜೀವಿಗಳಿಗೆ ಕೃತಜ್ಞತೆಯ ಮಾತುಗಳನ್ನು ಹೇಳುತ್ತಾರೆ.  ಈ ಹಾಸ್ಯವು ಸಿಂಹಗಳೊಂದಿಗೆ ಪ್ರಾರ್ಥನೆ / ಬೇಟೆಯ ಪದಗಳ ಮೇಲೆ ಆಡುತ್ತದೆ. ತಿನ್ನುವ ಮೊದಲು ಬೇಟೆಯಾಡುವುದು ಪ್ರಾರ್ಥನೆ ಅಲ್ಲ. ಇಲ್ಲಿ ಒಂದು ಸಿಂಹವು ಪ್ರಾರ್ಥಿಸುತ್ತಿರುವಂತೆ ಕಾಣುತ್ತದೆ. ಪ್ರಾಯಶಃ, ಸಾಮಾನ್ಯ  ಬಳಿಕೆಯಲ್ಲಿ ಪ್ರೇ ಎಂಬ ಆಂಗ್ಲ ಪದವನ್ನು ಪ್ರಾರ್ಥನೆ ಎಂಬ ಅರ್ಥದಲ್ಲಿ ಉಪಯೋಗಿಸುತ್ತಾರೆ . ಆದರೆ ಇಲ್ಲಿ ಅದೇ ಪದವನ್ನು ಬೇಟೆ ಎಂಬ ಅರ್ಥ ಬರುವ ರೀತಿಯಲ್ಲಿ ಉಪಯೋಗಿಸಲಾಗಿದೆ. ಅದಕ್ಕಾಗಿಯೇ ನಾನು ಹಾಸ್ಯವನ್ನು ಇಷ್ಟಪಡುತ್ತೇನೆ."},{"question":"Татаал сүйлөм деп эмнени айтабыз?","answer":"Эки же андан ашык жөнөкөй сүйлөмдөр маанилери жана интонациялык жактан өз ара бири-бири менен ажырагыс түрдө байланышып, кеңири мазмундагы бирдиктүү бир ойду туюндурса, татаал сүйлөм деп аталат."},{"question":"கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கேள்விக்குச் சரியான பதிலளி:இந்தியாவில் ஆங்கிலேயர்களால் கட்டப்பட்ட முதல் கோட்டை?1. டேவிட் கோட்டை 2. வில்லியம் கோட்டை  3. லூயிஸ் கோட்டை  4. செயின்ட் ஜார்ஜ் கோட்டை","answer":"விடை: 4. செயின்ட் ஜார்ஜ் கோட்டை. செயின்ட் ஜார்ஜ் கோட்டை (அல்லது வரலாற்று ரீதியாக, ஒயிட் டவுன்) என்பது இந்தியாவின் கடலோர நகரமான சென்னையில் உள்ள ஒரு கோட்டையாகும். 1639 இல் நிறுவப்பட்ட இது இந்தியாவின் முதல் ஆங்கில (பின்னர் பிரிட்டிஷ் ) கோட்டையாகும். கோட்டையின் கட்டுமானமானது, முதலில் மக்கள் வசிக்காத நிலத்தில் மேலும் குடியேற்றங்கள் மற்றும் வர்த்தக நடவடிக்கைகளுக்கு உத்வேகம் அளித்தது. இந்த கோட்டையில் தற்போது தமிழ்நாடு சட்டமன்றம் மற்றும் பிற அதிகாரப்பூர்வ கட்டிடங்கள் உள்ளன."},{"question":"Bilakah Hari Kemerdekaan Malaysia?","answer":"Hari Kemerdekaan Malaysia disambut pada setiap tanggal 31 Ogos setiap tahun untuk menyambut kemerdekaan Malaysia daripada penjajahan British pada tahun 1957."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இலக்கியம் என்பது நாகரிகத்தைப் புகட்ட வேண்டும்; மக்களிடம் உயரிய குணங்களைப் புகுத்தவதாக இருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Apakah tempura? ","answer":"Tempura adalah makanan Jepun berupa makanan laut, sayur-sayuran, atau ulam yang dicelup ke dalam adunan berupa tepung gandum dan kuning telur dicairkan dengan air bersuhu dingin lalu digoreng dengan minyak yang banyak hingga berwarna kuning muda. Tempura juga bermaksud cara menggoreng yang berbeza dengan furai (istilah bahasa Jepun untuk goreng celup)"},{"question":" Sheeg Wadanka Ugu dhaqashada badan Geela ee Jaamacadda Carabta ah","answer":" Waa wadanka Soomaaliya."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"જશોદા! તારા કાનુડાને\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"જશોદા ! તારા કાનુડાને સાદ કરીને વાર રે;આવડી ધુમ મચાવે વ્રજમાં, નહી કોઇ પૂછનાર રે.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"જશોદા ! તારા કાનુડાને સાદ કરીને વાર રે;આવડી ધુમ મચાવે વ્રજમાં, નહી કોઇ પૂછનાર રે. જશોદા.શીંકું તોડ્યું, ગોરસ ઢોળ્યું, ઉઘાડીને બાર રે;માંખણ ખાધુ ઢોળી નાખ્યું, જાન કીધું આ વાર રે. જશોદા.ખાંખા ખોળાં કરતો હીંડે, બિહે નહી લગાર રે;મહી મથવાની ગોળી ફોડી, આ શાં કહિયે લાડ રે. જશોદા.વારે વારે કહુંછું તમને, હવે ન રાખું ભાર રે;નિત ઊઠીને અને ક્યમ સહિયે, વસી નગર મોઝાર રે. ⁠ જશોદા.મારો કાનજી ઘરમાં હુતો, ક્યારે દીઠો નબ્હાર રે;દહીંદૂધનાં માટ ભર્યાં છે, બીજે ચાખે ન લગાર રે. જશોદા.શાને કાજે મળીને આવી, ટોળી વળી દશ-બાર રે;નરસંઇયાનો સ્વામી સાચો, જૂઠી વ્રજની નાર રે. જશોદા."},{"question":"Cheetham, nacido el 30 de enero de 1928 en El Paso, Texas, creció en Taos, Nuevo México, recibió B.S.Cheetham nació el 30 de enero de 1928 en Taos, Nuevo México, creció en El Paso, Texas, y recibió B.S.?¿Las oraciones anteriores se parafrasean entre sí?. ","answer":"No, se parafrasean entre sí. "},{"question":"Stephanie Okereke Linus","answer":"Stephanie Linus (Stephanie Onyekachi Okereke; 2 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀wá 1982) jẹ́ òṣèré, olùdarí eré àti afẹwàṣiṣẹ́. Ó ti gba ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ àti àwọn yíyàn fún iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ bí òṣèré, tó fi mọ́ àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Reel ti ọdún 2003 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ, àmì-ẹ̀yẹ Afro Hollywood ti ọdún 2006 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ, àti àwọn yíyàn mẹ́ta míràn fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ ní ipa asíwájú níbi ayẹyẹ Africa Movie Academy Awards ní ọdún 2005, 2009 ati 2010. Ó tún jẹ́ olùdíje níbi ìdíje ẹwà ti Nàìjíríà ní ọdún 2002. Ní ọdún 2011, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà da lọ́lá pẹ̀lú fífun ní oyè Memeber of the Order of the Federal Republic (MFR).Stephanie Okereke ni a bí ní Ngor Okpala, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ímò . Òun ni ọmọ ẹ̀kẹfà ti ọmọ mẹ́jọ àwọn òbí rẹ̀. Ó parí ilé-ìwé alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ àti girama ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Dẹ́ltà. Ó kẹ́ẹ̀kọ́ gíga ní Yunifásitì ìlú Calabar, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Cross River, níbi tí ó ti gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ èdè gẹ̀ẹ́sì.Ní àkókò ìgbà tí ó sì wà ní ọ̀dọ́ ní ọdún 1997, ó hàn nínu àwọn fíìmù Nollywood méjì kan; Compromise 2 àti Waterloo. Níbi ìdíje ẹwà Nàìjíríà ti ọdún 2002 tí ó ti kópa, Okereke ṣe ipò kejì. Ní ọdún 2003, Okereke gba àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ méjì, nínu mẹ́jọ tí wọ́n yàn-án fún, níbi ayẹyẹ Reel Awards ti ọdún 2003 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ. Lẹ́hìn ìparí ẹ̀kọ́ láti Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga New York Film Academy ní ọdún 2007, Okereke ṣe àgbéjáde fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Through the Glass èyítì ó ṣe pé òun ni ó ṣètò kíkọ àti dídarí eré náà, tí ó sì tún kópa nínu rẹ̀. Fíìmù náà rí yíyàn Africa Movie Academy fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ní ọdún 2009. Ní ọdún 2014, ó ṣe àgbéjáde fíìmù míràn tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Dry. Òun yìí kan náà lótún ṣètò kíkọ àti dídarí, bẹ́ẹ̀ ló sì tún kópa nínu eré náà, èyí tí ó gba ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ tó fi mọ́ ti Africa Movie Awards ẹlẹ́kejìlá àti ti Africa Magic Viewers Choice Awards ti ọdún 2016 fún fíìmù tí ó dára jùlọ pẹ̀lú ẹ̀bùn ọkọ̀ ayọ́kẹ́lẹ́ tuntun kan. Okereke ti kópa nínu fíìmù tó lé ní àádọ́rùn-ún."},{"question":"Apakah kata yang sesuai untuk mengisi tempat kosong dalam ayat berikut? Ayah belum membuat keputusan ____________ bercuti di dalam negara _________ di luar negara.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah \\"sama ada\\" dan \\"atau\\"."},{"question":"बॉइल्ड एग मसाला फ्रायलागणारे जिन्नस: ","answer":"६ उकडलेली अंडीतेल - २-३ चमचे२ मध्यम कांदे - उभे चिरुन१ मोठा टमॅटो - उभा चिरुनआलं लसुण पेस्ट - १ टे स्पुनकडीपत्ता - ७-८ पानं कुस्करुनलाल तीखट - झेपेल एव्हडंकाळीमीरी पुड - १/२ टि स्पुन (खुप जरुरी आहे)धणे पुड - १ टे स्पुनजीरे पुड - १ टि स्पुनगरम / कीचन कींग मसाला - १ टि स्पुन (मी कीचन कींग वापरला आहे)मीठ - चवीनुसार"},{"question":"ප්‍රථම යොවුන් ග්‍රීෂ්ම ඔලිම්පික් උළෙල පැවැත්වූ වසර කුමක්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රථම යොවුන් ග්‍රීෂ්ම ඔලිම්පික් උළෙල පැවැත්වූ වසර 2010 විය."},{"question":"Chọn câu đúng trong các câu sau. A. Số 0 không phải là số nguyênB. Số 0 là số nguyên âm C. Số 0 là số nguyên dương D. Số 0 là số nguyên","answer":"Chọn đáp án D. Theo lý thuyết: Số 0 là số nguyên và số 0 không phải số nguyên âm cũng không phải số nguyên dương. Vậy đáp án A, B, C sai và D đúng. "},{"question":"Ayat 1: Peralihan fasa dari feromagnet kepada paramagnet adalah berterusan dan merupakan perintah kedua. Ayat 2: Peralihan fasa dari feromagnet kepada paramagnet adalah berterusan dan merupakan urutan kedua. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"Gomina Rivers ati Eko fẹẹ bẹrẹ gbigba owo-ori ọja (VAT) ipinlẹ wọn, lawọn Hausa ba lawọn ko ni i gba","answer":"Owo kan wa ti wọn maa n yọ lori ọja teeyan ba ra, to ba ko wọ ilu, tabi iṣẹ to ba ṣe, VAT lawọn oloyinbo n pe e, itumọ rẹ ni kikun si ni Value Added Tax.Ijọba apapọ lo maa n gba owo yii lẹka Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS),bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn to n san an le ma fi bẹẹ mọ, nitori wọn yoo ti ṣi i mọ ojulowo owo ọja ni.Idajọ ile-ẹjọ giga kan ni Porthacourt to waa waye loṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, pe kijọba apapọ ma gba owo yii mọ, awọn ipinlẹ ni ki wọn maa gba a lo fẹẹ mu wahala ati awuyewuye dani bayii laarin ijọba apapọ atawọn ipinlẹ Naijiria.Adajọ Stephen Pam, lo gbe idajọ kalẹ lọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2021,pe eyi tijọba apapọ gba ninu owo-ori ọja yii to gẹẹ. O ni awọn gomina ni ki wọn maa gba a nipinlẹ wọn, ki wọn si maa fun ijọba apapọ niye to ba tọ si wọn.Ṣe tẹlẹ, bijọba apapọ ba gba owo yii, wọn yoo pin in si ọna mẹta ni. Ijọba apapọ yoo yọ ida mẹẹẹdogun (15%), wọn yoo fun ijọba ipinlẹ ni ipin aadọta (50%), ijọba ibilẹ yoo si gba ida marundinlogoji (35%).Ida marun-un ni ele owo-ori ọja yii tẹlẹ, (5%), ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu keje, ọdun 2020, ni wọn gbe ofin kan jade to sọ ọ di ida meje aabọ (7.5%) latigba naa lo si ti wa bẹẹ to jẹ ida meje aabọ yii lawọn eeyan n san.Nibi ti wahala ti waa ṣẹlẹ ni pe ipinlẹ Eko ati Rivers ti ni ofin ile-ẹjọ to ni kawọn maa gba owo naa gẹgẹ bii ipinlẹ lawọn yoo maa tẹle bayii, wọn ni ijọba apapọ ko lẹtọọ lati tun maa gba a mọ.Awọn ipinlẹ meji yii lowo lọwọ, wọn n gbe iṣẹ jade fawọn alagbaṣe, ero tun pọ nibẹ ti wọn n ṣiṣe aje, ti wọn si n pawo wọle funjọba ibẹ, iyẹn lawọn ṣe ni owo ilu awọn ko yẹ ko bọ sọdọ ijọba apapọ ju, ti wọn yoo maa waa yọ owo le awọn lọwọ. Wọn ni ohun to yẹ ni kawọn maa da owo ele ori ọja naa gba, kawọn si fun ijọba apapọ niye to ba tọ si wọn latọdọ awọn.Nibi tawọn ipinlẹ meji yii ti n sọ eyi lawọn ipinlẹ bii Gombe, Katsina atawọn ilẹ Hausa mi-in ti ni awọn ko gba idajọ ile-ẹjọ yii wọle ni tawọn. Wọn ni bawọn ba ni kawọn maa gba owo-ori ọja yii funra awọn, ohun tawọn yoo pada na gẹgẹ bii ipinlẹ yoo ju ohun tijọba apapọ n fun awọn lọ.Wọn ni bẹẹ si ree, owo tijọba apapọ n fun awọn lawọn fi n gbera. Awọn ipinlẹ mi-in ninu awọn ko le da owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ wọn san nilẹ Hausa yii bi ko ba jẹ pe ijọba apapọ fun wọn lowo ti wọn ti yatọ sọtọ fun wọn. Iyẹn lawọn ṣe ni awọn yoo pe ẹjọ ko-tẹmi-lọrun lori igbẹjọ to ni kijọba apapọ ma gba VAT mọ, wọn lawọn ko fara mọ ọn.Awọn akọṣẹmọṣẹ nipa eto iṣuna naa ti figba kan da si ọrọ yii, wọn ni iṣẹ ijọba apapọ ni lati gba maa gba owo yii, ẹka to si n gba a naa ni Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS). Wọn ni awọn naa lo tọ si lati maa gba a lọ, nitori bi awọn ipinlẹ ba ni awọn yoo maa gba owo yii, atari ajanaku ni yoo jẹ fun wọn, ti ki i ṣe ẹru ọmọde. Wọn ni owo buruku ni yoo pada maa bọ lapo wọn sọdọ ijọba apapọ, eyi ti ko le pe wọn rara, yoo wulẹ bu wọn lọwọ ni.Minisita eto iṣuna tẹlẹ, Kẹmi Adeọṣun, ti figba kan sọ ọ lọdun 2017, pe ipinlẹ Eko ni ida marundinlọgọta (55%) owo-ori ọja tijọba apapọ n san fawọn ipinlẹ ti n wa, ida marundinlogoji yooku, ọdọ awọn ipinlẹ marundinlogoji to ku ni Naijiria ni.Eyi naa lo jẹ ki ọkan lara awọn akọṣẹmọṣẹ nipa kinni yii, Ọgbẹni Taiwo Oyedele, sọ pe awọn ipinlẹ yooku yii yoo padanu pupọ bi wọn ba n da gba owo yii, nitori owo ti yoo ti apo wọn jade yoo ju ohun ti yoo wọle sibẹ lọ. Afi Eko nikan to yatọ, to jẹ ko si ẹlẹgbẹ ẹ ninu awọn  ipinlẹ Naijiria to ba di ti ọrọ aje.Ṣugbọn awọn ipinlẹ to fẹẹ gbe igbesẹ gbigba owo yii funra wọn ti yari, wọn ni ko si kinni kan ti yoo yi ero awọn pada, ibi teeyan ba ti n ṣe naa lo ti gbọdọ jẹ.Nyesom Wike, Gomina ipinlẹ Rivers, ti sọ ọ di aṣẹ nilẹ tiẹ, Eko naa, labẹ Gomina Babajide Sanwo-Olu, ti ni awọn ko ni i pẹẹ bẹrẹ si i gba owo-ori ọja yii funra awọn, bo ba jẹ kawọn kọwe sile-igbimọ aṣofin Eko ki wọn tete ṣe atunṣe sawọn ibi to yẹ labẹ ofin owo gbigba yii ni, kawọn si jẹ kawọn eeyan to ti n sanwo naa funjọba apapọ tẹlẹ ma ṣe bẹẹ mọ, ki wọn maa san an si asunwọn awọn, wọn lawọn yoo ṣe bẹẹ laipẹ rara."},{"question":"राणाकालमा खड्ग निशानको अड्डालाइ के ले जनाउँथ्यो ?","answer":"श्री ३ को कार्यलय (खरिदार २०६८)"},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Filazana\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Filazana\\" dia \\"Fanambarana\\"."},{"question":"ලොව වැඩිම ජල පරිමාවක් රැගෙන යන ගංගාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඇමසන් ගඟ"},{"question":"«Өлгөндөр баркталмайын, тирүүлөр даңкталбайт» дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Тагдыр бирде кысса, бирде жылмаят тура. Бир кезде кыргыз үчүн кан-жанын аябаган аталарыбыздын урматы бүгүнкү күндө опол тоо көтөрө алгыс. Ошон үчүн ар бирибиз, өзүбүздүн кимдигибизди таанып, келечекке болгон сапарыбыздын багытын туура коюп, ошонун үстүндө Алыкул айткандай иштей бериш керек. «Өлгөндөр баркталмайын, тирүүлөр даңкталбайт» деген сыңары, аталарыбыздын эмгегинин, биз үчүн төгүлгөн канынын, апалардын көз жашынын баркын билип, мүмкүн болсо, алар салган чыйыр менен өзүбүздүн заманга жараша элге, жерге кызмат кылуудан чегинбейли."},{"question":"Wahala niluu Aye, ọmọ kabiesi ku sinu igbo, lawọn araalu ba ni ọlọpaa lo yinbọn pa a","answer":"Ara o rọ okun, bẹẹ ni ko rọ adiyẹ bayii niluu Aye, nijọba ibilẹ Ejigbo, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, pẹlu bi awọn araalu ṣe fẹsun kan ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa pe wọn yinbọn pa ọkan lara awọn ọmọ kabiesi ilu naa.Ọkunrin kan, Jacob Ayọọla, la gbọ pe o kọ iwe ẹsun sawọn ọlọpaa nipa ọba ilu naa, Ọba Mathew Ajala, ati gbogbo ilu lapapọ lori ilẹ kan nibẹ.A gbọ pe awọn ọlọpaa lati ẹkun kọkanla, iyẹn Zone XI, si lọ siluu naa lati ba wọn yanju ẹ. Ori ilẹ yẹn ni wọn duro si lọjọ yii, aburo kabiesi, Gbenga Ajala, si ṣalaye bi ọrọ ṣe jẹ lorukọ awọn araalu, bo ṣe rojọ tan la gbọ pe o ṣubu lulẹ, ki wọn si to gbe e de ọsibitu, o ti jade laye.Ọrọ yii bi awọn ọdọ ilu ninu pupọ, bi wọn si ṣe sin oku Gbenga tan lọjọ keji ni wọn ya lọ sile Ayọọla pe afi ko fi ilu silẹ fun awọn. Nigba ti ọrọ naa le ju ni baba yii ko awọn ọmọ pẹlu awọn ọmọ-ọmọ rẹ, ti wọn si sa lọ.Ṣugbọn lẹyin ọjọ diẹ, gẹgẹ bi alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ejigbo tẹlẹ, Ẹnjinnia Yinka Adigun, ṣe wi, ṣe ni Ayọọla lọ sileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun, o si ko awọn ọlọpaa wọlu Aye ni nnkan bii aago kan oru.Lakọlakọ lawọn ọlọpaa naa n yinbọn, ti wọn si fi pampẹ gbe ọpọlọpọ awọn araalu lọjọ yii, laaarọ ọjọ keji ni wọn ba ọkan lara awọn ọmọ kabiesi, Isaiah Ajala, to ti ku sinu igbo.Ṣugbọn Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, sọ pe awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn lọ sibẹ ko pa ẹnikankan. O ni ẹsun igbiyanju lati paayan ati idunkooko mọ ẹmi ẹni ni Ayọọla fi kan awọn kan ninu ilu naa, idi si niyi tawọn ọlọpaa fi lọ sibẹ.Nipa idi ti wọn fi lọ laarin oru, Ọpalọla ṣalaye pe asiko yẹn lawọn ọlọpaa le ri awọn ti Ayọọla fẹsun kan mu, wọn si ti ri mọkanla mu ninu awọn mejila torukọ wọn wa niwaju awọn ọlọpaa bayii.Ọpalọla fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe ọmọkunrin to n jẹ Isaiah yii gan-an lo ṣa ọkan lara awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn lọ sibẹ ladaa, to si sa lọ lọjọ naa.O ṣeleri pe iwadii yoo bẹrẹ kiakia lati mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an."},{"question":"පහත නාම පදයට අදාළ පුරුෂ ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද? දායිකාව ","answer":"දායකයා"},{"question":"Maṣinni ti wọn fi n ṣe ọṣẹ lo ge akẹkọọ Fasiti Ibadan yii si wẹwẹ nibi to ti n ṣiṣẹ","answer":"Titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii lawọn eeayn ṣi n tara ikunlẹ abiyamọ lori iku buruku to pa ọdọmọkunrin ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun kan, Gbadebọ Richard, to jẹ akẹkọọ ọlọdun kẹta nileewe giga Fasiti Ibadan. Maṣinni to fi n ṣiṣẹ lo ge e si meji, o si ku nibi to ti n ṣiṣẹ aje lati ri owo lasiko ti ileewe wa lọlude Korona niluu Ibadan.ALAROYE gbọ pe ileeṣẹ awọn Ṣaina kan ti wọn n pe ni Hankel Nigeria Limited, ti wọn n ṣe ọṣẹ ifọṣọ WAW atawọn oriṣiiriṣii nnkan mi-in to wa ni Oluyọle, niluu Ibadan, ni ọmọkunrin yii lọ nitori ileewe to wa nisinmi Korona lati ṣiṣẹ.Ọkan ninu awọn ọrẹ rẹ ṣalaye pe ẹka ibi ti wọn ti n ṣe ọsẹ abufọ ti wọn n pe ni (detergent) ni Gbadebọ ti n ṣiṣẹ. Iṣẹ alẹ ni wọn lo ṣe lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii ti iṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ.Wọn niṣe ni ọmọkunrin naa lọọ bu ohun eelo ti wọn fi n ṣe ọṣẹ naa sinu maṣinni, lasiko to n bu u sinu rẹ ni apo ti ohun eelo ọṣẹ naa wa ninu rẹ kọ maṣinni naa, nibi to ti n gbiyanju lati yọ ọ lo ti wọ inu maṣinni naa, ti iyẹn si ge e si meji lọgbọọgba, to si kun un si wẹwẹ bii ẹran.Awọn tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣoju wọn sọ pe awọn yooku ko tete mọ pe nnkan ti ṣẹlẹ si Gbadebọ, afigba ti ọsẹ to n jade lodikeji lọhun-un ti wọn fẹẹ rọ sinu ọra jẹ kiki ẹjẹ, eyi lo mu ki wọn lọọ wo maṣinni to n po ọsẹ pọ naa, to si jẹ pe ẹsẹ ọmọkunrin yii ni wọn ri nilẹẹlẹ nibẹ.  Ilaji ara Gbadebọ ni wọn ni maṣinni naa ti lọ lubulubu. Ilaji ara to ku to ti run jegejege la gbọ pe wọn gbe fun awọn obi rẹ ti wọn lọọ gbe si ile igbokuu-si.Ohun to dun awọn eeyan, paapaa awọn akẹkọọ ẹgbẹ Gbadebọ, lori ọrọ yii ni iha ‘ko kan mi’  ti awọn to ni ileeṣẹ naa kọ si iṣẹlẹ ọhun. Wọn ni awọn eeyan naa ko tilẹ bikita lati ranṣẹ ibanikẹdun, tabi ki wọn ṣe abẹwo si ẹbi ọmọkunrin naa.Eyi lo mu ki awọn ẹgbẹ akẹkọọ fi ẹhonu wọn han lori iṣẹlẹ yii, ti wọn si bu ẹnu atẹ lu awọn ileeṣẹ naa.Lẹyin eyi ni awọn ileesẹ Hankel fi atẹjade kan sita, nibi ti wọn ti tọrọ aforiji pe o pẹ ki awọn too gbe igbesẹ lori iṣẹlẹ naa. Wọn ṣeleri lati ṣe iwadii to yẹ lori rẹ."},{"question":"Quem é a deusa grega do amanhecer?","answer":"Éos."},{"question":"Vertigo nasıl tanı konur?","answer":"Vertigo tanısında ilk yapılması gereken hastaya duyduğu hissin tarif ettirilmesidir. Daha sonra altta yatan nedeni bulmaya yönelik olarak merkezi sinir sistemi ve iç kulakla ilgili testler yapılır."},{"question":"ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਦੋ ਕੰਮ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"1. ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।2. ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਬੱਚੇ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਜੀਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Waa maxay geeraar? ","answer":"Geeraar waa god kamid ah godadka maansada kuwa ugu miisanka wayn. "},{"question":"问题：中国传统文化中有哪些重要的元素？","answer":"答案：中国传统文化中的重要元素包括但不限于语言文字、诗词歌赋、书法、绘画、音乐、戏曲、武术、茶艺、中医、园林艺术等。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੁਣਿਐ ਸਿਧ ਪੀਰ ਸੁਰਿ ਨਾਥ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"(ਸਾਦਾਰਨ ਮਨੱੁਖ) ਸਿੱਧਾਂ, ਪੀਰਾਂ, ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਨਾਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਦਵੀ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।\\""},{"question":"සාමාන්‍ය ලූනු කාණ්ඩය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සුලභ සාමන්‍ය ලූනු කාණ්ඩය, A. cepa කාණ්ඩයට අයිති විව්ධත්වයෙන් යුතු Allium භෝගය විශේෂිත වැදගත් කමකින් යුක්තය. මෙම කාණ්ඩයට අයත් ශාක තනි බල්බයක් සහිත වන අතර මේවා බීජ මගින් හෝ බීජ මගින් ඇති කරන තවාන් මගින් වර්ධනය කරගනී. ලූනු, සළාද ලූනු හා පික්ලිං ලූනු ප්‍රධාන වශයෙන් මෙම කාණ්ඩයට අයත් වගාවන් වේ. මෙම වගාවන්ගේ විවිධ වර්ගවල ව්‍යාප්තියට අංකුර හටගන්නා කාලසීමාව, ගබඩා කර තැබිය හැකි කාලසීමාව, රස හා පිට පොත්තේ වර්ණයද අයිති වේ. වියළන ලද ලූනු, සුප් සඳහා සහ ලූනු පිටි සඳහා භාවිතා කරන තියුණු සැරක් ඇති ලූනු වල සිට මෘදු පැණි රසැති ලූනු දක්වා මෙම සාමාන්‍ය ලූනු ව්‍යාප්ත වී ඇත. උදාහරණ ලෙස පෙතිගසා මස් වෙනුවට සැන්ඩ්විච් වලට යෙඑදිය හැකි, ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ජෝර්ජියා ප්‍රාන්තයේ විඩලියා ලූනු හෝ වොෂින්ටන් ප්‍රාන්තයේ වොල්ලා වොල්ලා හැඳින්විය හැක."},{"question":"Kaaramara xarunta?","answer":"Kaaramara Xarunti Geesiyada shuhadada Soomaliyeed🇸🇴 mar uun hankoodu wuu rumoobi doonaa Inshallaah.  Gobanida la sheegaye waa inay dadku kaa amaan helaan."},{"question":"Inona no toetra fototry ny mpandraharaha mahomby?","answer":"Ny toetra mampiavaka ny mpandraharaha mahomby dia ny fahaiza-mamorona, ny fandraisan'anjaran'ny risika, ny fikirizana, ny fahitana, ny faharetana ary ny fahaiza-mampifanaraka."},{"question":"' බීභත්ස්‍යය ' කියන එකේ තේරුම මොකක්ද?","answer":"පිළිකුලක් හෙවත් ජුගුප්සාවසංස්කෘත කාව්‍ය සම්ප්‍රදාය තුළ එන නවනළු රස වලින් එකකි.බීභත්ස්‍ය රසය හෙවත් පිළිකුල් රසය.. එවන් අවස්ථාවක් සදහා උදාහරණයක් ලෙස පන්සිය පණස් ජාතකය තුළ එන උම්මග්ග ජාතකයෙහි ගිරා පෝතකයා විසින් කේවට්ටයාගේ හිසට හා මුවට වර්චස් හෙළීම දැක්විය හැකිය"},{"question":"شیوه بازی قایم باشک به چه شکل است؟","answer":"قایم باشک بازی سرعت عمل، دقت و جایگیری مناسب است.در این بازی، حداقل باید ۳ نفر حضور داشته باشند و یک نفر به‌عنوان گرگ انتخاب شود. گرگ باید چشم بگذارد و از یک تا صد شروع به شمارش کند. در طول این زمان، سایر بازیکنان باید خود را در محلی قایم کنند، به‌گونه‌ای گرگ نتواند آن‌ها بیابد.اولین نفری را که گرگ محل او را پیدا کند، نفر بعدی برای چشم‌گذاشتن خواهد بود. همچنین اگر بازیکنی بتواند دور از چشم گرگ خود را به محل چشم‌گذاشتن برساند، برنده معرفی می‌شود. در قایم باشک، به‌عنوان یکی از جذاب‌ترین بازی های محلی، سرعت عمل و ابتکار بسیار مهم است."},{"question":"Manana teny mikorotana ianao : KALAOLAOmeno ny teny tena marina:","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"KALALAO\\""},{"question":" Qofka doona inuu islaamka soogalo, muxuu ku soo galayaa diinta","answer":" Wuxuu diinta islaamka ku soogelayaa inuu ku dhawaaqo Shahaada-teynka(Shahaadateyn= labada ashaado)."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Дүйнөдө сенин кучагынан артык жер жок. Ошол эле учурда, мен сени менен болгонумда ар дайым сүйүктүү, сооронуч жана коопсуз сезем! Туулган күнүң менен сүйүктүү күйөөм! "},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：临床心理学的目标是什么？","answer":"答案：临床心理学的目标是评估、诊断和治疗个体的心理问题，帮助他们实现心理健康和幸福。"},{"question":"จงเติมคำที่หายไปในประโยคต่อไปนี้ \\"เขา_เดินกับอาจารย์\\" โดยมีคำให้เลือกต่อไปนี้ กิน,นอน,กำลัง","answer":"กำลัง"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هى السورة التى يبلغ عدد آياتها ١١ آية فقط؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الجمعة."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waa Max’ed Cabdulle Xalane waxa uu ku geeriyooday Tog Wajaale sanadkii 1964."},{"question":"问题：铅笔刀的刀片如何进行安全更换？","answer":"答案：在更换铅笔刀的刀片时，应遵循生产商提供的指示，小心操作以避免刀片伤害。"},{"question":"Fortnite mobilde var mı?","answer":"ÖNEMLİ: Android'de Fortnite, şu anda Samsung Galaxy Store veya epicgames.com üzerinden edinebileceğin Epic Games Uygulaması'nda mevcuttur. Fortnite şu anda Google Play'de mevcut değildir. Daha fazla bilgi edin."},{"question":"No futebol paulista, o que é o majestoso?","answer":"O majestoso se refere ao confronto entre Corinthians e São Paulo."},{"question":"ドイツ語で「爆弾」の意味がある、高圧の気体を入れるための鉄の容器のことを何という？","answer":"ボンベです。"},{"question":"Isiokwu: Iko mbaụwa 2018: Rọshịa emeriela Ijipt 3-1nSummary: N'ọgbọ egwuregwu St. Petersburg, ndị n'ọchị ndị n'akwa ka ndị Rọshịa meriri Ijipt.","answer":"Ndị mba IjiptDaalụ maka isonyere anyị taa. Sonyekwa anyị echi mgbe anyị ga-ewetara gị ihe ndị ọzọ na-agba.E gbuchiela bọọlụ. Ndị Ijipt nwara ike ha, gbaa ezigbo bọọlụ mana ndị Rọshịa eburula ebube site na goolu atọ ha nyere.Nkeji 90 na ụma: Ijipt ka na-anwa ike ha ịma ma ha a ga-enyenwu goolu ọzọ, mana isi apụtaghị. Rọshịa emeriela ma gafee agba mgbapụ (knockout stages)Nkeji 90: Ogbu bọọlụ etinyekwuola nkeji anọ. Isi Ijipt a ga-apụtakwa?Nkeji 87: Salah enwetala ohere inye goolu, gbaa s"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Efter monarkins fall 1931 gav CNT endast begränsat stöd till Andra republiken då de nya republikanska regeringarna valde att fortsätta slå ner alla försök till strejk med storskaligt våld. Åren 1931-1933 inkluderade flera försök till både industrispecifika strejker och generalstrejker men samtliga krossades av militär och polis. Samtidigt ökade CNT sitt inflytande utanför Katalonien och det radikala FAI ökade sitt inflytande i CNT. 1932 bröt Ángel Pestaña med de radikala anarkisterna och bildade det icke-militanta Syndikalistiska partiet. Anarkisterna höll sig fortsättningsvis ofta i bakgrunden under de politiska oroligheterna på grund av statsmaktens hot om repressalier, vilket visade sig tydligt under","answer":"gruvarbetarstrejken i Asturien 1934. I parlamentsvalet 1936 var CNT delat mellan de som ville bojkotta valet, de som ville låta varje arbetare själv få välja om han ville rösta eller ej och de som ville organisera aktivt stöd för Folkfronten. Resultatet blev att förhålla sig neutralt till alla partier trots UGT:s försök att vinna över CNT till vänsterkoalitionen. 1 juni hölls dock en gemensam strejk med UGT men demonstrerande arbetare attackerades av högerextrema falangister varefter protesterna urartade, polis besköt arbetarna, anarkister hämnades genom ett attentat mot falangistledaren José Antonio Primo de Rivera och myndigheterna stängde ner CNT:s lokaler i Madrid. Detta bakslag till trots hade Folkfronten vunnit parlamentsvalet och förbudet mot CNT upphävdes. Trots det var CNT fortsatt skeptiska mot vänsterregeringen på grund av de ideologiska skillnaderna mot de som ville genomföra samhällsförändringar via statsapparaten och anarkisterna som helt förkastade statsapparaten som medel för förändring."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: സാറയുടെ പക്കൽ 20 പെൻസിലുകൾ ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നു. അവൾക്ക് 6 നഷ്ടപ്പെട്ടു, 3 കൊടുത്തു. ഇപ്പോൾ അവളുടെ പക്കൽ എത്ര പെൻസിലുകൾ ഉണ്ട്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: സാറയ്ക്ക് ഇപ്പോൾ 11 പെൻസിലുകൾ ഉണ്ട്."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ ፒዛ እና ፓስታ የሰጠን የትኛው ሀገር ነው? ","answer":"መልስ፦ ጣሊያን"},{"question":"Inona ilay biby izay miverina indray ny sandriny raha tapahina?","answer":"ilay biby izay miverina indray ny sandriny raha tapahina dia ny kitan-dranomasina"},{"question":"问题：朝鲜的传统杂技表演有哪些？","answer":"答案：朝鲜的传统杂技表演有踢毽子、抖空竹和玩纺锤等。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"beralih angin\\"? Berilah contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berpindah tempat tinggal. Setelah beralih angin ke Sarawak, penyakitnya beransur pulih."},{"question":"భారత జాతీయోద్యమంలో సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ పాత్రను అంచనా వేయండి.","answer":"భారత జాతీయోద్యమ చరిత్రలో ప్రముఖ స్థానాన్ని పొందిన దేశభక్తుడు సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్. సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ ఐ.సి.ఎస్ పరీక్ష పాసై సివిల్ సర్వెంట్గా తన జీవితాన్ని ప్రారంభించాడు. అయితే సహాయ నిరాకరణోద్యమ ప్రభావానికిలోనై తన సివిల్ సర్వీసు ఉద్యోగానికి రాజీనామా చేసి జాతీయోద్యమంలో పాల్గొన్నాడు.కాంగ్రెస్లో పాత్ర: సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ కాంగ్రెస్ రాజకీయాల్లో పాల్గొన్నాడు. 1938లో హరిపూర్లో జరిగిన జాతీయ కాంగ్రెస్ సమావేశానికి అధ్యక్షుడయ్యాడు. 1939లో త్రిపుర కాంగ్రెస్ సమావేశంలో గాంధీజీ అభ్యర్థియైన భోగరాజు పట్టాభి సీతారామయ్యను ఓడించి పార్టీ అధ్యక్షుడిగా గెలుపొందాడు. అయితే కాంగ్రెస్ అనుసరిస్తున్న శాంతియుత విధానాల యెడల బోస్కు విశ్వాసం లేదు. అందువల్ల గాంధీజీతో బోస్కు తీవ్రమైన భేదాభిప్రాయాలు కలిగాయి. అందువల్ల కాంగ్రెస్ నుంచి వైదొలగి ‘ఫార్వర్డ్ బ్లాక్’ అనే కొత్త పార్టీని స్థాపించాడు.ఆజాద్ హింద్ ఫౌజ్ స్థాపన: బ్రిటిష్ వారిని భారతదేశం నుంచి వెళ్లగొట్టాలంటే రెండవ ప్రపంచ యుద్ధం సరైన అవకాశమని బోస్ భావించాడు. అయితే యుద్ధకాలంలో బోస్ ను ప్రభుత్వం నిర్బంధించింది. బోస్ 1941లో నిర్భంధం నుంచి తప్పించుకొని మొదట రష్యాకు, తరువాత జర్మనీకి, జపాన్కు వెళ్ళాడు. యుద్ధసమయంలో ఆ దేశాల సహాయంతో ఇంగ్లీషువారితో పోరాడి, దేశానికి స్వాతంత్య్రం సాధించవచ్చని బోస్ తలచాడు. యుద్ధంలో జపాన్కు చిక్కిన భారతీయ యుద్ధఖైదీలందరినీ కూడగట్టుకొని 1943లో సింగపూర్లో ‘ఆజాద్ హింద్ ఫౌజ్’ లేక ‘ఇండియన్ నేషనల్ ఆర్మీ’ని స్థాపించాడు. ఐ.ఎన్.ఏ. స్థాపనలో బోస్కు రాస్ బిహారీ బోస్, మోహన్సింగ్లు సహకరించారు. ఐ.ఎన్.ఏలో చేరిన సేనలు బోస్ న్ను “నేతాజీ” అని గౌరవంగా పిలిచేవారు. “జైహింద్” అనే నినాదాన్ని చేపట్టి బోస్ తన అనుచరులందరితో తాత్కాలిక ప్రభుత్వాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేసి “ఛలో ఢిల్లీ” అంటూ భారతదేశంలో ఇంఫాల్ సమీపంలోని మోయిరాంగ్ వరకు వచ్చాడు. ఆయనకు తోడుగా వీరవనిత కెప్టెన్ లక్ష్మి మహిళలతో ఏర్పడిన ఝాన్సీరాణి దళనేత అయింది. ఆయన నాయకత్వంలోని ఐ.ఎన్.ఏ. సైన్యాలు దేశ స్వాతంత్ర్యానికి ప్రాణాలొడ్డి పోరాడాయి. కానీ దురదృష్టవశాత్తు 1945 సెప్టెంబర్ లో జపాన్ ఓడిపోవటంతో బోస్ ప్రయత్నాలు విఫలమైనాయి. తన ప్రయత్నాలు కార్యరూపం ధరించకుండానే బోస్ 1945లో ఒక విమాన ప్రమాదంలో మరణించాడు.ఆజాద్ హింద్ ఫౌజ్ సభ్యుల విచారణ: యుద్ధానంతరం ప్రభుత్వం ‘ఆజాద్ హింద్ ఫౌజ్’ సేనలను ఇండియాపై దాడిచేయడానికి ప్రయత్నించినందున దేశద్రోహులుగా ప్రకటించి ఎర్రకోటలో విచారణ జరిపించింది. సైనిక నాయకులైన మేజర్ జనరల్ షానవాజ్ ఖాన్ (ముస్లిం), కల్నల్ జి.ఎస్. ధిల్లాన్ (సిక్కు, మేజర్ ప్రేమ్ సెహగల్ (హిందూ) లపై విచారణ జరిపించింది. వారి తరఫున జవహర్లాల్ నెహ్రూ, తేజబహదూర్ సప్రూ, భూలాబాయ్ దేశాయ్లు వాదించారు. అయినప్పటికీ ప్రత్యేక న్యాయస్థానం వారికి శిక్షలు విధించింది. కానీ ఆ శిక్షలకు దేశవ్యాప్తంగా నిరసన వ్యక్తమవటంతో ప్రజాభిప్రాయాన్ని మన్నించి, ప్రభుత్వం వారిని విడుదల చేసింది. దీనితో ప్రజలకు, సైనికులకు ప్రభుత్వం పట్ల భయభక్తులు పోయాయి. హిందూ, సిక్కు, ముస్లింల సేనలను విచారించటం వలన కాంగ్రెస్, లీగ్లు సమైక్యంగా పోరాడాయి.ఘనత: సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ విజయాన్ని సాధించలేకపోయినా, ఆయన ధైర్యసాహసాలు దేశంలో చాలామందికి స్ఫూర్తినిచ్చాయి. ఆయన అచంచల దేశభక్తి, క్రమశిక్షణ, కార్యదీక్ష తరతరాల భారతీయులకు ఆదర్శప్రాయం."},{"question":"කාබන් සංයුතික ප්‍රතිරෝධක ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"මෙම ප්‍රතිරෝධවල අග්‍ර දෙක ඊයම් කබ්බියකින් යුත්තවන අතර ප්‍රතිරෝධයේ අගය වර්ණ කේත ක්‍රමයට සලකුණු කර ඇත.එහි අභ්‍යන්තරය කාබන් කුඩු අඩංගුකර ඇත.මෙම සංයුත්ක කාඉන් කුඩුවලට සෙරමික් වැනි පරිවාක ද්‍රව්‍ය මිශ්‍රකර ප්‍රතිරෝධය වැඩිකර ඇත.එයට හේතුව කාබන් යනු ඉතා හොද සන්නායකයක්වීමයි.මෙසේ කාබන් කුඩු අතරට පරිවාක ද්‍රව්‍ය එක්කිරීමෙන් ප්‍රතිරෝදීතාව පාලනය කලහැකිය.මෙම ප්‍රතිරෝධ අධික වෝල්ටීයතාවයන් හමුවේ පහසුවෙන් විනාශවීයයි.එසෙම අධිත ලෙස තාපය නිපදවීම මගින් ප්‍රතිරෝධකයේ ස්ථාවර ප්‍රතිරෝධය වෙනස්වේ.මෙම ප්‍රතිරෝධක විභව අන්තරය හා ධාරාව පාලනයකිරීම සදහා පරිපථවල යොදාගනී.මෙගා ඕම් 22 දක්වා අගයන්ගෙන් යුත් කාබන් සංයුක්ත ප්‍රතිරෝධ වෙළදපොලේ දක්නට ලැබේ.වර්තමානය වනවිට මෙම ප්‍රතිරෝධ භාවිතය ඉතා සීඝ්‍රෙයන් අඩුවී ඇත."},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny folo (10) Marsa fito amby sivifolo sy sivin - jato sy arivo (1997)?","answer":"Tamin' ny folo (10) Marsa fito amby sivifolo sy sivin - jato sy arivo (1997) dia nihaona ny filoha Didier Ratsiraka sy ny filoha frantsay \\"Jacques Chirac\\"."},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ kọmíṣọ́nà ọlọpa ni Ìpínlẹ̀ Akwa-Ibom ní ọdún 2023?","answer":"Ọlátóyè Dúrósinmí ni."},{"question":"UC Merced有哪些著名的校友？","answer":"答：由于UC Merced成立时间较短，其著名校友正在逐渐增加中。然而，许多毕业生已在科研、商业、政府等领域取得了显著的成就。"},{"question":"Enunciado 1: De esta población, el 87,91 % son rumanos, el 7,53 % húngaros y el 4,43 % romaníes.Enunciado 2: De su población, el 87,91 % son de origen húngaro, el 7,53 % de origen rumano y el 4,43 % de origen romaní.Pregunta: ¿El Enunciado 1 parafrasea al Enunciado 2? Responde Sí o No a la pregunta.","answer":"No, el Enunciado 1 no parafrasea al Enunciado 2."},{"question":"Catherine Zeta-Jones","answer":"Catherine Zeta-Jones, CBE, (oruko abiso Catherine Zeta Jones; 25 September 1969) je osere ara Welsi to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin Osere Keji Didarajulo ati Ebun Tony.Abi Catherine si Swansea, Arabinrin naa gbero lati jẹ óṣèrè lobinrin lati kekere nibi ti o ti kopa ninu Akojọpọ west end orin Annie ati Bugsy Malone. Nitoripè Catherine jẹ ọmọ to jafafa, iya rẹ ran lọ si Ilè ẹkọ Hazel Johnson to dale óri ijó nigba ti o pè ọmọ ọdun mẹrin. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa kẹkọ ni Ilẹ iwe Arts ni ilẹ london lori èrè oritage orin ti o si bẹrẹ sini kopa ni èrè oritage ni ọdun 1987 ninu èrè \\"42nd Street\\".Yatọsi jijẹ óṣèrè, arabinrin naa tun kopa ninu riran awọn alaini lọwọ. Óṣere naa jẹ Patron fun Longfields ilu Swansea to da lori awọn akanda. Catherine ta aṣọ ti ó wọ ninu ọkan ninu awọn ere rẹ \\"Mark of Zorro\\" lati fi kó òwó jọ fun awọn to ni arun kogbogun AID ni ilẹ Afirica. Zeta naa fẹ óṣere lọkunrin Michael Douglas ti o si bi ọmọ meji.Fun ikopa arabinrin naa ninu Chicago ti ọdun 2002, Zeta gba ami ẹyẹ ti óṣere screen guild ati ami ẹyẹ Bafta fun óṣèrè to rani lọwọ ju. Ni ọdun 2019, Catherine ni a fi jẹ̀ Ọgà Apaṣẹ ti British Empire latari óṣèrè ti o jẹ ati iran lọwọ fun alaini."},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la pregunta : ¿Cuántos presidentes estadounideses nacieron en Texas?.","answer":"La categoría corresponde a política. "},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:కం||| ధనమే మైత్రినిఁదెచ్చునుధనమే వైరమును దెచ్చు ధనమే సభలన్ఘనతను దెచ్చును నెంతటిగొనముల కుప్పలకునైన గువ్వలచెన్నా ! -గువ్వల చెన్న శతకం","answer":"ఓ గువ్వలచెన్నా ! ఎంత గొప్ప గుణవంతుల కైనా ధనమే స్నేహాన్ని పెంచుతుంది. డబ్బే విరోధం తెస్తుంది. సభలలో గొప్పతనాన్ని కూడా డబ్బే తెస్తుంది."},{"question":"Kiedy w Wielkiej Brytanii zaczęto wypłacać zasiłki dla dzieci?","answer":"Odpowiedź to: w 1975 r."},{"question":"Malawi ili ndi nyengo zingati?","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili mkati mwa madera otentha kwambiri. Dzikoli likukumana ndi nyengo zitatu; nthawi yozizira ndi yopanda mvula May mpaka August, kotentha ndi kopanda mvula kuyambira September mpaka pakati pa November ndi kotentha ndi konyowa kuyambira November mpaka April."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਜਾ ਕਉ ਅਪਨੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਧਾਰੈ ॥ਸੋ ਜਨੁ ਰਸਨਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਉਚਾਰੈ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਬਿਸਰਤ ਸਹਸਾ ਦੁਖੁ ਬਿਆਪੈ ॥ਸਿਮਰਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਭਰਮੁ ਭਉ ਭਾਗੈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਨੁ ਸੁਣੈ ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਨੁ ਗਾਵੈ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਜਨ ਦੂਖੁ ਨਿਕਟਿ ਨਹੀ ਆਵੈ ॥੨॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਟਹਲ ਕਰਤ ਜਨੁ ਸੋਹੈ ॥ਤਾ ਕਉ ਮਾਇਆ ਅਗਨਿ ਨ ਪੋਹੈ ॥੩॥ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਮੁਖਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦਇਆਲ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਤਜੀਅਲੇ ਅਵਰਿ ਜੰਜਾਲ ॥੪॥੫੨॥੧੨੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 190 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਪਰ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਭੀ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਸ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਆਪਣੀ) ਜੀਭ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਉਚਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਭੁਲਾਇਆਂ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦਾ) ਸਹਮ-ਦੁੱਖ (ਆਪਣਾ) ਜ਼ੋਰ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹ(ਪਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਹਰੇਕ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਨੱਠ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਸੁਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ(ਕੋਈ) ਦੁੱਖ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁੱਕਦਾ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ-ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ(ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੋਹ ਸਕਦੀ (ਉਸ ਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ ਸਾੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ) ।੩।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਦਇਆ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ) ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੰਜਾਲ ਲਾਹ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੫੨।੧੨੧।\\""},{"question":"Sheeg Meydka Kaliya Ee Aan La-Dhaqin?","answer":"Meydka Kaliya Ee Aan Ladhaqin Waa Meydka Shahiidka"},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Ever Funniest Airplane: Мультфильмдердин унааларына окшогон италиялык Caproni Stipa прототиби. Тарыхтагы эң күлкүлүү учак ."},{"question":"ਮੇਰੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਦੰਦਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਖਾਣਾ ਫਸਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਰਮਿੰਦੀ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਾਣ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਇਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਰਮਿੰਦੀ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਈ।"},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :জিম্বাবুয়ের দল নির্বাচকমণ্ডলীর আহ্বায়ক গিভমোর মাকোনি ২০০৯ সাল থেকে আন্তর্জাতিক ক্রিকেট অঙ্গনে যোগসূত্র না থাকলেও মুপারিয়াকে ২০১৫","answer":"সালের ক্রিকেট বিশ্বকাপে ১৫-সদস্যের চূড়ান্ত দলের অন্যতম সদস্য হিসেবে তাকে অন্তর্ভুক্ত করেন। তবে, জিম্বাবুয়ে এ-দলের বাংলাদেশ সফরে মুপারিয়া দুই খেলায় ১৯.৩৩ গড়ে তিন উইকেট পেয়েছিলেন।"},{"question":"ਇਸ ਹੁਕਮ ਨੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਕੰਟਰੋਲ ਅਤੇ ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ਯੋਗ ਤੇ ਗ਼ੈਰ-ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ਯੋਗ  ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਰੇਖਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਚਰਚਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ।ਕਿੱਥੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ 'ਸ਼ੁੱਧੀ' ਲਈ ਸੈਕਸ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਵਾਇਤ ਹੈ?ਸੈਕਸ ਡੌਲ ਦੀ ਖਿੱਚ-ਧੂਹ: ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਮਾਨਸਿਕਤਾ?ਸੈਕਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ 'ਤੇ ਪਤਨੀ ਦਾ ਕਤਲ ।ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਭਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. 'ਤੇ ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰ ਉਦਾਹਰਣਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਝਾਤ -ਯੂਕੇ ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ ਯੂਕੇ ਵਿਚ ਥ੍ਰੈਸ਼ਹੋਲਡ (ਇੱਕ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਸਮਾਂ) ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨੂੰ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫ੍ਰੀ-ਟੂ-ਏਅਰ ਚੈਨਲ ਰਾਤ ਨੌਂ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਵੇਰ ਸਾਢੇ ਪੰਜ ਵਜੇ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰ ਜਾਂ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਢੁੱਕਵੀਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ। ਸੈਕਸ ਸੀਡੀ, ਸਿਆਸਤ ਤੇ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਮਰਿਆਦਾ।ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਪੋਰਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਇਹ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਜਾਣਨੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹਨ।ਪ੍ਰੀਮੀਅਮ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਲਈ, ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ ਰਾਤ ਅੱਠ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਸਵੇਰੇ ਛੇ ਵਜੇ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਨਿਯਮ ਉਸ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ 'ਤੇ ਵੀ ਲਾਗੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਾਲ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਆਦਿ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਯੂਕੇ ਕਮਿਊਨੀਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਰੈਗੂਲੇਟਰ ਆਫ਼ ਕਾਮ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਹੋਏ ਇੱਕ ਸਰਵੇਖਣ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ 74% ਆਮ ਜਨਤਾ ਅਤੇ 78% ਮਾਪੇ ਵਿਸਵਾਸ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ 9 ਵਜੇ ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ ਜਾਂ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਲਈ ਸਹੀ ਸਮਾਂ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ 9 ਵਜੇ ਦੇ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ, ਘਰੇਲੂ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਦੇਖਣ ਯੋਗ ਹੋਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ। ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, \\"ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸੰਵੇਦਨਸ਼ੀਲ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ।\\"ਯੂ ਐਸ ਏ ਸੇਫ ਹਾਰਬਰ:ਯੂਨਾਈਟਿਡ ਸਟੇਟਸ ਫੈਡਰਲ ਕਮਿਊਨੀਕੇਸ਼ਨਜ਼ ਕਮਿਸ਼ਨ (ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ) ਨੇ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਲਈ ਨਿਯਮ ਨਿਰਧਾਰਿਤ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ।ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ. ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਰਾਤ ਦਸ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਵੇਰ ਛੇ ਵਜੇ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।'ਕੀ ਖਤਰਾ ਹੈ ਨੀਲੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇਖਣ ਨਾਲ' ।ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਘੰਟਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ 'ਸੁਰੱਖਿਅਤ ਹਾਰਬਰ ਘੰਟੇ' (ਸੇਫ ਹਾਰਬਰ ਆਵਰ) ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ. ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮ 'ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ' ਨੂੰ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਣਸੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਿਲ ਹੈ। ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਭਾਸ਼ਣ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਸੋਧ (ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਵੇ ਦੀ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ) ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਅਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।\\"ਐੱਫ.ਸੀ. ਸੀ. ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਕਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਮੀਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜਿਸ ਸਮਾਜ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਸੇਵਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਯਕੀਨੀ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਟੇਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰ ਗਲਤ ਜਾਂ ਗੁੰਮਰਾਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਾ ਹੋਣ।\\" ਐੱਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ. ਮੈਰਿਟ ਆਧਾਰ 'ਤੇ ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ਯੋਗ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਜਵਾਬ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਪੋਰਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਇਹ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਜਾਣਨੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹਨ।ਕੰਡੋਮ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰ꞉ ਕੰਡੋਮ ਤੋਂ ਸੌਫਟ ਪੋਰਨ ਤੱਕ।ਚਾਈਨਾ ਚੀਨ ਨੇ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਅਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਹਨ।ਬ੍ਰੌਡਕਾਸਟਿੰਗ  ਦੇ ਆਰਟਿਕਲ 32 ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਇਸੇ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੈ।ਕਨੂੰਨ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਟੀਵੀ ਸਟੇਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ 'ਤੇ ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਲਗਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ ਜੋ \\"ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲਤਾ, ਅੰਧ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਜਾਂ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਚਲਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ।\\"ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਅਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਹੋਰ ਕਈ ਸ਼ਰਤਾਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਟੀਵੀ ਜਾਂ ਰੇਡੀਓ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਕੰਟਰੋਲ ਕਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਚੀਨ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਡੋਮ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਇਸ਼ਤੀਹਾਰਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਸੈਕਸ-ਸਬੰਧਤ ਉਤਪਾਦਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਕਨੂੰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Emi o ni arun Korona o, irọ lawọn to sọ bẹẹ n pa- Bọla Tinubu","answer":"Bi awuyewuye ti gba igboro kan pe Aṣiwaju Bọla Ahmed Tinubu ti ko arun Koronafairọọsi, tawọn eeyan si n gbe e kiri ni Oluranlọwọ ẹ nipa eto iroyin, Tunde Rahman, ti bọ sita bayii lati sọ pe iroyin irọ lasan ni.Ninu iroyin ọhun ti wọn n pin kiri ni wọn ti sọ pe orilẹ-ede France ni aisan ọhun de e mọlẹ si, ṣugbọn oluranlọwọ ẹ ti sọ pe ko ri bẹẹ rara, ilu London lo wa, ati pe aisan kankan ko ṣe e, ọkunrin oṣelu naa kan lọọ gba atẹgun nibẹ ni.Tunde Rahman fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe o ti fẹẹ to igba mẹẹẹdogun ti Bọla Tinubu ti ṣayẹwo arun Koronafairọọsi yii, ṣugbọn ti ko si lara ẹ rara.O ni, “Ni gbogbo igba ti Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu ba ti ri i pe oun ti ṣepade tabi wa laarin awọn eeyan to pọ lo maa n saaba ṣayẹwo ọhun, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ki i fi ibomu ẹ silẹ nigba kan.“Ju gbogbo ẹ lọ, arun Koronafairọọsi ko kọ lu Bọla Tinubu o, awọn to n wi bẹẹ, iroyin ẹlẹjẹ ni wọn n gbe kiri. Bẹẹ ni ko si ni France, bi wọn ṣe n gbe e ka, ilu London ni baba wa, nibi to ti n gba atẹgun alaafia sara, ko sohun kan bayii to ṣe wọn.”"},{"question":"Tânia Burity","answer":"Tânia Cefira Gomes Burity (tí wọ́n bí ní 28 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀sán, Ọdún 1978) jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin, olùgbéròyìn, atọ́kùn, àti afẹwàṣiṣẹ́ ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Àngólà.Wọ́n bí Burity ní ìlú Luanda, orílẹ̀-èdè Àngólà. Ó gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ́ ìgbéròyìn láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Instituto Médio de Economia de Luanda (IMEL) kí ó tó tún kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìmọ̀ ìbáraẹnisọ̀rọ̀ ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Instituto Superior Privado de Angola. Burity ti ṣe iṣẹ́ olùgbéròyìn bẹ́ẹ̀ ló sì ti ṣiṣẹ́ rí ní ilé-ìtajà ṣáájú kí ó tó bọ́ sídi iṣẹ́ òṣèré.Láti ọdún 2001 sí 2004, òun ni atọ́kùn ètò tẹlifíṣọ̀nù kan tí wọ́n pè ní Angola dá Sorte. Ní ọdún 2001, Burity kópa nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Vidas Ocultas. Ní ọdún tí ó tẹ̀le, ó kó ipa ọmọ akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ kan tí orúkọ rẹ̀ n jẹ́ Djamila nínu eré Reviravolta. Ní ọdún 2005, Burity kó ipa Cláudia nínu eré Sede de Viver. Láti ọdún 2005 sí ọdún 2006, ó kó ipa Eugénia nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù oníṣókí kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ 113. Òun ni olùkéde àti olóòtú ìròyìn fún ètò rédíò kan tí wọ́n pè ní Boa Noite Angola láti ọdún 2005 sí ọdún 2006. Ní ọdún 2007, òṣèrékùnrin kan tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń ṣe Fredy Costa ṣí ọwọ́ rẹ̀ lé Burity lórí, èyí tí ó mu láti má leè ṣiṣẹ́ fún oṣù méjì tí wọ́n sì dá ẹ̀wọ̀n oṣù mẹ́fà fún Costa náà.Ní ọdún 2009, Burity kó ipa Camila gẹ́gẹ́ bi olùṣòwò nínu eré Minha Terra, Minha Mãe. Láàrin ọdún 2010 sí 2012, òun ni olùkéde àti olùdarí ètò rédíò kan tí ó wà fún àwọn ọmọdé tí wọ́n pè ní Karibrinca na Rádio. Burity tún ti ṣiṣẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bi afẹwàṣiṣẹ́, ó sì ti ṣe atọ́kùn níbi ìdíje ẹwà Miss Luanda ti ọdún 2011. Ó kó ipa gẹ́gẹ́ bi agbani-nímọ̀ràn lóri ọ̀rọ̀ oge nínu eré kan ti ọdún 2012 tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Windeck. Ní ọdún 2014, ó tún ṣe atọ́kùn níbi ètò ìfihàn Big Brother Angola. Ní ọdún 2016, Burity ṣe alága ìgbìmọ̀-onígbẹ̀ẹ́jọ́ fún ètò Casting JC Models àti Casting para Actores Agência Útima.Ọmọìyá rẹ̀ ni Dicla Burity, ẹni tí òun náà n ṣiṣẹ́ atọ́kùn ètò tẹlifíṣọ̀nù.[6] Ìlú Lisbon ni Tânia Burity fi ṣe ìbùgbé, ó sì ti ní àwọn ọmọbìnrin méjì"},{"question":"Wahala ẹgbẹ APC n le si i l’Ondo","answer":"Lati nnkan bii ọsẹ diẹ sẹyin ni nnkan ko ti fara rọ rara nile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ondo pẹlu bawọn aṣofin ọhun ṣe pin si meji latari wahala to n waye laarin Gomina Rotimi Akeredolu ati Igbakeji rẹ, Ọnarebu Ajayi Agboọla.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ni gbogbo nnkan dojuru mọ awọn aṣofin mẹrindinlọgbọn naa lọwọ, ti wọn ko si ti i ri kinni ọhun yanju titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii. Mẹrinla ninu wọn lo fọwọ siwee, ti wọn fẹẹ yọ Igbakeji gomina, Agboọla Ajayi, nipo, tawọn mẹsan-an, ninu eyi ti Igbakeji abẹnugan, olori awọn ọmọ ile to pọ ju lọ, ati olori awọn ọmọ ile to kere ju lọ kọ lati buwọ lu iwe iyọninipo ọhun.Ko jọ ija, ko jọ ariwo, ni wọn fi pari ijokoo wọn lọjọ naa, bi wọn si ṣe n pari ipade lawọn aṣofin to n ṣatilẹyin fun igbakeji gomina ti sare kọwe si adajọ agba ipinlẹ Ondo, Abilekọ Oluwatoyin Ọlanrewaju Akeredolu, pe awọn ko lọwọ ninu igbesẹ ti awọn ẹlẹgbẹ awọn fẹẹ gbe lati yọ Ajayi nipo. Wọn fi kun un pe awọn ti hu u gbọ pe awọn ẹgbẹ awọn kan n gbero lati jawee gbele ẹ fun awọn mẹsẹẹsan-an, ki wọn le lanfaani lati mu erongba wọn sẹ.Afi bii ẹni pe awọn aṣofin naa ti mọ ohun to fẹẹ ṣẹlẹ nitori pe asiko ti wọn tun pada jokoo lọjọ keji ti i ṣe Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ni wọn kede jija iwe gbele-ẹ fun mẹta ninu awọn aṣofin to ta ko iyọnipo Igbakeji gomina. Awọn mẹtẹẹta tọrọ kan ni: Ọnarebu Irọju Ogundeji to jẹ Igbakeji abẹnugan, ẹni to n ṣoju awọn eeyan ijọba ibilẹ Odigbo kin-in-ni, Adewale Williams Adewinlẹ, to n ṣoju awọn eeyan ijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo keji, ati Abilekọ Favour Ṣemilore Tomomẹwọ, lati ijọba ibilẹ Ilajẹ keji.Lati igba naa si lawuyewuye yii ti n tẹsiwaju, ti ko si ti i dawọ duro titi di asiko ta a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ lọwọ.Wahala eyi ni wọn n wa bi wọn yoo ṣe yanju rẹ ti Alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC nijọba ibilẹ Ẹsẹ Odo, Ọgbẹni Samuel Ọlọrunwa fi kọwe fipo silẹ, to si lọọ darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP pẹlu awọn alatilẹyin rẹ.ALAROYE gbiyanju lati ba awọn aṣofin tọrọ kan sọrọ. Igbakeji abẹnugan ile, Ọnarebu Irọju Ogundeji, toun naa jẹ ọkan lara awọn ti wọn jawee gbele-ẹ fun ṣalaye pe “Ohun tawọn ẹlẹgbẹ mi ṣe lodi patapata si ohun ti ofin sọ nitori pe iwe ofin orilẹ-ede yii, tọdun 1999 ti ṣe alakalẹ igbesẹ ti wọn fi n yọ gomina tabi igbakeji rẹ nipo.“Ko si ninu pe ka fi agbara mu eyikeyii ninu awọn aṣofin lati lọwọ ninu igbesẹ iyọninipo, o wa lori bi ọkan ẹni ọhun ba ṣe fẹ ni.“Mi o ri idi kankan to fi yẹ ki wọn yẹ aga mọ Ọnọrebu Ajayi nidii, ohun to si ṣokunfa idi ti mi o fi ba wọn kọwọ bọwe iyọnipo rẹ niyẹn.“Mo kilọ fun Abẹnugan ile, Ọnarebu Bamidele Ọlẹyẹlogun, pe ko ma darapọ mọ awọn eeyan lati huwa aitọ, ṣugbọn o ṣe ni laaanu pe ko gba si mi lẹnu.“Loootọ lo pe mi laaarọ kutukutu ọjọ ta a kọkọ fẹẹ bẹrẹ ijokoo, to si sọ fun mi pe gomina ati alaga ẹgbẹ APC nipinlẹ Ondo ti pasẹ foun lati bẹrẹ igbesẹ yiyọ Ọnarebu Ajayi kuro nipo igbakeji gomina.“Ọnarebu Ọlẹyẹlogun gba mi nimọran lati ma ṣe yọju sile-igbmọ lọjọ naa, o ni wọn ti paṣẹ fawọn ẹṣọ alaabo pe wọn ko gbọdọ jẹ ki n wọle.“Bo ṣe to akoko ti ipade fẹẹ bẹrẹ ni mo mori le ọna ile aṣofin, mo n reti ọlọpaa ti yoo da mi duro lati lọọ ṣe ojuṣe tawọn eeyan mi tori rẹ dibo fun mi.“O ba mi ninu jẹ pe Abẹnugan ile pada jiṣẹ ti wọn ran an lai ri ẹsun kan gboogi ka si wa lẹsẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn ko fun wa lanfaani lati sọ tẹnu wa ki wọn too jawe gbele-ẹ fun wa.“Ẹbẹ mi si ijọba apapọ ni pe ki wọn tete gbe igbesẹ ati gbe eto inawo gbogbo ile-igbimọ aṣofin to wa lorilẹ-ede yii kuro labẹ ijọba ipinlẹ, ki wọn si gbiyanju ati fun wọn lominira ti wọn n beere fun.“Igbesẹ yii nikan lo le gba awọn aṣofin kuro labẹ ajaga buruku tawọn gomina n fi wọn si.Ọrọ iyọninipo yii tun gbọna mi-in yọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja pẹlu bi Abilekọ Akeredolu to jẹ adajọ agba ipinlẹ Ondo ṣe kọ lati gba iwe iyọninipo tawọn aṣofin fi ṣọwọ si i wọle.Ọga awọn adajọ ọhun ni awọn aṣofin naa gbọdọ tẹle ohun ti ofin sọ ko too di pe oun bẹrẹ igbesẹ lori ṣiṣagbekalẹ igbimọ ẹlẹni meje ti yoo ṣewadii ẹsun ti wọn fi kan igbakeji gomina ti wọn fẹẹ yọ nipo.Iroyin ta a gbọ lati ijọba ibilẹ Ariwa/Iwọ-Oorun Akoko ni pe awọn agbaagba ẹgbẹ kan ti ko ara wọn jọ lati ta ko bi Ọnarebu Suleiman Jamiu Maito to jẹ olori awọn ọmọ ile to pọ ju lọ tẹlẹ ṣe kọ lati ṣatilẹyin fun Gomina Akeredolu lori igbesẹ yiyọ igbakeji rẹ nipo.Awọn agba ẹgbẹ ọhun sọ ninu iwe kan ti wọn fọwọ si pe ki i ṣe iṣẹ ti wọn ran ọkunrin naa lo lọọ jẹ nile-igbimọ aṣofin, wọn ni iṣẹ ara rẹ lo n jẹ pẹlu bo ṣe n ṣegbe lẹyin Ajayi lasiko ti wọn fẹẹ yọ ọ nipo.Bakan naa si lọrọ ri nijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo pẹlu bawọn asaaju ẹgbẹ APC kan ṣe kọwọ bọwe pe awọn fẹẹ pe Ọnarebu Adewale Williams Adewinlẹ pada fun bo ṣe fi gomina silẹ, to n ṣatilẹyin fun igbakeji rẹ.Ko ti i sẹni to mọ ibi ti wahala to n lọ ninu ẹgbẹ APC ipinlẹ Ondo yii yoo ja si nitori bi wọn ṣe n bọ ninu wahala kan ni wọn n ko sinu omi-in."},{"question":"SIDEE U HAQIIJIN KARTAA HADAFKAAGA AMA GANACSIGAG","answer":"Guul  ganacsi inta badan waxaa lagu gaaraa go’aan adag, geesinimo iyo in aad wax ka barato dadka waayo aragnimada buuxda u leh arirmaha ganacsiga,  islamarkaana hirgaliyay ganacsiyada horumarka gaaray ama guuleystay . Haddaba, Haddii aad doonayso in aad ganacsi horumar leh samayso waa in aad tixgalisaa talooyinka dadka waayoaragnimada leh ee soo arkay loolanka ganacsiga iyo horumarkiisa. Halkaan waxaan idinkugu soo gudbin doonana qaar ka mid ah talooyinka ugu muhiimsan ee laga dhaxlay qaar ka mid ah ganacsatada ugu taajirsan dunida,Waxaana ka mid ah :Naftaada loolan gali – Richard Branson oo ah ninka aasaasay shirkada Virgin ee caanka ah ayaa ku talinaya in qofka doonaya in uu ganacsi abuuro uu diyaar u noqdo in uu loolan joogto ah galiyo naftiisa. Waxa uu aaminsanyahay in noloshu ay tahay waxbarasho joogto ah oo aad maalinkasta wax-cusub barato.Qabo shaqo aad jeceshahay –  Steve Jobs oo ahaa ninkii horumarka weyn gaarsiiyay shirkadda Apple ayaa ku talin jiray in dadka dhalinyarada ah ay sameeyaan ganacsiyo aysan lacag darteed keliya u abuurin balse ay sameeyaan ganacsi la xiriira waxyaabaha ay jecelyihiin si ay ugu raaxaystaan.U barrer Qatarta – Jeﬀ Bezos oo ah agaasimaha Amazon waxa uu leeyahay in aadan waligaa ogaanayn qiimaha ﬁkradaada ilaa aad tijaabiso. Waxa uu sheegay in aad ka shalaaynayso in aadan tijaabin , halkii aad ka shalaayi lahayd fashilka. Waayo fashilkaas cashar ayaad ka qaadanaysaa balse ﬁkrad aadan tijaabin waxba kama faa’idaysid. Aragti lahoow– Agaasimaha Tumblr oo lagu magacaabo David Karp ayaa aaminsan in ganacsadaha halabuurka leh uu yahay mid aragti-dheer leh oo ay u caddahay waxyaabaha uu doonayo in uu sameeyo iyo sida uu ku gaarayo hadafkiisa.Naftaada aamin – Henry Ford oo ahaa ninkii aasaasay shirkada baabuurta ee Ford ayaa laga soo wariyay in uu yiri ” Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad wax samayn karto iyo haddii aad aamisantahay in aadan samayn Karin, Labadaba waa ku saxsantahay” Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad guuleysanayo, waad helaysaa wadooyinkii aad ku guuleysan lahayd balse haddii  aadan aaminsanayn waxaad helaysaa marmarsiiyo aad ku guuldaraysato."},{"question":"கேள்வி: பறவைகள்வானில் பறந்து சென்றன. இதில் வான் என்பதன் வேறு பெயர் என்ன?அ) நிலத்தில்ஆ) விசும்பில்இ) மரத்தில்ஈ) நீரில்","answer":"பதில்: ஆ) விசும்பில்குறிப்பு:          ஐம்பூதங்களில் ஒன்றே வானம் ஆகும். வானம் என்பது பூமியின் மேற்பரப்பில் குறிப்பிட்ட எல்லைக்கு அப்பால் விரிந்து காணப்படும் அனைத்தையும் உள்ளடக்கிய பரந்த வெளியை குறிக்கும். இது வளிமண்டலத்திற்கு அப்பால் உள்ள விண்வெளியையும் குறிக்கும். வானியலில் வானமானது “வானக்கோளம்” எனவும் அழைக்கப்படுகின்றது. வானம் என்பது கற்பனையானது என்றும் அதில் சூரியன், சந்திரன், விண்மீன் போன்றவை நிறுத்தி வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன என்று அறிஞர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.  இருப்பினும் வானம் என்பது இன்றியமையாதது இதனாலையே இந்துக்கள் சிதம்பரத்தை வானத்திற்கு உரிய தலமாக கொண்டு வழிபடுகின்றனர். அங்குள்ள இறைவனின் பெயர் ஆகாச லிங்கம் ஆகும். இவ்வாறு சிறப்புடைய வானத்திற்கு வேறு பல பெயர்கள் வழங்கப்படுகின்றன.வானம் வேறு பெயர்கள்:வானத்தின் நிறம்வானம் வேறு பெயர்கள்அண்டம்ககனம்ஆகாயம்உம்பர்எமிலிககண்டுகார்கொண்டல்சேண்நிருபம்மஞ்சுவிசும்புவிண்ஆகாயம்அத்திட்டம்மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள்வானம்:இந்த வெளியிலே சூரியன், நிலா, விண்மீன்கள், முகில், வானவில், வடமுனை ஒளி என்பன வானத்தில் காணக்கூடிய இயற்கையான சில தோற்றப்பாடுகளாகும். பொழிவு (வானிலையியல்), மின்னல் என்பனவும் வானத்துடன் தொடர்புடைய தோற்றங்களே ஆகும்.வானத்தின் நிறம்:     பகலில், முகில்களற்ற வானம் இருக்கையில் சூரியன் தெரியும். அத்துடன் முகில்களற்ற வானம் நீல நிறமாக இருக்கும். இதற்குக் காரணம் வளிமண்டலத்தில் இருக்கும் வளிமம் ஆகும். சூரிய ஒளியிலிருந்து வரும் வெவ்வேறு நிறங்களில், நீல நிற ஒளியை அதிகமாக சிதறடிக்கின்றது. நீல நிறத்தை விடவும் அலைநீளம் குறைவான ஊதா, கருநீலம் ஆகிய நிறங்கள் அதிகமாகச் சிதறடிக்கப்பட்டாலும், நமது கண்களில், குறிப்பிட்ட நிறக் கதிர்களைப் பெற்றுக் கொள்ளுவதற்கான உணர்திறன் குறைவாக இருப்பதனால் நீல நிறமே, பார்வையில் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்துகின்றது.அந்தி நேரத்தில், அல்லது அதிகாலை வேளைகளில் சூரியன் மிகவும் தூரத்திலும், ஒரு சாய்விலும் இருப்பதனால், சிதறடிக்கப்படும் நீல ஒளி வேறு திசைக்குச் சென்றுவிடும். எனவே வானம், மஞ்சள் அல்லது செம்மஞ்சள் நிறத்தில் இருக்கும்.இரவில் சூரிய ஒளி இன்மையால், வானம் இருண்ட நிறத்தில் தெரியும். இரவில் நமது பார்வையில், பிரகாசமான சூரிய ஒளியின் குறுக்கீடு இல்லாமல், சூரியனின் ஒளி விண்மீன்கள், கோள்கள், நிலா போன்றவற்றில் பட்டுத் தெறிப்பதால், நம்மால் அவற்றைப் பார்க்கக் கூடியதாக இருக்கும்.ஆனால், பகலிலோ, இரவிலோ, முகில்கள் வானத்தில் இருப்பின், முகிலினால் ஏற்படும் மறைப்பினால், சூரியனையோ, ஏனைய விண்மீன்கள், கோள்கள், நிலாவையோ நம்மால் பார்க்க முடியாது.இவ்வாறு சிறப்புடைய வானம் பற்றி பல அறிசஞர்கழ் தம் பாடல்களில் பாடி உள்ளனர். எனவே இயற்கை அன்னையின் கொடையான வானம் மேன்மையானது எனலாம்."},{"question":"El Reino Unido evacúa a sus ciudadanos de Libia, no sólo Trípoli ha sido escenario de combates. Bengasi, en el noreste del país también ha sido afectada por la violencia.Un barco británico va rumbo a Trípoli para evacuar a los ciudadanos británicos e irlandeses atrapados en los combates.Más de 200 personas han muerto por la violencia durante las últimas dos semanas. Sólo el fin de semana 20 personas murieron en los enfrentamientos entre milicias rivales que luchan por el control del aeropuerto internacional.Otra de las ciudades afectadas por la violencia es Bengasi. ","answer":"Personal de la embajada británica en Libia fueron evacuados el domingo, tras el aumento de la violencia entre milicias en la capital libia, Trípoli."},{"question":"قام سيدنا عثمان بن عفان رضي الله عنه بتجميع القرآن فمتى قام بذلك ؟\\t","answer":"العام 25 هجري"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini?  Banyak-banyak itik, itik apa yang boleh berjalan dengan dua kaki?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah semua itik"},{"question":"Fill in the Blanks:1۔ سعودی عرب کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟2۔ پاکستان کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟3۔ امریکہ کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟Return the answer in the following JSON format:\`\`\`json{Questions: [], Answers: []}\`\`\`","answer":"\`\`\`json{    \\"Questions\\": [        \\"سعودی عرب کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟\\",        \\"پاکستان کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟\\",        \\"امریکہ کا دار الحکومت ____ ہے؟\\",    ]        \\"Answers\\": [        \\"سعودی عرب کا دار الحکومت ریاض ہے\\",        \\"پاکستان کا دار الحکومت اسلام آباد ہے\\",        \\"امریکہ کا دار الحکومت واشنگٹن ڈی سی ہے\\"    ]}\`\`\`"},{"question":"ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੇ ਜੋੜੇ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਈ ਦਿੱਤੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਜੋੜੇ ਨੇ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵੱਖ ਹੋ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਜੋੜੇ ਨੇ ਘੋਸ਼ਣਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਬੱਚਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਜੋੜੇ ਨੇ ਘੋਸ਼ਣਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਬੱਚਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Gia thế khủng của tay đấm độc cô cầu bại","answer":"Có 3 con người luôn dõi theo sát nút từng bước chân của Nguyễn Trần Duy Nhất, trong đó có võ sĩ từng được phong là hổ xám thập kỷ 90 là Tấn Nhất Duy, quê ở tỉnh Quảng Ngãi. Ông Duy từng dìu dắt và dạy cháu trai theo kiểu vô chiêu. Trong trận thi đấu tại sân Quy Nhơn, tỉnh Nghĩa Bình (nguyên là tỉnh Quảng Ngãi và Bình Định) vào năm 1985, võ sĩ Minh Cảnh, nhà vô địch quyền Anh của Đông Dương giật mình vì nghe danh Tấn Nhất Duy đã lâu, nhưng không ngờ đánh quá dữ. Khi so găng với võ sĩ Trần Hoàng từ Sài Gòn ra, mới vô hiệp một thì võ sĩ này đã bị Tấn Nhất Duy lướt tới gạt đỡ vài đòn, sau đó quật ngã xuống sàn và trọng tài đếm tới 10, sau đó cho thắng knock out. Dân chơi võ kháo nhau rằng, Trần Hoàng là con của võ sư, sao lại bị đánh rớt quá nhanh, có thể là may rủi. Vậy là 2 võ sĩ lại tiếp tục so găng, nhưng tới hiệp 2 thì cú ra đòn khủng khiếp của Tấn Nhất Duy tiếp tục hạ knock out võ sĩ Trần Hoàng. Năm 1986, võ sĩ Tấn Nhất Duy (tên thật là Nguyễn Trần Duy, sinh năm 1962), hạng cân 57-60 kg tự dưng biến mất khỏi sàn thi đấu tự do ở trong nước. Người hâm mộ võ thuật miền Nam thời đó đoán già đoán non về việc có thể Tấn Nhất Duy đã vượt biển ra nước ngoài. Thời đó chưa có internet và điện thoại phổ biến như bây giờ, vì vậy người ta hay hỏi về Tấn Nhất Duy trong các buổi chợ, quán nước vỉa hè. Tại Quảng Ngãi, các ông bầu chuyên tổ chức các trận đánh đài như Bùi Tá Xuất, Khương Trí Đổng, Huỳnh Long Hổ… tỏ vẻ tiếc nuối, vì không có Tấn Nhất Duy thì việc kinh doanh, bán vé cho người tới xem đấu võ sẽ sụt giảm doanh số. Vì sao võ sĩ Tấn Nhất Duy lại được người hâm mộ săn đón và dõi theo như một diva hiện nay như vậy? Bởi tới thời điểm 1986, võ sĩ này được ví như hổ xám, đã thi đấu gần 200 trận võ tự do, nhưng chưa thua một trận nào. Ở khắp các tỉnh, thành từ Hà Nội, Thừa Thiên Huế, Quảng Nam, Đà Nẵng, Khánh Hòa… những trận có Tấn Nhất Duy thi đấu thì cả sân bãi nổi sóng và các ông bầu cảm thấy vui vì vé bán hết sạch. Trước thời đổi mới, các ông bầu kinh doanh võ thuật thường liên kết với địa phương để tổ chức, tăng thu ngân sách. Sau hơn 35 năm ngồi đúc kết chuyện đời võ thuật, câu trả lời của Tấn Nhất Duy đã khiến tôi nhận ra, đó là \\"vô chiêu\\". Anh thường sử dụng đòn nào tốt nhất? Khi tôi hỏi, Tấn Nhất Duy dừng lại hồi lâu rồi mới nói rằng, phải biến hóa, phải học hỏi rất nhiều thứ và mỗi trận, mỗi đối thủ thì mình đều có những chiêu thức khác nhau - gối, cỏ, rờ ve, đá phang… nhờ đó mới hạ được các đối thủ nặng ký. Sự biến mất của võ sĩ Tấn Nhất Duy vào năm 1986 do có những biến cố khó nói. Sau năm 1990, võ sĩ Tấn Nhất Duy đổi tên họ và phiêu dạt vào thi đấu ở các tỉnh phía Nam. Bên cạnh việc thi đấu võ, anh còn dành thời gian về chăm sóc cha là võ sư Tấn Diêu. Ông Diêu được vận động đưa gia đình lên cơ sở 2 của tỉnh Quảng Ngãi và được gọi là đi kinh tế mới. Tại huyện Cát Tiên, tỉnh Lâm Đồng, khi vừa hạ trại, làm chuồng gà, làm vài luống rau xong là ông Diêu đã bắt đầu dạy võ cùng 2 người con trai là Tấn Phi Diệu và Tấn Nhất Duy. Võ sĩ Tấn Phi Diệu lấy vợ là võ sĩ Minh Ánh Ngọc, thuộc võ đường Lữ Gia ở thành phố Nha Trang, tỉnh Khánh Hòa. Từ đó, ngôi nhà nằm ngay ngã 3 xã Quảng Ngãi, huyện Cát Tiên trở thành trung tâm rèn võ thuật bởi 4 con người, trong đó có võ sĩ hổ xám Tấn Nhất Duy. Năm 1989, vợ chồng võ sĩ Tấn Phi Diệu sinh được người con trai đặt tên là Nguyễn Trần Duy Nhất. Khi bắt đầu là cậu bé hơn 1 tuổi, Nhất đã suốt ngày leo trèo, cố đu ra khỏi cũi. Cậu trở nên khác thường so với những đứa trẻ cùng trang lứa. Đó là cứ nhìn ra sân thấy các võ sĩ tập võ thì cậu cũng múa tay chân. Cả đám đông thấy cậu nhảy nhót và múa may thì cũng đồng thanh cổ vũ \\"múa võ đi\\". Cậu Nhất khi lớn lên được học võ cùng một lúc 4 người, đó là ông nội là võ sư Tấn Diêu; học từ cha và mẹ, bên cạnh đó là chú ruột Tấn Nhất Duy. Võ sư Tấn Diêu thời còn sống đã nói rằng \\"thằng Nhất cháu của ông nó học được cách đánh của người cha là sự khôn ngoan, nhưng nó học được sự dũng mãnh ở người chú là Tấn Nhất Duy, lối đánh của nó chưa chắc bằng chú, nhưng mà cũng ảnh hưởng nhiều; bên cạnh đó là niềm tự hào về người chú bất bại cũng giúp cháu nhanh trưởng thành hơn\\". Võ sĩ Tấn Nhất Duy không kể về việc mình dạy võ cho cháu ra sao, anh chỉ nói rằng, \\"những trận đấu quan trọng thì chú có mặt, động viên, săn sóc, góp ý, sửa cho cháu, mình từng thi đấu khắp nơi trong nước, nhưng mong cháu được ra thi đấu quốc tế để làm rạng danh dòng họ 4 đời nghiệp võ\\". Giữa tháng 7/2022, võ sĩ vang bóng một thời Tấn Nhất Duy lại đưa gia đình từ Lâm Đồng về thăm lại quê hương Quảng Ngãi và gặp các đồng môn. Suốt mấy chục năm qua, ông vẫn dõi theo võ thuật và rút ra những điều chiêm nghiệm về võ để chia sẻ với lớp trẻ. Ông cho biết, nhiều người nghĩ đất võ là Bình Định, nhưng đó là miền đất có nền văn hóa võ thuật từ lâu đời với hệ thống môn phái đặc sắc. Còn Quảng Ngãi cũng chính là đất võ, nhưng các võ sĩ Quảng Ngãi chỉ tập trung vào một hướng duy nhất, đó là võ đối kháng, võ tự do, lên đài thi đấu và hãy tìm kiếm kết quả cuối cùng là \\"chiến thắng\\". Người cháu của ông là Nguyễn Trần Duy Nhất cũng chọn cách thức này - đi từ võ cổ truyền, sang Muay Thái, sau đó trở thành nhà vô địch thế giới, võ sĩ độc cô cầu bại. Có một thời, võ sĩ Quảng Ngãi làm mưa gió trên các sàn đài, soán luôn ngôi vị số 1 của kinh đô võ thuật thành phố Hồ Chí Minh. Thời điểm tỉnh Quảng Ngãi và Bình Định chưa tách tỉnh và còn chung 1 tỉnh Nghĩa Bình, chiếm 80% đội tuyển võ thuật trẻ của tỉnh là giới võ sĩ đến từ quê hương Quảng Ngãi. Tấn Nhất Duy không nói nhiều về việc truyền dạy cho cháu chiêu gì, nhưng anh đã truyền lại tinh thần \\"vô pháp vi pháp\\". Giống như chuyện anh nói về diện mạo của võ thuật Quảng Ngãi là \\"quyền thuật tự do\\". Giống như quan điểm của Lý Tiểu Long khi trả lời báo chí ở khu phố Tàu Los Angeles rằng: \\"Phải nhắm đến tính hiệu quả, không lệ thuộc quá đáng vào tính hình thức; đơn giản và trực tiếp\\". Khi lập ra môn phái Triệt Quyền đạo, Lý Tiểu Long cũng khái niệm về môn võ này bằng 2 từ \\"tự do\\"."},{"question":"Ẹya yoowu to ba fẹẹ yapa kuro ni Naijiria n wa iparun ni-Pasitọ Iyunade","answer":"Olori ijọ Pentecostal Sanctuary Bible Ministries (PSBM) Odo-Ẹgbọ, n’Ijebu Ode, Pasitọ Sunday Dare Iyunade, ti sọ pe ẹya yoowu to ba gbe igbesẹ lati yapa kuro lara Naijiria yoo parun ni, nitori Ọlọrun ko fọwọ si igbesẹ bẹẹ.‘Ọlọrun sọ pe bi ẹyakẹya, boya Igbo, Yoruba tabi Hausa, ba gbiyanju lati kuro lara Naijiria, ibi ti wọn fi ṣe ibugbe yoo di itan ni’’ Bẹẹ ni Pasitọ Iyunade wi fawọn akọroyin lọsẹ to kọja yii.Pasitọ yii sọ pe eyi tawọn eeyan kan fi n beere fun ipinya yii, adura lo yẹ ki wọn maa gba si i kikankikan, pe ki orilẹ-ede yii ma pin, o ni nitori ipinya yoo mu abamọ ati iṣoro wa ni.Ni ti ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progressives Party (APC) to n ṣejọba lọwọ, Pasitọ Iyunade sọ pe o ṣee ṣe kawọn ọmọ Naijiria sọ wọn loko laipẹ lati le wọn kuro lori aleefa, gẹgẹ bawọn funra wọn ṣe wi nigba ti wọn n polongo ibo lọdun 2014, pe bawọn ko ba ṣe daadaa, kawọn ọmọ Naijiria le awọn loko.Lori idi ti eyi yoo fi ri bẹẹ, Olori ijọ PSMB naa sọ pe gbogbo ileri tawọn APC ṣe faraalu nigba naa ni wọn ti kọyin si, ti wọn ko mu wọn ṣẹ rara. O tẹsiwaju pe Ọlọrun ti tilẹkun mọ ijọba Buhari, idi niyẹn ti wọn ko fi ri aṣeyọri ṣe, o ni bawọn Kristẹni ko ba tẹpẹlẹ mọ adura, nnkan yoo wulẹ maa le si i ni.Eto aabo to dojuru naa wa ninu ohun ti pasitọ yii ṣalaye, Iyunade sọ pe ogiri aabo ti wo lulẹ ni Naijiria, ṣugbọn o ni kawọn eeyan ma sọ ireti nu, nitori Oluwa ti sọ pe oun yoo fi opin si iṣejọba APC laipẹ, ijọba tuntun ti yoo laaanu awọn eeyan rẹ yoo de, ẹni ti yoo jẹ loun ko le sọ."},{"question":"የጣልያን ፋሺስት ጦር ኢትዮጵያን በ፲፱፻፳፰ ሲወር ንጉሠ ነገሥት ቀዳማዊ ኃይለ ሥላሴ ለተባበሩት መንግሥታት አባል ሀገራት አቤቱታ ያቀረቡት የት ነበር?","answer":"ጄኔቭ ስዊዘሪላንድ"},{"question":"Ady inona no namarana ny fanitarana an'i Napoleon Bonaparte tany Eoropa tamin'ny 1815?","answer":"Ny ady tao Waterloo tamin'ny 1815 dia namarana ny fanitarana an'i Napoleon Bonaparte tany Eoropa ary nitarika ny sesitany azy."},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: ഈ സംഭവം അറിഞ്ഞ് ഇ എം എസും ഇ കെ നായനാരും ഉൾപ്പെടെയുള്ള ജനനേതാക്കൾ ചീമേനിയിലെത്തി. ജാലിയൻവാലാബാഗിനു സമാനമാണ് സംഭവമെന്നാണ് ഇ എം എസ് പറഞ്ഞത്","answer":"ഈ വാചകം ജാലിയൻവാലാബാഗിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്. "},{"question":"Khabonina Qubeka","answer":"Khabonina Qubeka(bíi ni ọjọ́ kẹji lélógún, ọdún 1981) jẹ́ òṣèré, agbóhùnsáfẹ́fẹ́, oníjó àti olórin ni orílẹ̀ èdè South Áfríkà. Ní ọdún 2017, ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré bìnrin to dára jù lọ níbi ayẹyẹ Boston International Film Festival Awards, wọn si yàán kalẹ̀ fún ẹ̀bùn òṣèré bìnrin tó dára jù lọ níbi ayẹyẹ Florida Film Festival àti African Movie Academy Awards fun ipa Dora tó kó nínú eré Dora's Peace. Ní ọdún 2017, ó kó ipa Nínà Zamdela nínú eré Isindigo. Ó ṣe atọkun fún ètò Fix My Love tí ilé iṣẹ́ Bet gbé kalẹ̀, ó sì gbajúmọ̀ fún ipá Maxine tí ó kó nínú eré The Wild. Gẹ́gẹ́ bíi oníjó, ó ti ṣe atọkun àti adájọ́ fún oríṣiríṣi àwọn ètò ijó bíi Dance Your Butt Off, Step up or Step Out.Qubeka di gbajúmọ̀ fún ipá Doobsie tí ó kó nínú eré Muvhango ni ọdún 2006. Ó ti kopa ninu awọn eré bíi She is King ati Isidingo. Ní ọdún 2017, ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré bìnrin to dára jù lọ níbi ayẹyẹ Boston International Film Festival. Ni osu kewaa, ọdun 2017, o se atọkun fun eto ti won se fun awọn oluọ ni South Afrika."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake a wannan jumlar mai zuwa? \\"dan asalin liberia da ya zo Amurka gudun hijira ya zama magajin Garin helena a Jihar montana, Amurka\\":(a) Lafiya(b) Najeriya(c) Duniya(d) Siyasa(e) Afirka","answer":"  Jumlar \\"dan Asalin liberia da ya zo Amurka gudun hijira ya zama magajin garin helena a Jihar montana, Amurka\\" na batu ne a kan (c) Duniya."},{"question":"Wanene mawaki Shata Hausa?","answer":"Alhaji (Dr) Mamman Shata, MON, fitaccen mawaƙin Fulani ne na Najeriya wanda ya yi waƙa a cikin harshen Hausa. Tun yana matashi Mamman Shata ya halarci makarantar Islamiyya a Musawa, amma waka ta kasance abin shagaltuwa da wuri kuma ya kan yi wa abokansa waka. Mahaifinsa Ibrahim Yaro ya saba masa yana waka."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Rehefa nandany fotoana ela tao amin'ny maze aho dia nahita ny fivoahana.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Na dia very saina aza aho dia fantatro ny vahaolana.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Tsia, tsy mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"নিচের বাক্যটি পড় এবং প্রশ্নের উত্তর দাওকমলালেবু, লাল আপেল, হলুদ কলা এবং সবুজ তরমুজ রোদে শুয়ে ফলের বাজারটি বেশ সুন্দর লাগছিলপ্রশ্নফলের বাজারে কোন ফল বিক্রি হচ্ছে?","answer":"ফলের বাজারে বিক্রি হচ্ছে কমলা, আপেল, কলা ও তরমুজ"},{"question":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?","answer":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?Sheekooyinka Wiilwaal oo ay soomaalidu isu weriyaan waxaa kamid ah mar ayodayaal beeshiisa ah inta u yimaadeen isaga oo hurda ay ka xishoodeen inaykiciyaan, markii ay xaaskii Wiilwaal ka codsadeen inay u kiciso, inta dul istaagtayayay haraati ku kicisey. Xushmadda ay dumarku ku lahaayeen dhaqanka reerguuraaga soomaaliyeed, waxay ahayd mid muuqata xilli walba oo ay beeluhu kusugnaayeen. Arrintaasina waxaa laga garan karaa sida Raage Ugaas looga xaalmariyey xaaskiisii mar uu gabey wax uga sheegay. Raage, gabaygaas wuxuu kutilmaamayay falal uu quursadey oo uu gabadha ku arkey. Raage wuxuu yiri :-“Naa soow Xaliimaay Xadiyo xaalna kama raacdid,Naa soow dabkuba waa xurmee xaabo lama saaro,Naa soow ardaagaan xunka ah waana lama xaaqo,Naa soow xalid laguma dayo xeeradiyo dhiisha,Allahayoow xaraaraa anfaci xaleyto la´ isiiyey…”Aflagaaddada uu gabaygaas gaystey ayaa Raage waxaa lagu xukumay inuu gabadha siiyo kala bar magteedii oo dhan 50 halaad. Waxaa kale oo jirtey sheeko dhacdey mar Saahid Qamaan gabar uu jeclaa oo Mullaaxo la oran jiray uu nin xoolo badan leh ka qaaday. Qoyskii Saahid ayaa waxay u dooreen gabadhii qoyskooda ugu qurux badnayd si uu u illaawo Mullaaxo. Habeenkii markii gabadhii loo guri geeyay ayay gabadhii waxay istiri si uu ninku u illaawo gabadhuu jeclaa bal wax kasta oo uu uga samri karo u samee. Waxay ku dadaashay inay wax kasta oo uu jeclaysan karo horgeyso. Hufnaan sariireed, haybad dhago nugayl, haasaawe dabacsan, hooh gacanqabow, iyo heeh walaale waxaan ahayn kuma holliso. Gaarinnimo, gacalnimo,bilic gaammurtay, iyo xaal gobeed ayay gundhig uga dhigtay jeceylkeeda aangaamurin. Habeenkii danbe ayay iyada oo isleh ninku gabadhii hore ha illaawomaskaxdiisana kasaar, ayay waxay usoo dhigtay haruub si wanaagsan loo culayoo caano xoor lihi afkaa ka hayaan, waxayna soo raacisay luqmad ama oodkacay haweeney jari taqaan si wanaagsan ugu soo farayaraysatay, laguna soodaray neef yar oo xilli gu'ah jooga subaggiis, markaas ayay ku tiri, \\" Baashe balisku day xoogaagaan luqmadda ah, raallina ka noqo intaad caanaha lisiddoodasugaysay \\".  Dabadeed, inta dacalka maradeeda kusii jiidday ayay ku tiri, iskanadaa hammiga iyo walaaca aad la foorartid. Odaygii Saahid ahaa, afka ma saarinwixii cunto lasoo hordhigay. Markii ay tiri, \\" Saahid walaale maxaad cunnada uqaadan waydey, miyaad xanuunsan tahay?\\" Saahid wuxuu ku taamaygabaygaan, ay tixihiisa ka mid ahaayeen:-“…Haruub laban ah caanaha hoyaad halab karuurkeeda,Hilibka cusub haydaari iyo sogob la hoogaanshay,Habka fudud halkaan yeel ku oran hagar la'aantaada,Habkaad igu baayici kabahaad howda kaga yeerin,Haween baad tahee adiga oon hadin kobtaan joogo,Waa habbi la'aan dhuunigaad hoo ileedahaye,Hindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye,Haasaawahaan qaybsannaa magac habeenkiiye,Adoon i hubsan soortaad halligi haysku hanaq goyne,Haraggayga uun baad arkiye kuuma soo hoyane”.Gabaygu wuu dheeraa laakiin gabadhii waxay la gam'i waydey habeenkaasereyga ah “Hindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye, Haraggayga uun baadarkiye kuuma soo hoyane”. Waxay ogaatay in Saahid xabbad ku dhuftay, maxaayeelay waxay u qaadan waydey jacaylkii ay islahayd bal abuur oo wiilku yuusunku baabi'in jacaylkii laga qaaday, waxay kaloo istiri ninku waa qoyskaa oo ficilo ayaa ku khasabtay inay u hoyato, waxayse la kulantay dhacdadaas foosha xuniyo inuu ku caayo cunto siintii iyo raaligelintii ay ku wanaajinaysay. Habeenkaasayay goor madoow ka guuraysay, tolkii markay maqleenna sida gabadha loogalay, waxaa Saahid lagu xukumay oo laga qaaday magteedii illeen wuu dilaye."},{"question":"සාපේක්ෂතා න්‍යාය ලබා දුන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"ඇල්බට් අයින්ස්ටයින්"},{"question":"السؤال: كم مدة مباراة كرة القدم كاملة؟","answer":"الإجابة: تتألف المباراة الرسمية من نصفين مدة كل منهما 45 دقيقة، ويُعرفان بالشوطين، وهناك استراحة مدتها 15 دقيقة. فيكون المجموع الكلي ساعة و45 دقيقة."},{"question":"Ibi ti ileeṣẹ nla kan ko ọja si lawọn eleyii lọọ fọ l’Ado-Odo","answer":"Ṣinkun bayii lọwọ tẹ awọn baale ilẹ mẹta yii torukọ wọn n jẹ Jẹlili Waheed, Ọtun Taye ati Olu Adeniran, nibi ti wọn ti n fọ ile ikẹru-si ileeṣẹ nla kan ni Àgbárá, nijọba ibilẹ Ado-Odo Ọta, nipinlẹ Ogun.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹjọ yii, lọwọ ọlọpaa teṣan Agbara tẹ wọn, lẹyin ti olobo ta wọn pe awọn eeyan kan ti gbe mọto akẹru wa, wọn si ti n ko awọn ọja ileeṣẹ naa sọkọ ọhun, wọn fẹẹ ko o sa lọ.Nnkan bii aago mẹrin irọlẹ lawọn ọlọpaa naa dọdẹ awọn eeyan yii debẹ, wọn si ba wọn nibi ti wọn ti n ba awọn nnkan kan jẹ ki wọn le ri ohun ti wọn fẹẹ gbe jade.Awọn jẹnẹretọ nla meji meji ni wọn ti gbe sinu ọkọ Iveco to ni nọmba AKD 747XZ ti wọn gbe wa, wọn si tun gbe kinni kan ti wọn n pe ni’Fork lift’ naa si i.Awọn nnkan yii pẹlu mọto ti wọn fi kẹru naa lawọn ọlọpaa gba lọwọ wọn, wọn si ti taari awọn mẹtẹẹta  si atimọle, iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori wọn pẹlu, lati mọ iru itu ole jija ti wọn ti pa ri kọwọ too tẹ wọn lọtẹ yii."},{"question":"HABKA FALKA","answer":"Habka falku wuxuu caddeeyaa ama tifaftiraa sida ama habka falku u dhaco; wuxuuna u kala baxaa afar jaad.Tusaale :1. Ogeysiin : Warqad baan qoray.2. Amar : Warqadda qor.3. Madhacdo : haddaan wax baran lahaa, shaqo ma aan waayeen.4. Su’a a l: Yaad warqadda u qortay ?"},{"question":"Oración 1: El sendero de los Apalaches, un sendero escénico nacional desde Georgia hasta Maine, atraviesa Franconia Ridge, incluido Little Haystack.Oración 2: El sendero de los Apalaches, un sendero escénico nacional desde Maine hasta Georgia, cruza Franconia Ridge, incluido Little Haystack.Pregunta : ¿la oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2?. ","answer":"No lo hace. "},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Argentine?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Argentine mu ngi tudd Buenos Aires."},{"question":"Sheeg maalintii, bishii iyo sanadkii Cali Mahdi Max’ed Shirkii Jabuuti loogu doortay Madaxweynaha dalka?","answer":"Waxay ahayd 20/07/1991."},{"question":"भारतातील दुधाच्या उत्पादनात आघाडीचे राज्य कोणते आहे?(A) मध्य प्रदेश(B) पंजाब(C) उत्तर प्रदेश(D) हरियाणा=> ","answer":"(C) उत्तर प्रदेश"},{"question":"Arukaino Umukoro","answer":"Arukaino Umukoro je akọ̀wé lá tí orílẹ̀de Nàìjíríà tí a mọ fún bíborí CNN/MultiChoice Africa Journalist Award ni ọdún 2015.Ìwé kíkà Umukoro kàwé gboyẹ̀ nínú Industrial Chemistry ni Fáṣítì ti ìlú Delta, ó túbọ̀ lọ sí the Nigerian Institute of Journalism tí ó sì sàsẹ́yege ìwé kíkà naa. Ní ọdún 2016, Umukoro parí ẹ̀kọ́ Master's rẹ̀ lórí iṣẹ́ Media and Communication ní Fásiti tí amọ̀ sí Pan-African University.Lèyìn ti Umukoro kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyẹ̀ lórí ẹ̀kọ́ ìwé kíkà, ó bt Iṣẹ́ kíkà ìròyìn ní ilé iṣé ìwé ìròyìn National Standard News ni ọdún 2007. Iṣe Umukoro ni ìwé kíko bẹ̀rẹ̀ nígbà tí ó ń ṣíṣe sísọ ìròyìn lọ́dọ̀ the National Standard news magazine ni ọdún 2007. Ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ fún Writer of the Year’ award ni ọdún 2007 ni ilé-iṣẹ́ ìròyìn The National Standard. Ó tún bọ̀ dára pọ̀ mọ́ wọn ní ilé iṣé The stables of Tell Magazine láti báwo ṣiṣẹ́. Lèyìn èyi ó ṣíṣe ní ilẹ̀ iṣẹ ìròyìn The Punch Newspaper níbi tí ó ti dì Oga . Umukoro já èwè Olúborí nínú ìdílje The Nigeria Media Merit Award fún ìgbà Kínní ni ọdún 2013, eyi tí ó tún gbà àmi ẹyẹ lekan sì ni ọdún 2017.Ni ọdún 2015, wọ́n fún ní àmì ẹyẹ kan ní CNN/MultiChoice Africa Journalist nípa tí ìsòrí eré ìdárayá.Ó tunbọ̀ jáwé olúborí nínú ìdíje ti S.O. Idowu Prize fún sísọ ìròyìn eré ìdárayá tí ó jé wípé ó gba ipò Kejì ní ọdún 2017. Ní 2017, Ó jẹ ipò gẹ́gẹ́ bí agbẹnusọ ati iṣ ìbánisọ́rọ́ fún Ààrẹ ìgbà Kejì orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà, Yẹmí Òsínbàjò."},{"question":"Kodi matenda aakulu m'Malawi muno ndi ati?","answer":"HIV/AIDS yaposa malungo monga gwero lalikulu la matenda m’Malawi. Matenda awiri odziwika bwino omwe sanaphatikizidwe mu Malawi EHP ndi matenda amisala komanso ngozi zapamsewu. Malingaliro abwino kwambiri omwe alipo masiku ano ndi a WHO Global Burden of Disease Project."},{"question":"සිංහල ජන කතාවක් කියන්න ","answer":"එකමුතුකමදිනක් මීයෙක් කෑම සොයමින් ඇවිද ගියා. මීයාට ගොවි ගෙදරක මිදුලේ තිබී විශාල අලයක් හමු වුණා. මීයාට පෙරලගෙන යාමට නොහැකි තරමට ම මේ අලය ලොකුයි.නමුත් මීයා උත්සාහය අත නොහැර ම අලය ටික දුරක් පෙරලාගෙන ගියා. මීයාට හොඳටම මහන්සි යි. ඌ ටික වේලාවක් අලය ට ඇලවී මහන්සි ඇරියා. මෙන්න එතනට ආවා මුව පැටියෙක්.\\"එන්න යාළුවේ. !!! මන් ඔයාට මේ අල ගෙඩිය පෙරළන් යන්න උදව් කරන්නම්. අපි දෙන්නා එකතු වෙලා අල ගෙඩිය අරගෙන යමු\\" කියූ මුව පැටියා අලය පෙරලීමට මීයා ට සහය වුණා. දෙදෙනාම අලය ටික දුරක් පෙරලාගෙන ගියා.මෙන්න ටික දුරක් යන විට, පුංචි කුරුල්ලෙකුත් මෙයාලගේ උදව්වට අවා. \\" කොහොමද යාලුවනේ. !! මමත් ඔයාල ට අලය පෙරලන්න සහය වෙන්නම්\\" කියා මීයාට ත්, මුව පටියාට ත් සහය වුණා.මීයාට දැන් හරිම සතුටුයි. හැමෝම එකතු වෙලා අල ගෙඩිය මීයා ගේ ගෙදරටම පෙරලාගෙන ගියා. මීයා, මුව පැටියාටත්, පුංචි කුරුල්ලාටත් බොහෝම ස්තූතිවන්ත වුණා. "},{"question":"Dandan ni ki Fayẹmi dupo aarẹ ni 2023 – APC Ekiti","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progressives Congress (APC) tipinlẹ Ekiti ti ni dandan ni ki Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi dupo aarẹ ilẹ Naijiria lọdun 2023, bi ko tilẹ wu u ko ṣe e.Alaga igbimọ fidi-hẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọnarebu Paul Ọmọtọṣọ, lo sọrọ yii niluu Ayede-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Ọyẹ, lasiko ti oloye ẹgbẹ naa kan, Ọmọwe Oluṣẹgun Ọṣinkọlu, ṣayẹyẹ Keresi fun ẹgbẹrun kan ọmọ ẹgbẹ ọhun lẹkun idibo Ariwa Ekiti.Ọmọtọṣọ, ẹni ti Ọnarebu Ade Ajayi to jẹ Alukoro ẹgbẹ naa ṣoju fun, sọ pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe Fayẹmi ko ti i fifẹ han si ipo aarẹ, awọn yoo ri i daju o pe dupo naa dandan nitori iṣẹ nla to ti ṣe lagbo oṣelu.Ọmọtọṣọ ni, ‘‘Gbogbo ẹnu la le fi sọrọ pe APC ni yoo tun jawe olubori ninu ibo gomina ipinlẹ yii lọdun 2022, nitori awọn nnkan ribiribi ti Fayẹmi ti ṣe, a ko si fẹ ki ẹgbẹ rau-rau kan gbajọba ki wọn tun ba Ekiti jẹ.‘‘Lori ipo aarẹ ni 2023, asiko ti to ki aarẹ wa lati Ekiti. Idi niyi ta a fi n rọ gbogbo yin kẹ ẹ ṣatilẹyin fun Gomina Fayẹmi.‘‘Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Fayẹmi ko ti i sọ pe oun fẹẹ dupo, a maa wọ ọ sinu idije naa dandan ni nitori o kunju oṣuwọn, o ni ifarajin, bẹẹ lo jẹ oloootọ si APC.Bakan naa ni Ọmọtọṣọ gboriyin fun Ọsinkọlu to jẹ alaga ipolongo fun Buhari ati Oṣinbajo nipinlẹ Ekiti lasiko ibo ọdun 2019, ẹni to ni o duro ṣinṣin sinu ẹgbẹ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe igba meji lo padanu anfaani lati di sẹnetọ.Ninu ọrọ Ọṣinkọlu ti amugbalẹgbẹẹ ẹ, Ọgbẹni Ayọdeji Ọlọrunfẹmi, ṣoju fun, o bẹ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa lati sowọ pọ, ki wọn si ṣatilẹyin ti ko lẹgbẹ fun APC, eyi to pe ni ẹgbẹ gbogbo araalu."},{"question":"Trendyol entegrasyonu nasıl yapılır?","answer":"Trendyol Partner panelinden mağaza profiline tıkladıktan sonra Hesap Bilgilerim → Entegrasyon Bilgilerim sekmesine giriş yapılır. Buradan satıcı ID, satıcı adı, API kullanıcı adı ve şifresinden oluşan API bilgilerini abonesi olduğunuz yazılıma girmek yeterlidir."},{"question":"గురుపూజోత్సవం (ఉపాధ్యాయ దినోత్సవం) గురించి మిత్రునికి లేఖ","answer":"గుంటూరు,xxxxxxxప్రియమిత్రుడు పుష్పరాజ్ కు,గడచిన సెప్టెంబర్ 5న మా పాఠశాలలో గురుపూజోత్సవం బ్రహ్మాండంగా జరుపుకున్నాం. ఆ రోజు మన మాజీ రాష్ట్రపతి డాక్టర్ సర్వేపల్లి రాధాకృష్ణన్ జయంతి. ఆయన జయంతినే ప్రభుత్వం గురుపూజోత్సవం దినంగా ప్రకటించింది కదా ! మేము మా పాఠశాలలోని ఉపాధ్యాయులందరిని ఆ రోజున ప్రత్యేకంగా సన్మానించాం. వారి ఆశీర్వచనాలు పొందాం. మనకు విద్య నేర్పుతున్న గురువులను గౌరవించి సన్మానించడం నాకెంతో ఆనందాన్ని కలిగించింది.ఇట్లు,నీ మిత్రుడు,జయరాజ్.చిరునామా :ఎస్. పుష్పరాజ్, 6వ తరగతి,నవోదయ హైస్కూలు,నాయుడుపేట,నెల్లూరు."},{"question":"અહીં મીરાંબાઈ રચિત કૃતિ  \\"આવો તો રામરસ પીજીએ\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:'આવો તો રામરસ પીજીએહો ભાગ્યશાળી, આવો તો રામરસ પીજીએ.તજી દુઃસંગ સત્સંગમાં બેસી,હરિગુણ ગાઈ લહાવો લીજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"આવો તો રામરસ પીજીએહો ભાગ્યશાળી, આવો તો રામરસ પીજીએ.તજી દુઃસંગ સત્સંગમાં બેસી,હરિગુણ ગાઈ લહાવો લીજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી.મમતાને મોહજંજાળ જગ કેરી,ચિત્ત થકી દૂર કરી દીજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી.દેવોને દુર્લભ દેહ મળ્યો આ,તેને સફળ આજ કીજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી.રામનામ રીઝીએ, આનંદ લીજીએ,દુર્જનિયાંથી ન બ્હીજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી.મીરાં કહે પ્રભુ ગિરિધરના ગુણ,હેતે હરિરંગ ભીંજીએ ... હો ભાગ્યશાળી."},{"question":"Na mitologia egípcia quem é Ísis?","answer":"Esposa-irmã de Osíris e filha de Geb e Nur, é deusa do amor, da maternidade, da fertilidade e da magia. É protetora da natureza e considerada modelo de mãe e esposa."},{"question":"Chọn đáp án sai trong các đáp án sau:A. Số có chữ số tận cùng là 0 thì chia hết cho 5B. Số có chữ số tận cùng là 5 thì chia hết cho 5C. Số có chữ số tận cùng là 0 hoặc 5 thì chia hết cho 5D. Số có chữ số tận cùng là 2 thì chia hết cho 5","answer":"Lời giảiTheo dấu hiệu chia hết cho 5, các số có chữ số tận cùng là 0 hoặc 5 thì chia hết cho 5 và chỉ những số đó mới chia hết cho 5. Vậy đáp án A, B, C đúng và D sai.Chọn đáp án D. "},{"question":"Напишите продолжение следующего абзаца: Изабель Гульден - шведская гандболистка, разыгрывающий шведского клуба «Луги». Начиная с 2008 года стабильный игрок основы национальной команды, не пропустила ни одного международного турнира. Результаты: Олимпийские игры 2008 (Швеция: 8-е место), Евро 2008","answer":"(9-е), Кубок мира 2009 (13-е), Евро 2010 (2-е), Кубок мира 2011 (9-е), Олимпийские игры 2012 (11-е), Евро-2012 (9-е), Евро-2014 (3-е), Кубок мира 2015 (9-е), и Олимпийские игр 2016 (7-е)."},{"question":"Qual atriz interpretou Mary Poppins no filme de 1964, Mary Poppins?","answer":"Foi a atriz Julie Andrews. Além de atriz, foi cantora, dançarina, diretora teatral e escritora britânica, célebre especialmente por suas performances nos mais variados musicais do teatro e do cinema. Também sempre dedicou-se ao trabalho na televisão."},{"question":"வினா : திருக்குறளில் இடம்பெறும் மலர் என்ன?","answer":"விடை: அனிச்சம்"},{"question":"ናይጄሪያ ነጻነቷን ያገኘችው መቼ ነው?","answer":"በ1960 እ.ኤ.አ."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ 76 වන මහා මණ්ඩල සමුළුව පැවත්වෙන්නේ කුමන නගරයේද?","answer":"ඇමරිකා  එක්සත් ජනපදයේ නිව්යෝර්ක් එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ 76 වන මහා මණ්ඩල සමුළුව පැවත්වේ."},{"question":"काभ्रेपलान्चोक जिल्लाको बारेमा सानो अनुच्छेद लेख्नुहोस् र तेस्मा रहेको एउटा ऐतिहासिक स्थानको बारेमा पनि लेख्नुहोस् ।","answer":"काभ्रेपलान्चोक काठमाडौंको उत्तरी भागमा पर्ने एउटा जिल्ला हो । छोट्करिमा काभ्रेपलान्चोकलाई काभ्रे पनि भनिन्छ । एस्को  क्षेत्रफल १३९६ वर्गफुट छ । साथ्साथै काभ्रेको उचाइ दायरा २८० मिटर देखि ३०१८ मिटर सम्म छ । काभ्रेपलान्चोक जिल्ला मण्डनदेउपुर नगरपालिका मा एउटा महाकाली बिद्यालय रहेको छ। यो बिद्यालय सर्बझाङ डाँडामा रहेको महाकाली देवीको मन्दिर बाट थोरै विद्यार्थीहरुलाई शिक्षा दिदै सुरु गरिएको थियो । हालमा यो बिद्यालय चैनपुर डाँडामा रहेको छ र यहाँ सयौं विद्यार्थी अध्ययनरत छन् ।"},{"question":"Answer the following question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Question: డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్‌ ఎక్కువగా ఏ వయస్సు వారికి వస్తుంది ?Topic: డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్Article: డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్ లేదా డౌన్స్ సిండ్రోమ్ (Down syndrome) ఒక విధమైన జన్యు సంబంధమైన వ్యాధి. ఈ వ్యాధిగ్రస్తులలో క్రోమోజోము 21 (chromosome 21) లో రెండు ఉండాల్సిన పోగులు మూడు వుంటాయి. అందువలన దీనిని ట్రైసోమీ 21 అని కూడా పిలుస్తారు.[1] దీనిమూలంగా పిల్లలలొ భౌతికమైన పెరుగుదల మందగిస్తుంది. వీరి ముఖంలోని మార్పుల ఆధారంగా గుర్తించవచ్చును. వీరికి తెలివితేటలు చాలా తక్కువగా వుంటాయి.[1] వీరి IQ సుమారు 50 మాత్రమే వుంటుంది (సగటు IQ 100).[1][2]చాలా మంది పిల్లలు సామాన్యంగా పాఠశాలలో చదువుకోగలిగినా, కొంతమందికి ప్రత్యేకమైన విద్యా సౌకర్యాలు అవసరమౌతాయి. కొద్దిమంది పట్టభద్రులుగా కూడా చదువుకున్నారు.[3], [4] సరైన విద్య మరియు వీరి ఆరోగ్యం మీద కొంత శ్రద్ధ వహిస్తే వీరి జీవితంలో క్వాలిటీ బాగుంటుంది.[5]డౌన్ సిండ్రోం మానవులలో సంభవించే క్రోమోజోము లోపాలన్నింటిలోకి ప్రధానమైనది.[6] అమెరికాలో పుట్టిన ప్రతి 1000 పిల్లలలో 1.4 మందిలో ఈ లోపాన్ని గుర్తించారు.[7]డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్ మానవులలో చాలా సాధారణ క్రోమోజోమ్ అసాధారణలలో ఒకటి. ఇది సంవత్సరానికి 1,000 మంది పిల్లలు పుట్టుకొస్తుంది. డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్ 5.4 మిలియన్ల వ్యక్తులలో ఉంది మరియు 1990 లో 43,000 మరణాల నుండి 27,000 మంది మరణించారు. ఇది 1866 లో పూర్తిగా సిండ్రోమ్ను వర్ణించిన ఒక బ్రిటీష్ వైద్యుడు అయిన జాన్ లాంగ్డన్ డౌన్ తర్వాత పెట్టబడింది. 1838 లో జీన్-ఎటిఎన్నే డొమినిక్ ఎస్క్విరోల్ మరియు 1844 లో ఎడౌర్డ్ సెగిన్ ఈ పరిస్థితిని కొన్ని విషయాలు వివరించారు. 1959 లో, డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్ యొక్క జన్యుపరమైన కారణం, క్రోమోజోమ్ 21 అదనపు కాపీని కనుగొనబడింది.డౌన్ పేరుడౌన్ సిండ్రోం పేరును బ్రిటిష్ వైద్యుడైన జాన్ లాంగ్డన్ డౌన్ (John Langdon Down) జ్ఞాపకార్థం ఉంచారు. ఇతడు 1866లో ఈ వ్యాధిని గురించి వివరించాడు.[8] అయితే ఈ వ్యాధిని అంతకుముందే జీన్ డొమినిక్ ఎస్క్విరాల్ (Jean-Étienne Dominique Esquirol) 1838 లోను మరియు ఎడ్వర్డ్ సెక్విన్ (Édouard Séguin) 1844 లోను గుర్తించారు.[9] ఈ వ్యాధి క్రోమోజోము 21 కి సంబంధించినదని డా జెరోం లెజెయున్ (Jérôme Lejeune) 1959 లో గుర్తించాడు. ఈ వ్యాధిని ప్రస్తుతం శిశువు జన్మించక మునుపే గుర్తించే అవకాశం ఉన్నది.[1][10] అయితే అలాంటి గర్భాలు సామాన్యంగా అబార్షన్ చేయబడతాయి.సంకేతాలు మరియు లక్షణాలుడౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్ ఉన్న వారు దాదాపు భౌతిక మరియు మేధో వైకల్యాలు కలిగి ఉంటారు.[11] పెద్దలు, వారి మానసిక సామర్ధ్యాలు...","answer":"డౌన్ సిండ్రోమ్"},{"question":"சொற்களை இனம்கண்டு அதற்குரிய பெட்டிக்குக் கீழே எழுதுக.கண்ணாடித்துண்டு\\tநெகிழிப்பைகாகிதத்தாள்\\tசணல்பைபீங்கான் தட்டு\\tஇலை","answer":"மட்காத குப்பைப் பெட்டிகண்ணாடித்துண்டு,நெகிழிப்பை,பீங்கான் தட்டுமட்கும் குப்பைப் பெட்டிகாகிதத்தாள்,சணல்பைஇலை"},{"question":"විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග යනු මොනවාද ?","answer":"විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග යනු තරංගාකාර ලක්ෂණ දක්වමින් අවකාශය හරහා ශක්තිය ගලා යන ක්‍රමයකි. විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංගය විද්‍යුත් ක්ෂේත්‍රයක් සහ චුම්බක ක්ෂේත්‍රයක් එකිනෙකට ලම්බකව කම්පණය වීමෙන් ඇති වේ. විකිරණයේ ප්‍රගමන දිශාව ක්ෂේත්‍ර දෙකට ම ලම්බක වේ.සියලූ විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංග රික්තයක දී ගමන් කරන වේගය, ආලෝකයේ ප්‍රවේගයට සමාන වේ. (3.00 x108 ms-1)තරංග ආයමය λ හා සංඛ්‍යාතය f වන විට විද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංගයක ප්‍රවේගය, C = fλවිද්‍යුත් චුම්බක තරංගයක ශක්තිය E = hf (E යනු එක් ෆෝටෝනයක ශක්තියයි). මෙහි h යනු නියතයකි. එය ප්ලාන්ක් නියතය නම් වේ. (ප්ලාන්ක් නියතය 6.624 × 10-34 Js)"},{"question":"Euskal pilota modalitate anitzeko kirola da. Zein da handiena eta zein da handiena eta zer berezitasun du?","answer":"Euskal pilota modalitate anitzetako bat \\"pelota mano\\" da, non jokalariak beren eskuz jotzen duten pilota frontoiaren paretean."},{"question":"Inona no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eto an-tany?","answer":"Ny tendrombohitra avo indrindra eran-tany dia Everest, any amin'ny tandavan-tendrombohitra Himalaya eo amin'ny sisin-tanin'i Nepal sy Shina (Tibet)."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ Yoruba ṣedaro Olupo tilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo to waja","answer":"Awọn araalu ṣedaro Olupo tilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo, Ọba Sikiru Atanda Ọladọtun Wọleọla (Ilufẹmiloye) to waja lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe nnkan bii aago mọkanla aabọ alẹ lo papoda lẹyin aisan ranpẹ.Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, Abdulrahman Abdulrazaq, ti ba araalu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo, nijọba ibilẹ Irẹpọdun, kẹdun iku ọba onipo kin-in-ni (First Class) naa.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Akọwe iroyin rẹ, Rafiu Ajakaye, gbe sita laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, Gomina Abdulrahman ṣapejuwe oloogbe naa gẹgẹ bii akikanju ọkunrin, ẹni to fẹran araalu ilu ẹ, to si mu ilọsiwaju ba igbe-aye wọn ati ilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo lapapọ.Abdulrahman ba awọn oloye, mọlẹbi atawọn ọrẹ kabiyesi to waja naa kẹdun. O gbadura ki Ọlọrun tẹ ẹ safẹfẹ rere, ko si tu awọn to fi silẹ saye lọ ninu.Ọdun 2009 ni Ọba Wọleọla gun ori oye gẹgẹ bii Olupo kẹẹẹdogun.Ọba Wọleọla ni alaga gbogbo ọba ilẹ Igbomina nipinlẹ Kwara."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي تبدأ بآية “لَا أُقْسِمُ بِيَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ”؟\\t","answer":"سورة القيامة"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Nội dung trên được nêu trong công điện của Thủ tướng Chính phủ về việc tăng cường các biện pháp quản lý, điều hành giá gửi các bộ trưởng và chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành. Theo đó, Thủ tướng đề nghị các bộ trưởng, trưởng ngành và chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh theo dõi sát diễn biến thị trường, kịp thời thực hiện giải pháp đảm bảo cân đối cung cầu trong nước, ổn định giá cả, không để xảy ra tình trạng thiếu hàng, găm hàng, đầu cơ, tăng giá bất hợp lý. Trong đó, các mặt hàng chịu ảnh hưởng trực tiếp từ giá xăng dầu như dịch vụ vận tải hành khách, vận tải hàng hóa, logistics cần rà soát kê khai giá để đánh giá việc điều chỉnh giá phù hợp với biến động của các yếu tố đầu vào, trường hợp có thể giảm giá thì yêu cầu đơn vị thực hiện kê khai giảm giá kịp thời. Tăng cường kiểm tra việc chấp hành niêm yết giá, thu tiền dịch vụ đúng giá niêm yết của các doanh nghiệp, xử lý nghiêm các hành vi lợi dụng tăng giá bất hợp lý, kết cấu đưa thêm những khoản thu ngoài giá để thu cao hơn mức giá kê khai, niêm yết. Đối với các hàng hóa, dịch vụ thiết yếu, chịu ảnh hưởng gián tiếp từ giá xăng dầu, có tác động đến CPI và người dân, doanh nghiệp, cần theo dõi sát diễn biến giá cả. Nắm bắt tình hình giá cả để có các biện pháp điều hành, bình ổn giá phù hợp, tăng cường kiểm tra, kiểm soát kê khai, niêm yết giá, xử lý nghiêm các trường hợp lợi dụng để tăng giá bất hợp lý. Cụ thể, với giá lương thực thực phẩm, Thủ tướng yêu cầu đánh giá kỹ tình hình sản xuất, điều hòa cung cầu các mặt hàng phục vụ nhu cầu trong nước, giữa các vùng, địa phương và nhu cầu xuất khẩu để ổn định giá cả thị trường. Với mặt hàng thịt heo, thức ăn chăn nuôi, tiếp tục tập trung thúc đẩy sản xuất, chăn nuôi, tái đàn, chế biến, điều hòa và đảm bảo nguồn cung để bình ổn giá thịt heo; thực hiện công tác phòng, chống dịch. Tổ chức tái đàn phù hợp, bền vững, chăn nuôi theo mô hình khép kín và an toàn sinh học; đẩy mạnh sản xuất con giống, bảo đảm tổng đàn heo cả nước đáp ứng đủ nhu cầu. Đánh giá hệ thống kênh phân phối, cung ứng, lò mổ và đầu mối bán buôn, bán lẻ đối với mặt hàng thịt heo tính từ cửa trại, cửa chuồng của doanh nghiệp, người chăn nuôi đến doanh nghiệp, siêu thị, người bán cuối cùng trực tiếp cung ứng cho người tiêu dùng. Làm rõ các bất cập, hạn chế để đề xuất các giải pháp khắc phục đảm bảo giảm thiểu khâu trung gian đẩy chi phí lưu thông, tăng giá bán. Tiến tới hoàn thiện hệ thống phân phối, bán buôn, bán lẻ tinh gọn, hiệu quả, có chi phí lưu thông hợp lý trong cơ cấu giá bán. Với giá vật liệu xây dựng, cần đánh giá nguồn cung và xử lý kịp thời các trường hợp găm hàng, giữ hàng, làm đứt gãy chuỗi cung ứng, đẩy giá tăng cao bất hợp lý ảnh hưởng đến tiến độ xây dựng các công trình, dự án. Thực hiện công bố giá, rút ngắn quy trình công bố giá. Với các dịch vụ lưu trú, du lịch tăng cường kiểm tra việc niêm yết giá, xử nghiêm các hành vi lợi dụng các dịp cao điểm, diễn biến giá xăng dầu để tăng giá bất hợp lý. Tăng cường rà soát giá thuốc, vật tư y tế kê khai theo quy định, theo dõi sát sao tình hình dịch bệnh để đảm bảo cung ứng đủ thuốc và vật tư y tế với giá hợp lý phục vụ nhu cầu khám bệnh, chữa bệnh và phòng chống dịch bệnh. Với sách giáo khoa, cần tiếp tục tiếp nhận, rà soát kê khai giá theo quy định của pháp luật. Các đơn vị xuất bản tiếp tục rà soát và triển khai các biện pháp tiết giảm chi phí nhằm tiếp tục giảm giá, góp phần kiểm soát lạm phát, đảm bảo an sinh xã hội; chia sẻ với người dân. Điều hành giá mặt hàng xăng dầu bám sát giá thế giới, sử dụng linh hoạt công cụ quỹ bình ổn để có phương án phù hợp, xử lý nghiêm các hành vi đầu cơ, găm hàng. Chủ động có phương án điều chỉnh thuế tiêu thụ đặc biệt, thuế giá trị gia tăng.","answer":"Giá hàng hóa vẫn nhảy múa theo giá xăng, Thủ tướng ra chỉ đạo khẩn để 'hạ nhiệt'"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta da categoria Esportes","answer":"Qual time joga em casa na Flórida e da qual participaram Wade e Lebron? Miami Heat"},{"question":"பறவைகளிலேயே மிகவும் நீளமான நாக்கு உடையது எது?","answer":"மிக நீளமான நாக்கைக் கொண்ட பறவை வடக்கு ஃப்ளிக்கர் ஆகும். வடக்கு ஃப்ளிக்கர் அல்லது பொதுவான ஃப்ளிக்கர் என்பது மரங்கொத்தி குடும்பத்தைச் சேர்ந்த நடுத்தர அளவிலான பறவையாகும். இது வட அமெரிக்காவின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகள், மத்திய அமெரிக்காவின் சில பகுதிகள், கியூபா மற்றும் கேமன் தீவுகளுக்கு சொந்தமானது, மேலும் இது இடம்பெயர்ந்த சில மரங்கொத்தி இனங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். வடக்கு ஃப்ளிக்கருக்கு நூற்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட பொதுவான பெயர்கள் அறியப்படுகின்றன, இதில் யெல்லோஹாம்மர் (யூரேசியன் யெல்லோஹாமர் (எம்பெரிசா சிட்ரினெல்லா) உடன் குழப்பிக்கொள்ள வேண்டாம்), கிளேப், காஃபர் மரங்கொத்தி, ஹாரி-விக்கெட், ஹை-ஹோ, வேக்-அப், வாக்-அப். பல இந்த பெயர்கள் அதன் சில அழைப்புகளைப் பின்பற்றும் முயற்சியில் இருந்து பெறப்பட்டது.இது அலபாமாவின் மாநிலப் பறவையாகும் (அதன் பேச்சுவழக்கில் \\"மஞ்சள் சுத்தியல்\\" என்று அறியப்படுகிறது)"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੁਣਿਐ ਦੂਖ ਪਾਪ ਕਾ ਨਾਸੁ ॥੧੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 3 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਸੁਣਨ ਨਾਲ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ) ਦੱਖਾਂ ਤੇ ਪਾਪਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"Qual é o segundo menor estado do Brasil?","answer":"Alagoas é uma das 27 unidades federativas do Brasil. Está situado no leste da região Nordeste e tem como limites Pernambuco (N e NO), Sergipe (S), Bahia (SO) e o Oceano Atlântico (L). Ocupa uma área de 27 848,140 km², sendo ligeiramente menor que a Albânia, e é o segundo menor estado do país. Maior apenas que o estado de Sergipe, e que a região do Distrito Federal, que não tem status de estado."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai jawi terkurung siang\\"?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah \\"orang yang tidak dapat bertindak sesuka hatinya kerana terkongkong oleh adat\\"."},{"question":"Tsarin gini ya fi karfi a yankin New England saboda  abubuwan da ake gini da su: * yumbu. * masonry. * itace. * karfe.","answer":"itace."},{"question":"Siapakan di bawah ini yang BUKAN legenda bola sepak Malaysia? A. Santokh Signh B. Mokhtar Dahari C. Ghazali Shafie D. Soh Chin Aun","answer":"Jawapan yang betul adalah C. Ghazali Shafie.Mokhtar, Soh dan Santokh merupakan legenda bola sepak Malaysia pada era 1970-an. Ghazali merupakan bekas menteri dalam negeri."},{"question":"E devlette görünen sertifikalar ne işe yarar?","answer":"Sonuç olarak, E-Devlet Onaylı Sertifikalar, kişilerin internet ortamında güvenli işlem yapmalarına olanak tanır. Bu sertifikalar, birçok işlem için gereken kimlik doğrulama işlemlerinin yapılması için kullanılır ve kamu kurumları, bankalar, e-ticaret siteleri ve diğer birçok kuruluş tarafından kullanılır."},{"question":"Crank Shaft (වාහනයක) කියන වචනයට සිංහලෙන් මොකක්ද කියන්නෙ?","answer":"Crank Shaft = දඟර දන්ඩ"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Cùng với sông, Hà Nội còn có hệ thống đầm hồ dày đặc. Ở thế kỷ trước, thủ đô có trên 200 hồ lớn nhỏ, phần nhiều là hồ đầm tự nhiên do vết tích của những khúc sông chết để lại. Hiện nay, dù phần lớn hồ đã bị san lấp để lấy mặt bằng xây dựng, Hà Nội vẫn còn khoảng 100 hồ, phân bổ ở ","answer":"khắp xã phường như Hoàn Kiếm, Hồ Tây, Quảng Bá, Trúc Bạch, Thiền Quang, Bảy Mẫu, Thanh Nhàn, Linh Đàm, Yên Sở, Giảng Võ, Đồng Mô, Suối Hai... Cùng với các con sông, những hồ này không chỉ là một kho nước lớn mà còn góp phần điều hòa nhiệt độ tự nhiên, giúp giảm bớt nhiệt độ vùng nội đô."},{"question":"İlk takvimi hangi uygarlık tarafından bulunmuştur? ","answer":"Mezopotamya'daki Sümerler, bir yılı her biri 29 veya 30 günden oluşan 12 kameri aya bölen ilk takvimi yaptılar.  İlk Çağ Mısırlıları ise güneş yılına dayalı takvimi ilk geliştirenlerdir. "},{"question":"\\"මේං අපේ ඉස්කෝලේ\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"මේං අපේ ඉස්කෝලේරාං රුවයි ‍රැස් මාලේරෑන් පිටින් අපි ආවේපාන් වැටක සිරියාවේවැස්සට ගඟ ආවත් පන්ති වලටඅව්වට ඉර වැ‍ටුණත් හිස් මුදුනටවෙඩි පිට වෙඩි ඇහුණත් පැයෙන් පැයටඅපි ආදරෙයි අපේ ඉස්කෝලෙටකුඹුරේ වැඩ තිබුණත් යලට මහටඑනවා හැමදාමත් පන්ති වලටඩෙස් පු‍ටු බංකු නැතත් ඉඳ ගන්නටඅපි ආදරෙයි අපේ ඉස්කෝලෙටලස්සන සාරි නැතත් ටීචර්ලටමූණට එළිය ඇවිත් පිං පාටටකැන්දන් යන්න අපිව හෙට ලෝකෙටඅපි ආදරෙයි අපේ ඉස්කෝලෙටප්‍රදීපා ධර්මදාස"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Nga dội \\"mưa\\" rocket xuống thành phố miền Nam Ukraine | Báo Dân trí","answer":"\\"Thành phố của tôi, thành phố Mykolaiv anh hùng, đang trở thành Mariupol thứ hai... Khoảng 40 quả rocket và tên lửa hành trình nhắm vào Mykolaiv rạng sáng 31/7. Đây có thể nói là vụ tấn công khốc liệt nhất nhằm vào thành phố kể từ khi Nga mở chiến dịch quân sự\\", Hanna Zamazieieva, người đứng đầu chính quyền khu vực Mykolaiv, cho biết. Theo truyền thông địa phương, vụ tấn công đã phá hủy một số cơ sở hạ tầng của thành phố như khách sạn, trung tâm thể thao, 2 cơ sở giáo dục, một ga tàu và một số tòa nhà. Thống đốc vùng Mykolaiv Vitaliy Kim cho biết thêm, vụ tập kích khiến Oleksiy Vadatursky, người sáng lập và cũng là chủ sở hữu công ty nông nghiệp Nibulon, và vợ thiệt mạng tại nhà riêng do trúng đạn pháo. Nibulon chuyên sản xuất và xuất khẩu lúa mì, lúa mạch và ngô. Doanh nghiệp này có đội tàu vận tải và xưởng đóng tàu riêng. Tổng thống Volodymyr Zelensky mô tả cái chết của ông Vadatursky là \\"một tổn thất lớn đối với đất nước Ukraine\\". Cố vấn của Tổng thống Ukraine, ông Mykhailo Podolyak, cáo buộc phía Nga cố ý sát hại ông Vadatursky, vì một trong những tên lửa phóng vào phòng ngủ của doanh nhân này. Ông Vadartursky là người giàu thứ 24 Ukraine với khối tài sản ước tính 430 triệu USD. Nga hiện chưa bình luận về cáo buộc này. Cùng ngày, Thống đốc vùng Dnipropetrovsk Valentyn Reznichenko cho hay, thành phố Nikopol ở miền Nam Ukraine cũng hứng khoảng 50 quả rocket Grad. Chiến sự Nga - Ukraine có xu hướng leo thang gần đây và mặt trận miền Nam bắt đầu nóng trở lại với các cuộc phản công của Kiev. Ukraine bắt đầu chiến dịch phản công mạnh ở Kherson và một số khu vực lân cận khoảng vài tuần trở lại đây sau khi được tiếp nhận thêm pháo hạng nặng của phương Tây, trong đó có pháo phản lực phóng loạt HIMARS. Chính quyền quân sự Kherson hôm 31/7 cho hay, các cuộc giao tranh khốc liệt khiến hàng trăm ngôi làng ở khu vực rơi vào tình trạng chung: đường xá, nhà cửa, trường học bị hư hại, đồng ruộng, sông ngòi bị rải mìn, nhiều dân thường bị thương hoặc thiệt mạng. Một số ngôi làng bị phá hủy gần như hoàn toàn.Theo giới chức Ukraine, các đợt phản công mạnh buộc Nga phải dồn lực lượng cho các khu vực đã kiểm soát ở miền Nam. Tổng thống Ukraine Zelensky cho hay, Nga phải chuyển bớt lực lượng từ vùng Donbass đến Kherson và Zaporizhzhia. Nga kiểm soát hoàn toàn Kherson và một phần Zaporizhzhia từ tháng 3, không lâu sau khi mở chiến dịch quân sự ở Ukraine. Khoảng hơn 1 tháng trở lại đây, chính quyền Tổng thống Zelensky liên tục hối thúc người dân sơ tán khỏi các khu vực do Nga kiểm soát ở Kherson và Zaporizhzhia bởi quân đội nước này \\"chắc chắn sẽ phản công để giành lại lãnh thổ\\". Các vùng lãnh thổ miền Nam Ukraine có vai trò chiến lược trong kế hoạch của Nga nhằm thiết lập một hành lang trên bộ nối liền từ Donbass ở miền Đông đến bán đảo Crimea. Moscow hôm qua cáo buộc máy bay không người lái Ukraine tấn công trụ sở Hạm đội Biển Đen của Nga ở Crimea khiến 6 người bị thương. Tuy nhiên, Kiev đã bác bỏ thông tin này. Người phát ngôn chính quyền quân sự Odessa Sergiy Bratchuk cho biết: \\"Chúng tôi sẽ giải phóng Crimea theo cách khác hiệu quả hơn nhiều\\"."},{"question":"Terusno penggalan ukara ing ngisor iki nganggo minimal rong (2) ukara, supaya dadi paragraf sing runtun.Sampah bisa kagolongake dadi 2 jenis yaiku ...Jawaban:","answer":"sampah organik lan sampah an organik. Sampah organik yaiku sampah sing bisa diolah dene sampah anorganik yaiku sampah sing bisa kadaur ulang. Sampah organik bisa kaolah dadi pupuk lan sumber energi. Sampah paling akeh diasilake saka pomahan lan sampah organik (sampah teles) tuladha sampah saka pawon, sisa sayuran, kulit woh-wohan lan godhong. Dene sampah anorganik tuladha botol kaca, botol plastik, omplong lan dluwang. "},{"question":"Resaka famokarana, inona no mampalaza ny Fianarantsoa?","answer":"Raha resaka famokarana dia ny divay no mampalaza ny Fianarantsoa, ao amin'ny trano famokarana divay \\"Clos Malaza de Fianarantsoa\\"."},{"question":"“సంస్థ” అంటే ఏమిటి ?","answer":"“ఒక లక్ష్యసిద్ధికి గాని, కొన్ని ఆశయాల సాధనకు గాని నిర్ణీత పద్ధతిలో ఐక్యతతో కృషి చేయుటకు ఏర్పడిన వ్యక్తుల సముదాయమే సంస్థ. మానవుడు కొన్ని ప్రత్యేక ప్రయోజనాలు నెరవేర్చుకోవడానికి వివిధ రకాలైన సంస్థలను నిర్మించుకొన్నాడు. ఉదా: మత సంస్థలు, రాజకీయ సంస్థలు, ఆర్థిక సంస్థలు, సాంఘిక సంస్థలు, సాంస్కృతిక సంస్థలు మొ||నవి."},{"question":"पुढीलपैकी कोणते भारतातील व्यावसायिक ऊर्जेचे मुख्य स्त्रोत आहे?(A) आण्विक उर्जा(B) नैसर्गिक वायू(C) कोळसा(D) खनिज तेल=> ","answer":"(C) कोळसा"},{"question":" Sheeg yaa ugu Horeeyey Muslimiinta qof maka ka Haajira oo u Haajira Madiina?","answer":"Qofki ugu horeyay ee Maka ka Haajira oo Madiina u Haajira  wuxu ahaa Abuu Salaama RC."},{"question":"ਅਪ੍ਰਤੀਬੰਧਤ ਬਹੁ-ਪਤਨੀ ਵਿਆਹ ।","answer":"ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਤਨੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਸੀਮਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਜਿੰਨੀਆਂ ਮਰਜ਼ੀ ਚਾਹੇ ਪਤਨੀਆਂ ਰੱਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਾਚੀਨ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਿਤ ਸੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਰਾਜੇ ਬਗੈਰ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਦੇ ਪਤਨੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਣੀਆਂ ਰੱਖ ਸਕਦੇ ਸਨ ।"},{"question":"రేఖా వర్ణపటంలోని రేఖలు ఉపరేఖలుగా విడిపోవటాన్ని విశదీకరించిన శాస్త్రవేత్త ………A) మాక్స్ ప్లాంక్B) సోమర్ ఫెల్డ్C) మోస్లీD) లూయిస్","answer":"B) సోమర్ ఫెల్డ్"},{"question":"Bài học em rút ra được từ ruyện Ông lão đánh cá và con cá vàng là gì?","answer":"Bài học em rút ra là không tham lam, ích kỉ, vong ân bội nghĩa; phải biết sống có trước có sau, nhân hậu với mọi người,…"},{"question":"شكون هو القائد المسلم المشهور اللي فتح شمال أفريقيا ؟","answer":"الإجابة : القائد المسلم عقبة بن نافع وكان من التابعين"},{"question":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !IMAAM CALI BIN ABII DHAALIB OO LAGU MASABITAY IN UU JIDEEYEY IN DIYADA DUMARKA NUS LAGA DHIGO?","answer":"MAGTA LAGA BIXINAYO HADDII HAWEENEY LA DILO !IMAAM CALI BIN ABII DHAALIB OO LAGU MASABITAY IN UU JIDEEYEY IN DIYADA DUMARKA NUS LAGA DHIGO?Haddaan wax ka xusno xadiisyada ama wararka loo ekaysiiyey ee aan dhumucda la cuskan karo lahayn ee ay adeegsadaan, waxaa ka mid ah; in laga maqlay Cali bin Abi dhaalib iyo Xasan al-basri in “dumarku aysan guud ahaanba la sinayn ragga ee ay aad uga hooseeyaan. Haddii uu, hadaba, nin dilo naag, cideedii – awliyadeedii iyagaa laba u door leh; hadday doonaan waxa ay dilin kii ka dilay, waxayse markaa iska bixinayaan diyadiisii badhkeed. Hadday doonaana way isku xishoonayaan oo waxa ay ka qaadanayaan diyadii qofka dumara ahayd (oo dabcan bardh ka ah tii ninka). Haddii ay haweeney nin dishana haday doonaan way dilayaan iyada waxayna hadana qaadanayaan diyadii ninka badhkeed, hadday doonaana way isku xishoon oo waxa ay qaadanayaan diyadii ninkii laga dilay”31. Jawaabta hadalkaani waxa ay ku soo gaaban tahay; ugu horayba sheekadaani waa  waxba kama jiraan oo waa been abuur. Lama odhan karo xadiis war aan loo celinaynin Nebiga (NNKHA). Haddiise taas laga nabad galo, sheekadani waxa kale oo ay ku beenowday; in la yiri “ninka lagu magacaabo Shacbi ayaa ka soo weriyey Cali bin Abi dhalib”. Hase ahaatee waxaa sugan oo aan lagu doodi karin in uusan Shacbi weligiiba arag Cali bin Abi dhaalib, waayo iskuma aysan soo gaarin nolol32. Iska daa in uu Cali (Allaha karaameeye ) ku hadlo warkaas ee waxaa laga hayaa oo sugan sida uu Xakam ka soo weriyey Cali iyo Cabullaahiba in ay dheheen; “ Haddii uu nin ula kac ahaan u dilo naag waa in loo dilaa”33.  Mar Haddii ay sida muuqataba kaaf iyo kala dheeri yihiin labadaan riwaayadood, waxaa mudan in isha lagu eego teebaa xaqiiqada u dhaw. Sidaa oo kale waa in raaciyey dumarka iyo caruurta, isla markaasna uu halkaa ku saraysiiyey ama door biday caruurta. Sida ku qoran kitaabka “Dacaa’imul al-Islam”, waxa uu Cali yiri: “ kuma banaana maragfurka dumarku xuduud iyo dhiig dhaw toona, wuxuuna oran jiray “ Caruurtu dhexdooda waa isugu maragkici karaan dambiyada la xiriira dhiig dhawga, inta aysan weli kala tagin oo aysan cidohoodii u galban ama aysan  la kulmin qof weyn oo hadalka u dhaha”35. Waxaaba taas ka sii qallafsan in la qoro; “ Haddii dambiga loo galay si ula kac ah, kama gudayaan maragfurka wax ka yar laba markhaati oo caddaalad ah. Laakiin haddii loo galay si kama’ ah waxaa gudi kara hal marag oo rag ah iyo hal marag oo dumar ah, ama marag nin keliya iyo dhaar”36.   "},{"question":"أكمل النص التالي: أثناء الغزو المغولي لروسيا ، أخذ المغول","answer":"العديد من الكرملين من الخشب والحجارة وحرقوها (مثل في كوزلسك وريازان ). جمد غزو التتار التطور المعماري للكرملين لمدة قرن ونصف."},{"question":"Ọrọ ilẹ ti yanju, ẹ ba mi gbadura ki Ọlọrun falubarika si i","answer":"Ẹ wo o, ki ire Ọlọrun ma jinna si gbogbo wa. Gbogbo ohun ti a n wa yii, gbogbo ohun ti a n le kiri laye yii, ko to Ọlọrun i ṣe laarin iṣẹju kan. Yoo si ṣe e, yoo si yanju ẹ, yoo si maa ya ọlọrọ funra ẹ lẹnu. Ọlọrun Ọba nikan lo le ṣe iru ẹ, ko si ẹda aye ti i ṣe iru ẹ fun ni. Bi mo ba n sọ iru ọrọ yii, afi kẹ ẹ gba mi gbọ, nitori ohun to ṣẹlẹ si mi ni mo n sọ yii, loju wa nibi yii naa si ni, lori bi nnkan ṣe le to yii naa si ni. Bi ki i ba si i ṣe pe o ṣẹlẹ si emi naa, bo ba jẹ ẹnikan lo sọ ọ, mo maa maa wo o ni, nitori o ṣoroo gbagbọ gan-an ni.Nigba ti mo de ṣọọbu, Sinkafi ko ti i de, ṣugbọn ọkan Safu ko balẹ, o si han loju ẹ pe inu ẹ ko dun. Mo kọkọ ro pe nnkan mi-in lo n ṣe e ni, afi nigba ti mo beere, ti mo ni ki lo de, ki lo n ṣe e. Lo ba ni ọrọ irẹsi yii naa ni, nigba ti a ko ti i ri awọn ti wọn yoo ko irẹsi fun wa, bawo la ṣe waa fẹẹ ṣe.Ni mo ba rẹrin-in musẹ, mo ni ṣebi oun lo ti sọ fun mi tẹlẹ pe Ọlọrun maa ṣe gbogbo ẹ ni aṣeyọri, o ni bẹẹ ni. Mo ni, “Ẹn ẹn, Ọlọrun ti ṣe e!” Ni mo ba ṣalaye fun un bo ṣe jẹ Alaaji Ṣinkafi to wa lọ si Tinkan, l’Apapa, ti ko ri funra ẹ lo pe mi o.Mo ṣalaye fun un pe bo ṣe kuro lọdọ mi yẹn, bẹẹ ni ipe Alaaji yẹn wọle. O ni ki lo waa sọ fun mi. Mo ni o n wa mi ni, koda o n ba mi ja ni. O ni ki lo de to n ba mi ja. Mo ni o n ba mi ja pe oun ti ni irẹsi lati ọjọ yii, irẹsi awọn ti wa lori omi tipẹ, emi o ba oun da si i, n o fẹẹ gba ọja tabi ki n ba oun wa awọn to maa waa ko o, pe mo waa fi oun silẹ lati ọjọ yii wa. Niṣe ni Safu pariwo, ‘Alau akbar, Alau akbar!’ Lo ba n jẹnu wuyẹwuyẹ lo n ke awọn kewu kan. Emi naa mi o mọgba ti mo bẹrẹ si i rawọ si Ọlọrun Ọba. Mo n dupẹ naa ni.Kia ni Safu ti bẹrẹ si i palẹmọ, to n tun ibi to ti tun ṣe tẹlẹ ṣe. Gbogbo eyi ti a n ṣe yii, a ko ti i pari ẹ nigba ti mọto kan duro sita, pikọọbu tuntun ni, kiakia ni Alaaji Ṣinkafi bọ silẹ niwaju ẹ, ni mo ba n sọ fun Safu pe ẹni ti a n wi niyẹn o.Safu ni ọkunrin ọhun ṣe waa dudu bii eedu bayii, to tun kuru, pẹlu ikun kẹrẹbẹtẹ, ni mo ba sọ fun un pe ko rọra sọrọ o, Ṣinkafi gbọ Yoruba taataataa o. Kia lo ti yaa yi oju ẹ si tẹrin, to fi ọyaya pade Alaaji onirẹsi yii. Nigba tiyẹn wọle naa, ija nla lo tun gbe ko mi. ‘Alaaja, ẹ ko ṣe daadaa fun mi rara! Baa ṣau walai!”Mo ṣalaye fun un pe ki i ṣe bẹẹ, mo ni ọja ni ko ta, ati ọrọ ogun onikorona yii. O ni o ye oun, ṣugbọn awọn ti fẹẹ jẹ gbese bayii, ki n mọ bi a ṣe maa waa ko o ni. Ni mo ba pe Safu si i, mo ni eelo lawọn eeyan n ṣe irẹsi bayii lọja, Safu ni ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa naira ma ni, tipatipa lawọn fi n ti ẹgbẹrun mọkanla ti i mọ wọn lọrun. Mo fẹẹ pariwo pe ‘Safuuuuuu, aye ẹ ree!’ Abi bawo leeyan ṣe n moju owo to bayii. Irẹsi to ti pe ni bii ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn fun awọn ti wọn fẹẹ ra a, to wa n sọ pe ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa si mọkanla fawọn toun fẹẹ ra a lọwọ ẹ.Ṣugbọn iyanu to wa nibẹ ni pe Alaaji Ṣinkafi ni ọrọ emi ati oun ko ni wahala ninu. Alaaji ni ko gba iye ti Safu pe e yẹn, koda ko jẹ olokuta ti wọn ko fẹ rara to jẹ kiki panti, ṣugbọn iye to ba dara ni ki n ra a lọwọ awọn, ki n ṣaa waa maa ko o kuro nibẹ. Bi mo ṣe ni ko maa lọ niyẹn. Bo ba ti di lọla, mo maa ran tirela si i. Inu ẹ ti dun ju, a lo tun fun Safu lowo, faifu taosan. O ni ki n ṣaa maa kọ iye apo irẹsi ti a ba ko silẹ, oun maa waa gbowo to ba ya. Bi mo ṣe pe awọn araabi yii ree, iyẹn awọn onirẹsi, mo ni ki wọn ṣeto tirela ranṣẹ, pe ọja wọn ti wa nilẹ. Wọn ni tireeni lawọn fẹẹ fi ko o, ki awa ṣaa ti ba awọn ko o de Ido, o pari niyẹn.Mo ni ko si owo mọto ninu owo ta a gba o, wọn ni awọn mọ. Pe awọn maa ṣẹ owo mọto mọ owo fun mi, wọn ni awọn ti beere, wọn ni tirela kan to maa n loodu simẹnti kun lati Apapa de Ido, pe ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọfa ni wọn n gba. Mo fẹẹ pariwo, ṣugbọn nigba to jẹ awọn funra wọn ni wọn sọ bẹẹ, Ọlọrun lo mọ awọn ti wọn jọ n ṣe to sọ iyẹn fun wọn. Alaaji Ṣinkafi ni mo pe pe ko wa awọn tirela ti a n lo, ko si ti de Apapa to ti maa n pade wa, ko ti ṣeto bii ogun tirela ti wọn le ko irẹsi de Ido lẹẹkan. Ti mo ba sọ fun yin pe ohun ti a fi gbogbo ọsẹ to lọ lọhun-un yẹn ṣe niyẹn nkọ!Nigba ti awọn ọrẹ mi to n ra irẹsi gbọ pe tirela ogun lo loodu lẹẹkan, ti wọn ko irẹsi wa si Ido, niṣe ni wọn tun fi owo mi-in ranṣẹ sinu akaunti mi. Emi o kuku tiẹ mọ, nitori n ko ri alaati, wọn ni nẹtiwọọku ko daa, afi nigba ti wọn pe mi ti mo lọọ wo o, mo ri i pe wọn ti fi owo irẹsi mi-in ranṣẹ, wọn san balansi eyi ti wọn ra tẹlẹ, wọn si fi ọpọlọpọ owo ti wọn ni owo tirela si i. Owo ti wọn n san lori tirela yii gan-an tooyan ṣe nnkan rere, ka ma ti i sọ owo ti irẹsi funra ẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn tun n sọ pe awọn tun maa fẹ iye apo irẹsi ti awọn ra yẹn si i. Owo naa pọ ju.Ohun to jẹ ki n rẹrin-in de ọfiisi lọọya mi ree, emi ati Sẹki ati Safu, aago mẹrin irọlẹ ko ti i lu ti awa fi debẹ, nitori asiko ti wọn fi ipade naa si niyẹn. Ṣugbọn bo tilẹ jẹ pe aago naa ko ti i lu, awọn eeyan yẹn ti de sọdọ lọọya, ko sẹni kan to ṣẹku ninu wọn. Nitori ẹ lo ṣe jẹ nigba ti wọn ni mo de bayii, niṣe ni awọn lọọya yẹn sare waa pade mi, ti wọn fi mi si yara ọtọ. Wọn ni ki n jokoo, pe awọn maa lọọ sanwo fun wọn, ki n kọ ṣẹẹki, awọn maa gbawee waa ba mi lẹyin ti a ba ti ṣe gbogbo eto, lẹyin naa la maa too maa rira wa.Bi awa ṣe fun wọn ni ṣẹẹki ti wọn lọ niyẹn. Ko pẹ ni wọn gbe iwe de, bi wọn ṣe gbe iwe de, a ri i pe wọn ti sain sibẹ, n lemi naa ba sain ati awọn ọmọ mi. Lẹyin iyẹn ni wọn tun lọ, wọn ṣẹṣẹ waa pada waa pe mi nigba to ya. Awọn araabi yẹn ko le gba oju wọn gbọ nigba ti wọn ri i pe emi ni. “Iya Biọla! Iya Biọla! Haa, Iya Biọla!” Bi wọn ṣe n pariwo niyẹn. Emi naa yaa kunlẹ fun wọn, gbogbo wọn ni mo ki tọyaya-tọyaya.Wọn ya fọto wa, wọn fidio wa, ni gbogbo ẹ ba pari. Lawọn iya yẹn ati awọn baba wọn ba ṣeṣe waa bẹrẹ.Wọn ni owo ilẹ baba awọn lawọn gba yẹn, ṣugbọn awọn fẹẹ gbowo ti Iya Biọla, nitori eeyan awọn ni, ọmọ awọn ni, ẹgbọn awọn ni, aburo awọn ni. Ni mo ba ni ki Safu ba mi gbe baagi, ni mo ba yọ idi kan ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un, ni mo ba gbe e le wọn lọwọ. Kẹ ẹ waa maa gbọ ariwo, kẹẹ waa maa gbọ adura, adua n rọ bii ojo lẹnu wọn ni. Inu emi naa dun gan-an, nitori mo ri i pe tidunnu-tidunnu ni gbogbo wọn fi tuka nijọ yẹn. Bi mo ṣe ra ilẹ ṣọọbu mi l’Oṣodi ree o."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn tun ji awọn oyinbo mẹta gbe l’Akoko","answer":"Awọn oyinbo mẹta to n mojuto atunṣe ọna Ikaram si Akunnu Akoko, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Ila-Oorun Akoko, lawọn agbebọn kan ti ji gbe sa lọ lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe iṣẹlẹ yii waye lẹyin tawọn oyinbo agbaṣẹṣe ọhun ti ṣiwọ iṣẹ ọjọ naa ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa aabọ irọlẹ.Awọn ọlọdẹ ibilẹ, fijilante atawọn ọlọpaa agbegbe Akoko la gbọ pe wọn ti wa ninu igbo to wa lagbegbe naa lati ṣawari awọn ti wọn ji gbe ọhun lọnakọna.Ko ti i ju bii ọjọ mẹta sẹyin ti wọn ji awọn ero inu ambulansi kan gbe laarin Ajọwa Akoko si Iyere, nipinlẹ Kogi, ti wọn ko si ti i mọ ibi tawọn eeyan ọhun wọlẹ si titi di ba a ṣe n sọrọ yii.Akala ti Ikaram, Ọba Andrew Mọmọdu, ti rọ ijọba lati ko ọpọlọpọ ẹsọ alaabo wa si agbegbe naa kọwọ le tete tẹ awọn onisẹẹbi ọhun ki wọn too ṣe awọn to wa ni igbekun wọn leṣe. Adele ọga agba ọlọpaa to n mojuto ẹkun Ikarẹ Akoko, Ọgbẹni Timibra Toikima, rọ awọn araalu lati fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu awọn ẹsọ alaabo, ki wọn si tete waa fẹjọ ẹnikẹni ti wọn ba fura si sun ni teṣan."},{"question":"サッカーの勝ち負けを予想し当てるスポーツ復興くじ。通称カタカナ２文字で何とよばれているでしょうか？","answer":"トトです。"},{"question":"Sobre o quê esse texto fala: Os cenários dos primeiros títulos da série \\"Call of Duty\\", suas expansões e \\"spin-off\\" são centrados nos campos de batalha da Segunda Guerra Mundial, com o jogador na maioria das vezes controlando um soldado pertencente as forças Aliadas. Exemplos claros são: a Batalha da Normandia e Falaise por parte dos Aliados (\\"Call of Duty 3\\"), a Batalha de Stalingrado por parte da União Soviética (\\"Call of Duty\\", ' e \\"Call of Duty 2\\"), Batalha das Ardenas na Bélgica ('), Segunda Batalha de El Alamein no Egito (\\"Call of Duty 2\\"), Operação Husky , Operação Market Garden, a batalha do Rio Escalda e a Operação Varsity ,entre outras.","answer":"Exemplos de cenários em jogos eletrônicos."},{"question":"¿Qué sistema político rige en Cuba?","answer":"Cuba tiene un sistema político de partido único basado en el comunismo, donde el Partido Comunista de Cuba (PCC) desempeña un papel central en la toma de decisiones políticas. El sistema político de Cuba se caracteriza por la ausencia de elecciones multipartidistas y la concentración del poder en el PCC. El líder del PCC también ocupa el cargo de Presidente del Consejo de Estado y Presidente del Consejo de Ministros, lo que en la práctica le confiere un poder significativo.Cuba ha estado gobernada por el PCC desde la Revolución Cubana en 1959, liderada por Fidel Castro. El sistema político cubano ha sido objeto de debate y controversia a lo largo de los años debido a las restricciones a la libertad política y las libertades civiles."},{"question":"কম্পিউটার আবিষ্কারের সংক্ষিপ্ত ইতিহাস বলো।","answer":"কম্পিউটার শব্দের অর্থ গণনাকারী যন্ত্র। এটি এমন এক যন্ত্র, যা তথ্য গ্রহণ করে এবং বিভিন্ন প্রক্রিয়ার মাধ্যমে তা বিশ্লেষণ ও উপস্থাপন করে। সভ্যতার বিকাশ ও দ্রুত অগ্রগতির মূলে রয়েছে কম্পিউটারের প্রবল প্রভাব।খ্রিস্টপূর্ব ২৪০০ সালে ব্যাবিলনে আবিষ্কৃত অ্যাবাকাস থেকেই কম্পিউটারের ইতিহাসের শুরু। পরবর্তী সময়ে ১৬১৬ সালে গণিতবিদ জন নেপিয়ারের গণনার কাজে অবদান, ১৬৪২ সালে ফরাসি বিজ্ঞানী রেইজ প্যাসকেলের যান্ত্রিক ক্যালকুলেটর আবিষ্কার, ১৬৭১ সালে জার্মান গণিতবিদ গটফ্রাইড ভন লিবনিজের 'রিকোনিং যন্ত্র' আবিষ্কার এবং ১৮৩৩ সালে চার্লস ব্যাবেজের 'অ্যানালিটিক্যাল ইঞ্জিন' আবিষ্কার কম্পিউটারের বিকাশে বিশেষ ভূমিকা রাখে। এভাবে বিশ শতকের মধ্যভাগে আধুনিক কম্পিউটারের বিকাশ ঘটতে শুরু করে। প্রথম ডিজিটাল কম্পিউটারের নাম মার্ক-১।১৯৭১ সালে মাইক্রোপ্রসেসর আবিষ্কারের ফলে মাইক্রো কম্পিউটারের দ্রুত বিকাশ ঘটতে থাকে। প্রথম মাইক্রো কম্পিউটার 'অলটিয়ার ৮৮০০' তৈরি করা হয় ১৯৭৫ সালে।বাংলাদেশে কম্পিউটার ব্যবহারের সূচনা হয় ষাটের দশকে এবং নব্বই-এর দশকে তা ব্যাপকতা লাভ করে। সেই সাথে কম্পিউটারের আকৃতি ও কার্যক্ষমতায় এক বিরাট বিপ্লব সাধিত হয়। বর্তমানে অফিস, কল-কারখানা, এমনকি আবাসস্থল সর্বত্র কম্পিউটারের নানাবিধ প্রয়োগ কাজকে করেছে সহজ ও গতিশীল। বর্তমানের আধুনিক প্রযুক্তিনির্ভর জীবনব্যবস্থা কম্পিউটারেরই দান।"},{"question":"ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරඟවලදී ලකුණු නොලබා දැවීගිය , පළමුවැනි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පිතිකරුවා කවුද ?","answer":"ටෙස්ට් ක්‍රිකට් තරඟවලදී ලකුණු නොලබා දැවීගිය , පළමුවැනි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික පිතිකරුවා රෝයි ඩයස්ය (එංගලන්තයට එරෙහිව)."},{"question":"Tadiavo ny fehezan-kevitra mandrafitra ity fehezan-teny ity:\\"Nandoto ny tokon-tany izahay ka nosazin'i neny.\\"","answer":"Io fehezan-teny io dia azo zaraina ho fehezan-kevitra roa:-Nandoto ny tokon-tany izahay.-nosazin'i neny."},{"question":"Ba ci kanam","answer":"Ba ci kanam"},{"question":"Nganong maglain man akong pamati kung mokaon ko'g daghang chocolate?","answer":"Ang mga pagkaong daghan og sugar sama sa chocolate o mga candy kay makapataas sa imohang dopamine, usa ka neurotransmitter, nga makatabang nga mahimo kang energized og malipay. Pero, kung mawala na ang taas kaayo nga level sa imong dopamine o ma \\"crash,\\" ang bation pod sa imohang lawas kay ang opposite: kapuyon ka, saputon, og mahutdan og gana. Tungod ni kay ang dopamine usa sa mga nagregulate sa mood, motivation, og pleasure sa tawo. Kung atoang ipasaka og kalit ang levels, dako atong mabati nga gana, pero dako pod ang pagkakapoy nga mabati nato inig kahurot sa dopamine."},{"question":"На какой вопрос отвечает этот текст: Большеберцовая кость является крупнейшей и сильнейшей из двух костей в ноге ниже колены у позвоночных (другая - фибула) и соединяет колено с костями лодыжки. Она вторая по размерам кость в теле человека (после бедренной).Тема: Большеберцовая костьНа какой вопрос отвечает этот текст: Большеберцовая кость является крупнейшей и сильнейшей из двух костей в ноге ниже колены у позвоночных (другая - фибула) и соединяет колено с костями лодыжки. Она вторая по размерам кость в теле человека (после бедренной).Тема: Большеберцовая кость","answer":"Вопрос: Какая кость является крупнейшей и сильнейшей из двух костей в ноге ниже колена у позвоночных и соединяет колено с костями лодыжки?"}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:M},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:C,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},T={class:"search-container"},O={class:"card-container"},B=["disabled"],K={key:0},D={key:1};function P(e,a,s,h,t,u){const d=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",T,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",O,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,m)=>(i(),j(d,{key:m,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",D,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",K,"See more"))],8,B)):f("",!0)])}const E=g(I,[["render",P],["__scopeId","data-v-7716981e"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"people/3.md","filePath":"people/3.md"}'),L={name:"people/3.md"},G=Object.assign(L,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(E)]))}});export{F as __pageData,G as default};
